(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(ALARM CLOCK BUZZES)
-Bye.
-See you later.
Bye!
WOMAN: (ON PA)
This is a customer announcement.
The store will be closing
in five minutes. Thank you.
Oi!
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Wilson?
Wilson, I've got
the lottery money.
Wilson?
-(KNOCKING)
-You there?
Look, I can't hang about
'cause they're closing the shop.
Wilson?
(MUTTERS) Oh, come on.
(CLATTERING)
Hello?
Hello? Wilson, it's Rose.
(STAMMERS) Wilson?
(SWITCH CLICKS)
Wilson?
Wilson!
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(MUTTERING)
Oh, you're kidding me!
(CLANKING)
Is that someone
mucking about?
Who is it?
Okay. You got me.
Very funny.
Right, I've got the joke!
Whose idea was this?
Is it Derek's?
Is it?
Derek, is this you?
(WHIMPERS)
Run!
(GRUNTING)
-You pulled his arm off!
-Yep, plastic.
Very clever, nice trick.
Who are they then, students?
Is this a student thing
or what?
-Why would they be students?
-I don't know!
Well, you said it.
Why students?
'Cause... To get that many
people dressed up and being silly,
they got to be students.
That makes sense. Well done.
-Thanks.
-They're not students.
Whoever they are, when Wilson finds
them, he's going to call the police.
-Who's Wilson?
-Chief electrician.
Wilson's dead.
-That's just not funny. That's sick!
-Hold on!
-Mind your eyes.
-I've had enough of this now.
(WHIMPERS) Who are you, then?
Who's that lot down there?
I said who are they?
They're made of plastic.
Living plastic creatures.
And they're being controlled
by a relay device on the roof.
Which would be a great big
problem if I didn't have this.
So, I'm gonna go upstairs
and blow it up.
And I might well die in the
process, but don't worry about me.
No, you go home. Go on, go and have
your lovely beans on toast.
Don't tell anyone about this, 'cause
if you do, you'll get them killed.
I'm the Doctor, by the way.
-What's your name?
-Rose.
Nice to meet you, Rose.
Run for your life!
-(CAR HONKING)
-(GASPS)
(DRIVER SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(LOUD EXPLOSION)
REPORTER: The whole of Central
London has been closed off
as police investigate
the fire.
I know, it's on the telly! It's
everywhere, she's lucky to be alive.
Honestly, it's aged her.
Skin like an old Bible.
He's walking in now.
You'd think I was her daughter.
Oh, and here's himself.
I've been phoning your mobile!
You could have been dead!
It's on the news
and everything!
I can't believe
that your shop went up!
I'm all right.
Honestly, I'm fine. Don't make a fuss!
-But what happened?
-I don't know.
What was it though?
What caused it?
I wasn't in the shop.
I was outside. Didn't see anything.
It's Debbie. She knows a man on
The Mirror, 500 quid for an interview.
Oh, that's brilliant,
give it here.
(PHONE BEEPS)
You've got to find some way
of making money.
Your job's kaput
and I'm not bailing you out.
(PHONE RINGS)
Bey, she's alive!
I've told her,
sue for compensation.
She was within
seconds of death!
What are you drinking, tea? No, no, no.
That's no good! That's no good!
You're in shock.
-You need something stronger.
-I'm all right.
Now, come one. You deserve a proper
drink. We're going down the pub.
You and me, my treat.
How about it?
Is there a match on?
No, no.
I'm just thinking about you!
There's a match on,
ain't there?
Well that's not the point. But we
could catch the last five minutes.
Go on, then.
I'm fine, really, go.
And get rid of that.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-Bye-bye.
-Bye!
(IMITATES CHOKING)
Fifteen fire crews are
in attendance,
though it's thought there's very little
chance of saving the infrastructure.
(MAN AND WOMAN ARGUING)
(ALARM CLOCK BUZZES)
There's no point in getting up,
sweetheart. You've no job to go to.
There's Finch's.
You could try them.
-They've always got jobs.
-Oh, great, the butcher's.
It might do you good. That shop
was giving you airs and graces.
I'm not joking about
compensation.
You've had genuine
shock and trauma.
Ariana got two thousand
quid off the council
just because the old man behind
the desk said she looked Greek!
I know she is Greek,
but that's not the point.
It was a valid claim.
(RATTLING)
(PATTERING)
Mum, you're such a liar!
I said to nail that cat-flap down.
We're gonna get strays!
-I did it weeks back.
-Nah, you thought about it.
(RATTLES)
(GASPS)
-What are you doing here?
-I live here.
-What do you do that for?
-'Cause I do!
I'm only home
"cause someone blew up my job!
Must have got
the wrong signal.
You're not plastic,
are you? Nope, bonehead. Bye, then!
You, inside, right now.
Who is it?
It's about last night. He's part
of the inquiry. Give us 10 minutes.
She deserves compensation!
Oh, we're talking millions.
I'm... (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm in my dressing gown.
Yes, you are.
There's a strange man
in my bedroom.
Yes, there is.
Well, anything could happen.
No.
Don't mind the mess.
Do you want a coffee?
Might as well, thanks,
just milk.
We should go
to the police.
Seriously.
Both of us.
That won't last.
He's gay and she's an alien.
I'm not blaming you, even if
it was some sort of joke...
Mmm. Sad ending.
-It said on the news they found a body.
-"Rose Tyler."
Ah, could've been worse.
Look at the ears!
...all the same, he was nice.
He was a nice bloke.
Anyway, if we are gonna
go to the police,
I wanna know
what I'm saying.
-I want you to explain everything.
-Maybe not.
-(PATTERING)
-What's that then?
Have you got a cat?
No.
We did have, but we just get
strays. They come in off the estate.
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
I told Mickey
to chuck that out.
You're all the same.
Give a man a plastic hand...
Anyway, I don't even
know your name. Doctor what was it?
(SHRIEKS)
(HAIR BLOWER WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
It's all right,
I've stopped it.
-There you go, you see, arm less!
-Do you think?
Ow!
ROSE: Hold on a minute,
you can't just go swanning off!
Yes. I can. Here I am.
This is me, swanning off, see ya!
ROSE: That arm was moving,
it tried to kill me!
DOCTOR: Ten out of ten
for observation.
You can't just walk away.
That's not fair.
You've got to tell me
what's going on.
No, I don't.
All right, then. I'll go
to the police. I'll tell everyone.
You said if I did that
I'd get people killed, so, your choice.
Tell me or I'll start talking.
-Is that supposed to sound tough?
-Sort of.
Doesn't work.
-Who are you?
-Told you, the Doctor.
Yeah, but Doctor what?
-Just the Doctor.
-The Doctor?
Hello!
Is that supposed
to sound impressive?
Sort of.
Come on then,
you can tell me. I've seen enough.
-Are you the police?
-No! I was just passing through.
I'm a long way from home...
What have I done wrong? How come those
plastic things keep coming after me?
Oh, suddenly
the entire world revolves around you.
You were just an accident.
You got in the way, that's all.
-It tried to kill me!
-It was after me, not you!
Last night, in the shop,
I was there, you blundered in,
almost ruined the whole thing.
This morning, I was tracking it
down, it was tracking me down...
The only reason it fixed
on you is because you met me.
So, what you're saying
is the entire world revolves around you?
-Sort of, yeah.
-You're full of it!
Sort of, yeah.
All this plastic stuff,
who else knows about it?
No one.
What, you're on your own?
Well, who else is there? I mean,
you lot, all you do is eat chips,
got to bed and watch telly,
while all the time
underneath you, there's a war going on.
Okay. Start from
the beginning.
I mean, if we're going with the living
plastic, and I don't even believe that,
but if we do...
How did you kill it?
The thing controlling it projects life
into the arm. Cut off the signal - dead.
-So, that's radio control?
-Thought control.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
So who's
controlling it, then?
-Long story.
-What's it all for?
I mean, shop window dummies,
what's that about?
Is someone trying
to take over Britain's shops?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
No!
-Well, no!
-It's not a price war.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
They want to overthrow
the human race and destroy you.
-Do you believe me?
-No.
But you're still listening.
Really, though, Doctor,
tell me, who are you?
Do you know like we were saying?
About the Earth revolving?
It's like when you're a kid.
The first time they tell you
that the world's turning
and you just can't quite believe it
'cause everything looks
like it's standing still.
I can feel it.
The turn of the Earth.
The ground beneath our feet
is spinning at 1,000 miles an hour.
And the entire planet is hurtling
round the sun at 67,000 miles an hour.
I can feel it,
we're falling through space, you and me.
Clinging to the skin of this
tiny little world, and if we let go...
That's who I am.
Now forget me, Rose Tyler.
Go home.
(WIND BLOWING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-Hey, here's my woman! Kit off.
-Oh, shut up.
-Coffee?
-Yeah, only if you wash the mug.
And I don't mean rinse,
I mean wash. Can I use your computer?
Yeah, any excuse
to get in the bedroom.
Don't read my e-mails!
ROSE: You're not
coming in.
He's safe, he's got
a wife and kids.
Yeah, who told you that?
He did. That's exactly what an
internet lunatic murderer would say.
(KNOCKING)
(SIGHS)
Um, hello, I've come
to see Clive. We've been e-mailing.
Oh, Dad! It's one
of your nutters.
Sorry, hello!
You must be Rose. I'm Clive. Obviously.
I'd better tell you now,
my boyfriend's in the car,
just in case you're gonna
kill me!
(LAUGHS) No, good point!
No murders!
WOMAN: Who is it?
Oh, it's something to do
with the Doctor.
She's been reading
the website.
Please come through.
I'm in the shed.
She? She's read a website
about the Doctor, she's a she?
CLIVE: A lot of this stuff is
quite sensitive,
I couldn't just send it to you.
People might intercept...
If you know what I mean.
If you dig deep enough
and keep a lively mind,
this Doctor keeps
cropping up all over the place.
Political diaries,
conspiracy theories, even ghost stories.
No first name, no last name,
just "the Doctor”.
Always the Doctor.
And the title seems to be
passed down from father to son,
appears to be
an inheritance.
That's your Doctor
there, isn't it?
Yeah.
I tracked it down to the Washington
Public Archive, just last year.
The online photo's enhanced,
but if we look at the original...
November 22nd 1963,
the assassination of President Kennedy.
See?
Must be his father.
Going further back,
April 1912,
this is a photograph of
the Daniels family of Southampton
and friend.
Taken the day before they were due to
sail to the new world. On the Titanic.
And for some unknown reason,
they cancelled the trip, and survived.
And here we are,
1883, another Doctor.
Look, the same lineage,
he's identical.
This one washed up
on the coast of Sumatra,
and the very night
the Krakatoa exploded.
The Doctor is a legend
woven throughout history.
When disaster comes,
he's there.
He brings the storm
in his wake.
-And he has one constant companion.
-Who's that?
Death.
If the Doctor's back,
if you've seen him, Rose,
then one thing's for certain.
We're all in danger.
Come on then.
If he singled you out,
if the Doctor's making house calls,
then God help you.
(BIN GROWLS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(BIN BELCHES)
But who is he?
Who do you think he is?
I think he's the same man.
I think he's immortal.
I think he's an alien
from another world.
All right, he's a nutter.
Off his head.
Complete online
conspiracy freak, you win!
(SIGHS) What are we
going to do tonight?
I fancy a pizza.
Pizza! (STAMMERING)
-Pizza!
-Or Chinese.
Pizza!
Do you think I should
try the hospital?
Suki said they had jobs going
in the canteen.
Is that it then,
dishing out chips?
I could do A-levels.
I don't know.
It's all Jimmy Stone's fault.
I went and left school
because of him, look where I ended up.
What do you think?
So where did you
meet this Doctor?
I'm sorry,
was I talking about me for a second?
'Cause I reckon it all
started back at the shop, am I right?
-Was he something to do with that?
-No.
Come on.
Sort of.
What was he doing there?
I'm not going on about it,
Mickey, really I'm not.
'Cause I know it
sounds daft, but,
I don't think he's safe.
-He's dangerous.
-But you can trust me, sweetheart.
(MALFUNCTIONING ROBOTIC VOICE)
Babe, darling, sugar...
You can tell me anything. Tell me about
the Doctor and what he's planning,
and I can help you, Rose.
That's all I want to do,
sweetheart.
Darling, babe, babe,
sugar, sweetheart.
What are you doing that for?
-Your champagne.
-We didn't order any champagne.
-Where's the Doctor?
-Madam, your champagne.
It's not ours.
Mickey, what is it, what's wrong?
I need to find out
how much he knows, so where is he?
-Doesn't anybody want this champagne?
-Look, we didn't order...
-Ah, got you.
-Don't mind me.
I'm just toasting
the happy couple.
On the house!
Anyway!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Don't think that's
gonna stop me.
(SCREAMS)
-(ALARM RINGS)
-Everyone, out! Out now!
Get out, get out, get out!
Open the gate!
Use that tube thing! Come on!
-Sonic screwdriver.
-Use it!
Nah, tell you what,
let's go in here.
You can't hide
inside a wooden box!
He's gonna get us!
Doctor!
It's gonna follow us.
The assembled hordes of Genghis Khan
couldn't get through that door.
Believe me, they've tried!
Now, shut up a minute.
You see, the arm
was too simple, but the head's perfect.
I can use it to trace
the signal back to the original source.
Right. Where do you
want to start?
Um... The inside's bigger
than the outside.
-Yes.
-It's alien.
Yep.
Are you alien?
Yes.
-Is that all right?
-Yeah.
It's called the Tardis,
this thing.
T-A-R-D-I-S, that's Time And
Relative Dimension In Space.
(SOBBING)
That's okay. Culture shock.
-Happens to the best of us.
-Did they kill him? Mickey?
Did they kill Mickey?
Is he dead?
Oh, I didn't think of that.
He's my boyfriend.
You pulled off his head.
They copied him,
and you didn't even think.
-And now you're just gonna let him melt.
-Melt?
Aw, no, no, no, no!
-What are you doing?
-Following the signal. It's fading!
Wait a minute.
I've got it.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Almost there, almost there.
Here we go!
(RUMBLING)
You can't go out there.
It's not safe!
I lost the signal.
I got so close.
(DOOR SLAMS)
We've moved.
Does it fly?
It disappears there and reappears
here. You wouldn't understand.
But if we're somewhere else, what about
that headless thing that's on the loose?
Melted with the head.
Are you going to witter on all night?
I'LL have to tell his mother.
Mickey... I'll have to
tell his mother he's dead,
and you just went and
forgot him, again!
You were right.
You are alien.
-If I forgot some kid called Mickey...
-He's not a kid!
...it's because I'm trying
to save the life of every stupid ape
blundering about
on this planet, all right?
-All right?
-Yes, it is!
If you are an alien, why do you
sound like you're from the north?
Lots of planets have a north!
(STAMMERS) What's a police
public call box?
It's a telephone box,
from the 1950s. It's a disguise.
(CHUCKLES) Okay... And, this living
plastic, what's it got against us?
Nothing. It loves you. You've got such
a good planet, lots of smoke and oil,
plenty of toxins and dioxins
in the air. Perfect.
Just what the Nestene
Consciousness needs.
Its food stock was destroyed in the
war, its protein planets rotted.
-So. Earth. Dinner.
-Any way of stopping it?
Antiplastic.
-Antiplastic?
-Antiplastic!
But first,
I've got to find it.
How can you hide
something that big in a city this small?
-Hold on, hide what?
-The transmitter.
The Consciousness is controlling
every single piece of plastic,
so it needs a transmitter
to boost the signal.
-What does it look like?
-Like a transmitter!
Round and massive, somewhere
slap-bang in the middle of London.
A huge, metal, circular structure
like a dish, like a wheel, radial,
close to where we're standing.
It must be
completely invisible.
What?
What is it? What?
Oh.
Fantastic!
Think of it.
Plastic all over the world,
every artificial thing
waiting to be alive.
The shop window dummies,
the phones, the wires, the cables.
The breast implants.
Still, we've found
the transmitter.
The Consciousness must be
somewhere underneath.
What about down here?
Looks good to me.
The Nestene Consciousness.
That's it, inside the vat,
a living plastic creature.
Well then, tip in
your Antiplastic and let's go.
I'm not here to kill it.
I've got to give it a chance.
I seek audience with the Nestene
Consciousness under peaceful contract
according to Convention 15
of the Shadow Proclamation.
(GURGLES)
Thank you. If I might have
permission to approach.
Oh, my God.
Mickey! It's me!
It's okay.
-It's all right. It's all right.
-Shhh.
That thing, down there...
The liquid, Rose, it can talk!
Oh, you're stinking!
Doctor, they kept him alive!
Yeah, that was always a possibility,
keep him alive to maintain the copy.
You knew that and never said?
Can we keep the domestics
outside, thank you?
(NESTENE GURGLING)
Am I addressing
the Consciousness?
Thank you.
If I might observe,
you infiltrated this civilization by
means of warped, shunt technology.
So, may I suggest, with the greatest
respect, that you shunt off?
(GROWLING)
Oh, don't give me that!
It's an invasion, plain and simple.
Don't talk about
constitutional rights.
I am talking!
This planet is just starting.
These stupid little people
have only just learned how to walk.
But they're capable
of so much more.
I'm asking you,
on their behalf. Please, just go.
Doctor!
That was just insurance!
I wasn't gonna use it.
(GROWLING)
I was not attacking you.
I'm here to help.
I'm not your enemy,
I swear, I'm not.
What do you mean?
No, no, no! Honestly, no.
Yes, that's my ship.
(SQUEALING)
That's not true!
I should know, I was there.
I fought in the war. It wasn't my fault.
I couldn't save your world.
I couldn't save any of them.
-What's it doing?
-It's the Tardis.
The Nestene's identified it
as superior technology. It's terrified!
It's going to the final base.
It's starting the invasion.
Get out, Rose! Just leg it, now!
(CONTINUES SQUEALING)
-Mum?
-There you are! I was just gonna phone.
You can get compensation,
I said so.
I've got this document
thing off the police, don't thank me...
-Where are you, Mum?
-I'm in town.
Look, just go home!
Just go home right now.
Darling, you're breaking up. I'm just
gonna do a bit of late night shopping
I'll see you later. Ta-ra!
Mum? Mum?
It's the activation signal!
It's transmitting.
It's the end of the world.
There's no point
creating a spreadsheet
if you're gonna spend
summer money in winter months.
(GASPS) Oh, my God!
I thought they were dummies!
I nearly had a heart attack.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
It's true.
Everything I've read,
all those stories, it's all true!
(SCREAMING)
(SQUEALING)
Get out, Rose! Just get out!
Run!
ROSE: The stairs have gone.
I haven't got the key.
MICKEY: We're gonna die!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(CAR HONKING)
(SCREAMS)
NESTENE: Time Lord!
Leave him!
There's nothing you can do!
I've got no A-levels.
No job.
No future.
But I'll tell you what I have got.
Jericho Street Junior School
under-sevens gymnastics team.
I got the bronze!
(GRUNTS)
(SQUEALING)
Rose!
Now we're in trouble!
(ALARM BELL RINGING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(MAN COUGHING)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(SIREN WAILING
IN THE DISTANCE)
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Rose, don't go out
of the house, it's not safe!
There are these things,
they were shooting and...
Hello? Hello?
Fat lot of good you were!
(WHIMPERING)
Nestene Consciousness?
Easy!
You were useless in there!
You'd be dead if it wasn't for me.
Yes, I would.
Thank you.
Right, then! I'll be off.
Unless... I don't know.
You could come with me.
This box isn't just
a London-op, you know,
it goes anywhere
in the universe.
Free of charge.
Don't! He's an alien.
He's a thing.
He's not invited.
What do you think?
You could stay here.
Fill your life with work
and food and sleep, or you could go...
Anywhere.
-Is it always this dangerous?
-Yeah.
Yeah, I can't.
I've gotta go and
find my mum,
and someone's gotta look after
this stupid lump, so...
Okay.
See you around.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Come on, let's go.
Come on. Come on.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
By the way, did I mention
it also travels in time?
-Thanks.
-Thanks for what?
Exactly.
This is the year five billion,
and this is the day...
Hold on...
Welcome to
the end of the world.
Who the hell are you?
Oh, I'm the Doctor,
this is Rose Tyler.
She's my plus one,
is that all right?
Representing
the Forest of Cheam,
we have Trees,
the Moxx of Balhoon,
the Face of Boe, the last human,
the Lady Cassandra O'Brien.
Oh, now, don't stare,
look how thin I am.
That's not supposed to happen.