(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(WHISTLING)
-Hey, you.
-Hey!
Listen, can we talk?
Rory!
No, shut up.
I've just got a question, that's all.
-You okay up there?
-Yeah, fine. No problem.
-What are you doing?
-Helping the Doctor. Um, it's humming.
-Is that okay?
-Yeah, it's fine.
We're just entering conceptual space.
Imagine a banana or anything curved...
Actually don't,
"cause it's not curved or like a banana.
Forget the banana!
Uh, is he helping you fly the Tardis?
Attach thermo couplings two,
seven and 11,
like I showed you.
How come he gets a go?
You never let me have a go.
RORY: Uh, Doctor, don't.
-Seriously, I let her drive my car once.
-Yeah, to the end of the road!
Where, according to Amy,
there was an "unexpected house".
Oh, he's jealous because I passed
my test first time.
-You cheated. You wore a skirt.
-I didn't wear a skirt.
-Well, luck would have worked, too.
-No, no,
I did wear a skirt,
but it was any old skirt.
-You ever seen Amy drive, Doctor?
-No.
Neither did her driving examiner.
Actually, it was this one.
It was this skirt!
(CRASHING)
-What was that?
-Rory!
Did you drop a thermo coupling?
-Sorry.
-Ah! How did you do that?
I told you, "Don't drop them.”
I specifically mentioned
not dropping them.
-It was my fault.
-Of course it wasn't your fault.
-It kind of was her fault.
-How could it be her fault?
Because it was my skirt
and my husband and your glass floor.
Oh, Rory!
-Sorry.
-Well, we've landed.
Emergency materialisation.
It should be fine,
should have locked onto the
safest space available.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
AMY: Doctor, what's happened?
The safest spot available. The Tardis
has materialised inside itself.
-Is that supposed to happen?
-Take a guess.
RORY: No?
DOCTOR: That's the one.
Whoa, what are you doing?
I have absolutely no idea.
Okay, that is a bit weird.
-That is actually pretty cool.
-Oh, I'm glad you're entertained, Rory.
Now that we're stuck here for all
eternity, at least you won't be bored.
Wait, what? We're stuck?
The inside of the Tardis is now joined
to the outside of the Tardis.
Worse than a time loop, a space loop.
Nothing can enter or leave this ship
ever again.
(DOOR OPENING)
Okay, kids,
this is where it gets complicated.