Greetings, Mr Castavilian, I take it.
Yes, Davros. An honour
to work for you, sir.
Then allow me to show you the
future of our beloved Kaled race.
Go, my Mark III travel machine.
The war has caused
the Kaled race to mutate,
but within this
casing we can evolve.
We can start anew. We can
become stronger than ever.
We will become the
supreme race in the universe!
Observe a bonded polycarbide
shell, a ruby-ray blaster,
and a multi-dextrous claw capable
of annihilating a million foes.
My ultimate masterpiece of design!
Yes, I did some research on the name, sir.
Since we're called Kaleds, I thought our
future selves could be an anagram of Kaled.
Like... Lekad?
No.
Adlek?
Klaid?
No.
Adleka?
Davros, I need your confirmation
to begin the next bombardment, sir.
One moment. And touch
nothing. Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
Adlek.
Hello.
Just passing by because I got a bit lost.
It's funny. Sixty minutes
ago I was this really brilliant
woman, and now I've got
this old face back again.
I mean, why?
Why? I ask of you, my
brand new friend. Why?
You're a bit of a puzzle.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
No...
I am so, so sorry. I think I broke this...
multi-claw adaptable...
What is it?
Oh.
That's a Dalek.
Good word.
Dalek.
Yes, that's it.
I'm lucky I wasn't exterminated.
Exterminated? Yes. Yes. Good word. Great.
Wait a minute. Do you mean
this is the genesis of the Daleks?
Oh, this is the stuff.
Thank you. Thank you.
No, no, no. Stop it. Look. I
was never ever here. Never.
The timelines of the
canon are rupturing. I'm just
going to go, and you're not
going to say a word. Okay?
No, but you broke the
multi-claw adaptable thingy-majig.
Oh, yeah.
Right.
Hold on.
Never here.
Ah, where were we, Mr. Cassivilian?
Ah, the splendid design of my secondary.
I like it.