Aargh!
(HE GRUNTS)
(BIG BEN STRIKES)
Aaargh!
(HE SIGHS)
YOUNG GIRL: Dear Santa, thank you
for the dolls and pencils and the fish.
It's Easter now,
so I hope I didn't wake you.
But honest, it is an emergency.
There's a crack in my wall.
Aunt Sharon says
it's just an ordinary crack, but...
I know it's not, because...
at night, there's voices.
So please, please,
could you send someone to fix it?
Or a policeman. Or...
(METALLIC THRUMMING OUTSIDE)
(CRASH!)
Back in a moment.
Thank you, Santa.
Can I have an apple?
All I can think about - apples.
I love apples.
Maybe I'm having a craving.
That's new -
never had cravings before.
Whoa!
Look at that!
Are you OK?
Just had a fall. All the way down there,
right to the library.
Hell of a climb back up.
- You're soaking wet.
- I was in the swimming pool.
- You said you were in the library.
- So was the swimming pool.
- Are you a policeman?
- Why?
Did you call a policeman?
Did you come about
the crack in my wall?
What cra...? Argh!
Are you all right, mister?
No, I'm fine, it's OK.
This is all perfectly norm...
Who are you?
I don't know yet. I'm still cooking.
Does it scare you?
No, it just looks a bit weird.
No, no, no. The crack in your wall.
- Does it scare you?
- Yes.
Well, then, no time to lose.
I'm the Doctor.
Do everything I tell you,
don't ask stupid questions
and don't wander off.
Are you all right?
Early days.
Steering's a bit off.
If you're a doctor,
why does your box say Police?
(HE COUGHS)
That's disgusting. What is that?
- An apple.
- Apples are rubbish. I hate apples.
You said you loved them.
No, no, I love yoghurt. Yoghurt's
my favourite. Give me yoghurt.
I hate yoghurt,
it's just stuff with bits in.
- You said it was your favourite.
- New mouth, new rules.
It's like eating after cleaning your
teeth, everything tastes...wro-agh!
What is it? What's wrong with you?
Wrong with me? It's not my fault.
Why can't you give me decent food?
You're Scottish - fry something.
Ah! Bacon!
Bacon.
That's bacon.
Are you trying to poison me?
Ah. You see? Beans.
Beans are evil. Bad, bad beans.
Bread and butter.
Now you're talking.
- (PLATE SMASHES, CAT MIAOWS)
- And stay out!
We've got some carrots.
Carrots? Are you insane?
No, wait, hang on.
I know what I need.
I need...I need...I need...
fish fingers and custard.
- Funny.
- Am I?
Good. Funny's good.
- What's your name?
- Amelia Pond.
Ah, that's a brilliant name.
"Amelia Pond",
like a name in a fairy tale.
Are we in Scotland, Amelia?
No. Had to move to England.
It's rubbish.
So what about your mum and dad, then?
Are they upstairs?
- Thought we'd have woken them by now.
- I don't have a mum and dad.
Just an aunt.
I don't even have an aunt.
You're lucky.
I know.
So, your aunt.
Where is she?
She's out.
And she left you all alone?
- I'm not scared.
- You're not scared of anything!
Box falls out of the sky, man falls
out of box, man eats fish custard,
and look at you,
just sitting there.
- So you know what I think?
- What?
Must be a hell of a scary crack
in your wall.
You've had some cowboys in here.
Not actual cowboys,
though that can happen.
I used to hate apples,
so my mum put faces on them.
She sounds good, your mum.
I'll keep it for later.
This wall is solid and the crack
doesn't go all the way through it.
So here's a thing -
where's the draught coming from?
Wibbly-wobbly, timey-wimey.
You know what the crack is?
What?
It's a crack.
I'll tell you something funny.
If you knocked this wall down,
the crack would stay put,
cos the crack isn't in the wall.
- Where is it, then?
- Everywhere.
In everything. It's a split
in the skin of the world.
Two parts of space and time
that should never have touched,
pressed together...
...right here in the wall
of your bedroom.
- Sometimes, can you hear...?
- A voice.
Yes.
(ECHOING VOICE)
Prisoner Zero has escaped.
- Prisoner Zero?
- "Prisoner Zero has escaped."”
That's what I heard.
What does it mean?
Prisoner Zero has escaped.
It means that, on the other side
of this wall, there's a prison
and they've lost a prisoner.
Do you know what that means?
- What?
- You need a better wall.
The only way to close the breach
is to open it all the way.
The forces will invert
and it'll snap itself shut.
- Or...
- What?
You know when grown-ups tell you
everything's going to be fine
and you think they're probably lying
to make you feel better?
Yes.
Everything's going to be fine.
Prisoner Zero has escaped.
Hello?
Hello!
What's that?
There. You see, told you it would close.
Good as new.
What was that thing?
Was that Prisoner Zero?
No. I think that was
Prisoner Zero's guard.
Whatever it was, it sent me
a message. Psychic paper -
takes a lovely little message.
"Prisoner Zero has escaped.”
But why tell us?
Unless...
Unless what?
Unless Prisoner Zero
escaped through here.
But he couldn't have.
We'd know.
It's difficult.
Brand-new me, nothing works yet.
But there's something
I'm missing...
...in the corner...
...of my eye.
(ECHOED BANGING)
No, no, no, no, no, no!
I've got to get back in there.
The engines are phasing.
It's going to burn!
But...
...it's just a box!
- How can a box have engines?
- It's not a box.
It's a time machine.
What, a real one?
You've got a real time machine?
Not for much longer
if I can't get her stabilised.
Five-minute hop into the future
should do it.
Can I come?
Not safe in here, not yet. Five minutes.
Give me five minutes.
I'll be right back.
People always say that.
Am I people?
Do I even look like people?
Trust me.
I'm the Doctor.
Geronimo!
(SPLASH!)
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
(CLOCK TICKS)
Amelia!
Amelia, I worked out what it was.
I know what I was missing!
You've got to get out of there!
Amelia?
Amelia, are you all right?
Are you there?
Prisoner Zero is here.
Prisoner Zero is here!
Do you understand me?
Prisoner Zero is...
(SIREN BLARES)
So...they all called out at once,
that's what you're saying?
All of them, all the coma patients.
You do understand that these people
are all comatose, don't you?
- They can't speak.
- Yes, Dr Ramsden.
Then why are you wasting my time?
- Because they called for you.
- Me?
MAN: Doctor.
Doctor.
Doctor. Doctor...
ALL PATIENTS: Doctor... Doctor...
Doctor... Doctor...
VOICES ECHO: Doctor...!
White male, mid-20s,
breaking and entering.
Send me some back-up,
I've got him restrained.
Oi, you! Sit still.
Cricket bat.
I'm getting cricket bat.
You were breaking and entering.
That's much better.
Brand-new me, whack on the head.
Just what it needed.
Do you want to shut up now?
I've got back-up on the way.
Hang on, wait -
you're a policewoman.
You're breaking and entering.
See how this works?
What are you doing here?
Where's Amelia?
Amelia Pond?
Yeah. Amelia. Little Scottish girl.
Where is she?
I promised her five minutes
but the engines were phasing.
I suppose I must have gone a bit far.
Has something happened to her?
Amelia Pond hasn't lived here
in a long time.
How long?
- Six months.
- No!
No, no, no!
I can't be six months late!
I said five minutes. I promised.
What happened to her?
What happened to Amelia Pond?
Sarge, it's me again. Hurry it up.
This guy knows something
about Amelia Pond.
I don't think they were even conscious.
Dr Ramsden, there is another
sort of, um...funny thing.
Yes, I know. Dr Carver told me
about your conversation.
We've been very patient with you, Rory.
You're a good nurse, but for God's sake!
I've seen them.
These patients are under
24-hour supervision!
We know if their blood pressure changes.
There's no possibility
you'd have seen them
wandering in the village!
Why are you giving me your phone?!
It's a camera too.
(PAGER BEEPS)
You need to take some time off, Rory.
A lot of time off.
Start now.
Now!
I need to speak to whoever lives
in this house right now.
- I live here.
- But you're the police.
And this is where I live!
You got a problem with that?
How many rooms?
- I'm sorry, what?
- On this floor.
How many rooms on this floor?
Count them.
Why?
Because it will change your life.
Five.
- One, two, three, four, five.
- Six.
- Six?
- Look.
- Look where?
- Exactly where you never want to look.
The corner of your eye. Look behind you.
That's... That is not possible.
How's that possible?
There's a perception filter all round
the door. Sensed it last time I was here.
Should've seen it.
But that's a whole room. That's
a whole room I've never even noticed.
The filter stops you noticing.
Something came here a while ago to hide.
It's still hiding
and you need to uncuff me now!
- I don't have the key. I lost it.
- How can you have lost it?!
Stay away from that door!
Do not touch that door!
Listen to me! Do not open that...
Why does no-one ever listen to me?
Do I just have a face
that nobody listens to?
Again?
My screwdriver, where is it? Silver thing,
blue at the end. Where did it go?
- There's nothing here.
- Whatever's in there stopped you seeing
the whole room -
what makes you think you could see it?
Now, please, just get out!
- Silver, blue at the end?
- My screwdriver, yeah.
It's here.
Must have rolled under the door.
Yeah. Must have.
And then it must have jumped up
on the table.
Get out of there.
Get out of there!
Get out!
What is it? What are you doing?
There's nothing here, but...
Corner of your eye.
What is it?
Don't try to see it. If it knows
you've seen it, it will kill you.
Don't look at it.
Do not...look.
- (SHE SCREAMS)
- Get out!
Give me that!
(LATCH CLICKS)
Come on. What's the bad alien done to you?
- Will that door hold it?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, course!
It's an inter-dimensional multi-form
from outer space -
they're all terrified of wood(!)
What's that? What's it doing?
I don't know. Getting dressed?
Run. Just go.
- Your back-up's coming, I'll be fine.
- There is no back-up.
- I heard you call for back-up.
- It's a pretend radio.
- But you're a policewoman.
- I'm a kissogram!
- But it's just...
- No, it isn't.
Look at the faces.
(GROWLING)
(HE BARKS)
What? I'm sorry, but what?!
It's all one creature.
One creature disguised as two.
Clever old multi-form.
A bit of a rush job, though.
Got the voice a bit muddled, did you?
Mind you, where did you get
the pattern from?
You'd need a psychic link, a live feed.
How did you fix that?
(SNARLS LIKE DOG)
(SNARLING ECHOES)
(SNARLS NOT LIKE DOG)
Stay, boy!
Her and me, we're safe.
Want to know why? She sent for back-up.
I didn't send for back-up!
I know. That was a clever lie to save
our lives. OK, yeah, no back-up!
That's why we're safe.
Alone, we're not a threat to you.
If we had back-up,
then you'd have to kill us!
VOICE: Attention, Prisoner Zero.
The human residence is surrounded.
- Attention Prisoner Zero...
- What's that?
- ...the human residence is surrounded.
- That would be back-up. OK,
one more time. We do have back-up
and that's definitely why we're safe.
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Safe apart from,
you know, incineration.
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
- or the human residence will be...
- Wait, come on.
Prisoner Zero will vacate the human
residence, or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
- or the human residence will be...
- Run!
...the human residence, or the human
residence will be incinerated.
- Kissogram?
- Yes, a kissogram!
Why do you pretend
to be a policewoman?
You broke into my house!
It was this or a French maid!
What's going on? Tell me!
Tell me!
An alien convict is hiding in your spare
room disguised as a man and a dog,
and some other aliens are about to
incinerate your house. Any questions?
- Yes.
- Me, too.
No, no, no! Don't do that, not now!
It's still rebuilding, not letting us in!
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence...
Come on!
No, wait, hang on, hang on,
wait, wait, wait. The shed.
I destroyed that shed last time
I was here, smashed it to pieces.
- So there's a new one. Let's go.
- But the new one's got old.
It's ten years old at least.
12 years. I'm not six months late,
I'm 12 years late.
- He's coming.
- You said six months.
- Why did you say six months?
- We've got to go.
This matters. This is important.
Why did you say six months?
(SCOTTISH ACCENT) Well,
why did you say five minutes?!
- What?
- Come on.
What?
- Come on!
- What?
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
- You're Amelia.
- You're late.
- Amelia Pond. You're the little girl.
- I'm Amelia and you're late.
- What happened?
- 12 years.
- You hit me with a cricket bat.
- A cricket bat.
- 12 years and four psychiatrists.
- Four?
- I kept biting them.
- Why?
- They said you weren't real.
(GARBLED, THROUGH SPEAKER) Prisoner
Zero will vacate the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated. Repeat...
No, no, no, come on.
What? We're being staked out
by an ice-cream van?
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence...
What's that?
Why are you playing that?
It's supposed to be Clair De Lune.
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated. Repeat,
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated. Repeat...
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence...
...or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Doctor, what's happening?
(ANNOUNCEMENT CONTINUES)
Repeat, Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Repeat, Prisoner Zero
will vacate the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Hello! Sorry to burst in,
we're doing a special on television
faults in this area. ...Also, crimes.
- Let's have a look.
- I was just about to phone.
It's on every channel.
Hello, Amy, dear.
Are you a policewoman now?
- Well, sometimes...
- I thought you were a nurse.
I can be a nurse.
- Or, actually, a nun?
- I dabble.
Amy, who is your friend?
- Who's Amy? You were Amelia.
- Yeah, now I'm Amy.
Amelia Pond - that was a great name.
Bit fairy tale.
I know you, don't I?
I've seen you somewhere before.
Not me. Brand-new face...
First time on.
And what sort of job's a kissogram?
I go to parties and I kiss people.
With outfits. It's a laugh.
- You were a little girl five minutes ago.
- You're worse than my aunt.
I'm the Doctor,
I'm worse than everybody's aunt.
And that is not
how I'm introducing myself.
RADIO: Repetez, le Prisonnier...
...2Zero wird der menschliche...
OK, so it's everywhere,
in every language.
They're broadcasting
to the whole world.
AMY: What's up there?
What are you looking for?
OK, planet this size, two poles,
your basic molten core...
they're going to need
a 40% fission blast.
But they'll have to power up first,
won't they?
So assuming a medium-sized starship,
that's 20 minutes.
What do you think? 20 minutes?
Yeah, 20 minutes.
We've got 20 minutes.
- 20 minutes to what?
- Are you the Doctor?
He is, isn't he? He's the Doctor!
The Raggedy Doctor.
All those cartoons you did,
when you were little.
The Raggedy Doctor - it's him.
(WHISPERS) Shut up.
Cartoons?
Gran, it's him, isn't it?
- It's really him!
- Jeff, shut up! 20 minutes to what?
TV: ...human residence
will be incinerated. Repeat...
The human residence.
They're not talking about your house,
they're talking about the planet.
Somewhere up there, there's a spaceship.
And it's going to incinerate the planet.
...will be incinerated. Repeat, Prisoner
Zero will vacate the human residence,
- or the human residence will be...
- 20 minutes to the end of the world.
...residence will be incinerated.
Repeat,
Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
Repeat, Prisoner Zero will vacate
the human residence,
or the human residence
will be incinerated.
- What is this place? Where am I?
- Leadworth.
- Where's the rest of it?
- This is it.
- Is there an airport?
- No.
- A nuclear power station?
- Even a little one?
- No.
- Nearest city?
- Gloucester, half an hour by car.
We don't have half an hour.
Do we have a car?
- No.
- Well, that's good! Fantastic, that is(!)
20 minutes to save the world
and I've got a post office. And it's shut!
What is that?
It's a duck pond.
- Why aren't there any ducks?
- I don't know. There's never any ducks.
Then how do you know it's a duck pond?
It just is.
Is it important, the duck pond?
I don't know. Why would I know?
This is too soon.
I'm not ready, I'm not done yet.
What's happening?
Why's it going dark?
- So what's wrong with the sun?
- Nothing.
You're looking at it
through a force-field.
They've sealed off
your upper atmosphere,
now they're getting ready
to boil the planet.
Oh, and here they come -
the human race.
The end comes, as it was
always going to - down a video phone!
This isn't real, is it?
- This is some kind of big wind-up.
- Why would I wind you up?
- You told me you had a time machine.
- And you believed me.
Then I grew up.
Oh, you never want to do that.
No, hang on, shut up, wait!
I missed it. I saw it
and I missed it. What did I see?
I saw... What did I see?
(RAPID CLICKING)
20 minutes.
I can do it.
20 minutes, the planet burns.
Run to your loved ones and say goodbye,
or stay and help me.
- No.
- I'm sorry?
No!
Amy, no, no, what are you doing?
- (LOCK BEEPS)
- Are you out of your mind?
- Who are you?
- You know who I am.
No, really, who are you?
Look at the sky!
End of the world, 20 minutes.
- Better talk quickly, then!
- Amy, I am going to need my car back.
Yes, in a bit.
Now go and have coffee.
Right, yes.
Catch.
I'm the Doctor.
I'm a time traveller.
Everything I told you
12 years ago is true. I'm real.
What's happening in the sky is real,
and if you don't let me go now,
everything you've ever known is over.
- I don't believe you.
- Just 20 minutes.
Just believe me for 20 minutes.
Look at it.
Fresh as the day you gave it to me.
And you know it's the same one.
Amy...
believe for 20 minutes.
- What do we do?
- Stop that nurse!
The sun's going out, and you're
photographing a man and a dog. Why?
- Amy?
- Hi!
Oh, this is Rory, he's a.. friend.
- Boyfriend.
- Kind of boyfriend.
Amy! Man and dog, why?
- Oh, my God, it's him.
- Just answer his question, please.
It's him, though. The Doctor.
- The Raggedy Doctor.
- Yeah, he came back.
- But he was a story. He was a game.
- Man and dog - why? Tell me now.
Sorry. Because he can't be there.
- Because he's in a hospital, in a coma.
- In a hospital, in a coma.
Yeah.
Knew it. Multi-form, you see?
Disguise itself as anything,
but it needs a live feed.
A psychic link with a living
but dormant mind.
(IT SNAPS AND SNARLS)
Prisoner Zero.
- What, there's a Prisoner Zero too?
- Yes.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
See, that ship up there
is scanning this area
for non-terrestrial technology.
And nothing says non-terrestrial
like a sonic screwdriver.
- (GLASS SMASHES, CAR ALARMS BLARE)
- Aargh!
- (SIREN WAILS)
- MAN: Hey, come back here!
Oi, come back here! Come back!
I think someone's going to notice.
Don't you?
(BARKING)
No, no, no, don't do that!
- Look, it's going.
- No, come back, he's here!
Come back! He's here,
Prisoner Zero is here.
Come back, he's here!
Prisoner Zero is...here.
Doctor!
The drain. It just sort of melted
and went down the drain.
- Well, of course it did.
- What do we do now?
It's hiding in human form.
We need to drive it into the open.
No TARDIS, no screwdriver,
17 minutes.
Come on, think. Think!
DR RAMSDEN: Barney? Barney...
Barney? Can you hear me, Barney?
Barney? Barney?
So that thing,
that hid in my house for 12 years?
Multi-forms can live for millennia.
12 years is a pit-stop.
So how come you show up on the same day
that lot do, the same minute?
They're looking for him, but followed me.
They saw me through the crack, got a fix.
They're only late cos I am.
Give me your phone.
- How can he be real? He was never real.
- Phone, now, gimme!
He was just a game, we were kids.
You made me dress up as him.
- These photos are all coma patients?
- Yeah.
No, they're all the multi-form.
Eight comas, eight disguises
for Prisoner Zero.
He had a dog.
There's a dog in a coma?
The coma patient dreams
he's walking a dog,
Prisoner Zero gets a dog. Laptop!
Your friend, what was his name?
- Not him, the good-looking one.
- Thanks.
- Jeff
h, thanks(!)
He had a laptop in his bag, a laptop.
Big bag, big laptop,
I need Jeff's laptop.
You two, get to the hospital,
get everyone out.
Clear the whole floor.
Phone me when you're done.
- Your car, come on.
- Um...but how can he be here?
How can the Doctor be here?
- Hello! Laptop, gimme!
- No, no, no, no, wait.
- It's fine.
- Hang on!
Give it here.
Blimey! Get a girlfriend, Jeff.
- Gran.
- What are you doing?
The sun's gone wibbly,
so right now,
somewhere out there, there's going
to be a big video conference call.
All the experts in the world panicking
at once, and do you know what they need?
Me. Ah, and here they all are.
All the big boys - NASA, Jodrell Bank,
Tokyo Space Centre, Patrick Moore.
- I like Patrick Moore.
- I'll get you his number,
but watch him, he's a devil.
- You can't just hack in on a call.
- Can't I?
Who are you? This is a secure call,
what are you doing?
Hello, I know, you should switch me off.
But before you do, watch this.
- It's here too, I'm getting it.
- Fermat's Theorem, the proof,
and I mean the real one,
never seen before.
Poor old Fermat, got killed in a duel
before he could write it down.
My fault, I slept in.
Oh, and here's an oldie, but a goo die -
why electrons have mass.
And a personal favourite of mine,
faster-than-light travel
with two diagrams and a joke.
Look at your screens.
Whoever I am, I'm a genius.
Look at the sun.
You need all the help you can get.
Fellas, pay attention.
AMERICAN MAN: Sir, what are you doing?
I'm writing a computer virus.
Very clever, super-fast,
and a tiny bit alive, but don't let on.
Why am I writing it on a phone?
Never mind, you'll find out.
OK, I'm sending this
to all your computers.
Get everyone who works for you
sending this everywhere.
E-mail, text, Facebook, Bebo, Twitter,
radar dish -
whatever you've got. Any questions?
- Who was your lady friend?
- Patrick, behave!
- What does this virus do?
- It's a reset command, that's all.
It resets counters, gets in the WiFi
and resets every counter it can find.
Anything with a chip will default
at zero at exactly the same time.
But, yeah, I could be lying.
Why should you trust me?
I'll let my best man explain.
Jeff...you're my best man.
You what?
Listen to me. In ten minutes,
you're going to be a legend.
In ten minutes, everyone is going to be
offering you any job you want.
But first, you have to be magnificent.
You have to make them trust you
and get them working. This is it, Jeff.
Right here, right now.
This is when you fly.
Today's the day you save the world.
- Why me?
- It's your bedroom.
Now go, go, go.
OK, guys,
let's do this.
Oh, and delete
your internet history.
Something's happened up there,
we can't get through.
Yes, but what's happened?
I don't know. No-one knows.
Phone him.
I'm phoning him.
Doctor? We're at the hospital,
but we can't get through.
Oh!
- What did he say?
- Look in the mirror.
Ha-ha! Uniform!
Are you on your way?
You're going to need a car.
Don't worry.
I've commandeered a vehicle.
(SIREN WAILS)
Oh, God!
- Officer.
- What happened?
There was a man. A man with a dog.
I think Dr Ramsden's dead.
And the nurses.
(MOBILE RINGS)
- Are you in?
- Yep.
- But so's Prisoner Zero.
- You need to get out of there.
WOMAN'S VOICE: He was so angry.
He kept shouting. And that dog,
the size of that dog,
I swear it was rabid.
WOMAN'S VOICE: And he just went mad,
attacking everyone.
Where did he go, did you see?
Has he gone? We hid in the ladies'.
Oh, I'm getting it wrong again, aren't I?
I'm always doing that.
So many mouths.
- RORY: Oh, my God!
- (SNARLING)
Amy? Amy, what's happening?
(SIREN WAILS)
Amy, talk to me!
We're in the coma ward.
But it's here, it's getting in.
- Which window are you?
- What, sorry?
- Which window?
- First floor on the left,
fourth from the end.
(SNARLING)
Oh, dear. Little Amelia Pond.
I've watched you grow up.
12 years, and you never even knew
I was there.
Little Amelia Pond,
waiting for her magic Doctor to return.
But not this time, Amelia.
(MOBILE BEEPS)
(SIREN WAILS)
Right! Hello! Am I late?
No, three minutes to go.
So still time.
Time for what...Time Lord?
Take the disguise off.
They'll find you in a heartbeat.
Nobody dies.
The Atraxi will kill me this time.
If I am to die,
let there be fire.
OK. You came to this world
by opening a crack in space and time.
- Do it again - just leave.
- I did not open the crack.
Somebody did.
The cracks in the skin of the universe -
don't you know where they came from?
You don't, do you?
GIRL'S VOICE: The Doctor
in the TARDIS doesn't know.
(CHANTS) Doesn't know, doesn't know!
WOMAN'S VOICE:
The universe is cracked.
The Pandorica will open.
Silence will fall.
(CLICKING)
And we're off!
Look at that.
Look at that!
Yeah, I know,
just a clock, whatever.
But do you know
what's happening right now?
In one little bedroom,
my team are working.
Jeff and the world.
And do you know what they're doing?
They're spreading the word
all over the world, quantum fast.
The word is out.
And do you know what the word is?
The word is zero.
Now, me, if I was up
in the sky in a battleship,
monitoring all Earth communications,
I'd take that as a hint.
And if I had a whole battle fleet
surrounding the planet,
I'd be able track a simple
old computer virus to its source
in, what, under a minute?
The source, by the way,
is right here.
Oh! And I think they just found us!
The Atraxi are limited.
While I'm in this form,
they'll still be unable to detect me.
- They've tracked a phone, not me.
- Yeah,
but this is the good bit.
I mean, this is my favourite bit.
Do you know
what this phone is full of?
Pictures of you.
Every form you've learned to take,
right here.
Oh, and being uploaded about now.
And the final score is -
no TARDIS, no screwdriver -
two minutes to spare. Who da man?
Oh, I'm never saying that again. Fine.
Then I shall take a new form.
Oh, stop it, you know you can't.
Takes months to form
that kind of psychic link.
And I've had years.
No! Amy?
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
You've got to hold on. Amy!
Don't sleep!
You've got to stay awake, please.
Doctor?
Well, that's rubbish.
Who's that supposed to be?
- It's you.
- Me? Is that what I look like?
- You don't know?
- Busy day. Why me, though?
You're linked with her.
Why are you copying me?
GIRL'S VOICE: I'm not.
Poor Amy Pond.
Still such a child inside.
Dreaming of the magic Doctor
she knows will return to save her.
What a disappointment you've been.
No, she's dreaming about me
cos she can hear me.
Amy, don't just hear me, listen.
Remember the room, the room
in your house you couldn't see?
Remember you went inside?
I tried to stop you, but you did.
You went in the room.
You went inside.
Amy...
dream about what you saw.
No!
- Well done, Prisoner Zero.
- (ROARS)
A perfect impersonation of yourself.
Prisoner Zero is located.
Prisoner Zero is restrained.
(HISSING) Silence, Doctor.
Silence will fall.
(WHOOSHING)
(BIRDSONG)
The sun - it's back to normal, right?
That's... That's good, yeah?
That means it's over.
Amy?
- Are you OK? Are you with us?
- What happened?
- He did it. The Doctor did it.
- No, I didn't.
- What are you doing?
- Tracking the signal back.
- Sorry...in advance.
- About what?
The bill.
-Um...
- Oi, I didn't say you could go!
Article 57
of the Shadow Proclamation.
This is a fully established,
level 5 planet,
and you were going to burn it? What?
Did you think no-one was watching?
You lot, back here, now!
OK.
Now I've done it.
Did he just bring them back?
Did he just save the world from aliens
and then bring all the aliens back again?
- Where are you going?
- The roof.
No, hang on.
- What's in here?
- I'm saving the world.
I need a decent shirt.
To hell with the raggedy.
Time to put on a show!
You just summoned aliens back to Earth.
Actual aliens,
deadly aliens,
aliens of death,
and now you're taking your clothes off.
- Amy, he's taking his clothes off.
- Turn your back if it embarrasses you.
Are you stealing clothes now?
Those clothes belong to people, you know.
Are you not going to turn your back?
Nope.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
So this was a good idea, was it(?)
They were leaving.
Leaving is good.
Never coming back is better.
Come on, then!
The Doctor will see you now.
(WHIRRING)
You are not of this world.
No, but I've put a lot of work into it.
Hmm...
I don't know.
What do you think?
Is this world important?
Important?
What's that mean, "important"?
Six billion people live here -
is that important?
Here's a better question.
Is this world a threat to the Atraxi?
Well, come on.
You're monitoring the whole planet.
Is this world a threat?
No.
Are the peoples of this world
guilty of any crime
by the laws of the Atraxi?
No.
OK.
One more. Just one.
Is this world protected?
Because you're not the first lot to come
here. Oh, there have been so many!
And what you've got to ask is...
...what happened to them?
Hello.
I'm the Doctor.
Basically...
---Fun.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
Is that it?
Is that them gone for good?
Who were they?
OK!
What have you got for me this time?
Look at you!
Oh, you sexy thing!
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
Sorry about running off earlier.
Brand-new TARDIS - bit exciting.
Just had a quick hop to the moon
and back to run her in.
She's ready for the big stuff now.
(OWL HOOTS)
It's you. You came back.
Course I came back.
I always come back.
- Something wrong with that?
- And you kept the clothes.
Well, I just saved the world,
the whole planet,
for about the millionth time,
no charge. Yeah, shoot me!
- I kept the clothes.
- Including the bow tie.
- Yeah, it's cool. Bow ties are cool.
- Are you from another planet?
- Yeah.
- OK.
So what do you think?
- Of what?
- Other planets. Want to check some out?
- What does that mean?
- It means...
Well, it means...come with me.
Where?
Wherever you like.
(OWL HOOTS)
All that stuff - the hospital,
the spaceships, Prisoner Zero...
Oh, don't worry. That's just
the beginning. There's loads more.
Yeah, but those things, those...
amazing things, all that stuff...
- ...that was two years ago!
- Oh-oh!
- Oops.
- Yeah.
- So that's...
- 14 years!
14 years since fish custard.
Amy Pond, the girl who waited,
you've waited long enough.
When I was a kid, you said there was
a swimming pool and a library,
- and the pool was /777 the library.
- Yeah.
Not sure where it is now. So...coming?
No.
- You wanted to come 14 years ago.
- I grew up.
Don't worry.
I'll soon fix that.
Well?
Anything you want to say?
Any passing remarks?
I've heard them all.
I'm in my nightie.
Oh, don't worry.
Plenty of clothes in the wardrobe.
And possibly a swimming pool.
So...all of time and space,
everything that ever happened
or ever will...
Where do you want to start?
You are so sure that I'm coming.
- Yeah, I am.
- Why?
Cos you're the Scottish girl
in the English village,
- and I know how that feels.
- Oh, do you?
All these years living here,
most of your life...
and you've still got that accent.
Yeah, you're coming.
(BELL RINGS)
- Can I be back by tomorrow morning?
- It's a time machine.
You can be back five minutes ago.
Why, what's tomorrow?
Nothing. Nothing. Just...you know, stuff.
All right, then.
Back in time for "stuff".
Oh! A new one!
Lovely.
(WHISPERS) Thanks, dear!
(BEEPING)
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
Why me?
- Why not?
- Seriously. You are asking me
to run away with you
in the middle of the night.
It's a fair question. Why me?
- I don't know. Fun. Do I need a reason? -
People always have a reason.
- Do I look like people?
- Yes.
Been knocking around
on my own for a while.
My choice. But I've started talking
to myself. It's giving me earache.
- You're lonely. That's it? Just that?
- Just that.
Promise.
(RUMBLING)
OK.
So, are you OK, then?
Cos this place, sometimes
it can make people feel a bit...
- you know...
- I'm fine.
It's just...there's a whole world in here,
just like you said.
It's all true. I thought...
Well, I started to think that maybe
- you were just like a madman with a box.
- Amy Pond,
there's something you'd better understand,
cos one day your life may depend on it.
I am definitely a madman with a box.
Ha-ha! Yeah.
(SHE LAUGHS)
Goodbye, Leadworth.
Hello, everything!
WWhoo!
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
Ha-ha!