(BEEPS)
Sontar-Ha!
Strategic Intelligence Update 427.
Subject, the Doctor.
Commander Strax reporting.
Strax, what are you doing?
This ship is about to crash
into the heart of London.
Reporting to Sontar.
I have acquired vital
tactical information
-which could change the course...
-By the Goddess, are you blogging?
I resent your attitude
to my status updates.
Millions of innocent people are going
to be vaporised in 12 minutes!
Exactly. I've got to pass
the time somehow.
(SIGHS)
Come on, Jenny! Work to do!
Men!
The Time Lord known as the Doctor.
Sontaran enemy number one.
(RUMBLING)
There are many myths and legends
concerning the Doctor,
and principal among them
is his secret ability
to change appearance.
This is the First Doctor,
designated Doctor number one.
Although the numbering
does get a little trickier later on.
As you can see,
this Doctor is a woman,
a delusional crone
with unpleasant trousers
and unrealistic hair.
The Doctor is able,
when damaged or injured,
to renew his physical form.
This is a process
known as deterioration.
Faced with certain death
after an encounter with the Cybermen,
the First Doctor
was forced to regenerate
into a new and younger form.
This process...
failed.
This Doctor, Doctor number two,
was captured by his own people
and sentenced to a fate
worse than death.
The Third Doctor,
a strange and tragic hybrid,
half man, half granny,
was forced to regenerate
because he was frightened
-by a big spider.
-(SCREECHES)
The Fourth Doctor was no improvement
and took to wearing a giant sheep frond
to lend himself color and personality.
Unsuccessfully.
The Fifth Doctor showed some grasp
of the military virtue of camouflage
by having no distinguishing
features whatsoever.
Following events
on the planet Androzani,
this Doctor was unavoidably...
inflated.
The Sixth Doctor
showed significantly less
-understanding of camouflage...
-(RUMBLING)
...and died during his single attempt
at physical exercise.
The Sixth Doctor's regeneration
into his seventh form
brings us to a great
and terrible mystery.
What happened to the rest of him?
Where is all the leftover Doctor?
Stored somewhere, perhaps?
In secret vats?
Beware, fellow Sontarans,
there may be more of him out there.
The Eighth Doctor added
a new dimension to his persona,
undreamt of by his
previous incarnations.
(SIGHS)
Puberty.
These new activities
and the attendant lifestyle
had an inevitable consequence.
The War Doctor.
The only Doctor with any potential
for being any good at all.
Sadly, however, he was rubbish.
(EXPLOSION)
Despite promising tendencies
towards death and destruction,
when it came to the pleas
of the suffering and dying,
the Doctor was once again all ears.
(STRAX SNICKERS)
All ears!
(LAUGHS)
Sorry.
A bit of human humor for you there.
(LAUGHING)
All ears!
After another kissing incident,
this Doctor liked girls so much
he decided to become one.
The Tenth Doctor was on a voyage
of discovery, self-improvement
and personal development
that led to his regeneration into
the Tenth Doctor.
He just didn't want to go!
What was he so afraid of?
The Eleventh Doctor.
Or possibly the Twelfth.
Technically the Thirteenth.
Who can say?
By now the Doctor had learned
to take it all on the chin.
(EXPLOSION)
Chin.
I didn't even mean that one.
(LAUGHING)
Why's that funny? That isn't even funny.
Why am I laughing?
What's funny about chins?
(STRAX LAUGHING)
Stop it. Stop all the chins.
It's not funny!
(LAUGHING)
Be warned, fellow Sontarans,
word has reached us
on all sub-space channels,
a new incarnation
of the Doctor is imminent.
Information is scarce at this point,
-but early indications suggest...
-Strax, with me, now.
We must get to London immediately!
But I thought we were going?
Oh, no, we've fixed
the engines, it's fine.
But we've just had a message
from Scotland Yard.
Apparently, there's something
impossible in the Thames.
(BEEPS)