Listen to me, Karvanista.
If you think you have won
this little skirmish,
you are very much mistaken.
Do not imagine for a second
that you have got the better of us.
Right, Yaz?
Oh, yeah. We are totally in command.
Is that right?
Cos from where I'm hovering,
you seem to be handcuffed and
footlocked to a gravity bar,
which in 79 seconds will release you
into the boiling acid ocean
directly below
where your bodies
will instantly disintegrate.
Even if you survive that,
which you won't, in four minutes' time,
the entire planet will be engulfed
by a nearby giant red star.
Oh, and if you try to escape,
my Kill Disks will blast you to pieces.
Meanwhile, I am now far away,
travelling towards
what will in future be known
as the final hours of planet Earth.
What?
Don't worry.
You'll be long dead.
I must admit, Yaz,
I can't help feeling
that some of this is my fault.
Some?
- All of this is your fault.
- What do you mean?
Accidentally blowing up
Karvanista droid guards
when we were trying to sneak into
his operations base unnoticed?
It's very temperamental, Nitro-9.
Suggesting we escape his base
by air-surfing on this gravbar?
How was I to know
the force shield would reboot
at the exact moment we were
heading towards it?
And when we got captured,
you had to mention
the two sets of cuffs in your pocket?
Two words, Yaz. Trapezium Seven.
- Okay.
- Trapezium Seven.
That high-gravity circus workshop.
Who were the top two in the class?
- Ready?
- No!
Me neither. I love not being ready.
Three. Two. One.
Alley-oop!
Got it!
Time to go.
How do we get these cuffs off?
Very easily. Because, Yasmin Khan,
they're voice activated!
That's why I told him
they were in my pocket!
Release.
- Release!
Release! Or maybe I was Scottish
when I set them up.
Release.
Release!
Doctor!
Doctor, the gravbar's breaking.
That's inconvenient!
Release. Release. Release!
Maybe it's my tone of voice.
It's there!
- Call it!
- Now!
What a relief.
Right. No one gets away with
doing that to us, Yaz.
What was it he said?
Final few hours of planet Earth?
He doesn't get rid of us that easily.
Not enough.
That is not enough.
We need more workers.
Returned soldiers, the poor,
they must all be brought here
and put to work.
Ah. There's still far to go.
Of course, sir.
May I also remind you,
Mr Stonehouse is due shortly.
Williamson,
for the love of God,
what are you doing here?
Why all this digging?
I provide work and wages for those
who would not otherwise find it.
Is that not enough?
Of course, it is laudable.
But do you not think about
what you are creating?
I think very deeply about it.
More deeply than you can possibly know.
Then why can I see
no rational plan at work here?
The designs are eccentric.
The work is random.
And as for the tunnels being excavated,
they are without purpose.
Without purpose?
If I were to speak to you
about their true purpose,
your mind would buckle
under the pressure.
With respect, sir,
of the two of us,
my mind is clearly
the more robust and rational.
You imagine what lies ahead
can be defeated with rationale?
And pray, Mr Williamson,
what do you imagine to lie ahead of us?
The cataclysmic.
The impossible.
Doesn't matter
where you go in the world,
it could be the greatest museums
in the biggest cities,
none of them have got
what we've got, right here.
Nobody has got a top floor
like the Museum of Liverpool.
Cos nobody has got our history.
Over there, we've got the writers.
Over there, the musicians.
And over there, the footballers.
These are massive.
They're the pinnacle of this building,
and this city.
These define us.
These make Liverpool.
Dan. Dan!
That's enough from me now. I'll let you
have a look round on your own.
All right, Di.
How many times?
Dan, you've got to stop.
You don't work here. You're not a guide.
Stop pretending to be official.
I am official. Official Scouse.
Just think of me as a free exhibit.
Just a little bit livelier
than the others.
Lad, you've got a trade. Do that.
I know, but I'm good at this.
And I'm only chatting.
I make your punters happy.
What's the point of being alive
if it's not to make others happy?
Alan says, if you do it again,
he'll ban you permanently.
- What if we say just mornings?
- No.
So, we still on
for Halloween drinks tonight?
Yeah, yeah.
Unless you've changed your mind.
No. No, I haven't.
No. Good. Me neither.
Eight o'clock, the corner of Lark Lane.
- It's a date.
- Yeah.
- Not a date date I'm presuming. Yeah.
- No. Yeah. But... Yeah, Okay.
I've got to go.
And don't keep me waiting, you,
the Late Dan Lewis.
Not tonight.
Go on.
That's the fourth time.
I know. This is
the simplest trajectory, Earth.
We should be there already.
What's wrong with you?
Psychic connection
reactivating, Doctor.
Who's that?
How am I seeing this?
Just watch.
Still alive.
After all this time.
How long has it been here?
Imprisoned since
the dawn of the universe.
That's what I was told.
People embellish though.
Our job is to ensure
all incarceration systems
are still functional,
and get the hell out.
Evaluation report on prisoner Swarm.
Confinement location,
remnants of
The Burnished Rage battleground.
Incarceration systems remain active.
Approaching prisoner
for distanced live check.
Do not engage
with the prisoner in conversation.
Do not do anything that it asks,
no matter what it asks
or how persuasive it seems.
I mean, obviously. I have
done my psych-resistance training.
Containment chamber active.
Physical securings still in place.
Stratospheric impoundment systems
operative.
Prisoner remains secure.
Your last tour, En Sentac.
How does it know that?
How many times across the millennia
have you stared at me in silence?
Now you're handing over your task...
to a child.
The kid will do fine.
You're as confined
as you always have been,
and always will be.
Wrong.
Containment chamber malfunction.
- Boss?
- Feeling paralysed?
Proof that your life's work has ended
in failure.
Your reward
for admirable service, to Division.
Renewed at last!
What have you done?
I waited.
I planned.
And now, I'm going to execute.
That won't work, child.
Your time is over.
As mine...
has begun once more.
Huh.
Trick or treat, Doctor.
Doctor! Doctor!
Have you seen this?
It's like the TARDIS is leaking.
Do you know what it is?
Nothing to worry about. It's fine.
I'm fine, TARDIS is fine.
We're all fine.
We'll be on Earth any moment.
Right. Dateline.
October 31st.
Halloween. Trick or treat.
Yeah, that'll see you right for a bit.
- Thanks.
- Oh, hang on.
Take a couple of them for tonight,
as long as you promise not to haunt me.
- Look after yourselves, ta-ra.
- Come on.
Yeah. Will I make up a box for you?
No, I'm sound, thanks.
Well, at least take some soup. Hmm?
Wilma, who likes soup? Really.
Don't be proud, Daniel, come on.
There's plenty of people
who need soup a lot more than me.
And anyway, my numbers
are coming up Wednesday.
You don't even play the lottery.
I know, that's how lucky I am.
Wait.
Did you see that?
What?
There's something out there.
You've been on the sherry early tonight.
Come on.
Let's lock up.
Trick or treat.
Oh. You scared me there.
Yeah. You can have the last ones.
You look great.
Go on, go home safe now.
Night night.
All right, la.
Trick or treat.
No.
- You what?
- How old are you?
- What's the difference?
- You're not even dressed up.
- Yeah, well, neither are you.
- You're just going round
knocking on people's doors.
I heard you had sweets.
Go on. Get off with youse.
Don't be throwing eggs at my house.
Take the soup, will you?
Yes. Gaze upon my might.
What is it with you lot tonight?
Kneel before the might of the Lupari.
You're paying for that door, you know.
Be silent!
Or face execution
at the hands of Karvanista.
Vanquisher of
the Thousand Civilisations.
Submit or die.
Well, you've
definitely put the effort in.
You will not resist.
You will do exactly as I command.
Don't think I will.
I said, you will not resist.
You'll do exactly as I command.
And I said,
get back out through that door.
Or I'm getting the bizzies.
Why's that not working?
- What's the matter with you?
- What's the matter with me?
I'm not the one going around
smashing into people's houses
dressed as a dog.
What did you just call me?
I mean it's good, like it's...
it's cute.
It looks dead soft.
Is it real fur?
You defile the sacred legacy
of my forebears!
You don't look anything like four bears.
Go on, shoo. Get back to your mom.
Tell her what a brave lad you've been.
Never talk of my mother.
Liverpool.
Anfield.
Klopp era. Classic.
Oh, Yaz, maybe we could take in a game,
I've seen
the Barcelona match nine times.
I was a ball boy for Trent, once.
Hmm.
Number 37.
Non-terrestrial weapon dispersal traces.
And a door that's left open.
Anyone home?
I'm guessing, single bloke,
definitely a Red.
Someone's made a right mess in here.
Ugh. Stun cube. Lupari tech.
Karvanista was here.
Looks like he took whoever lived here.
Why would he do that?
Daniel Lewis.
- This could be him.
- So where is he now?
Ah. Quick check of planetary orbit.
Nice laptop, Dan.
Right.
There. 7.2 minutes ago,
Karvanista's ship, leaving Earth,
shielded against detection.
- We're just behind him.
- So where's he going?
Why am I getting multiple traces?
Hang on while I zoom out.
Seven billion Lupari ships
coming this way.
That's an invasion fleet, right?
Looks like it.
Karvanista's species, all heading here.
Why was he ahead of them?
And why take the bloke that lives here?
Also, one other thing
that's bugging me, tiny detail.
Why does Dan have
such a flashy computer?
Because it's not his.
Get out!
Oops.
- Ah. Sorry.
- Sorry.
Hey, what have you done
with the chilies?
Mm. Have you tried the fridge?
- Why would they be in the fridge?
- Well,
- sometimes you put them in the fridge.
- I do not.
They're in the fridge.
Amazing.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Can we ignore it?
They promised this would never happen.
Except in the gravest of emergencies.
We didn't receive the warning.
Come on. Let's eat.
A dog shot me.
How can a dog shoot me? Ow!
The bars on that holding pen
are electrified.
What am I doing here, eh?
Hang on. Holding pen?
- I'm not an animal.
- No.
Animals know when to be silent.
You wait till I get out of here.
- Why, what are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna report you.
To who?
I'm gonna report you for kidnapping,
what do you think of that?
Well, that's what's happening. So, fine.
What?
You're mine.
- And I'm taking you off-world.
- What do you mean, off-world?
That's space.
And they say you're a low-IQ species.
Well done.
We're travelling away from your planet,
through space, on my spaceship.
Oh. Look at your little brain
trying to work it all out.
Embarrassing.
Why, though?
Why are you doing this?
What's so special about me?
Nothing. There's nothing special
about you.
You're insignificant, irrelevant,
and utterly meaningless.
You've gone to a lot of trouble
to kidnap someone who's
completely irrelevant.
Or maybe I should just kill you! Yeah?
- I could, right here.
- Yeah, but you haven't though, have you?
No, you're not going to kill me.
You could've done that in my kitchen.
If you've gone to all this trouble
to kidnap me,
killing me wouldn't make sense.
Oh, I'm done talking to you.
I'm right, though, aren't I?
Go on. Off you go.
Hang on. Come back!
Where are we actually going?
Compressor blast.
Tripped by the sonic.
He's deliberately leaving traps,
in case he's followed.
Clever, and dangerous, our Karvanista.
So why are you obsessed
with following him?
I don't know what you're talking about.
"I need to see a man about a dog."
That's all you said.
But it turns out the man is a dog,
and he's called Karvanista,
and you won't tell me why
you're so interested in him.
Oh, my God.
- Doctor!
- Who's that?
I have no idea.
Erm, I didn't expect to see you here.
Not tonight.
Hi. Really sorry. We're in the middle
of something quite important.
- Have we met?
- Not yet. But we will.
In the past, I think. If it's true.
I'm Claire.
If what's true, Claire?
You don't seem too sure about your past.
Oh God, look at your faces.
I know, I sound like a loon.
Don't let me distract you.
I didn't even know you'd be here.
I was just...
taking the long way home.
Cos it's Halloween.
Lupari fleet is getting closer.
We don't have any more time.
Come on, Yaz.
It's okay.
We'll see each other again.
Look after yourself.
Woah. That's not right.
The door's moved.
Yeah.
That's never happened before.
No.
You've got to go home now, Claire.
Right, let's get a lock on Karvanista.
- Co-pilot?
- Course.
Sending Karvanista's Craft ID.
Cross-referencing
with spatial-temporal locations,
I'll restrict to this solar system
and time zone
for exact trajectory.
Yeah. I'll jam his radar,
and find a sweet spot on his ship
for us to land unnoticed.
- Ah.
- Final adjustment?
Final adjustment.
Ah.
Right.
What are you doing?
Checking all systems for malfunctions.
Also, quick MOT check on my mind,
had a little glitch earlier.
What sort of glitch?
You didn't mention it.
You know what, Yaz,
I don't mention everything.
- No kidding.
- Are you being mardy?
What sort of glitch?
A glitchy glitch. What does it matter?
Because I thought we were friends.
We are friends.
Then why won't you let me in?
- What's going on with you?
- Nothing is going on with me.
Don't lie.
Have we not had a good time together?
Since Ryan and Graham left,
- have I not taken you to amazing places?
- Of course, but...
I thought I was showing you
experiences of a lifetime.
You're hiding something, about him.
About why you tracked him down
in the first place.
Tell me.
What was that?
Temporal residue surrounding
Karvanista's ship.
Is it us or him?
Him. Very much him.
It's like his ship's covered in it.
That shouldn't be happening.
We're pushing through it to land.
Nothing is as it should be, Yaz.
Too much out of the ordinary tonight.
Mustn't blink.
If you blink, it will move.
Don't blink.
The universe is looking
particularly beautiful today.
Observation officer Vinder reporting,
as per assigned duty.
Status report, rotation number 21,754.
No activity. No change in status.
Summary, constant.
Everything remains as per my previous
21,753 reports.
Nothing has changed.
Nothing ever changes.
But then, you know that.
Additional comments.
My spirits remain high,
while there is little or no activity.
The sheer beauty of what I can see is...
unimaginable!
I'm lucky to observe that
which few others will ever see.
For that at least, I thank you.
In all other respects,
I conclude this report with my usual
sign-off request,
that you all go to hell.
System?
Yes, Commander.
Amplify Thoribus section.
Of course. Amplifying.
What is that?
System, analyse and focus on
the Thoribus Trifecta.
Analysing Thoribus Trifecta.
Unknown phenomena detected.
Analysing,
anomalous property detected.
What in the names of the saints...
Thoribus minor destroyed.
Unknown phenomena approaching.
Outpost Rose is compromised.
Emergency status update.
Urgent warning transmission.
Jon?
Don't touch anything!
Why is this thought in my mind?
What thought?
Thank you.
My sister...
how I have missed you.
So we think this Dan bloke
is somewhere on board?
Yep. Now just gonna take
out his security systems
before we get spotted.
And lay in one other hack.
Here, hold this.
Well... where is it?
Left over hopper virus particles
should do the trick.
Right, you find Dan.
I'll confront Karvanista,
meet back here.
Confront him? Do you not remember
how that ended up last time?
Yes, we got away.
- Doctor!
- The prisoner's hold is that way.
If you hear gunfire or explosions,
get back sharpish.
Wait, synchronise watches.
Forget that, not wearing a watch.
Any questions?
No? See you soon.
"Does that make any sense to you, Yaz?"
Not really Doctor, no.
Karvanista to Lupari command,
unknown temporal propulsion
has been corrected.
Now activating strategic formation
realignment to re-join battalion.
Also sharing mission intel
of Earth festival Halloween
which may affect
some operational deployments.
I've got a bone to pick with you.
Oh, come on!
How many traps
do I have to leave to get rid of you?
More than you have done so far.
I don't have time for you right now.
You're gonna make time.
Did you just shut my ship down?
Yes, I did.
And now your weapon as well.
Because I've tracked you down across
half the universe
and you're gonna stand there
while I tell you two things.
Number one, the Lupari invasion
of Earth is off.
What are you talking about?
I couldn't be clearer.
You tell the rest of your people
to stay away from Earth.
It is protected, is protected,
protected by me, to be clear.
Number two, do tell me everything
you know about The Division.
Dan Lewis, right?
Might be. Who are you?
Rescue party.
Keep quiet and stay still.
It looks like this holding pen has
nine different booby traps.
How do you know that?
I've had a lot of experience of getting
out places like this, bear with me.
Where have you come from?
Why fussy about who you get rescued by?
No, but how do I know I can trust you?
You might be with the dog feller.
Does this look like a face
you can trust?
- Maybe.
- Maybe?
Are you an alien, too?
I am Yaz, Yasmin Khan.
Formerly PC Yasmin Khan
of Hallamshire Police
Very human, very much
not with dog feller.
Hallamshire, what? Like Sheffield?
Why, what's the matter with Sheffield?
Too near Leeds.
Pro tip, Dan Lewis,
don't diss the designated rescuer.
How're you here,
If you're from Sheffield?
Got a mate who's an alien.
Does he look like a dog?
No, but she's got her own ship
and we can get you back to Earth.
- You can come out.
- And the bars won't zap me?
Not if I've done it properly.
Which I'm pretty sure I have.
- How sure?
- Well, you know life's a gamble.
- Nice work, girl.
- Yaz is fine.
Now I don't want to hear another word
against Yorkshire again.
Come on, we're meeting the Doctor
back at our ship.
- Assuming nothing goes wrong.
- Why, do things often go wrong?
Come on!
Stop asking about The Division.
That's not a question I can answer.
Yes, you can. You have to.
I've spent a long time hunting you down.
You are the only known Division
operative, I can find alive.
The only one who can...
Right, sorry about that.
What is that call sign?
Why is it bothering me so much?
Species Recall. Universal pattern.
That's it. Thank you!
No, what, wait! You're on Species
Recall? Right now?
The Lupari are species,
bonded to humanity.
And for every human,
there is a paired guardian Lupar.
The bond is our genetic obligation
and our honour.
Only ever to come into effect
in the ultimate crisis.
But that would mean you're not abducting
Dan then?
I'm saving him, you idiot!
Right. Every Lupar has
a designated human.
He's mine, we have to save them,
before it's too late.
But you used a stun cube on him.
Just because we have to save,
that doesn't mean
I have to like them.
They're infuriating.
Seven billion ships.
Seven billion humans.
Man's best friend.
Not if you don't power up my ship.
But what is it you're saving them from?
You don't know?
I've been busy.
The Flux.
What's the Flux?
A hurricane, ripping through
the structure of this universe.
Disrupting every particle.
The falling of the structure
of the universe.
A cataclysm of unknown proportions
or patterns.
We don't know for sure.
And when is this Flux due to happen?
It's already begun.
Update from Thoribus Trifecta.
Three planets now compromised.
Wait. No, I don't mean compromised.
I mean destroyed. Disintegrated.
But not by weapons.
Like they were folding in on themselves.
Because of proximity to...
I don't know what. System?
Catastrophic event compromising
base level integrity of all structures.
Did you mean something
is erasing this galaxy?
Warning! Urgent update.
Observation Outpost Rose
will be compromised.
Evacuation procedures
urgently recommended.
You hear that System advice?
This is Serving Commander
Inston-Vee Vinder,
of Kasto-Winfer-Foxfell
doing the unthinkable
and leaving his post.
Escape procedures activated.
Survival pod ejection imminent.
Data, I need data.
What causes this Flux?
And where does it start?
I don't know.
I don't have a guidebook to it.
The other side of the universe,
somewhere.
Now, unblock my ship's systems.
I need to re-align with my battalion.
Fine, doing it!
But I'm keeping your weapons
powered down.
It doesn't make any sense.
You're moving away from Earth
but the rest are traveling towards it.
My ship hit a time disturbance
at the head of the battalion.
It meant I got to Earth a few hours
ahead of the others.
And your battalion aim to transport
humanity off Earth before the Flux hits.
That's what species bond means,
to protect when called upon.
And how will this ship survive the Flux?
Our survival battalion was engineered
and built to weather
whatever the Flux can throw at us.
Once the humans are on board,
the individual ships unite
to form a long-term survival structure.
Clever, except has anyone asked
humanity about this?
Because I think they're
going to have an opinion.
We don't need to ask them.
We're protecting them.
Yeah, well, we don't want
your protection.
We were supposed to be
sneaking in quietly.
Sorry.
Did you release him?
Yeah, I did.
And that's payback for
dangling me over boiling acid.
All systems back online,
including weapons.
Okay, plan modifications, in two stages.
One, this is not over, between me
and you, we are not done.
Two, run!
- Run, Doctor, Doctor, Dan!
- All right, Doc!
Nice to meet you Dan,
run for your life!
Give me back my human.
That's my human.
I am not your human!
You said it was a ship.
This isn't a ship.
It is, get in!
Why have you put a door
in the floor?
Bit of a daft place to have a door,
isn't it?
Seem to have a bit of a surplus
of doors right now, I'm not sure why.
Is this all inside that box?
It's bigger on the inside.
I can see that.
It's called a TARDIS.
I had a mate who had one of these.
I think his was a bit bigger actually.
Shut up.
By the way, here's your house.
What? How did that happen?
Karvanista set a trap for us,
which miniaturised it.
I can't live in that.
Right now you don't have a house.
Very soon you may not have a planet
and there may not be a universe.
- Is she joking?
- Are you joking?
Not joking, I'm trying to locate
an event called the Flux.
Karvanista seems to think
it will overwhelm most of the universe.
And you're looking for it?
We are.
Why don't I know about this?
And who else does?
Finally!
Psychic Surveyor Kragar,
concluding assessment, Commander.
It's been a long time, old comrade.
You look old.
My mission has withered me.
It is true.
Really? You look disgusting!
Yes, Well, no point dwelling on it.
Really disgusting.
Continue.
I have analysed the psychic waves
and it is my privilege to report
the cataclysm approaches.
The Flux is imminent.
I forecast incredible suffering,
vast bloodshed.
A conflict that will dwarf all
that has come before.
The greatest of times are upon us.
We must be ready to take advantage.
My old friend, I find myself, excited!
Yesss!
Why have you brought us here?
Multiple readings? It's one event.
I said, trace one event.
In all of time and space
and you bring us here, why?
- Who is she talking to?
- The TARDIS.
What, is it alive?
No idea, but they do chat.
It's brought us to the edge
of your solar system.
It doesn't make any sense.
There's nothing here.
Whoa, when you say nothing...
Yeah, nothing here
except an amazing view.
How could we breathe?
Protective air bubble.
I'll take your word for it.
What is it?
The Cloister Bell. It's a warning.
- Of what?
- The TARDIS is worried.
What's that?
The Flux! This is what
the Lupari have seen.
What they were trying to protect
humanity from.
What's it doing?
Disobeying every law of time and space.
Disrupting every particle
it comes into contact with.
Doctor, what's the matter?
I can feel it all.
I can feel the universe breaking.
But you can stop it, right?
No.
Hello again, Doctor.
Who are you?
They were so efficient.
There is not a tiny corner of you
that remembers.
Remembers what?
You and I,
dancing across space and time,
locked in combat.
And now, after so long apart,
we get to do it once more.
I don't know you.
Yet, I know you.
I remember every battle.
Which gives me the advantage.
Our final fight has begun.
Doctor, are you all right?
Stop asking me that.
Is it me, or does it look like
it's changing direction?
It's like it's coming for us!
Get inside!
Do not stall on me now.
Taking evasive action.
Sorry!
Really sorry!
This is impossible!
The end of universe is chasing us!
So what are you doing?
The only thing I can do.
If the Flux is coming for us,
we're gonna head to Earth.
What?
TARDIS calling Karvanista!
Bring me back my human, now!
I am not your human!
I'm trying to save your worthless life.
Listen to me,
we are approaching you fast
and the Flux is right behind us.
Following us, as we head to Earth.
It can't be.
We don't have enough time
to get all the humans
on board the ships.
The battalion's only on
the edge of the planet.
We have to have time, Doctor,
my family are there.
Mine too. And Di.
I'm late to meet Diane.
Diane,
inside the house.
Come on in.
I said...
come on in!
Stop walking, Di.
Stop walking now.
No, no.
We're going to have fun with you.
I've got a plan here!
There's only one chance to survive this!
Karvanista, you said the battalion ships
were designed to fit together
to form a protective structure.
What about it?
I am sending you a formation
for the ships,
get it communicated to them instantly.
You have to move fast!
What good will that do?
Just do it!
That shape, that formation,
got to outrun this thing.
We are being dragged
into the heart of the Flux!
Can the TARDIS withstand it?
I don't know! I don't understand it!
I hate not understanding.
Battalion positioned
just as you ordered!
Lock them into the pattern now!
This better work.
You're telling me!
Interlocking.
Lupari Battalion, now encasing Earth.
It worked! The pattern worked!
The battalion is shielding Earth!
Your ships better be as good
as you say they are, Karvanista.
What about you?
Get your ship behind
that Battalion wall.
Doing it now!
Trouble, right?
I can't get us out of its pull!
We can't outrun it!
But we are safe in here.
We are sealed in.
Oh, no!
Come on Doctor,
there must be something you can do!
One last throw of the dice...
Get down!
Flux, meet Vortex energy.
See what that does to you!
Ah, not much by the look of things.
Attack!
The end of the universe!
I always wondered
what it would feel like.
Please tell me you're not about
to engage Sontarans in battle?
Mrs Secole to you.
I accept your offer
of a massacre.