OHILA: He has asked to see you.
His servants seek you everywhere.
-Will you go?
-DOCTOR: No.
Why do you always lie?
-Why do you always assume I'm lying?
-It saves time. The truth.
-Will you go?
-No.
-When?
-Soon.
Why?
-Did something happen?
-No.
Was it recent?
Yes.
Whatever it was,
you owe that creature nothing.
He and I have known each other
a long time.
You've been enemies for all of it.
An enemy is just a friend
you don't really know yet.
Sorry, was that me being cynical again?
Aren't we friends, Doctor?
That's different. I don't like you.
(CHUCKLES) Which means you can trust me.
-You know who to give that to.
-(SIGHS)
I won't go straight away.
I'll hang out for a bit.
Probably meditate on a rock somewhere.
Get myself ready.
You are embarking on an enterprise
that will end in your destruction.
You can say that I'm being born.
Wherever you go,
there are people
who care enough to find you.
Look after the universe for me.
I've put a lot of work into it.
Anyone can hide from an enemy, Doctor...
No one from a friend.
(THUNDER CRACKS)