(HIGH PITCHED BUZZING)
-Have you got everything?
-I've got everything. Don't worry.
Be careful.
-You have to call Mo about...
-Never mind Mo.
-Okay, I'm going now. I love you.
-Love you.
-Bye.
-So where are we going?
-Further than we've ever gone before.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
It's the year five billion and twenty-three.
We're in the galaxy M87 and this...
This is New Earth.
ROSE: It's just...
That's just...
Not bad. Not bad at all.
ROSE: That's amazing.
I'll never get used to this, never.
Different ground beneath my feet.
Different sky.
What's that smell?
-Apple grass.
-Apple grass. It's beautiful.
Oh, I love this.
Can I just say, travelling with you...
I love it.
Me, too.
Come on.
Human! She's pure-blood human.
Closer, closer.
So, the year five billion,
the sun expands, the Earth gets roasted.
That was our first date.
We had chips.
So anyway, planet gone, all rocks and dust,
but the human race lives on,
spread out across the stars.
As soon as the Earth burns up,
oh, they get all nostalgic.
Big revival movement. They find this place.
Same size as the Earth,
same air, same orbit, lovely.
The call goes out, the humans move in.
-What's the city called?
-New New York.
-Oh, come on.
-It is!
It's the City of New New York.
Strictly speaking, it's the fifteenth
New York since the original.
So that makes it
New New New New New New New New New
New New New New New New York.
-What?
-You're so different.
New new Doctor.
CASSANDRA: Impossible!
I recognise that child.
Her face! Show me her face!
Closer, closer.
Face, face, face!
Can we go and visit New New York?
So good they named it twice.
Well, I thought we might go there first.
-Why? What is it?
-Some sort of hospital.
Green moon on the side,
that's the universal symbol for hospitals.
I got this. A message on the psychic paper.
Someone wants to see me.
Oh, and I thought we were just sightseeing.
Come on, then,
let's go and buy some grapes.
Rose Tyler! I knew it!
-That dirty blonde assassin.
-She's coming here, mistress.
But this is beyond coincidence.
This is destiny.
At last, I can be revenged on that little...
A bit rich coming from you.
I can't help it. I don't like hospitals.
They give me the creeps.
(PA) The pleasure gardens
will now take visitors
carrying green or blue identification cards
for the next 15 minutes.
Visitors are reminded that cuttings
from the gardens are not permitted.
Very smart. Not exactly NHS.
No shop. I like the little shop.
I thought this far in the future,
they'd have cured everything.
The human race moves on,
but so do the viruses. It's an ongoing war.
(PA) Hope, harmony and health.
-They're cats.
-Now, don't stare.
Think what you look like to them.
All pink and yellow.
That's where I'd put the shop, right there.
Ward 26, thanks.
Override controls.
Hold on, hold on!
-Oh, too late. I'm going up.
-All right, there's another lift.
Ward 26!
-And watch out for the disinfectant.
-Watch out for what?
-The disinfectant!
-The what?
The dis... Oh, you'll find out.
Ward 26, thanks.
(PA) Commence stage one disinfection.
Commence stage one disinfection.
The human child is clean.
Erm, I'm looking for ward 26.
This way, Rose Tyler.
Nice place.
No shop downstairs. I'd have a shop.
Not a big one, just a shop.
So people can shop.
The hospital is a place of healing.
A shop does some people
the world of good. Not me, other people.
The Sisters of Plenitude
take a lifelong vow to help and to mend.
(GROANING)
Excuse me!
Members of the public may only gaze
upon the Duke of Manhattan
with written permission from
the Senate of New New York.
-That's petrifold regression, right?
-I'm dying, sir.
A lifetime of charity and abstinence
and it ends like this.
Any statements made by
the Duke of Manhattan
may not be made public
without official clearance.
Frau Clovis...
I'm so weak.
Sister Jatt, a little privacy, please.
-He'll be up and about in no time.
-I doubt it.
Petrifold regression, he's turning to stone.
There won't be a cure for a thousand years.
He might be up and about
but only as a statue.
Have faith in the Sisterhood.
But is there no one here you recognise?
It's rather unusual to visit
without knowing the patient.
No, I think I've found him.
Novice Hame, if I can leave
this gentleman in your care.
Oh, I think my friend got lost.
Rose Tyler. Could you ask at reception?
Certainly, sir.
I'm afraid the Face of Boe is asleep.
That's all he tends to do these days.
Are you a friend, or...
We met just the once. On Platform One.
What's wrong with him?
I'm so sorry. I thought you knew.
The Face of Boe is dying.
-Of what?
-Old age. One thing we can't cure.
He's thousands of years old,
some people say millions,
although that's impossible.
Oh, I don't know. I like impossible.
I'm here. I look a bit different, but it's me.
It's the Doctor.
(THE FACE OF BOE GROANING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Look at me!
Isn't it wonderful?
Well, you never know what
your life is going to be like, ever.
I'm bored with this drink. Anyway...
Oh, hello, darling. Oh! Now don't. Stop It.
Wait a minute. That's...
Peek-a-boo!
Don't you come
anywhere near me, Cassandra.
Why? What do you think I'm going to do?
Flap you to death?
-Yeah, but what about Gollum?
-Oh, that's just Chip. He's my pet.
I worship the mistress.
Moisturise me, moisturise me.
He's not even a proper life form.
He's a force-grown clone.
I model led him on my favourite pattern.
But he's so faithful.
Chip sees to my physical needs.
I hope that means food.
How come you're still alive?
-After you murdered me?
-That was your own fault.
The brain of my mistress survived.
And her pretty blue eyes
were salvaged from the bin.
What about the skin?
I saw it. You got ripped apart.
That piece of skin
was taken from the front of my body.
This piece is the back.
-Right, so you're talking out of your...
-Ask not!
The mistress was lucky to survive.
Chip secreted m'lady into the hospital.
-So they don't know you're here?
-Chip steals medicine.
Helps m'lady. Soothes her.
-Strokes her.
-You can stop right there, Chip.
But I'm so alone, hidden down here.
-The last human in existence.
-Don't start that again.
-They've called this planet New Earth.
-A vegetable patch.
And there's millions of humans out there,
millions of them.
Mutant stock.
They evolved, Cassandra, they just evolved.
Like they should.
You stayed still, you got yourself
all pickled and preserved,
and what good did it do you?
I remember that night.
Drinks for the Ambassador of Thrace.
That was the last time anyone told me
I was beautiful.
After that, it all became such hard work.
You've got a knack for survival,
I'll give you that.
But I've not been idle, Rose.
Tucked away, underneath this hospital,
I've been listening.
The Sisters are hiding something.
What do you mean?
These cats have secrets.
Hush. Let me whisper, come close.
You must be joking
if you think I'm coming anywhere near you.
Chip! Activate the psycho-graft!
I can't move. Cassandra, let me go!
-What are you doing?
-The lady's moving on.
It's goodbye trampoline and hello blondie!
Mistress.
Moisturise me.
How bizarre. Arms.
Fingers!
Hair!
Let me see, let me see.
Oh, my God!
I'm a chav.
(PA) Hope, harmony and health.
Hope, harmony and health.
That's very kind. There's no need.
-You're the one working.
-There's not much to do.
Just maintain his smoke.
And I suppose I'm company.
I can hear him singing sometimes,
in my mind.
Such ancient songs.
Am I the only visitor?
The rest of Boekind
became extinct long ago.
He's the only one left.
Legend says that the Face of Boe
has watched the universe grow old.
There's all sorts of superstitions
around him.
One story says that just before his death,
the Face of Boe will impart his great secret.
That he will speak those words
only to one like himself.
-What does that mean?
-It's just a story.
Tell me the rest.
It's said he'll talk to a wanderer.
To the man without a home.
The lonely god.
Look at me. From class to brass.
Although...
Ooh.
Curves. Oh, baby!
It's like living inside a bouncy castle.
-The mistress is beautiful.
-Absolument.
Oh, but look.
Aw, the brain meat expired.
My old mistress has gone.
But safe and sound in here.
But what of the Rose child's mind?
Tucked away. I can just about access
the surface memory. She's...
God, she's with the Doctor.
That man, he's the Doctor.
The same Doctor with a new face!
That hypocrite!
I must get the name of his surgeon.
I could do with a little work. Although...
nice rear bumper.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh! It seems to be ringing.
Is it meant to ring?
A primitive communications device.
DOCTOR: Rose, where are you?
-How does she speak?
-Old Earth cockney.
Um...
-Wotcha.
-Where've you been?
-How long does it take to get to ward 267
-I'm on my way, guv'nor.
I shall proceed up the apples and pears.
You'll never guess!
I'm with the Face of Boe. Remember him?
Of course I do.
That big old...boat race.
I'd better go. See you in a minute.
(CHUCKLING)
I didn't think I was going to make it.
It's that man again!
He's my good luck charm.
Come in! Don't be shy.
Any friendship expressed by
the Duke of Manhattan does not constitute
-a form of legal contract.
-Winch me up!
-Up! Look at me. No sign of infection.
-Champagne, sir?
No, thanks.
-You had petrifold regression, right?
-"Had" being the operative word.
Past tense!
Completely cured.
-But that's impossible.
-Primitive species would accuse us of magic
but it's merely
the tender application of science.
How on earth did you cure him?
How on New Earth, you might say.
-What's in that solution?
-A simple remedy.
Then tell me what it is.
I'm sorry. Patient confidentiality.
I don't believe we've met.
My name is Matron Casp.
I'm the Doctor.
I think you'll find
that we are the doctors here.
Matron Casp,
you're needed in intensive care.
If you would excuse me.
It's happened again.
One of the patients is conscious.
Well, we can't have that.
This Doctor man is dangerous.
Dangerous and clever.
I might need a mind like his.
The Sisterhood is up to something.
Remember that old Earth saying?
"Never trust a nun...
"never trust a nurse and never trust a cat."
Perfume?
It was having a perfectly
normal blood-wash,
then all of a sudden it started crying.
It's this one.
CREATURE: Please.
-Look at its eyes. So alive.
-Help me.
-Positively sparkling.
-Please.
-Where am I?
-And speech.
How can it even have a vocabulary?
Sister Corvin has written a thesis
on the migration of sentience.
She calls it 7he Echo of Life.
It's well worth a read.
Help me.
I've seen enough, thank you.
If this happens again, we might
have to review our brainstem policy.
-And what should we do with the patient?
-Standard procedure. Incinerate.
(SCREAMING)
(PA) Ambient temperature
stands at 14 degrees cohezic.
Repeat, 14 degrees cohezic.
This temperature is designed to promote
healing and well-being.
There you are.
Come and look at this patient.
Marconi's disease.
Should take years to recover.
Two days. I've never seen anything like it.
They've invented a cell-washing cascade.
It's amazing.
Their medical science is way advanced.
And this one.
Pallidome pancrosis.
Kills you in ten minutes, and he's fine.
I need to find a terminal.
I've got to see how they do this.
'Cause if they've got the best medicine
in the world, then why is it such a secret?
I can't Adam and Eve it.
What... What's with the voice?
I don't know, just larking about. New Earth.
New me.
Well, I can talk. New new Doctor.
Mmm, aren't you just?
(STUTTERING) Terminal's this way.
Yeah, still got it.
No, nothing odd. Surgery. Post-op.
Nanodentistry.
No sign of a shop. They should have a shop.
No, it's missing something else.
When I was downstairs,
those nurse-cat-nuns
were talking about intensive care,
but where is it?
You're right. Well done.
Why would they hide a whole department?
It's got to be there somewhere.
Search the subframe.
What if the subframe's locked?
Try the installation protocol.
Yeah. Course. Sorry.
(DOOR OPENING)
Intensive care.
Certainly looks intensive.
That's disgusting. What's wrong with him?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
What disease is that?
All of them.
Every single disease in the galaxy.
They've been infected with everything.
What about us? Are we safe?
The air's sterile. Just don't touch them.
How many patients are there?
They're not patients.
But they're sick.
They were born sick.
They're meant to be sick.
They exist to be sick.
Lab rats.
No wonder the Sisters
have got a cure for everything.
They've built
the ultimate research laboratory.
A human farm!
Why don't they just die?
Plague carriers. The last to go.
It's for the greater cause.
Novice Hame.
When you took your vows,
did you agree to this?
The Sisterhood has sworn to help.
-What, by killing?
-But they're not real people.
They're specially grown.
They have no proper existence.
What's the turnover?
A thousand a day? Thousand the next?
Thousand the next? How many thousands?
For how many years? How many?
Mankind needed us.
They came to this planet
with so many illnesses, we couldn't cope.
We did try. We tried everything.
We tried using clone meat and bio-cattle,
but the results were too slow.
So the Sisterhood grew its own flesh.
That's all they are. Flesh.
These people are alive.
But think of those humans
out there, healthy,
and happy, because of us.
If they live because of this
then life is worthless.
But who are you to decide that?
I'm the Doctor.
And if you don't like it, if you want to take
it to a higher authority, there isn't one.
It stops with me.
Just to confirm...
none of the humans in the city
actually know about this?
-We thought it best not...
-Hold on. I can understand the bodies,
I can understand your vows,
but one thing I can't understand.
-What have you done to Rose?
-I don't know what you mean.
And I'm being very, very calm.
You want to be aware of that.
Very, very calm.
And the only reason
I'm being so very, very calm
is that the brain is a delicate thing.
Whatever you've done to Rose's head,
I want it reversed.
We haven't done anything.
I'm perfectly fine.
These people are dying
and Rose would care.
All right, clever clogs. Smarty-pants.
-Ladykiller.
-What's happened to you?
I knew something
was going on in this hospital
but I needed this body
and your mind to find it out.
Who are you?
The last human.
Cassandra?
Wake up and smell the perfume.
You've hurt him.
I don't understand.
I'll have to fetch Matron.
You do that 'cause I want to see her.
Now run along! Sound the alarm!
-Matron, it's that man and the girl.
-We heard the alarm.
Now, get back to work.
Tend to your patients.
Let me out! Let me out!
Aren't you lucky there was a spare?
Standing room only.
You've stolen Rose's body!
Over the years, I've thought of
a thousand ways to kill you, Doctor.
And now that's exactly what I've got.
One thousand diseases.
They pump the patients with a top-up
every 10 minutes.
You've got about three minutes left.
Enjoy.
-Just let Rose go, Cassandra.
-I will.
As soon as I find someone
younger and less common.
Then I'lWl junk her with the waste.
Now hush-a-bye.
It's showtime.
Anything we can do to help?
Straight to the point, whiskers.
I want money.
The Sisterhood is a charity,
we don't give money. We only accept.
The humans across the water
pay you a fortune,
and that's exactly what I need.
A one-off payment, that's all I want.
Oh, and perhaps a yacht,
in return for which
I will tell the city
nothing of your institutional murder.
-Is that a deal?
-I'm afraid not.
I'd really advise you to think about this.
Oh, there's no need. I have to decline.
I'll tell them.
And you've no way of stopping me.
You're not exactly nuns with guns.
You're not even armed.
Who needs arms when we have claws?
(SNARLING)
Well, nice try. Chip, plan B!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
What have you done?
Gave the system a shot of adrenalin,
just to wake them up. See ya!
Don't touch them!
Whatever you do, don't touch!
WOMAN: Save us.
I think we should withdraw.
We understood what you did to us.
As part of the machine,
we know the machine.
Fascinating. It's actually
constructing an argument.
And we will end it.
(ALL GROANING) Save us.
They're free.
By the goddess Santori!
The flesh is free!
(GROANING) Stop the pain.
(SCREAMING)
ROSE: Oh, my God!
-What the hell have you done?
-It wasn't me.
One touch
and you get every disease in the world.
And I want that body safe, Cassandra.
We've got to go down.
But there's thousands of them.
DOCTOR: Down, down, go down!
Quarantine the building!
(PA) This building is under quarantine.
Repeat, this building is under quarantine.
No one may leave the premises.
Repeat, no one may leave the premises.
DOCTOR: Keep going! Go down!
(WHISPERING) Help us. Save us.
(SCREAMING) Help me!
No, the lifts have closed down.
There's a quarantine, nothing's moving.
This way!
Don't let them touch you!
Leave him! This is a clone thing.
He's only got a half-life. Come on!
-Mistress!
-I'm sorry, I can't let her escape.
My mistress!
Excuse me, can we get some service?
(SCREAMING)
We're trapped! What are we going to do?
Well, for starters,
you're going to leave that body.
That psycho-graft is banned
on every civilised planet.
You're compressing Rose to death.
But I've got nowhere to go.
My original skin's dead.
Not my problem. You can float
as atoms in the air. Now get out.
Give her back to me.
You asked for it.
Blimey, my head.
Where did she go?
Oh my, this is...different.
-Cassandra?
-Goodness me, I'm a man.
Yum. So many parts. And hardly used.
Oh! Ah! Two hearts!
Oh, baby, I'm beating out a samba.
-Get out of him!
-Ooh, he's slim.
And a little bit foxy.
You thought so, too.
I've been inside your head.
You've been looking.
You like it.
What do we do? What would he do?
The Doctor! What the hell would he do?
Ladder. We've got to get up.
Out of the way, blondie!
Please! Help us!
If you get out of the Doctor's body,
he can think of something.
(MIMICKING ROSE)
God, it was tedious inside your head.
Hormone city.
But we're gonna die if... Ow!
Get off!
All our good work. All that healing.
The good name of the Sisterhood.
You have destroyed everything!
-Go and play with a ball of string.
-Everywhere, disease.
This is the human world. Sickness!
(SCREAMING)
Move!
(PA) Maximum quarantine.
Divert all shuttles.
Help us.
-Now what do we do?
-Use the sonic screwdriver.
-You mean this thing?
-Yes, I mean that thing!
But I don't know how!
That Doctor's hidden away all his thoughts.
Cassandra, go back into me.
The Doctor can open it.
Do it!
Hold on tight.
Oh, chav-tastic again.
-Open it!
-Not till you get out of her!
-We need the Doctor.
-I order you to leave her!
No matter how difficult the situation,
there is no need to shout.
Cassandra, get out of him!
But if I go into you, he simply refuses.
He's so rude.
I don't care, just do something!
Oh, I'm so going to regret this.
Oh, sweet Lord! I look disgusting.
-Nice to have you back.
-No, you don't.
That is your last warning, Cassandra.
Inside her head...
They're so alone.
They keep reaching out, just to hold us.
All their lives
and they've never been touched.
(BANGING)
We're safe, we're safe, we're safe!
We're clean, we're clean! Look, look.
-Show me your skin.
-Look! Clean! Look!
If we'd been touched, we'd be dead.
How's it going up here? What's the status?
Nothing but silence from the other wards.
I think we're the only ones left.
I've been trying to override the quarantine.
If I can trip a signal over to New New York,
they can send a private executive squad.
You can't do that. If they forced entry,
they'd break quarantine.
I am not dying in here.
We can't let
a single particle of disease get out.
There's 10 million people in that city,
they'd all be at risk. Now turn that off.
Not if it gets me out.
All right, fine.
So I have to stop you lot as well. Suits me.
Rose, Novice Hame, everyone!
Excuse me, Your Grace.
Get me the intravenous solutions
for every single disease! Move it!
-How's that? Will that do?
-I don't know. Will it do for what?
The lifts aren't working...
Not moving, different thing.
Here we go.
But you're not going to...
What do you think you're doing?
(MUMBLING)
Come on.
Not in a million years.
I need another pair of hands.
What do you think?
If you're so desperate to stay alive,
why don't you live a little?
Seal the door!
(MOANING) Help.
No!
You're completely mad.
I can see why she likes you.
Going down!
Well, that's one way to lose weight.
Now, listen.
When I say so, take hold of that lever.
There's still a quarantine down there.
We can't...
Hold that lever!
I'm cooking up a cocktail.
I know a bit about medicine myself.
Now, that lever's gonna resist,
but keep it in position.
-Hold on to it with everything you've got.
-What about you?
I've got an appointment. The Doctor is in.
I'm in here! Come on!
Don't tell them!
Pull that lever!
DOCTOR: Come and get me! Come on.
I'm in here! Come on!
-(PA) Commence stage one disinfection.
-Come and get me. Come on!
Come on. Come on.
All they want to do is pass it on.
Pass it on!
Pass on what?
(HISSING)
What did they pass on? Did you kill them?
All of them?
No, that's your way of doing things.
I'm the Doctor and I cured them.
That's right. Hey! There we go, sweetheart.
Hey?
Go to him. Go. That's it. That's it.
It's a new subspecies, Cassandra.
A brand-new form of life.
New humans. Look at them! Look!
Run by cats, kept in the dark, fed by tubes,
but completely, completely alive!
You can't deny them
'cause you helped create them.
The human race just keeps on going.
Keeps on changing. Life will out.
Ha!
MAN: This is the NNYPD.
Please step away from the shuttles.
(PA) All staff will present themselves
to the officers for immediate arrest.
I repeat. Immediate arrest.
All new life forms will be catalogued
and taken into care.
All visitors to the hospital will be
required to make a statement
to the NNYPD.
The Face of Boe!
You were supposed to be dying.
There are better things to do today.
Dying can wait.
Oh, I hate telepathy.
Just what I need, a head full of big-face.
Shh!
I had grown tired with the universe, Doctor,
but you have taught me to look at it anew.
There are legends, you know,
saying that you're millions of years old.
Well, now, that would be impossible.
DOCTOR: Wouldn't it just?
I got the impression there was
something you wanted to tell me.
A great secret.
So the legend says.
It can wait.
Oh, does it have to?
We shall meet again, Doctor,
for the third time, for the last time,
and the truth shall be told.
Until that day...
That is enigmatic.
That is...that is textbook enigmatic.
And now for you.
But everything's happy.
Everything's fine. Can't you just leave me?
You've lived long enough.
Leave that body and end it, Cassandra.
I don't want to die.
No one does.
-Help me.
-I can't.
Mistress...
Oh! You're alive!
I kept myself safe for you, mistress.
A body!
And not just that. A volunteer!
Don't you dare! He's got a life of his own.
But I worship the mistress.
I welcome her.
You can't, Cassandra. You...
Oh! You all right?
Okay?
Yeah.
Hello.
Hello. Welcome back.
Oh, sweet Lord! I'm a walking doodle.
You can't stay in there.
I'm sorry, Cassandra, but that's not fair.
I can take you to the city.
They can build you a skin-tank,
and you can stand trial
for what you've done.
Well, that would be rather dramatic.
Possibly my finest hour,
and certainly my finest hat.
But I'm afraid we don't have time.
Poor little Chip, he's only a half-life.
And he's been through so much.
His heart is racing so.
He's failing.
I don't think he's going to last...
-You all right?
-I'm fine.
I'm dying.
But that's fine.
I can take you to the city.
No, you won't.
Everything's new on this planet.
There's no place for Chip and me anymore.
You were right, Doctor.
It's time to die.
And that's good.
Come on, there's one last thing I can do.
(WHOOSHING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
CASSANDRA: Oh, no don't!
That's simply not true.
And believe me, it was so dismal.
And the mosquitoes, I can't tell you.
They were...
Thank you.
Just go. And don't look back.
Good luck.
And if you actually see them, you're shot!
But don't quote me on that.
-A bientot.
-Excuse me, the Lady Cassandra?
I'm sorry, I don't need anything right now.
I'm fine, thank you.
No, I just wanted to say...
you look beautiful.
Well. That's very kind,
you strange little thing.
Thank you very much.
I mean it.
You look...
so beautiful.
Thank you.
Oh, my Lord. Are you all right?
What is it? What's wrong?
Someone get some help!
Call a medic or something, quickly.
I don't know, he just came up to me.
Don't even know his name.
He just collapsed.
I think he's dying. Someone do something!
I've got you, sweetheart. It's all right.
There you are.
There you are. I've got you.
It'll be alright. There, there.
You poor little thing.
Might I introduce
Her Majesty Queen Victoria?
MAN: Every full moon,
the howling rings through the valley.
This is a man who becomes an animal.
A werewolf?
WOMAN: But it can't be an actual wolf.
(GROWLING)
Bullets can't stop it!
(HOWLING)