(BIRDSONG)
Come on.
Got ya.
(CRACKING)
Just a little closer...
(SCREAMS)
TANNOY: Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be commencing
our descent into Tokyo
in approximately 30 minutes.
Please take a moment
to use the washrooms
and collect up
all your belongings.
Excuse me.
Is this wash bag yours?
I just found it in the aisle.
Yes. Sorry.
I'm so clumsy.
My sister's always having
a go at me for this.
- Thanks.
- No problem at all.
Enjoy your flight.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(CRACKING)
(GASPS)
(CAR HORN BLARES)
I'm at the safe house. How long
for the extraction team?
Just make it fast.
(GENTLE PATTERING)
(CRACKING)
(PLAYERS CALL OUT)
(FOOTAGE SLOWS)
(MUFFLED) Go on, Ryan!
Shoot!
- (NORMAL-SPEED FOOTAGE)
- (PLAYERS JEER AND SHOUT)
(BELL RINGS)
Unlucky, man.
- So, next week?
- Yeah.
Laters.
You can play now, man.
You never used
to step on the court.
I should've got it in.
I'll get it in next time.
You've been sick, though.
Appendicitis, right?
That's why we ain't seen you?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- And the hernia before that?
Oh, yeah. That was bad.
And that detached retina?
Pt!
That sounds painful.
You've been so unlucky.
- So unlucky.
- So what, we don't see you
and now you're off travelling?
- Only for a bit.
- Better be.
I've missed you, man.
We all do.
Is there a problem, guys?
WOMAN: Just give me his number.
No!
Alexa, play Rubber Soul.
- Why not?
- Because!
I don't want to give you
his number. I'm packing.
This is the third secondment
you've been selected for.
Is it?
I thought it was the second.
You're not even
going to be here.
And all this
during your probationer period?
I know. It's amazing.
Is his number in here? Oh!
Play Rubber Soul!
ALEXA: The nearest shoe shop
ls 1.2 miles walking distance.
I think it just hates
your voice, Dad.
And your boss is all right
with you being away on this?
Totally.
He's totally all right with it.
I'm not all right
with this, Yaz.
This is your fourth secondment.
Fourth time I get a load
of secretive paperwork,
and you not telling me
anything.
Why do I keep losing
my best probationer?
It's all really good
experience. Honest.
I'm not daft.
Have you had a tap on the
shoulder? Is this undercover?
Sort of.
Last time.
You have to be here
to finish your probation.
I know. I'm coming back,
I promise.
And I presume they're with you?
Four years since
your procedure. Time flies.
- Yeah. Don't it just?
- Test results are all
as they should be,
you'll be pleased to hear.
Any weight fluctuations?
No.
Tiredness?
Muscular aches or pains?
None of that.
I was sorry to hear
about your wife.
Yeah. Thanks.
- We all miss her.
- Yeah.
Right. I don't need to keep you
any longer. Sign on there.
Tick all the boxes.
Data protection.
Right.
- Are you working?
- Um, no. Travelling.
Oh. Anywhere nice?
Sometimes.
(MACHINERY WHIRS)
Ah! There's the blockage.
Oh, sorry! Group message.
Got to concentrate.
Just calling to say hi, fam.
Where are you?
We said an hour. You're late.
Very late.
All of you?
(CAR DOORS OPEN AND CLOSE)
Hi, fellas.
Rocking the ominous look.
We need you to come with us.
Can I finish up first?
Just draining the water slides.
And the boating lakes.
And the rain forest floor.
Plus, I'm waiting for my mates.
Your friends
are inside the car.
Worst Uber ever!
Look, it's in
all your best interests
that you come with us.
SAT NAV: In half a mile,
continue ahead
and merge with motorway.
How are you doing?
Everything go all right?
Apart from being kidnapped!
Come on. What's the plan?
I thought, let him take us
to where we're going.
That way,
we find out who wants us.
What if he kills us
along the way?
Look at him.
He's obviously doing this
at someone else's orders.
Don't you want to know
who that is?
SAT NAV: In 7100 yards...
(AUDIO DISTORTS)
Your equipment's
not up to much.
It shouldn't be doing that.
(GASPS)
(TYRES SCREECH)
(ALL SCREAM)
(HORNS BLARE)
We can't get out!
- Yes, I got that, Yaz!
- Hey!
Doc, the sat nav's
just started again!
SAT NAV: In five seconds,
- die.
- (BEEPING)
SAT NAV: Die. Die.
Die. Die. Die...
(AUDIO DISTORTS)
...Die. Die. Die...
(TYRES SCREECH)
The brake's not working!
Someone's controlling this car,
and it isn't me!
(SCREAMING)
(SONIC BUZZES)
There's got to be a way
to stop it!
(SCREAMING)
Look behind us! The road's out!
We're going over the edge!
SAT NAV: ...Die. Die. Die...
I need a reflective surface...
- Hold on!
- (TYRES SCREECH)
(ALL GASP)
SPEAKER: What the hell
Just happened?
What have you idiots
done with my car?
Who's talking?
Your car just assassinated
its driver
and then attempted
to kill us!
That's not possible.
Tell me who you are,
and I'll tell you face to face
just how possible
that actually was.
This is C. I was having you
brought to London.
To MI6.
What? MI6 is trying to kill us?
- No/
- Well, you nearly managed it.
All right, C, you want us?
We want answers.
We're coming in.
Ah! At least they managed
to transport my TARDIS
without damage.
GRAHAM: Ryan, MI6!
I always wanted to be a spy.
- You'd be a rubbish spy.
- I'd be a great spy.
- I'd just blend in.
- Well, well, well.
Finally we meet.
You actually do exist!
- What?
- (WHISPERS)
Don't be ridiculous, Franklin.
I've read the files.
The Doctor is a man.
I've had an upgrade.
Hi.
Oh...
You just had us picked up
like criminals
and put in a car
which tried to kill us.
We were trying to bring
you here, not kill you,
but our systems got hacked.
Not exactly the best
demonstration of MI6 skills.
I have been authorised
to speak on behalf
of every security agency
around the globe.
We need your help...
...Doctor.
Over the past week,
there's been a spate of attacks
on intelligence officers
worldwide,
of every nationality.
None of these attacks
has been ordered
by rival intelligence agencies.
At least that's what
you're all telling each other.
No, we all have a very good
working knowledge
of what our enemies are up to.
No agency possesses
the technology
to carry out
one of these attacks.
None of us understands
how it was done.
Or even what has been done.
But every agent
has suffered the same fate.
(MONITORS BEEP)
She was found unconscious
on the floor
of an aeroplane washroom
on a flight to Tokyo.
She'd made pre-arranged contact
with an informant.
Is she in a coma?
Apparently, it's a little
more horrific than that.
Now, I'm told
this is your expertise -
dealing with the impossible.
You're right.
That is impossible.
Her DNA's been rewritten.
Every strand corrupted
and reshaped.
She's no longer human.
Just a shell
with a human appearance.
Is she going to live, Doc?
There's nothing of her fo live.
It's like she's been erased.
This is beyond
any human technology.
Ah.
I was rather worried
you were going to say that.
Doctor, the security of
this entire planet is at stake.
Can we rely upon you?
C: Anaesthetic darts,
laser shoe gun,
infrared ID duplicator,
calendar hacker,
lock-breakers,
rocket-launcher cuff links,
retinal ID decoder and
tongue-immobiliser chewing gum.
How much more do you want?
Yeah, it's great.
Keep 'em coming, C.
- Yeah, bring on the bling.
- They are not toys!
Yeah. They're not toys, Graham.
No, they're not, Ryan,
and if you say otherwise,
I will shoot you
with my laser shoe!
C: All of the assassinated
agents were investigating
leads relating to this man.
Daniel Barton.
Born in Bromsgrove.
Now lives
just north of San Francisco.
- He's the founder of VOR.
- The search engine.
Web, apps, social,
global mapping, advertising,
scientific
and medical research,
robotics, data polling,
human analytics...
Right now, VOR is more powerful
than most nations.
Daniel Barton is the man
who built it all up
from the ground.
We're going to need
your best man on this.
What do you call him?
Horizon-watcher?
Oh.
- Exactly.
- Well, he...um...
He left.
I...sacked him.
The only person with
an open mind about all this
and you let him go?
MI6 has never countenanced
the possibility
of extraterrestrial life.
Well, you should talk
to your mates at GCHQ!
The country
has other organisations
that deal with all that!
UNIT. Even Torchwood.
They're all gone.
Oh, C! You took your eye
off the horizon
just as things
were coming over it.
Don't worry. I'll call him.
You can't. He's off-grid.
We can't find him anywhere.
Believe me, we've tried.
Shh. I'm WhatsApping.
Hi. It's me.
I'm at MI6 with C. Crisis.
Big crisis.
Serious crisis.
Big, serious crisis.
And C says you were right and
he's sorry for being an idiot.
I did not use those words!
Send us your location. Kisses.
It's quite French, that,
isn't it?
- Kisses?
- (PHONE PINGS)
Ah!
- See?
- G Yes?
- It's a fish.
- I know!
C: Can we please focus?
Daniel Barton
isn't just
a powerful businessman.
He was also one of our agents
when he first went
to work in the US.
Then he withdrew cooperation.
It's possible
he became a double agent.
- Or even a triple.
- Who for?
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
(GASPS)
- Down!
- (ALL GASP)
Go!
(GROANS)
Get to the TARDIS!
Agh!
DOCTOR: We've got
to get out of here.
GRAHAM: We've still got
the gadgets.
We just saw the head of MI6
get assassinated.
Yeah, by the same sort of bolts
that came through that sat nav.
Where's that picture?
I need to set the coordinates.
Ooh, I've got it.
So, wrong place, wrong time
twice in one day.
That's got to make us targets.
And why do you keep looking
at pictures of a fish?
Steganography.
There's another image
hidden within the pixels
of that photo.
It's basic spy craft
in your time.
Easy way to smuggle out
information
because there's
no pattern to look for.
- (CRACKING)
- No two stegs are the same.
RYAN: So one's hidden
inside the other?
- Doc.
- Exactly.
Luckily, I can read pixels.
I took a correspondence class.
- Doc...
- Ooh, the outback.
Gone full hermit.
Doctor,
something's trying to get in!
(CRACKING)
Oh, no, you don't.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
(SONIC BUZZES)
(BUZZING AND THRUMMING STOP)
I didn't know things could get
into the TARDIS like that.
Neither did 1.
RYAN: But you got rid of it.
GRAHAM: Yeah, but what was it?
At a guess, the same thing
that attacked all those spies.
- And possibly us.
- (SONIC BLOOPS)
What?
No readings?
The sonic can usually
read everything.
All right, park that.
Live attacks. They're after us,
but we need intel.
Split resources. Graham,
me and you are off to Australia
to see my old mate
from MI6. I say old mate -
I've met him once,
but he seemed very nice.
We text, though.
Does that count?
- If you say so.
- Yaz, Ryan,
how do you feel
about undercover work?
- Definitely!
- I don't know.
Daniel Barton -
he's our best lead.
Well, he's our only lead.
We'll get you a cover story.
Hack his diary, get in there,
check him out. Infiltrate VOR.
Have a nose
- around their systems.
- Be spies, basically.
GRAHAM: What,
with absolutely no training?
- We got the gadgets.
- All the gear, but no idea.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
- No, I think you'll be great.
I have total confidence,
you know?
Just, um...
Just be careful, though.
It's safe for them, though,
right?
Yeah. 80% sure.
75.
40% - absolute minimum.
Take this.
Bio-scanner disguised
as a digital recorder.
I want to know everything
about Daniel Barton.
Like Graham said, be careful.
Stay in touch.
And remember,
rule 1 of espionage -
trust no-one.
Diary hacked, got us in.
Loving these toys.
- Which building is it?
- That one there.
Though according to the files,
this whole development
is down to Barton.
So, you journalist,
me photographer?
Yeah. That works, doesn't it?
I reckon.
We've just got to try and be
confident with it, haven't we?
Try not to panic that
we're blagging our way in
on someone
who might be dangerous.
And don't obsess on
our total lack of spy training.
Yeah. Don't obsess on that.
Think how
the Doctor would do it.
Swan in there
like she owns the place,
big smiles, loads of chat,
total confidence.
We can do this.
Why are you looking so worried?
I decided my spy name would be
Logan, and now I'm worried
I don't look anything
like Hugh Jackman.
Ryan, you're panicking.
Rule 1 - no panicking.
I thought rule I was
don't trust anybody!
Rule 13, then - no panicking
while you're not
trusting anyone!
I am so sorry about
the diary snafu, sir.
Oh, dear, this must be them.
Hi! I'm sure
you recognise Mr Barton.
RYAN: Certainly do.
- This is Sofia Afzal.
- Hi.
- And this is Logan...?
- I'm Logan.
The name's Logan Jackson.
I'm the photographer.
I'm Sofia. He's nervous.
Big fan of yours.
(GIGGLES) I'm not nervous.
Who's nervous?
Hi.
Logan. I'm... I'm Logan.
Daniel.
Don't be nervous. I don't bite.
Only my own staff.
Especially after this mix-up.
I had to fire half the PR team.
- You haven't?
- No, not half.
Uh... He's kidding. Just...two.
Shall we go up?
I'm sure they'll be able
to find other jobs. Won't they?
(TARDIS THRUMS)
Worth racing up from the city
- just for that.
- Got to be a trick, right?
Projection? Mirrors?
Say hello to the Doctor.
I see you decoded the fish.
- Fancy a cuppa?
- Very much.
Hello.
This is my friend Graham.
O!
- Sorry, you're...?
- 0.
- 07
- Oh.
- It was a joke
by the others at MI6.
Whenever I came into the room
to meet C,
he'd go, "Oh, God!"
Oh!
It sort of stuck,
and now I've owned it.
This is Seesay and Browning.
Just arrived.
Australian secret service.
We'll be out here
for the whole of your visit.
We're under orders
to keep all of you safe.
Safe from what?
Not sure.
You're going to be a right lot
of help, then, aren't you?
Can I take a nose
around your gaff?
I love the outback.
I once lived in the outback
for 123 years.
I saw some great rocks.
Cosy!
You mean messy.
You're right, I do.
Didn't realise you were
this much of a hoarder.
What is all this stuff?
The full MI6 record
of the unexplained.
As compiled by me.
Human disappearances, sightings
of unidentified objects,
mysterious beings,
possible alien incursions
going back centuries.
And a complete set of Fortean
Times in mint condition.
Look at all the evidence
I gathered.
And they just mocked me.
No-one's mocking you now.
I heard C was shot.
We were there.
Nearly got us an' all.
Does this connect
to the attacks on agents?
I have been monitoring
the chatter, Doctor.
Is it aliens?
Aliens attacking spies
all over the world?
And rewriting their DNA.
That's terrifying. But...
- Wow! Why would they do that?
- I don't know.
They almost infiltrated my
TARDIS as we were taking off.
I thought you might
have something
in your research banks
that might give us some clues.
Wow! This is some setup.
Paranoid, are we?
No. I prefer cautious.
I like to know
if anything's watching me.
And if you're already
in the middle of all of this,
how do you know
they won't follow you here?
How do you know
you haven't become targets too?
I have to be honest
with you - you only got in
cos you're Brits.
And my mum reads your paper.
She's old.
Still into legacy media.
We know you're busy,
so Logan will take a few photos
while we chat.
OK if I record?
- (BEEPS)
- Right, then.
Good to go?
Just searching you up.
Check you are
who you say you are.
Fire away, then.
Boy from Bromsgrove.
Council estate,
local comprehensive.
Now with his own collection
of planes and motorbikes.
And a private airport.
We couldn't afford to go abroad
when I was a kid.
Now flying's
one of my big hobbies.
I've even got
my own passenger plane.
I fly my mates around the world
and insult them over
the intercom during the flight.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
I bet that goes down well. So,
how did you end up here, then?
A combination of inspiring
computer science teacher,
plus being one of the few
non-white faces at my school.
I spent a lot of time
in my bedroom with my computer.
I started small,
just trying to build
a knowledge base.
Trying to connect people
with data.
And that became the biggest
search engine on the planet.
And more.
This company is far more
than just a search engine now.
Sure.
But the same principles apply.
The more data we share,
the better it is for the world.
Unless you count
disinformation.
Online abuse. Cyber bullying.
All of which you've been
accused of ignoring.
Haven't you?
Well, we have three start-ups
currently trying to figure out
how to combat them.
We did something great,
and it got hijacked.
I get to see both sides
of humanity in this job.
And do you know what, Sofia?
It turns out
you can't entirely
trust everyone.
(PHONE VIBRATES)
Sorry.
I've got to cut this short.
- Something needs my attention.
- We were just getting started.
You want to know who I am?
You want to see my house,
meet my friends?
Cos it's my birthday tomorrow.
I'm having a party.
Everyone who knows me
will be there. Come along -
as my apology
for running out on you.
I've managed
to duplicate his access pass.
If we find a place to hide
and do some snooping around
whilst everyone knocks off...
Hey!
Why are you looking all weird?
DNA profile.
Only 93% human.
What's the other 7%?
Who is this guy?
This place - it's open and flat
and empty the whole way round.
So why does it feel like
there are things
moving out there?
(WHIRRING AND BEEPING)
GRAHAM: What just happened?
Two movement sensors tripped.
(SECURITY LIGHT TRIPS)
What's doing that?
What have you brought here,
Doctor?
I don't know.
Let's take a look outside.
Looking outside was actually
quite low on my list.
But when does she
ever listen to me?
(ANIMAL HOWLS)
(DOOR CLATTERS)
Please, all of you,
back inside!
(SONIC BUZZES)
No readings.
You didn't get any readings
off that thing
in the TARDIS either.
Exactly. There's something...
It's like I can sense them.
- I know what you mean.
- They're out there, hiding.
Tripping the sensors to let us
know that they're here.
It's like they're watching us.
Like animals
stalking their prey.
Sorry, that wasn't helpful.
From what I understand, we were
sent here cos you're one
of the few people that can stop
the attacks on our colleagues.
So, please, go inside,
figure it out, and let us
do the job we came for.
Doc... Come on.
SEESAY: I'll take round
the back. Stay on comms.
OVER RADIO:
Circling around eastwards.
Understood.
(LIGHT CLICKS OFF)
(LIGHT CLICKS ON)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
SEESAY: See those lights
going on and off?
BROWNING: It's where I am,
but it's not me.
(BROWNING GASPS)
Browning!
Stay back!
Run!
Oh, my God!
What are they?
Get away from them!
(ROARING)
We can't fight them out here,
Doctor.
Strategic retreat.
Fine.
No signals off any of them.
They've just obliterated
those bodies. What can they be?
(BEEPING)
Looks like they're moving.
They're surrounding
the building, look.
- That's what we want?
- Do we?
Yeah.
Just a little closer...
(GASPS)
- Did you kill 'em?
- More like they retreated.
- How did you know that'd work?
- I didn't. Gambled.
Some kit you've got here.
I've had a few years
to rig it out.
- Just in case.
- No, no, look.
There's one still outside.
Plan B. I've got a plan B.
It's in the blueprints, Doctor,
just under the folder.
I rigged it
in case anything got past
the first line of defence.
GRAHAM: It's coming through
the wall! How can it do that?
DOCTOR: Physical boundaries
don't stop it.
It's still not used
to this planet
or maybe even this reality.
- Spring-loaded?
- Yep.
What are you talking about?
Oh, you could have warned me
about that!
Re-route the charge.
We've got to keep it in there.
- A bit quicker!
- Yes! Doing my best.
That thing can't hold it.
Is he just here for
the running commentary?
(SCREECHES)
It worked! It actually worked!
(SPARKING AND FIZZING)
Who are you?
What are you doing
to the people on this planet?
Why are you changing their DNA?
And why spies? Why are you
only attacking spies?
What are you, exactly,
except for reluctant to talk?
I'm thinking one more blast.
How many are you
in your race or species
or whatever you are?
Where are you from?
CREATURE: Far beyond.
So you can communicate, then.
Beyond where?
CREATURE: Your understanding!
(CHUCKLES)
I think it's laughing
at you, Doc.
Yes, I got that!
Is this your native form,
wherever it is you're from?
Is this what you look like
at home?
CREATURE:
We take this form to mock you.
Your shape amuses us.
Very funny.
CREATURE: We are stable now.
We are ready.
What does that mean, "stable"?
Ready for what?
- CREATURE: To take this.
- To take this what? Hut?
Country? Planet?
CREATURE: Universe.
RYAN: Data from Barton's pass
says
he left the building hours ago.
Everyone must have gone by now.
Let's have a look.
(BEEP)
- (BEEP)
- RYAN: We're in.
YAZ: Right.
We've got to be quick.
If the Doctor's right,
that should download
every piece of data
his computer has ever
had access to.
- Have you seen this?
- RYAN: What? That thing
in the case over there?
Yeah, a bit creepy.
YAZ: No. All these cameras.
He's got screens
monitoring half the building.
Control freak, innit?
How long do you reckon
the thing's going to take?
Let's see.
YAZ: Still clear?
RYAN: Yep, all good.
YAZ: You know my sister's
still proper cross
I haven't given her
your phone number.
- Why haven't you?
- Ryan, you're my mate.
I don't want you
snogging my sister!
She's all right, your sister.
- Can you not, please?
- Just give me her number, Yaz.
Shut up!
I could be your brother-in-law.
I'd be a good brother-in-law.
(BEEPING)
Barton's back in the building.
His pass just got access.
He's coming this way!
I'm not done! How close is he?
Quick, Yaz! He's coming!
Get off the computer!
Bag, bag, bag...
There it is.
I know you're here.
Show yourselves.
(FIZZING AND CRACKING)
CREATURE: There have been
obstacles.
I told you to be discreet.
CREATURE: We must
remove them all
- immediately.
- No.
CREATURE: The project
must continue as planned.
We must defend.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
He knows what they are.
Come on, out!
No.
Let's see what else is here.
No. No.
(FIZZING AND CRACKING)
- Yaz!
- CREATURE: Obstacle!
(SCREAMS)
Yaz!
What have you done with her?
Get her back here right now!
Where is she?!
CREATURE: She is gone.
I'm sorry, Yaz.
(GASPS)
OK.
PC Khan.
Nothing to worry about.
(ECHOING) Hello?
Anyone here?
Ryan?!
Interesting.
That glow's increasing.
Life getting more intense...
- O: It's fighting back.
- ...or something going on?
No...
Stay away from me!
What's happening?
This isn't good, Doctor.
It's trying to overload
my system.
(GROANS)
It's like
it's taken a suicide pill!
No.
(SCREAMS)
(ALL GASP)
Yaz!
- Turn the power off in there.
- 0. W's already blown out.
Yaz! How are you even here?
(PHONE RINGS)
Doctor, you've got to help!
I've lost Yaz!
Yaz? I've got her.
We're coming for you now.
You OK?
You get any sleep?
What happened to you?
Don't know.
It were just like...
...nothingness.
Nowhere.
And I was totally alone.
I was so scared.
Ryan...
...I thought I was dead.
Nah.
I'm never going
to let that happen to you.
GRAHAM: You chose
to exile yourself here?
- Yeah.
- Ta.
Thanks. You never get lonely?
Yeah.
- But it's for the best.
- Right.
How long have you known
the Doctor, Graham?
Oh, it's a tricky one
to answer, that. You see,
things never really happen in
a straight line with the Doc.
How much do you know about her?
A bit.
Our paths crossed very briefly
once, when she was a man.
- When she was a what?
- Has she never mentioned that?
I thought she was joking!
You got any idea
where she's from?
Well, we've tried to ask,
but she just changes
the subject, you know?
I've got a whole shelf over
there all about the Doctor.
Everything I could gather.
A lot of inconsistencies,
but it's very,
very interesting.
Do you want to have a look?
(DOOR OPENS)
Come on, you two.
Everyone out front. Lots to
catch up on. I made iced tea.
Possibly.
Daniel Barton's DNA
registers as 93% human.
Which makes him, what, alien?
No, it can't be. I've been
through Barton's records.
There are thousands of photos
of him online at all ages.
If he's not human,
that's one very impressive
legend he's put together.
Not impossible, though.
All right, MI6,
help me with something,
cos I can't get me nut
round it.
C told us that Barton's company
is more powerful
than most countries.
That can't be true.
Governments these days
are full of people
who don't understand
technology,
so countries rely
on outsourcing
their tech requirements
and expertise
to private companies that
transcend national boundaries.
Companies like VOR.
VOR seeps into every corner
of modern technology.
We're talking leisure,
commercial, military.
It leads the way
on face-tagging,
bio data, robotics.
And then there's all
the military systems
across the globe which rely
on servers operated by VOR.
So do we think Barton's behind
the assassination of C?
And the attacking of us
in the car?
Andie in league
with these aliens?
What did he say to
those creatures in his office?
That they should have been
discreet.
So it was like he was
in control of them?
I couldn't work out
who's in charge of who.
(LAPTOP BEEPS)
Ah, found something.
I've been searching
through all the data
you took from Barton
for any codes
or languages
not of this planet,
and it's found something.
In the furthest corner
of the smallest system
of the most obscure company
in Barton's empire -
alien code!
Just decrypting.
Running about 90 billion
possible languages.
Ah.
Nothing.
That can't be right.
I've checked it against every
known language in the universe
and there's no match.
Ah, wait!
I keep the TARDIS systems open
for new languages,
even on the fringes
of the known universe.
If I can synch that...
Bingo! Right, we need
a dark wall. Come on!
RYAN: What is that?
Not sure. A single image
encrypted in alien code.
Trying to decode.
One image, though.
Steganography.
Like what he sent you -
a picture of a fish?
I can't see a pattern
at all, Doc.
Decoding takes a moment.
(SONIC BUZZES)
RYAN: What's that?
Join the dots?
I think it's coordinates.
Coordinates for what?
Locations for those creatures
across planet Earth.
Oh..
That's more than just a few.
There's hundreds of 'em.
We can't deal with all those.
What are they doing here,
anyway?
It's all in the patterns.
Steganography, encrypted code,
attacks on intelligence agents.
It's all spy craft!
They're alien spies
embedded here on Earth!
No, that's not possible.
- Spies from where?
- I don't know.
I don't recognise them.
I don't recognise the language.
Or why
they're attacking people.
Or what happened to you.
The image is still changing,
Doc.
More layers
still being decrypted.
Oh...
Why's it doing that?
I don't understand.
Multiple Earths -
what does that even mean?
OK. OK. If you really think
they're spies,
we should be asking,
"Who's the spymaster?
"Who's running
the alien spies?”
Because that's the person
who holds the answers.
That's got to be
that Daniel Barton, right?
C said they thought Barton
was a double or triple agent.
We need to pay Barton a visit.
Good thing he's having a party,
then. We got invites.
Yes! Nice work, you two.
Got invites for us all,
have you?
I'm sure I can hack a guest
list. What do you reckon, O?
Fancy a trip in the box?
I really, really would.
Be my guest.
Shut up!
Ridiculous.
Somewhere
in the lower substrata
there's a wardrobe hall.
I think it's the first right
after the karaoke buses.
What do we need a wardrobe for?
Shall we?
The name's Doctor. The Doctor.
- We're on the list.
- Welcome. Go right on in.
Thanks for coming.
Is this a bad time to mention
I've never really done
undercover work?
- You said you worked for MI6!
- As an analyst. In the office.
It's a party. We're guests.
Blend in.
And keep an eye out
for Daniel Barton.
YAZ: That should download
every piece of data
his computer
has ever had access to.
Thanks, Anya.
RYAN: Red seven!
Put it on red seven.
- Lucky number seven.
- GRAHAM: All of it?
- CROUPIER: No more bets.
- You'd better be right. Seven.
CROUPIER: Seven.
RYAN: Get in!
I'm rich!
Good evening, ladies.
That's my grandson.
Seven! Get it!
Card.
Snap!
(GUESTS LAUGH)
Is that not the game?
- Did we win?
- No.
Didn't know
what I was doing anyway.
You know what they say -
lucky at dice, unlucky in love.
- Do they say that?
- No.
(DOOR OPENS)
Time for a chat.
Nice party.
Nice house.
Daniel. I don't think
we've been introduced.
I'm the Doctor.
I'm a plus-one.
So, did you assassinate
the head of MI6 yourself,
or just order it?
I think
you're at the wrong party.
Casino theme, not whodunnit.
Why is there an alien code
embedded at the edge
of your company's systems?
We both know you're in league
with a race of alien creatures.
I think you'd better get your
medication checked, Doctor,
or maybe some psychiatric help,
because I don't know
who you are
or what you're talking about.
How long have they been here?
Where are they from?
Who recruited whom?
Are you running them,
or are they running you?
Why is your DNA 7% non-human?
You're properly unhinged.
No. I'm onto you,
and1'm going to stop you.
I'm going to walk away now
and you're going
to stay away from me
for the rest of both our lives,
either voluntarily or because
of my security people.
Understand?
I'm really hard to get rid of,
Mr Barton.
Are you?
Barton's heading your way,
gang.
Keep an eye on him.
Don't let him
out of your sight.
None of you saw him
come back in?
- He must be here somewhere.
- There he is!
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
Oh, no, you don't.
(TYRES SCREECH)
GRAHAM: He's off!
RYAN: I mean, who leaves
their own birthday party?
He's definitely guilty.
So what do we do now?
Remember our trip to
the Great Kalisperon Bike-Off?
Sir, it seems we have three of
your motorcycles following us.
What exactly do I pay you for?
- Go, go, go, go!
- I'm going! I'm going!
- (GUNSHOT)
- (LAUGHS)
(GUNSHOTS)
- Hey! He's shooting at us!
- Yes, I got that!
Oh!
Is this what it's like
being with the Doctor?
(YELLS)
Mate, this is one
of the quiet days! Agh!
What now?
(HANGAR DOOR BANGS SHUT)
(SONIC BUZZES)
- BARTON: She ready to go?
- All secure, Mr Barton.
How many planes
does one guy need?
There he is.
- That's one big plane.
- Where's he going in that?
I don't know,
but we can't let him get away.
How? It's not as if we're gonna
just jump on a plane
with him, is it?
Aww, come on!
(SIGHS)
Lonsdale tower,
Barton one-niner,
request clearance.
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- Oh!
(GROANS)
COMMS: Cleared to Hawkston
radar vectors to Skaggs Island,
- then as filed. Squawk 4634.
- (CONTROL PANEL BEEPS)
She's in!
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- Fix alert sensors.
- Agh!
- I've got you, Yaz.
COMMS: Barton one-niner,
climb 3,000 feet
maintain runway heading.
Cleared for takeoff.
- Runway zero one.
- Cleared for takeoff.
Runway zero one.
Maintain runway heading.
Climb 3,000 feet,
Barton one-niner.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Hey, where are you going?
- Come on, son!
I need to close the door!
Sorry. I've never been good
at sprinting.
What?!
Come on, Doctor.
We're about to take off.
In the main cabin!
(SONIC BUZZES)
Here...
YAZ: What are we
actually going to do?
Sit tight.
See where he's going.
Never been good at sprinting?
I was the last one
in every race at school.
No, no, no. I read your file.
You were a champion sprinter.
Mmm.
Got me.
Well done.
- GRAHAM: What's going on, Doc?
- I don't know.
You'd best take a look
out of the window.
GRAHAM: How's your house
out there?
Bit Wicked Witch of the West,
but you get the gist.
Maybe. Maybe not.
No...
Oh, come on, Doctor, catch up.
You can do it.
Ohh...
That's...that's my name,
and that is why I chose it.
So satisfying.
Doctor, I did say
look for the spymaster.
Or should I say spy...
...Master?
Hi.
You can't be...
Oh, I can be. I very much am.
So what's going on, then?
He's not really 0?
I'm her best enemy.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
- Call me Master.
- GRAHAM: Call you what?
"Master"?
Me and her,
we go way, way, way back.
- I met O!
- I know.
- Years ago.
- I know!
(CACKLES)
But there was an O at MI6.
- C was talking about him.
- Yeah.
A man very close to my heart.
Well, in my pocket, actually.
Do you want to see him?
It's always good to keep
a backup of one's work.
Tissue compression
is a classic.
Ohh...
Ambushed him on his way to work
for his first day.
Shrunk him, took his identity
and set myself up in MI6.
Surprisingly good
staff canteen.
I have had a lot of fun.
I need to warn Barton!
He's not here!
Where's Barton?
What have you done to him?
Barton!
GRAHAM: Who's flying the plane?
Wrong question. Check the seat.
(BEEPING)
Cockpit bomb.
Short fuse.
I can relate to that!
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- Now, do you really think
that I would not make that
sonic-proof, Doctor?
Come on!
Deadlock sealed.
And I made sure -
no parachutes on board.
There must be a way!
(GASPS) OK. OK.
But where's Barton?
We saw him coming in.
Called away before takeoff.
By me!
Stick with me, Yaz,
cos I control...
...everything.
Even these guys.
(WHISTLES)
(FIZZING AND CRACKING)
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
Yes!
I can't do it!
Get away!
Yah!
(SCREAMS)
One last thing.
Something you should know
in the seconds
before you die...
Everything that you think
you know...
...is a lie.
Got you...finally.
(ALL SCREAM)
- (GASPS)
- (AUDIO SLOWS)
No...
No, no, no, no, no.
(BEEPS)
A little chaos
is a wonderful thing.
When I arrange for your death,
I expect you to stay dead.
Welcome
to the end of your lives.