EXTERMINATE!
SEEK, LOCATE, DESTROY!
What was that thing?
A Dalek.
A what?
What's a Dalek?
Never mind. It's a Dalek.
Well, that's not explaining.
That's just saying a word.
What's a Dalek?
It's an alien war machine.
The deadliest alien war machine ever devised.
Fat, though.
Sorry.
We'll never get through that door. It's too wide.
It's a tank.
A tank driven by a super evolved mutant
programmed to wipe out all other life forms.
So please, keep your voice down.
It's got a sucker on it.
It's also got a gun.
Well, it's got a gun and a sucker.
Why?
They run out of guns.
Now, please.
Is there a Dalek at the back with no gun and two suckers
and he's really hacked off?
I don't know.
I've never asked
because I've always been too busy running away.
No, please.
One more question.
Oh, you do surprise me.
Why do they keep saying exterminate?
Because they want to kill us.
Wouldn't it be quicker to just say kill?
Do we really want them to save time?
Good point.
Oh, no.
We need to get back.
Back where?
To the future.
2017 needs us.
EXTERMINATE!
NEW ANOTHER LIFE DETECTED.