DOCTOR: Hello, Ponds.
Checking in. How are you?
Really?
Not much to report.
Surfed the Fire Falls of Florinel 9.
Not deliberately,
Just the easiest way out.
Met Mata Hari in a Paris hotel room.
What an interesting woman!
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Laid down some backing vocals.
I should be with you any day now,
literally any day.
Helmic regulator's playing up.
Can't get the temporal steering right.
Oh, dear! I appear to have collided
with ancient Greece.
(DOCTOR YELLING)
-(BEEPING)
-AMY: The Doctor.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-(EXCLAIMS) Stop everything!
-What's going on?
-Doctor, bedroom!
-We have a rule about the bedroom.
No one on this planet is safe right now.
We have to solve this
before it's too late.
Get your clothes on!
If we move fast enough,
we at least stand a chance.
And you have no idea
what I'm talking about, do you?
-BOTH: No.
-Oh, helmic regulator again!
Too early! Wrong point! As you were!
Doctor, you can't just go like that.
What's happening? Don't we need to know?
Popped up in the wrong order.
Easy mistake to make.
Nothing to alarm you,
forget I was ever here.
I'll be back soon enough,
I would've thought.
Everything's fine, pretty much.
Don't worry about the future.
The future's really...
safe.
Really, really safe.
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(WHISPERS) Sleep well.
-(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-I really hate it when he does that.
Whoa!
Out of the way, Mr Pond.
What? Why not?
May I be of any assistance?
-Ood on the loo.
-Yeah.
Ood! Yes!
I was wondering where he'd got to.
I thought he'd just gone
for a walk in the Tardis.
Must've wandered off
when I popped in the other night...
If it was the other night.
You know, I rescued him from the middle
of the Androvax Conflict.
I was taking him back
to the Ood Sphere.
Anyway, he's not being a nuisance,
is he?
-Enjoy your workday experience.
-Thanks.
Doctor. Doctor!
He, um...
He seems to think that he's our butler.
He's conditioned to serve.
You know the best thing is
let him do just that,
I'll come and pick him up tonight.
Whenever "tonight” is.
(ALARM BLARING)
Oh, no! Gotta go!
Power drain's threatening
to cause the Tardis to implode.
Oh no, that's bad. Why is it doing that?
No, no, no! Don't do that!
Your infusions.
How else may I be of service?
- I feel so guilty.
-You just eat your breakfast.
BOTH: Mmm!
Ponds. Me again.
Sorry about the gaps in communications.
Dropped your Ood back home.
Reconnected it to the hive mind.
Helmic regulator's still not working.
Got hit by an arrow at Hastings Hill.
Also, rode a horse through
11th-century Coventry.
Also, I think I may have
accidentally invented pasta.
Ah! Mmm...
I popped 'round but you were out,
which is fine.
Everything's all right, isn't it?
With you two?
Of course it is.
Ponds, always fine.
Just worrying unnecessarily.
Anyway, just call me
if you need me. Okay?
Toodle pip!
(BUZZING)
(BLEEPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Message deleted.
We need you, Raggedy Man.
I need you.