-(CREAKING)
-(WHIMPERING)
Run.
I'm the Doctor, by the way.
What's your name?
-Rose.
-Nice to meet you, Rose. Run for your life!
It's gonna follow us!
The assembled hoards of Genghis Khan
couldn't get through that door,
and believe me, they've tried.
-Are you alien?
-Yes.
(GRUNTING)
You could come with me.
-Is it always this dangerous?
-Yeah.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Right, Rose Tyler,
you tell me, where do you wanna go?
Backwards or forwards in time?
It's your choice. What's it gonna be?
Forwards.
(TARDIS POWERING UP)
-How far?
-One hundred years.
(RUMBLING)
There you go! Step outside those
doors, it's the 22nd century.
-You're kidding.
-That's a bit boring, though.
Do you wanna go further?
Fine by me.
(RUMBLING)
Ten thousand years
in the future.
Step outside,
it's the year 12005. The new Roman Empire.
You think
you're so impressive.
-I am so impressive.
-You wish!
Right, then. You asked for it.
I know exactly where to go.
Hold on!
(RUMBLING)
(DINGS)
Where are we?
(METALLIC CREAKING)
What's out there?
(MACHINE HUMMING)
(KEYS BLEEPING)
You lot...
You spend all your time thinking about dying.
How you're gonna get killed by eggs or beef
or global warming or asteroids.
But you never take time
to imagine the impossible.
That maybe you survived.
This is the year 5.5/Apple/26.
Five billion years
in your future.
And this is the day...
Hold on...
This is the day
the sun expands.
Welcome to
the end of the world.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Shuttles
five and six now docking.
Guests are reminded
that Platform One
forbids the use of weapons,
teleportation and religion.
Earth-death
ls scheduled for 715:39,
followed by drinks
in the Manchester Suite.
ROSE: So when it says
"guests”, does that mean people?
Depends what you mean
by people.
-I mean people. What do you mean?
-Aliens.
What are they doing
on board this spaceship? What's it all for?
It's not really a spaceship,
more like an observation deck.
The great and the good
are gathering to watch the planet burn.
-What for?
-Fun!
Mind you, when I say "the great and the
good”, what I mean is the rich.
But... Hold on, they did this
once on Newsround Extra, the sun expanding,
-that takes hundreds of years.
-Millions.
But the planet's now
the property of the National Trust.
They've been
keeping it preserved.
See down there?
Gravity satellites holding back the sun.
The planet looks
the same as ever.
I thought the continent
shifted and things.
They did, and the Trust
shifted 'em back! That's a classic Earth.
But now
the money's run out, nature takes over.
How long's it got?
About half an hour.
Then the planet gets roasted.
Is that why we're here?
I mean, is that what you do?
Jump in at the last minute
and save the Earth?
I'm not saving it. Time's up.
-But what about the people?
-It's empty. They've all gone. All left.
-Just me, then.
-Who the hell are you?
-Oh, that's nice. Thanks.
-But how did you get in?
This is a maximum
hospitality zone.
The guests have disembarked!
They're on their way any second...
No! That's me. I'm a guest.
Look, I've got an invitation.
Look, there you see?
It's fine. You see?
"The Doctor, plus one.”
I'm the Doctor,
this is Rose Tyler, she's my "plus one".
Is that all right?
Well, obviously.
Apologies, et cetera.
If you're on board,
we'd better start.
Enjoy.
The paper's slightly psychic.
It shows them whatever I want them to see.
Saves a lot of time.
-He's blue.
-Yeah.
Okay.
We have in attendance,
the Doctor and Rose Tyler!
Thank you.
All staff to their positions.
Hurry now! Thank you!
Quick as we can, come along, come along!
And now, might I introduce
the next honoured guest
representing
the Forest of Cheem, we have trees.
Namely Jabe, Lute and Coffa.
There will be an exchange
of gifts, representing peace.
If you could keep the room
circulating, thank you.
Next, from the solicitors Jolco and Jolco, we
have the Moxx of Balhoon.
And next,
from Financial Family Seven,
we have the Adherents
of the Repeated Meme.
The inventors of hyposlip travel systems, the
brothers Hop Pyleen! Thank you.
Cal "Sparkplug"...
Mr and Mrs Pakoo.
The ambassadors from
the City State of Binding Light...
The gift of peace. I bring you
a cutting of my grandfather.
Thank you.
Yes, gifts, um... (CLEARS THROAT)
I give you in return
air from my lungs.
How intimate.
There's more
where that came from.
I bet there is.
The sponsor
of the main event, please welcome...
the Face of Boe.
The Moxx of Balhoon.
My felicitations upon this
historical happenstance.
I bring you the gift
of bodily salivas.
(HAWKS AND SPITS)
Thank you very much.
Ah! The Adherents
of the Repeated Meme!
I bring you air from my lungs.
(EXHALES)
A gift of peace.
In all good faith.
STEWARD:
And last but not least, our very special guest.
Ladies and gentlemen and trees and
multiforms, consider the Earth, below.
In memory of this dying world,
we call forth...
the last human.
The Lady Cassandra O'Brien
Dot Delta Seventeen.
Oh, now don't stare!
I know, I know. It's shocking, isn't it?
I've had my chin completely taken
away and look at the difference!
Look how thin I am.
Thin and dainty!
I don't look a day over 2,000.
Moisturise me, moisturise me!
Truly, I am the last human.
My father was a Texan,
my mother was from the Arctic desert.
They were born on the Earth
and they were the last
to be buried in its soil.
(SNIFFLING) I have come
to honour them and say goodbye.
Oh, no tears, no tears...
I'm sorry.
But behold!
I bring gifts!
From Earth itself,
the last remaining ostrich egg.
Legend says, it had
a wingspan of 50 feet!
And blew fire
from its nostrils.
Or was that my third husband?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, no, oh, don't laugh, I'll get laughter-lines.
No, stop!
(CLEARING THROAT) Mercy!
And here! Another rarity.
According to the archives,
this was called an iPod.
It stores classical music from
humanity's greatest composers.
Play on!
(TAINTED LOVE PLAYING)
The refreshments
will now be served.
Earth-death in 30 minutes.
# Sometimes I feel
I've got to run away
# I've got to get away
from the pain
# That you drive
into the heart of me
# The love we share
seems to go nowhere
# And I've lost my light
# For I toss and turn
I can't sleep at night... #
-Doctor.
-(DEVICE CHIRPS)
Thank you.
A gift of peace
in all good faith.
No, you're very kind,
but I'm just the steward.
A gift of peace
in all good faith.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
Of course.
Identify species.
(DEVICE CHIRPING)
Please identify species.
-(WHISTLING)
-Now stop it!
Identify his race.
Where's he from?
(DEVICE TWITTERING)
It's impossible.
ROSE: Sorry, am I allowed
to be in here?
You have to give us
permission to talk.
Um...
-You have permission.
-Thank you.
And, no,
you're not in the way.
-Guests are allowed anywhere.
-Okay.
(KEYS BLEEPING)
-What's your name?
-Raffalo.
-Raffalo?
-Yes, miss.
I won't be long, I've just got
to carry out some maintenance.
There's a tiny little glitch
in the Face of Boe's suite.
There must be something
blocking the system.
He's not getting
any hot water.
-So, you're a plumber?
-That's right, miss.
They still have plumbers?
I hope so,
else I'm out of a job!
-Where are you from?
-Crespallion.
ROSE: That's a planet, is it?
No, Crespallion's part of
the Jaggit Brocade,
affiliated to the
Scarlet Junction, Convex 56.
And where are you from, miss?
If you don't mind me asking.
No, not at all. Um...
I don't know. A long way away.
I just sort of hitched a lift
with this man...
I didn't even think about it.
Don't even know who he is.
He's a complete stranger.
Anyway,
don't let me keep you. Good luck with it!
Thank you, miss.
And thank you for the permission.
Not many people are
that considerate.
Okay. See you later.
Now, then.
Control, I'm at junction 19.
I think the problem's coming from in here.
I'll go inside
and have a look.
(LIGHT CLANKING)
What's that?
Something in there?
Ooh. Who are you, then?
Hold on!
If you're an upgrade,
I just need to register you, that's all.
Oh, come back.
Ah, there you are.
Now, I just need
to register your ident.
Aw, there's two of ya!
Got yourself a little mate?
I think I'd better
report this to control.
How many of you are there?
What are you?
Oh, no! No! (SCREAMING)
(BLEEPING)
-What's that?
-(BLEEPS)
-Well, how should I know?
(OVER PA) Would the owner
of the blue box in private gallery 15
please report to
the steward's office immediately.
Guests are reminded
that the use of teleportation devices
is strictly prohibited under
Peace Treaty 5.4/Cup/16. Thank you.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Earth-death in 25 minutes.
Oh, thanks.
Hello!
My name's Rose.
That's a sort of plant.
We might be related.
I'm talking to a twig.
(GRUNTING)
Oi, now, careful with that,
park it properly. No scratches.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
DOCTOR:
Rose, are you in there?
Aye-aye!
-What do you think, then?
-Great, yeah. Fine.
Once you get past
the slightly psychic paper.
(CHUCKLES)
They're just so alien!
The aliens are so alien.
You look at 'em,
and they're alien.
Good thing I didn't take you
to the deep south.
-Where are you from?
-All over the place.
-They all speak English.
-No, you just hear English.
It's a gift of the Tardis.
It's the telepathic field,
gets inside your brain,
translates.
-It's inside my brain?
-Well, in a good way.
Your machine gets
inside my head?
It gets inside and it changes my
mind and you didn't even ask.
I didn't think
about it like that.
No, you were too busy thinking up cheap
shots about the deep south!
Who are you then, Doctor.
What're you called?
What sort of alien are you?
-I'm just a Doctor.
-From what planet?
(SNIGGERS)
Well, it's not as if you'd know where it is.
-Where're you from?
-What does it matter?
-Tell me who you are!
-This is who I am.
Right here, right now.
All right?
All that counts
is here and now, and this is me!
Yeah, and I'm here too
"cause you brought me here! So just tell me!
Earth-death in 20 minutes.
All right.
As my mate Shireen says,
"Don't argue with
the designated driver."
Can't exactly call for a taxi.
(BEEPING)
There's no signal.
We're out of range.
Just a bit.
Tell you what,
with a little bit of jiggery-pokery...
Is that a technical term,
"jiggery-pokery"?
Yeah, I came first
in jiggery-pokery. What about you?
-No, I failed hullabaloo.
-Aw.
There you go.
(BEEPS)
(RINGING TONE)
-Hello?
-Mum?
Oh, what is it?
What's wrong? What have I done now?
Ooh, this red top's falling
to bits! You should get your money back.
Go on,
there must be something.
You never phone
in the middle of the day.
-(CHUCKLES)
-What's so funny?
Nothing.
You all right, though?
Yeah, why wouldn't I be?
-What day is it?
-Wednesday all day. You got a hangover?
Oh, I tell you what,
put a quid in that lottery syndicate.
I'll pay you back later.
Yeah, um, I was just calling
'cause I might be late home.
Is there something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Top of the world!
If you think that's amazing,
you wanna see the bill.
That was five billion
years ago.
So...
She's dead now.
Five billion years later,
my mum's dead.
Bundle of laughs, you are.
(RUMBLING)
That's not supposed to happen.
Well, what was it?
I'm just getting green lights at this end.
(OVER PA) Honoured guests
may be reassured
that gravity pockets
may cause slight turbulence. Thanking you.
The whole place shook!
I felt it!
I've hosted all sorts of events on platforms
one, three, six and fifteen
and I've never felt
the slightest tremor!
I warn you, if this lot
decide to sue...
I'm gonna scan
the infrastructure.
(MACHINE BLEEPING)
What's that?
Control, I don't want to worry
you, but I'm picking up readings...
(BLEEPING)
I have no idea! They're small.
The scan says they're metal...
-(BLEEPS)
-I don't know what they look like!
Although I imagine they might
look rather like that.
You're not on the guest list.
How did you get on board?
(BEEPS)
-No! No!
-AUTOMATED VOICE: Sunfilter deactivated.
Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter up! No, no, no!
External temperature
430 degrees.
-Control! Respond!
-Sunfilter descending.
-Sunfilter up!
(SCREAMING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
That wasn't a gravity pocket. I know gravity
pockets, and they don't feel like that.
What do you think, Jabe?
Listen to the engines,
they're pitched up about 30 Hertz.
Is that dodgy or what?
It's the sound of metal,
that doesn't make any sense to me.
-Where's the engine room?
-I don't know.
But the maintenance duct is just behind our
guests' suite, I could show you.
And your wife.
Oh, she's not my wife.
-Partner?
-No.
-Concubine?
-Nope.
Prostitute?
Whatever I am,
it must be invisible! Do you mind?
Tell you what,
you two go and pollinate.
I'm gonna catch up
with the Family.
Quick word
with Michael Jackson.
Don't start a fight.
I'm all yours.
And I want you home
by midnight!
AUTOMATED VOICE: Earth-death in 15
minutes. Earth-death in 15 minutes.
Who's in charge
of Platform One? Has it got a captain or what?
There's just the steward
and the staff.
All the rest is controlled
by the metal mind.
You mean, the computer?
Well, who controls that?
The Corporation.
They move Platform One
from one artistic event to another.
Well, there's no one
from the Corporation on board.
They're not needed.
This facility is purely automatic.
It's the height of
the Alpha Class.
-Nothing can go wrong.
-Unsinkable?
If you like. The nautical
metaphor is appropriate.
You're telling me!
I was on board another ship once.
They said that was unsinkable.
I ended up
clinging to an iceberg. It wasn't half cold.
So, what you're saying is, if we get in
trouble, there's no one to help us out?
-I'm afraid not.
-Fantastic!
I don't understand.
In what way is that fantastic?
CASSANDRA: Soon the sun
will blossom into a red giant,
and my home will die.
That's where I used to live,
when I was a little boy. Down there.
Mummy and Daddy had a house built into the
side of the Los Angeles Crevasse.
(SIGHS) I'd have such fun.
What happened
to everyone else?
The human race,
where did it go?
They say mankind has touched
every star in the sky.
So you're not the last human.
I am the last pure human.
The others mingled.
Oh, they call themselves
New-humans and Proto-humans
and Digi-humans,
even Human-ish!
But do you know
what I call them?
Mongrels.
Right. And you stayed behind.
-I kept myself pure.
-Hmm.
How many operations
have you had?
708. Next week, it's 709.
I'm having my blood bleached.
Is that why you wanted a word?
You could be flatter, Rose.
You've got a little bit
of a chin poking out.
-I'd rather die.
-Honestly, it doesn't hurt.
I mean it. I would rather die.
It's better to die
than to live like you, a bitchy trampoline.
Oh, well, what do you know?
I was born on that planet!
And so was my mum
and so was my dad.
And that makes me, officially,
the last human being in this room.
'Cause you're not human.
You've had it all nipped and tucked and
flattened till there's nothing left.
Anything human
got chucked in the bin!
You're just skin, Cassandra!
Lipstick and skin.
Nice talking.
So, tell me, Jabe, what's a tree like
you doing in a place like this?
-Respect for the Earth.
-Come on!
Everyone on this platform is worth zillions!
Well, perhaps it's a case of
having to be seen at the right occasions.
In case
your share prices drop?
I know you lot. You've got massive forests
everywhere, roots everywhere!
And there's
always money in land.
All the same.
We respect
the Earth as family.
So many species
evolved from that planet. Mankind is only one.
I am another.
My ancestors were transplanted
from the planet down below.
And I'm a direct descendant
of the tropical rain forest.
Excuse me.
And what about your ancestry,
Doctor?
Perhaps you could tell
a story or two.
Perhaps a man only enjoys trouble
when there's nothing else left?
I scanned you earlier.
The metal machine had trouble
identifying your species.
It refused to admit
your existence.
And even when it named you,
I wouldn't believe it.
But it was right.
I know where you're from!
Forgive me for intruding,
but it's remarkable that you even exist!
I just want to say...
how sorry I am.
(SLOW CHUFFING)
Is it me,
or is it a bit nippy?
(GROANS)
Fair dos, though,
that's a great bit of air-conditioning.
Sort of nice
and old fashioned.
Bet they call it retro.
(WHINING)
Gotcha!
-What the hell is that?
-Is it part of the "retro"?
I don't think so, hold on.
-Hey, nice Liana!
-Thank you.
Not supposed to
show them in public.
Don't worry,
I won't tell anybody.
Now, then, who's been
bringing their pets on board?
-What does it do?
-Sabotage...
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Earth-death in 10 minutes...
And the temperature's
about to rocket. Come on.
The planet's end!
Come gather, come gather!
Bid farewell to the cradle
of civilisation.
Let us mourn her
with a traditional ballad.
(TOXIC PLAYING)
# Baby, can't you see?
I'm calling
# A guy like you
should wear a warning
# It's dangerous
I'm fallin'... #
All right, hold on, get back!
(ALARM WAILING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Sunfilter rising. Sunfilter rising.
-Is the steward in there?
-You can smell him.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Hold on. There's another
sun filter programed to descend.
# Too high can't come down
# Losing my head
Spinning round and round
# Do you feel me now? #
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Sunfilter descending. Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter descending.
-Let me out! Let me out!
-Sunfilter descending.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
ROSE: Let me out!
Let me out! Let me out!
Sunfilter descending.
-(BANGING CONTINUES)
-Anyone in there?
-Let me out!
-Oh, well, it would be you.
-Open the door!
-Hold on, give us two ticks.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Sunfilter descending. Sunfilter descending.
(BEEPING)
Sunfilter rising.
Sunfilter rising...
Sunfilter descending.
It's just what I need.
The computer's getting clever.
-Stop mucking about!
-I'm not mucking about! It's fighting back.
-Sunfilter descending.
-Open the door!
DOCTOR: I know!
-Sunfilter descending.
-ROSE: The lock's melted!
Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter rising.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
The opening's jammed!
I can't open the door. Stay there, don't move!
Where am I gonna go? Ipswich?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Earth-death in five minutes.
The metal machine confirms...
the spider devices
have infiltrated the whole of Platform One.
(GUESTS GASP)
How's that possible? Our private rooms
are protected by a code-wall.
Moisturise me, moisturise me.
Summon the steward!
I'm afraid
the steward is dead.
(ALL GASPING)
(ALL MURMURING)
Who killed him?
This whole event was sponsored
by the Face of Boe! He invited us.
Talk to the face!
Easy way of finding out.
Someone brought their little pet on board.
Let's send him back to master.
(BEEPING)
The Adherents of
the Repeated Meme! f'accuse!
That's all very well
and really kinda obvious.
But if you stop
and think about it...
(GROANS)
A Repeated Meme
is just an idea.
And that's all they are,
an idea.
(POWERS DOWN)
Remote-control droids.
Nice little cover for the real troublemaker.
Go on, Jimbo. Go home.
(GUESTS GASP)
I bet you were the school swot
and never got kissed.
At arms!
What you gonna do,
moisturise me?
With acid.
Oh, you're too late anyway.
My spiders have control
of the main frame.
Oh, you all carried them
as gifts, tax-free, past every code-wall.
I'm not just a pretty face.
Sabotaging a ship
while you're still inside it, how stupid is that?
I'd hoped to manufacture
a hostage situation.
With myself
as one of the victims.
The compensation
would've been enormous.
Five billion years,
and it still comes down to money.
Do you think it's cheap,
looking like this?
Flatness costs a fortune!
I am the last human, Doctor.
Me, not that
freaky little kid of yours.
Arrest her! The infidel!
Oh, shut it, pixie!
I've still got my final option.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Earth-death in three minutes.
And here it comes.
You're just as useful dead, all of you.
I have shares in
your rival companies.
And they'll triple in price
as soon as your dead.
My spiders are primed
and ready to destroy the safety systems.
How did that
old Earth song go?
"Burn baby, burn."
Then you'll burn with us!
Oh, I'm so sorry!
I know the use
of teleportation is strictly forbidden, but...
I'm such a naughty thing.
Spiders, activate!
(THUNDEROUS WHOOSHES)
Force-fields gone,
with the planet about to explode...
At least it'll be quick.
Just like my fifth husband...
(LAUGHS)
Oh, shame on me!
Bye-bye, darlings.
-AUTOMATED VOICE: Safety systems failing.
-Bye-bye, my darlings!
Heat levels rising.
-Reset the computer!
-Only the steward would know how.
No, we can do it by hand.
There must be
a system restore switch. Jabe, come on!
You lot, just chill.
...Heat levels rising.
(ALARM BLARING)
Earth-death in two minutes.
Heat levels critical
Oh, and guess
where the switch is.
Heat levels rising.
(GRUNTS)
External temperature
5,000 degrees.
You can't, the heat's gonna
vent through this place.
-I know.
-Jabe, you're made of wood.
Then stop wasting time,
Time Lord.
Heat levels rising.
-(PANICKED GASPS)
-(WINDOW CRACKING)
Heat levels hazardous.
-We're going to die!
-Heat levels hazardous.
Shields malfunction.
-(GASPS)
-Shields malfunction.
Heat levels critical
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERS)
Heat levels rising.
(JABE SCREAMING)
Planet explodes in...
ten,
nine,
eight,
seven,
Six,
five,
four...
Raise shields!
...one.
(LOUD EXPLOSION)
Exoglass repair.
(PANTING)
(SIZZLING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(SOBBING)
-ROSE: You all right?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm full of ideas.
I'm bristling with 'em!
Idea number one,
teleportation through 5,000 degrees
needs some kind of feed.
Idea number two.
This feed must be hidden nearby.
Idea number three.
If you're as clever as me,
then a teleportation-feed can be reversed.
(WHINING)
Oh, you should've seen
their little alien faces...
-Oh.
-The last human.
So, you passed
my little test. Bravo!
This makes you eligible
to join the...the Human Club.
People have died Cassandra,
you murdered them.
It depends on your definition
of people!
And that's enough of a technicality to keep
your lawyers dizzy for centuries!
Take me to court then, Doctor,
and watch me smile and cry...
(CREAKING)
-...and flutter.
-And creak?
-And what?
-Creak! You're creaking.
What?
(GRUNTING) I'm drying out!
Oh, sweet heavens!
Moisturise me, moisturise me!
Where are my surgeons?
My lovely boys!
-It's too hot! (GROANING)
-You raised the temperature.
Have pity!
Moisturise me!
(GROANING) Oh, Doctor!
Help her.
Everything has its time
and everything dies.
(SCREAMING)
I'm too young!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Shuttles four and six departing.
This unit now closing
down for maintenance.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
The end of the Earth.
It's gone.
We were too busy
saving ourselves. No one saw it go.
All those years,
all that history, and no one was even looking!
It's just...
Come with me.
(CHILD CRYING)
(LAUGHING)
Big Issue!
You think it'll last forever,
people and cars and concrete.
But it won't.
One day, it's all gone.
Even the sky.
My planet's gone.
It's dead.
It burned, like the Earth.
It's just rocks and dust.
Before its time.
What happened?
There was a war, and we lost.
ROSE: A war with who?
(CLEARS THROAT)
What about your people?
I'm a Time Lord.
I'm the last of
the Time Lords.
They're all gone.
I'm the only survivor.
I'm left traveling on my own
'cause there's no-one else.
There's me.
You've seen
how dangerous it is. Do you wanna go home?
I don't know.
I want...
(SNIFFING)
Oh. Can you smell chips?
-(LAUGHING) Yeah! Yeah.
-I want chips.
Me too!
All right then, before you can get me in that
box, chips it is and you can pay.
-No money.
-What sort of date are you?
Come on then, tightwad.
Chips are on me.
We've only got
five billion years till the shops close.
(CHUCKLES)
Now, you've seen
the future, so let's have a look at the past.
1860. How does 1860 sound?
-What happened in 18607
-I don't know! Let's find out.
REDPATH:
I can't believe she's gone.
Not gone, Mr Redpath, sir.
Merely sleeping.
She's up and on her feet
and out there somewhere!
Mr Sneed, for shame,
how many more times? It's ungodly!
(SHRIEKING)
Excuse me, sir.
Mr Dickens, this is your call.
Use the sight.
Find the old lady or you're dismissed.
What phantasmagoria is this?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
That's more like it!