VENDOR: Fish! Get your fresh fish!
Ancient Rome!
Well, not to them, obviously.
To all intents and purposes, right now,
this is brand-new Rome.
Oh, my God! It's...
It's so Roman!
This is fantastic.
Ha, ha!
I'm here!
In Rome. Donna Noble, in Rome!
This is just weird!
I mean, everyone here's dead.
Well, don't go telling them that.
Hold on a minute.
That sign over there is in English.
Are you having me on? Are we in Epcot?
No, no, no,
that's the Tardis translation circuits.
Just makes it look like English.
Speech as well.
-We're talking Latin right now.
-Seriously?
-I just said "seriously” in Latin!
-Well, yeah.
What if I said something
in actual Latin?
Like veni, vidi, vici. My dad said that
when he came back from football.
If I said, "Veni, vidi, vici, "
to that lot, what would it sound like?
I'm not sure. You have to think of
difficult questions, don't you?
I'm going to try it!
Hello, sweetheart.
What can I get you, my love?
Um...
Veni vidi vici.
Huh? Sorry?
(IN LOUD, SLOW VOICE)
Me no speak Celtic. No can do, missy.
Yeah.
-How's he mean, Celtic?
-Welsh. You sound Welsh.
Well, there we are. Learnt something.
-Don't our clothes look a bit odd?
-Nah! Ancient Rome, anything goes.
It's like Soho, but bigger.
-Have you been here before, then?
-Mmm, ages ago.
Before you ask,
that fire had nothing to do with me.
Well, a little bit. But I never got
the chance to look around properly.
Colosseum, Pantheon, Circus Maximus...
You'd expect them to be looming by now.
Where is everything?
Try this way.
I'm not an expert,
but there are seven hills of Rome,
aren't there?
How come they've only got one?
(RUMBLING)
MAN: Here we go again!
Wait a minute.
One mountain, with smoke,
which makes this...
Pompeii.
We're in Pompeii.
And it's volcano day!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
I beg audience with
the High Priestess of the Sibylline.
The High Priestess cannot be seen.
What would you tell her, sister?
It has come,
as foretold in the prophecy.
The box. The blue box.
You're kidding.
You're not telling me
the Tardis has gone.
-Okay.
-Where is it, then?
You told me not to tell you.
Oi! Don't get clever in Latin.
Um...
Excuse me, excuse me!
There was a box, a big, blue box.
A big, blue, wooden box just over there.
-Where has it gone?
-Sold it, didn't I?
But it wasn't yours to sell!
It was on my patch, wasn't it?
I got 15 ses 30 for it. Lovely jubbly!
-Who'd you sell it to?
-Old Caecilius.
Look, if you want to argue,
why don't you take it up with him?
He's on Foss Street.
Big fellow, can't miss him.
Thanks!
What did he buy
a big, blue, wooden box for?
Modern art!
Out of the way! That's it!
Oh, Rhombus, I'm a little bit peckish.
Get me some ants in honey,
there's a good lad.
Ooh! Maybe a dormouse?
What do you think?
You call it modern art, I call it
a blooming great waste of space.
But we're going up in the world,
my love.
Lucius Dextrus himself
is coming to the house this afternoon.
What with that and our Evelina
about to be elevated...
Oh, don't go on about it, Dad.
If we'd moved to Rome, like I said,
she could have been a vestal virgin.
Someone mention vestal virgins?
Quintus, don't be so rude!
You apologise to the household gods!
-Get off.
-Apologise right now.
The gods are always watching.
Positions!
There. Now you've
made the heavens angry.
Just say sorry.
I tell you, Caecilius,
that boy will come to no good.
Sorry, household gods.
So where were you last night?
Down the thermapolium, I bet.
Cavorting with Etruscans
and Christians and all sorts.
How's your head, sunshine?
-How's your head!
-All right, Dad, give us a break.
You want to
smarten yourself up, Quintus,
before Lucius Dextrus gets here.
Look at your sister.
She's giving us status.
Oh, yeah, 'cause it's all about Evelina.
She has the gift.
Be proud of your sister for once.
-Have you been consuming?
-Not this morning.
Well, come on, sweetheart, practise!
It's hot today,
the hypocaust is on full blast.
The mountain god must be happy.
Breathe deeply.
Remember what the sisterhood said.
-It hurts.
-Oh, my love, is it too hot?
Sometimes, in the smoke,
I see the most terrible things.
Like what?
A face.
A face of stone.
It'll make sense. One day.
Sister Spurrina promised.
The veil will be parted,
and you'll be a seer.
(GROWLING)
Who are you?
-Ha! I've got it! Foss Street, this way!
-No!
I found this big
sort of amphitheatre thing.
We can start there,
we could gather everyone together.
They maybe have a great, big bell
or something we could ring.
-Have they invented bells yet?
-What do you want a bell for?
To warn everyone, start the evacuation!
What time does Vesuvius erupt?
When's it due?
It's 79 AD, 23rd of August,
which makes volcano day tomorrow.
Plenty of time.
We'll get everyone out easy!
Yeah, except we're not going to.
But that's what you do.
You're the Doctor, you save people.
Not this time.
Pompeii is a fixed point in history.
What happens, happens.
There is no stopping it.
-Says who?
-Says me.
-What, and you're in charge?
-Well, this Time Lord, yeah.
Donna, human, no. I don't need
your permission, I'll tell them myself.
If you stand in the marketplace
announcing the end of the world,
they'll think
you're a mad old soothsayer.
Now, come on! Tardis.
We are getting out of here!
Well, I might just have something
to say about that, spaceman!
Oh, I bet you will!
The tall one, he calls us mad.
Then he is a stranger to Pompe:ii.
Soon he will learn.
We have found I, Sister Spurring,
in the thirteenth book
of the Sibylline Oracles.
The blue box.
A temple made of wood,
and yet the sibyl foretold
that the box would appear
at the time of storms
and fire and betrayal.
HIGH PRIESTESS: Sisters!
Revered Mother, you should sleep.
The Sibylline Oracles are wrong!
But we have venerated her words
for generations.
This is a new age.
Heed my words.
I predict a future
of prosperity and might,
an endless empire of Pompeii,
reaching out from this city
to topple Rome itself
and encompass the whole wide world.
If the disciples of the blue box
defy this prophecy,
their blood will run
across the temple floor.
(ALL GASP)
The gods approve!
Positions!
Whoa!
There you go.
Thank you, kind sir.
I'm afraid business
is closed for the day.
-I'm expecting a visitor.
-Well, that's me, I'm a visitor.
Hello!
-Who are you?
-I am
Spartacus.
-And so am L.
-Mr and Mrs Spartacus?
-Oh, no, no, no. We're not married.
-Not together.
Oh, brother and sister? Yes, of course!
-You look very much alike.
-(BOTH) Really?
I'm sorry, but I'm not open for trading.
-And that trade would be...?
-Marble.
Lobus Caecilius, mining,
polishing and design thereof.
-If you want marble, I'm your man.
-That's good.
That's good,
"cause I'm the marble inspector.
By the gods of commerce, an inspection!
I'm sorry, sir,
I do apologise for my son.
-QUINTUS: Oi!
-This is my good wife Metella.
I must confess,
we're not prepared for...
Nothing to worry about,
I'm sure you've got nothing to hide.
Although, frankly, that object
looks rather like wood to me.
I told you to get rid of it!
I only bought it today!
Ah, well. Caveat emptor.
Oh, you're Celtic. There's lovely!
I'm sure it's fine, but I might have to
take it off your hands
for a proper inspection.
While we're here, wouldn't you
recommend a holiday, Spartacus?
Don't know what you mean, Spartacus.
This lovely family,
mother and father and son,
don't you think they should
get out of town?
-Why should we do that?
-The volcano for starters.
-What?
-The volcano.
-The what-ano?
-The big volcano right on your doorstep.
Oh, Spartacus, for shame!
We haven't even greeted
the household gods yet.
They don't know what it is.
Vesuvius is just a mountain to them.
The top hasn't blown off yet.
The Romans haven't even got a word
for "volcano”. Not until tomorrow.
Oh, great. They can learn a new word.
As they die.
Donna, stop it.
I don't know what sort of kids you been
flying around with in outer space,
but you're not telling me to shut up.
That boy, how old is he, 167
-And tomorrow he burns to death.
-And that's my fault?
Right now, yes.
Announcing Lucius Petrus Dextrus,
chief augur of the city government.
Lucius! My pleasure, as always.
Quintus, stand up.
A rare and great honour, sir,
for you to come to my house.
The birds are flying north
and the wind is in the west.
Right, absolutely. That's good, is it?
Only the grain of wheat knows
where it will grow.
There now, Metella,
have you ever heard such wisdom?
Never. It's an honour.
Pardon me, sir, I have guests.
This is Spartacus and, uh, Spartacus.
A name is but a cloud
upon a summer wind.
But the wind is felt
most keenly in the dark.
Dark!
But what is the dark
other than an omen of the sun?
-I concede that every sun must set.
-Ha!
And yet the son of the father
must also rise.
Damn. Very clever, sir.
Evidently a man of learning.
Oh, yes, but don't mind me.
Don't want to disturb the status quo.
-He's Celtic.
-We'll be off in a minute.
-I'm not going.
-It's ready, sir.
-You've got to.
-Well, I'm not.
The moment of revelation.
And here it is,
exactly as you've specified.
-It pleases you, sir?
-As the rain pleases the soil.
Oh, now, that's different.
Who designed that, then?
My lord Lucius was very specific.
-Where'd you get the pattern?
-On the rain and mist and wind.
-But that looks like a circuit.
-Made of stone.
Do you mean you just
dreamt that thing up?
That is my job as city augur.
What's that, then, like the mayor?
Oh, you must excuse my friend,
she's from Barcelona.
This is an age of superstition,
of official superstition.
The augur is paid by the city
to tell the future.
"The wind will blow from the west."”
That's the equivalent of
the ten o'clock news.
They're laughing at us.
Those two, they use words
like tricksters. They're mocking us.
No, no, no, I meant no offence.
I'm sorry, my daughter's been
consuming the vapours.
By the gods, Mother,
what have you been doing to her?
-Not now, Quintus.
-But she's sick. Just look at her!
I gather I have a rival
in this household.
Another with the gift.
Oh, she has been promised
to the Sibylline Sisterhood.
They say she has remarkable visions.
The prophesies of women
are limited and dull.
Only the menfolk have the capacity
for true perception.
I'll tell you where the wind's
blowing right now, mate.
(RUMBLING)
The mountain god marks your words.
I'd be careful if I were you.
Consuming the vapours, you say?
-They give me strength.
-It doesn't look like it to me.
Is that your opinion as a doctor?
- I beg your pardon?
-Doctor, that's your name.
-How did you know that?
-And you.
You call yourself "noble”.
Now then, Evelina, don't be rude.
-DOCTOR: No, no, not at all.
-You both come from so far away.
A female soothsayer is inclined
to invent all sorts of vagaries.
Oh, not this time, Lucius.
I reckon you've been out-soothsayed.
Is that so?
Man from Gallifrey.
What?
(FIERCE RUMBLING)
The strangest of images.
Your home is lost in fire, is it not?
-Doctor, what are they doing?
-And you, daughter of
-London.
-How does he know that?
This is the gift of Pompeii.
-Every single oracle tells the truth.
-That's impossible.
Doctor, she is returning.
Who is? Who's "she"?
And you, daughter of London,
there is something on your back.
-What's that mean?
-Even the word "Doctor" is false.
Your real name is hidden.
It burns in the stars,
in the cascade of Medusa herself.
You are a lord, sir.
A lord of time.
Evelina!
She didn't mean to be rude.
She's ever such a good girl.
But when the gods speak through her...
-What's wrong with her arm?
-An irritation of the skin.
She never complains, bless her.
-We bathe it in olive oil every night.
-What is it?
Evelina said you'd come from far away.
Please, have you ever seen
anything like it?
It's stone.
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
Different sort of hypocaust.
Oh, yes, we're very advanced in Pompeii.
In Rome, they're still using
the old wood-burning furnaces,
but we've got hot springs
heated from Vesuvius itself.
-Who thought of that?
-The soothsayers.
After the great earthquake 17 years ago.
An awful lot of damage. But we rebuilt.
Didn't you think of moving away?
Oh, no, then again, San Francisco.
That's a restaurant in Naples, isn't it?
What's that noise?
Don't know, happens all the time.
They say the gods
of the underworld are stirring.
But after the earthquake, let me guess,
is that when the soothsayers
started making sense?
Oh, yes, very much so.
I mean, they had always been,
shall we say, imprecise.
But then, the soothsayers, the augurs,
the haruspices, all of them,
they saw the truth again and again.
It's quite amazing.
They can predict crops and rainfall
with absolute precision.
-Have they said anything about tomorrow?
-No.
-Why, should they? Why do you ask?
-No, no, no reason, just asking.
But the soothsayers,
they all consume the vapours?
That's how they see.
Ipso facto...
Look, you...
-They're all consuming this.
-Dust?
Tiny particles of rock.
They're breathing in Vesuvius.
Quintus, me old son,
this Lucius Petrus Dextrus.
-Where does he live?
-It's nothing to do with me.
Let me try again.
This Lucius Petrus Dextrus...
Where does he live?
Don't tell my dad.
Only if you don't tell mine.
Pass me that torch.
The liar!
He told my father it was the only one.
Well, plenty of marble merchants
in this town.
Tell them all the same thing, get all
the components from different places
so no one can see what you're building.
-Which is what?
-The future, Doctor!
We are building the future
as dictated by the gods.
You're not supposed to laugh.
Thanks for that.
What do you think?
-The goddess Venus.
-(CHUCKLING) That's sacrilege!
Nice to see you laugh, though.
What do you do in old Pompeii, then,
girls your age?
You got mates?
Do you go hanging about round the shops?
TK Maximus?
I am promised to the sisterhood
for the rest of my life.
-Do you get any choice in that?
-It's not my decision.
The sisters chose for me.
I have the gift of sight.
Then what can you see
happening tomorrow?
Is tomorrow special?
You tell me.
What do you see?
The sun will rise, the sun will set.
Nothing special at all.
Look, don't tell the Doctor
I said anything 'cause he'll kill me,
but I've got a prophecy, too.
DONNA: Evelina, I'm sorry,
but you've got to hear me out.
-Sisters!
-DONNA: Evelina, can you hear me?
Listen!
EVELINA: There is only one prophecy!
Everything I'm about
to say to you is true, I swear.
Just listen to me.
(ECHOING) Tomorrow
that mountain is going to explode.
Evelina, please listen.
The air is going to fill with
ash and rocks, tons and tons of it
and this whole town
ls going to get buried.
-EVELINA: That's not true.
-I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
But everyone's going to die.
-A new prophecy!
-Impossible. There is only one.
Even if you don't believe me, just
tell your family to get out of town.
Just for one day, just for tomorrow,
but you've got to get out.
-You've got to leave Pompeii.
-This is false prophecy!
The Noble woman,
she spoke of a new prophecy,
the fall of Pompeii.
HIGH PRIESTESS:
Pompeii will last forever.
-Then what must we do?
-The false prophet must die.
Sacrifice her!
Put this one there,
this one
there...Er, keep that one upside down.
-What have you got?
-Enlighten me.
What, the soothsayer doesn't know?
The seed may float on the breeze
in any direction.
Yeah, I knew you were going to say that.
But it's an energy converter.
-An energy converter of what?
-I don't know.
Isn't that brilliant?
I love not knowing, keeps me on my toes.
It must be awful being a prophet.
Waking up every morning,
"Is it raining? Yes, it is. I said so."
Takes all the fun out of life.
But who designed this, Lucius?
Hmm? Who gave you these instructions?
I think you've babbled enough!
Lucius, really, tell me. Honestly,
I'm on your side, I can help.
You insult the gods!
There can be only one sentence. At arms!
(SPEAKING LATIN)
Celtic prayers won't help you now.
But it was him, sir, he made me do it.
Mr Dextrus, please don't.
Come on now, Quintus, dignity in death.
I respect your victory, Lucius.
Shake on it?
Come on.
Dying man's wish.
-But he's...
-Show me.
The work of the gods.
-He's stone!
-Armless enough, though!
DOCTOR: Quintus!
The carvings!
Run!
My carvings!
The work is unbroken.
Oh, lord of the mountain, I beseech you.
This man
would prevent the rise of Pompeii!
(GROWLING)
Lord, I beg of you, show yourself.
Show yourself!
(GROWLING)
No sign of them.
I think we're all right.
But his arm, Doctor...
Is that what's happening to Evelina?
(POUNDING)
What was that?
The mountain?
No, it's closer.
(POUNDING INTENSIFIES)
They're footsteps.
It can't be.
-Footsteps on the ground.
-What is it?
What is it?
What is it? What's that noise?
That doesn't sound like Vesuvius.
Caecilius? All of you, get out!
-Doctor, what is it?
-Think we're being followed.
(GROWLING)
Just get out!
The gods are with us.
Water, we need water!
Quintus, all of you, get water! Donna!
Blessed are we to see the gods!
(CAECILIUS YELLING)
Talk to me, that's all I want.
Talk to me, just tell me who you are.
Don't hurt these people!
Talk to me.
I'm the Doctor.
Just tell me who you are.
-What was it?
-A carapace of stone.
Held together by internal magma.
Not too difficult to stop, but I reckon
that's just the foot soldier.
Doctor, or whatever your name is,
you bring bad luck in this house.
I thought your son was brilliant.
Aren't you gonna thank him?
I don't know...
If there are aliens at work in Pompeii,
it's a good thing we stayed.
Donna!
Donna?
You have got to be kidding me.
The false prophet will surrender
both her blood
-and her breath.
-I'll surrender you in a minute.
-Don't you dare.
-You will be silent.
Listen, sister, you might have eyes
on the back of your hands,
but you'll have eyes in the back of
your head by the time I finish with you.
Let me go!
This prattling voice will cease forever!
DOCTOR: That'll be the day.
No man is allowed to enter
the Temple of Sybil.
Well, that's all right. Just us girls.
Do you know, I met the Sybil once?
Hell of a woman. Blimey!
She can dance the tarantella.
Nice teeth. Truth be told,
I think she had a bit of a thing for me.
I said it'd never last.
She said, "I know." Well, she would.
-You all right there?
-Never better.
-I like the toga.
-Thank you.
-And the ropes?
-Yeah, not so much.
What magic is this?
Let me tell you about the Sybil,
the founder of this religion.
She would be ashamed of you.
All her wisdom and insight turned sour.
Is that how you spread the word, eh?
On the blade of a knife?
Yes, a knife that now welcomes you.
HIGH PRIESTESS: Show me this man.
High Priestess,
the stranger will defile us.
Let me see. This one is different.
He carries starlight in his wake.
Oh, very perceptive.
Where do these words
of wisdom come from?
HIGH PRIESTESS: The gods whisper to me.
They've done far more than that.
Might I beg audience?
Look upon the High Priestess.
Oh, my God! What's happened to you?
The heavens have blessed me.
If I might...
-Does it hurt?
-It is necessary.
-Who told you that?
-The voices.
Is that what's gonna happen to Evelina?
Is this what's gonna happen
to all of you?
The blessings are manifold.
They're stone.
Exactly.
The people of Pompeii are turning
to stone before the volcano erupts.
-But why?
-This word, this image in your mind,
this volcano, what is that?
More to the point,
why don't you know about it?
-Who are you?
-High Priestess of the Sibylline.
No, no, no, I'm talking to
the creature inside you.
The thing that's seeding itself into
a human body, in the dust in the lungs.
Taking over the flesh
and turning it into what?
Your knowledge is impossible.
Oh, but you can read my mind.
You know it's not.
I demand you tell me who you are!
DEEP VOICE: We are awakening.
The voice of the gods!
ALL CHANTING:
Words of wisdom. Words of power.
Words of wisdom...
Name yourself. Planet of origin,
galactic coordinates,
species designation,
according to the universal ratification
of the Shadow Proclamation.
We are rising!
Tell me your name!
Pyrovile!
Pyrovile, Pyrovile, Pyrovile...
-What's a Pyrovile?
-That's a Pyrovile. Growing inside her.
-She's at halfway stage.
-What, and that turns into?
That thing in the villa,
that was an adult Pyrovile.
And the birth of a Pyrovile
will incinerate you, Doctor.
I warn you. I'm armed.
Donna, get that grille open.
-What the...
-Just...
-What are the Pyrovile doing here?
-We fell from the heavens.
We fell so far and so fast,
we were rendered into dust.
Right. Creatures of stone
shatter on impact.
When was that, 17 years ago?
We have slept beneath
for thousands of years.
Okay, so 17 years ago woke you up.
And now you're using human bodies
to reconstitute yourself.
But why the psychic powers?
We opened their minds
and found such gifts.
Fine, so you force yourself
inside a human brain,
use their latent psychic talent,
I get that, yeah.
But seeing the future,
that is way beyond psychic.
You can see through time.
Where does the gift
of prophecy come from?
DONNA: I've got it.
DOCTOR: Now, get down.
-What? Down there?
-Yes, down there.
Why can't this lot predict the volcano?
Why is it being hidden?
Sisters, I see into his mind.
The weapon is harmless.
Yeah, but it's gotta sting.
You fought her off with a water pistol.
I bloody love you!
This way!
-Where we going now?
-Into the volcano.
-No way.
-Yes way.
Have it your way.
The stranger would threaten
our great endeavour.
The time has come.
The prophecy must advance!
The prophecy must advance.
Thy will be done.
-Summon the Cult of Vulcan.
-Yes, sir.
We must go to the mountain.
Vesuvius awaits.
Sunrise, my love.
A new day.
Even the longest night must end.
But the mountain's worse than ever.
We killed a messenger of the gods
in our own house.
Sweetheart, can you see?
Tell us, what's going to happen?
Just leave her alone.
-I can see.
-What is it?
A choice.
Someone must make a choice.
The most terrible choice.
But if it's aliens
setting off the volcano,
doesn't that make it all right
for you to stop it?
DOCTOR: It's still part of history.
DONNA: But I'm history to you.
You saved me in 2008, you saved us all.
Why is that different?
Some things are fixed,
some things are in flux.
Pompeii is fixed.
-How do you know which is which?
-Because that's how I see the universe.
Every waking second I can see what is,
what was, what could be, what must not.
It's the burden of a Time Lord, Donna.
And I'm the only one left.
-How many people died?
-Stop it!
Doctor! How many people died?
Twenty thousand.
Is that what you can see, Doctor?
All 20,0007
And you think that's all right, do you?
(PYROVILE WAILING)
They know we're here. Come on!
O mighty Vesuvius,
accept these offerings
in Vulcan's design
and show unto us, I beseech you,
the gods of the underworld!
(ROARING)
It's the heart of Vesuvius.
We're right inside the mountain.
There's tons of 'em.
What's that thing?
Well, you better hurry up and think of
something. Rocky IV's on its way.
DOCTOR: That's how they arrive.
Or what's left of it. Escape pod.
Prison ship. Gene bank.
But why do they need a volcano?
Maybe it erupts and they launch
themselves back into space or something.
No, I think it's worse than that.
How can it be worse?
(ROARING)
Doctor, it's getting closer.
Heathens!
Defile us!
They would desecrate your temple,
my lord gods!
Come on.
-We can't go in!
-Well, we can't go back.
Crush them! Burn them!
(PYROVILE ROARING)
There's nowhere to run,
Doctor and daughter of London!
Now then, Lucius, my Lord Pyrovillian.
Don't get yourselves in a lava.
-In a lava? No?
-No.
But if I might beg the wisdom
of the gods before we perish.
Once this new race of creatures
is complete, then what?
My masters will follow the example
of Rome itself,
an almighty empire,
bestriding the whole of civilisation!
But if you've crashed,
and you've got all this technology,
why don't you just go home?
The heaven of Pyrovillia is gone.
What do you mean, gone? Where's it gone?
It was taken! Pyrovillia is lost.
But there is heat enough in this world
for a new species to rise!
Yeah, I should warn you.
It's 70 percent water out there.
Water can boil
and everything will burn, Doctor!
Then the whole planet is at stake.
Thank you, that's all I needed to know.
DOCTOR: Donna!
You have them, my lords.
Could we be any more trapped?
A little bit hot.
See, the energy converter
takes the lava.
Uses the power to create a fusion matrix
which welds Pyrovile to human.
Now it's complete,
they can convert millions.
Can't you change it with these controls?
Of course I can. But don't you see?
That's why the soothsayers
can't see the volcano.
There is no volcano.
Vesuvius is never gonna erupt.
The Pyrovile are stealing all its power.
They're gonna use it
to take over the world.
But you can change it back.
Well, I can invert the system so that
the volcano will blow them up, yes,
but that's the choice, Donna.
It's Pompeii or the world.
Oh, my God.
If Pompeii is destroyed,
then it's not just history. It's me.
I make it happen.
But the Pyrovile are made of rocks.
Maybe they can't be blown up.
Vesuvius exploded
with the force of 24 nuclear bombs.
Nothing can survive it.
Certainly not us.
Never mind us.
Push this lever and it's over.
Twenty thousand people...
No!
(SCREAMING)
A new prophecy!
The future is changing.
(DONNA SCREAMING)
The sky is falling!
Death. Only death!
It was an escape pod.
Out! Out! Everybody out! Quickly!
(MAN SHOUTING)
You lied to us!
And yet this was meant to be.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BABY CRYING)
No, don't go to the beach!
Don't go to the beach! Go to the hills!
Listen to me!
Don't go to the beach! It's not safe!
(CHILD CRYING)
-Come here.
-MOTHER: Give him to me!
Come on.
You can't save us, Doctor.
No!
Doctor, you can't!
Doctor!
You can't just leave them!
Don't you think I've done enough?
History is back in place
and everyone dies.
You've got to go back! Doctor, I'm
telling you, take this thing back!
It's not fair.
No, it's not.
But your own planet. It burned.
That's just it. Don't you see, Donna?
Can't you understand?
If I could go back and save them,
then I would. But I can't.
I can never go back. I can't.
I just can't. I can't.
Just someone. Please.
Not the whole town. Just save someone.
(WHOOSHING)
Come with me.
It's never forgotten, Caecilius.
Oh, time will pass, man will move on
and stories will fade, but one day,
Pompeii will be found again.
In thousands of years.
And everyone will remember you.
What about you, Evelina?
Can you see anything?
The visions have gone.
The explosion was so powerful,
it cracked open a rift in time.
Just for a second. That's what gave you
the gift of prophecy.
It echoed back
into the Pyrovillian alternative.
But not any more.
You're free.
But tell me, who are you, Doctor?
With your words and your temple
containing such size within.
Oh, I was never here.
Don't tell anyone.
The great god Vulcan must be enraged.
It's so volcanic.
It's like some sort of...volcano.
All of those people.
Thank you.
Yeah.
You were right.
Sometimes I need someone.
Welcome aboard.
Yeah.
Metella, my love,
have you seen that clasp?
The beetle one.
The Egyptians do love a scarab.
Here we are. I was giving it a polish.
Now calm down.
If I get that contract
for the marble granaries of Alexandria,
we'll be rich. You'll see.
Hold on there, Evelina.
You are not going out wearing that!
Don't start, Dad. It's what
all the girls in Rome are wearing.
I'll see you later.
Are you seeing that boy again?
Oh, look at Quintus. My son, the doctor.
Mum, I've told you.
I'm not a doctor. Not yet.
I'm just a student
of the physical sciences.
Well, that's a doctor to me.
Give thanks to the household gods
before you go. There's a good boy.
Come here, let me fix it.
You've got that folded all wrong.
Thank you, household gods.
Thank you for everything.
Now then, Dr Noble, Mrs Noble,
if you'd like to come with me?
-Oh, no, no. We're not married.
-We're so not married.
-Never.
-Never, ever.
Here at Ood Operations we like to think
of the Ood as our trusted friends.
I've found your unwanted guests.
Because at heart, what is an Ood...
I'm on your side!
...but a reflection of us?
It's a revolution.
If your Ood is happy...
The circle must be broken.
What is it? What is the circle?
...then you'll be happy, too.
MAN: Shoot to kill!
-Doctor, Donna. Friends!
-The circle must be broken!