(INDISTINCT TALKING)
I don't think I asked you to sit.
There is a woman who wants to meet you.
That's nice, but I'm married.
Your help is required.
I don't discuss my business in public.
I know.
(WHOOSHING)
-Who are you?
-A messenger.
Whose messenger?
Darla Von Karlsen.
Never heard of her.
-Where's the tea room?
-We were never in the tea room.
Oh, of course.
Psychic projection.
Someone sending me a dream message.
Well, I hope I fell asleep
somewhere comfy.
Do you recognise where you are?
(DISTANT CHILDREN'S LAUGHTER)
Can't remember.
How do you hang up on this thing?
-You can't.
-Oh, yeah?
And what if I just wake up?
No, Doctor, the beach isn't real either.
You are still dreaming.
Space-time coordinates.
You will meet Darla Von Karlsen here.
Her daughter is in danger.
But only you can save her.
You recognise the planet?
Yes.
-Say it, name the planet.
-No. I will not say that.
-Say it!
-No!
Name the planet.
(VOICES OVERLAPPING)
-Name the planet.
-Skaro.