(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Who the hell are you?
I'm you, from your future.
Tell me exactly what's happened.
Well, the exterior shell of the Tardis
has drifted forwards in time.
If you step into the box now,
you step inside the control room
a tiny bit into the past.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
You just said it.
No, I'm just repeating it.
I'm just remembering
what I heard myself saying
when I was standing where you are now.
And repeating it. I'm just
repeating this, too. And this. And this.
Oh, I still don't understand.
-You still don't.
-Okay, when does this Amy
step inside the box?
We need to maintain the timeline.
Ah! As soon as she's slapped Rory.
-Okay.
-Ha! No. Why do I get slapped?
Because we have to stick to the
established chain of events.
One mistake and the whole timeline
could collapse.
We'll end up with two Amy Ponds
forever, and then what would you do?
-Oh!
-Okay, you,
into the police box now.
-What, and then I become her?
-Yes, go, go, go!
Do I really look like that?
Yeah. Yeah, you do.
Oh! I'd give you a driving license.
-Mmm, I bet you would.
-Oh, this is how it all ends.
Pond flirting with herself,
true love at last.
-Oh, sorry, Rory.
-Absolutely no problem at all.
-Now, Amy!
-What's the first line?
"Okay, kids,
this is where it gets complicated.”
Gotcha!
-So, is that it? Are we okay now?
-No, we're still trapped.
-What are you doing?
-You told us to get into the police box.
Well, from your point of view,
you're about to tell us
to get into the police box.
From our point of view, you just told us
to get into the police box, which is
why we got into the police box,
which is why we're here.
Do I have to remember all of that?
-It sort of happens.
-Hi.
-Hey, stop that.
You two, into the police box now, run.
-So, what now?
-You two, stay where you are.
What are you doing?
I'm setting up a
controlled temporal implosion.
It's the only way to reset the Tardis,
but unless I find exactly the right
lever to control the implosion,
we're all going to die.
You don't know which lever?
Well, no, but I'm about to find out.
-(GASPS)
-The wibbly lever.
The wibbly lever, thank you!
(WHOOSHING)
Okay, we're back in normal flight.
The Tardis is no longer inside itself,
the localised time field
is no longer about to implode
and rip a hole in all causality,
but just in case,
Pond, put some trousers on.