Come now, Father, you should know better.
You're not welcome here,
and especially not today.
I've got no time to start old arguments.
-We want only one thing.
-And what would that be?
-This house.
-You want the house?
We will take the house.
Would you like my wife while you're at it?
If you won't stand aside,
then we'll take it by force.
And by what power? The hand of God?
No, the fist of man.
(MAN GRUNTING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
In the name of Heaven.
My Lady?
What's in there? What is it?
What's under the canvas?
Father, answer me. What's in there?
May God forgive me.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
-What do you think of this? Will it do?
-The late 1970s?
You'd be better off in a bin bag.
Hold on, listen to this.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Ian Dury and The Blockheads.
Number one in 1979.
You're a punk!
# It's good to be a lunatic #
That's what you are, a big old punk
with a bit of rockabilly thrown in.
-Do you want to go and see him?
-How do you mean, in concert?
What else is the Tardis for?
I can take you to the Battle of Trafalgar,
the First Antigravity Olympics,
Caesar crossing the Rubicon
or Ian Dury at the Top Rank, Sheffield,
England, Earth, 21st November 1979,
what do you think?
-Sheffield it is!
-Hold on tight.
(HIT ME WITH YOUR RHYTHM STICK BY
IAN DURY AND THE BLOCKHEADS PLAYING)
Landing!
1979! Hell of a year!
China invades Vietnam.
The Muppet Movie, love that film.
Margaret Thatcher. Skylab falls to Earth
with a little help from me.
Nearly took off my thumb,
and I like my thumb.
I need my thumb.
I'm very attached to...my thumb.
1879. Same difference.
You will explain your presence,
and the nakedness of this girl.
-Are we in Scotland?
-How can you be ignorant of that?
(SCOTTISH ACCENT)
I'm dazed and confused.
I've been chasing this wee naked child
over hill and over dale.
Isn't that right, you timorous beastie?
(SCOTTISH ACCENT) Och, aye.
I've been "oot" and "a boot."
-No, don't do that.
-Hoots, mon?
No, really don't. Really.
Will you identify yourself, sir?
I'm Doctor James McCrimmon
from the township of Balamory.
I have my credentials, if I may?
As you can see, a doctorate
from the University of Edinburgh.
I trained under Doctor Bell himself.
WOMAN: Let them approach.
-I don't think that's wise, ma'am.
-Let them approach.
You will approach the carriage,
and show all due deference.
Rose, might I introduce
Her Majesty Queen Victoria,
Empress of India and Defender of the Faith.
Rose Tyler, ma'am.
And my apologies for being so naked.
I've had five daughters. It's nothing to me.
But you, Doctor, show me these credentials.
Why didn't you say so immediately?
It states clearly here
that you have been appointed
by the Lord Provost as my protector.
Does it? Yes, it does. Good. Good.
Erm, then let me ask,
why is Your Majesty travelling by road
when there's a train
all the way to Aberdeen?
-A tree on the line.
-An accident?
I am the Queen of the United Kingdom
of Great Britain and Ireland.
-Everything around me tends to be planned.
-An assassination attempt?
What, seriously?
There's people out to kill you?
I'm quite used to staring down
the barrel of a gun.
Sir Robert MaclLeish
lives but 10 miles hence.
We've sent word ahead.
He'll shelter us for tonight,
then we can reach Balmoral tomorrow.
This Doctor and his timorous beastie
will come with us.
Yes, ma'am.
We'd better get moving.
It's almost nightfall.
Indeed, and there are stories of wolves
in these parts.
Fanciful tales,
intended to scare the children,
but good for the blood, I think. Drive on.
ROSE: It's funny, though,
'cause you say assassination,
and you just think of Kennedy and stuff,
not her.
She's had, oh, six attempts on her life.
And I'll tell you something else.
-We just met Queen Victoria.
-I know!
-What a laugh!
-She was just sitting there!
-Like a stamp.
-I want her to say, "We are not amused.”
I bet you 5 quid I can make her say it.
Well, if I gambled on that,
it would be an abuse of my privilege
as a traveller in time.
-10 quid.
-Done.
I can't do this. It's treason.
Then your wife
will suffer the consequences.
Believe me, Sir Robert,
she will be devoured.
-Your Majesty.
-Sir Robert.
My apologies for the emergency.
And how is Lady Isobel?
She's indisposed, I'm afraid.
She's gone to Edinburgh for the season,
and she's taken the cook with her,
the kitchens are barely stocked.
I wouldn't blame Your Majesty
if you wanted to ride on.
Not at all.
I've had quite enough carriage exercise,
and this is charming, if rustic.
It's my first visit to this house.
My late husband spoke of it often,
the Torchwood Estate.
Now, shall we go inside?
And please excuse the naked girl.
-Sorry!
-She's a feral child.
I bought her for sixpence
in old London town.
It was her or the Elephant Man, so...
Thinks he's funny, but I'm so not amused.
What do you think, ma'am?
It hardly matters. Shall we proceed?
So close.
Mackeson and Ramsay,
you will escort the property. Hurry up.
-Yes, sir.
So what's in there, then?
Property of the Crown.
You will dismiss any further thoughts, sir.
The rest of you, go to the rear of the house.
Assume the designated positions.
-You heard the orders, positions.
-Sir.
SOLDIER: You two, come with me...
(SHUSHING)
Guard it with your life.
This, I take it, is the famous endeavour.
All my father's work.
Built by hand in his final years.
It became something of an obsession.
He spent his money on this,
rather than caring for the house or himself.
I wish I'd met him. I like him.
-That thing's beautiful, can I...
-Help yourself.
-What did he model it on?
-I know nothing about it.
To be honest,
most of us thought him a little,
shall we say, eccentric.
I wish now I'd spent more time with him
and listened to his stories.
It's a bit rubbish.
How many prisms has it got?
Way too many!
The magnification's gone right over the top.
That's a stupid kind of...
-Am I being rude again?
-Yep!
But it's pretty! It's very pretty.
And the imagination of it
should be applauded.
Hmm. I thought you might disapprove,
Your Majesty.
Stargazing. Isn't that a bit fanciful?
You could easily not be amused,
or something. No?
This device surveys
the infinite work of God.
What could be finer?
Sir Robert's father was an example
to us all,
a polymath,
steeped in astronomy and the sciences,
yet equally well-versed
in folklore and fairy tales.
Stars and magic. I like him more and more.
Oh, my late husband enjoyed his company.
Prince Albert himself was acquainted
with many rural superstitions,
coming as he did from Saxe-Coburg.
That's Bavaria.
When Albert was told about your local wolf,
he was transported.
So what's this wolf, then?
-It's just a story.
-Then tell it.
-It's said that...
-Excuse me, sir.
Perhaps Her Majesty's party
could repair to their rooms.
It's almost dark.
Of course. Yes, of course.
And then supper.
And could we find some clothes
for Miss Tyler?
-I'm tired of nakedness.
-It's not amusing, is it?
Sir Robert, your wife
must have left some clothes. See to it.
We shall dine at 7:00,
and talk some more of this wolf.
After all, there is a full moon tonight.
So there is, ma'am.
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS)
They came through the house in silence.
They took the steward and the master,
and my lady.
Listen, I've got a friend.
He's called the Doctor.
He'll know what to do.
-You've got to come with me.
-Oh, but I can't, Miss.
-What's your name?
-Flora.
Flora, we'll be safe.
There's more people arrived downstairs,
soldiers and everything.
They can help us. I promise.
Come on. Okay? Come on.
Oh, Miss, I did warn you.
He's not dead, I don't think.
He must be drugged or something.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Your companion begs an apology, Doctor.
Her clothing has somewhat delayed her.
Oh, that's all right.
Save her a wee bit of ham.
The feral child could probably eat it raw.
(LAUGHING)
-Very wise, ma'am. Very witty.
-Slightly witty, perhaps.
I know you rarely get the chance to dine
with me, Captain, but don't get too excited.
I shall contain my wit
in case I do you further injury.
Yes, ma'am. Sorry, ma'am.
Besides, we're all waiting on Sir Robert.
Come, sir.
-You promised us a tale of nightmares.
-VICTORIA: Indeed.
Since my husband's death,
I find myself with more of a taste
for supernatural fiction.
You must miss him.
Very much.
Oh, completely.
And that's the charm of a ghost story,
isn't it?
Not the scares and chills,
that's just for children,
but the hope of some contact
with the great beyond.
We all want some message from that place.
It's the Creator's greatest mystery
that we're allowed no such consolation.
The dead stay silent,
and we must wait.
Come, begin your tale, Sir Robert.
There's a chill in the air.
The wind is howling through the eaves.
Tell us of monsters.
Don't make a sound.
They said if we scream or shout,
then he will slaughter us.
But he's in a cage. He's a prisoner.
He's the same as us.
He's nothing like us.
That creature is not mortal.
The story goes back 300 years.
Every full moon,
the howling rings through the valley.
Next morning, livestock is found
ripped apart and devoured.
Oh, tales like this just disguise
the work of thieves.
Steal the sheep and blame a wolf,
simple as that.
ROBERT:
But sometimes a child goes missing.
Once in a generation,
a boy will vanish from his homestead.
ISOBEL: Don't, child.
-Who are you?
-Don't enrage him.
Where are you from? You're not from Earth.
What planet are you from?
Oh...intelligence.
-Where were you born?
-This body?
Ten miles away.
A weakling, heartsick boy,
stolen away at night by the Brethren
for my cultivation.
I carved out his soul and sat in his heart.
-Are there descriptions of the creature?
-Oh, yes, Doctor.
Drawings and wood carvings.
And it's not merely a wolf,
it's more than that.
This is a man who becomes an animal.
A werewolf?
ROSE: All right, so the body's human.
What about you, the thing inside?
So far from home.
If you want to get back home, we can help.
Why would I leave this place?
A world of industry,
of workforce and warfare.
-I could turn it to such purpose.
-How would you do that?
I would migrate to the Holy Monarch.
You mean Queen Victoria?
With one bite, I would pass into her blood.
And then it begins, the Empire of the Wolf.
So many questions.
Look! Inside your eyes. You've seen it, too.
Seen what?
The wolf.
There is something of the wolf about you.
I don't know what you mean.
Oh, you burn like the sun,
but all I require is the moon.
My father didn't treat it as a story.
He said it was fact.
He even claimed to have communed
with the beast, to have learned its purpose.
I should have listened.
His work was hindered. He made enemies.
There's a monastery
in the Glen of St Catherine.
The Brethren
opposed my father's investigations.
Perhaps they thought his work ungodly.
That's what I thought, but now I wonder.
(FATHER CHANTING IN LATIN)
What if they had a different reason
for wanting the story kept quiet?
What if they turned from God
and worshipped the wolf?
And what if they were with us right now?
Moonlight.
All of you, stop looking at him.
Flora, don't look, listen to me.
Grab hold of the chain and pull!
Come on, with me! Pull!
I said pull! Stop your whining
and listen to me! All of yous!
And that means you, your Ladyship.
Now, come on! Pull!
-What is the meaning of this?
-Explain yourself, sir.
I'm sorry, Your Majesty,
they've got my wife.
Rose, where's Rose? Where is she?
(FATHER CHANTING IN LATIN)
Sir Robert, come on!
...three, pull!
One, two, three, pull!
Tell me, sir.
I demand to know your intention.
(FATHER CHANTING IN LATIN)
What is it that you want?
The throne.
(GROANING)
ROSE: ...two, three, pull!
One, two, three,
pull!
Where the hell have you been?
-Oh, that's beautiful.
-Isobel!
Get out, all of you! Come on! Out! Out! Out!
I take it, sir, that you halted my train
to bring me here.
We've waited so long
for one of your journeys
to coincide with the moon.
Then you have waited in vain.
After six attempts on my life,
I am hardly unprepared.
Oh, I don't think so, woman.
The correct form of address
is "Your Majesty".
-Guns.
-I need five.
Lady Isobel, take the girls!
Get them out through the kitchen.
Jackson, at arms...
I can't leave you. What will you do?
I must defend Her Majesty.
Now, don't think of me, just go.
All of you at my side! Come on!
Could be any form of
light-modulating species
triggered by specific wavelengths.
Did it say what it wanted?
The Queen, the crown, the throne,
you name it.
(LOUD CRASHING)
(WEREWOLF GROWLING)
Fire! Fire!
-It won't open. They've sealed us in.
-Oh, my lady, look.
They'll never let us out.
-They mean for us to die.
-Don't say that, Flora!
All right, you men,
we should retreat upstairs. Come with me.
I'll not retreat. The battle's done.
There's no creature on God's earth
could survive such an assault.
I'm telling you, come upstairs!
And I'm telling you, sir,
I will sleep well tonight
with that thing's hide upon my wall.
It must have crawled away to die.
(MAN SCREAMING)
There's nothing we can do!
(GROWLING)
No!
(GUNS FIRING)
(MAN SHOUTING)
Did they kill it?
Come close.
(GROWLING)
(FOOTSTEPS RETREATING)
-Your Majesty, Your Majesty!
-Sir Robert, what's happening?
I heard such terrible noises.
Your Majesty, we've got to get out.
But what of Father Angelo, is he still here?
Captain Reynolds disposed of him.
The front door's no good.
It's been boarded shut.
Pardon me, Your Majesty,
you'll have to leg it out of a window.
Excuse my manners, ma'am,
but I shall go first,
the better to assist Her Majesty's egress.
A noble sentiment, my Sir Walter Raleigh.
Yeah, any chance you could hurry up?
I reckon the monky-boys
want us to stay inside.
-Do they know who I am?
-Yeah, that's why they want you.
The wolf's lined you up for a biting.
Now, stop this talk.
There can't be an actual wolf.
(HOWLING)
(BANGING AT DOOR)
-What do we do?
-We run.
-Is that it?
-You got any silver bullets?
-Not on me, no.
-There we are, then. We run.
Your Majesty, as a doctor,
I recommend a vigorous jog,
good for the health.
(WOLF SNARLING)
Come on. Come on.
(YELPING)
I'll take this position and hold it.
You keep moving, for God's sake.
Your Majesty, I went to look
for the property and it was taken.
-The chest was empty.
-I have it. It's safe.
Then remove yourself, ma'am.
Doctor, you stand
as Her Majesty's protector.
And you, Sir Robert.
You're a traitor to the Crown.
-Bullets can't stop it.
-They'll buy you time. Now, run!
(CAPTAIN REYNOLDS SCREAMING)
DOCTOR: Rose!
Barricade the door.
Wait a minute. Shh. Wait, wait, wait. Shh.
(HOWLING)
It stopped.
It's gone.
Listen.
(WOLF SNARLING)
(PAWS STOMPING)
-(WHISPERING) Is this the only door?
-Yes.
No!
(SNARLING)
ROSE: Shh!
(WOOD CREAKING)
(PANTING)
(SNARLING)
(STEPS RETREATING)
I don't understand. What's stopping it?
Something inside this room.
What is it? Why can't it get in?
-I tell you what, though.
-What?
-Werewolf.
-I know!
-You all right?
-I'm okay, yeah.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
It's all my fault.
I should have sent you away.
I tried to suggest something was wrong.
I thought you might notice.
Did you think there was nothing strange
about my household staff?
Well, they were bald, athletic.
Your wife's away,
I just thought you were happy.
I'll tell you what though, ma'am,
I bet you're not amused now.
-Do you think this funny?
-No, ma'am, I'm sorry.
What, exactly, I pray,
tell me, someone, please,
what exactly is that creature?
You'd call it a werewolf,
but technically it's more
of a lupine-wavelength haemovariform.
And should I trust you, sir?
You, who change your voice so easily?
What happened to your accent?
-Oh, right, sorry, that...
-I'll not have it.
No, sir. Not you, not that thing, none of it.
This is not my world.
Mistletoe.
They're all garlanded in mistletoe
and the wolf doesn't attack them.
-Who brought this into the kitchen?
-Must have been the Brethren.
Gather it up, quickly.
Every last scrap. Quick, now!
Mistletoe.
Sir Robert, did your father put that there?
I don't know. I suppose.
And on the other door, too.
Though a carving wouldn't be enough.
I wonder.
Viscum album, the oil of the mistletoe.
It's been worked into the wood
like a varnish.
How clever was your dad? I love him!
Powerful stuff, mistletoe,
bursting with lectins and viscotoxins.
-And the wolf's allergic to it?
-Or it thinks it is.
The monky-monk-monks need a way
of controlling the wolf,
maybe they trained it
to react against certain things.
Nevertheless,
that creature won't give up, Doctor,
and we still don't possess
an actual weapon.
Oh, your father got all the brains,
didn't he?
-Being rude again.
-Good, I meant that one.
You want weapons?
We're in a library. Books!
Best weapons in the world.
This room is the greatest arsenal
we could have.
Arm yourself.
There's no sound of the wolf, my lady,
perhaps it's gone.
And perhaps it's toying with us.
But my husband's up there,
and if there's any chance he's still alive,
then, by God, I'll assist him.
Look up biology and zoology.
-There might be something on wolves.
-DOCTOR: What about this?
-A whole book on mistletoe.
-ROBERT: "The application of gunpowder..."
-If we could build some form of explosive.
-Hmm, that's the sort of thing.
Ohhh.
Look what your old dad found.
Something fell to Earth.
-A spaceship?
-Shooting star.
"In the year of our Lord 1540,
under the reign of King James V,
"an almighty fire did burn in the pit.”
That's the Glen of Saint Catherine,
just by the monastery.
But that's over 300 years ago.
What's it been waiting for?
Maybe just a single cell survived.
Adapting slowly down the generations,
it survived through the humans,
host after host after host.
But why does it want the throne?
That's what it wants, it said so.
The Empire of the Wolf.
Imagine it. The Victorian Age accelerated.
Starships and missiles fuel led by coal
and driven by steam,
leaving history devastated in its wake.
-Sir Robert. If I am to die here...
-Don't say that, Your Majesty.
...] would destroy myself
rather than let that creature infect me,
but that's no matter.
I ask only that you find
some place of safekeeping
for something far older
and more precious than myself.
Hardly the time
to worry about your valuables.
Thank you for your opinion,
but there is nothing
more valuable than this.
ROBERT: Oh, Your Majesty.
-Is that the Koh-i-noor?
-Oh, yes.
The greatest diamond in the world.
Given to me as the spoils of war.
Perhaps its legend is now coming true.
It is said that whoever owns it
must surely die.
Well, that's true of anything,
if you wait long enough. Can I?
-That is so beautiful.
-How much is that worth?
They say, the wages of the entire planet
for a whole week.
Good job my mum's not here,
she'd be fighting the wolf off
with her bare hands for that thing.
-And she'd win.
-Where is the wolf?
-I don't trust this silence.
-Why do you travel with it?
My annual pilgrimage.
I'm taking it to Hellier and Carew,
the Royal Jewellers at Hazlehead.
The stone needs recutting.
-But it's perfect.
-My late husband never thought so.
Now, there's a fact.
Prince Albert kept on having
the Koh-i-noor cut down.
It used to be 40% bigger than this,
but he was never happy.
Kept on cutting and cutting.
He always said
the shine was not quite right,
but he died with it still unfinished.
Unfinished.
Oh, yes!
There's a lot of unfinished business
in this house.
His father's research
and your husband, ma'am.
He came here
and he sought the perfect diamond.
Hold on, oh, hold on.
All these separate things,
they're not separate at all,
they're connected.
Oh, my head, my head!
What if this house... It's a trap for you.
Is that right, ma"am?
-Obviously.
-At least, that's what the wolf intended,
but what if there's a trap inside the trap?
Explain yourself, Doctor.
What if his father and your husband
weren't just telling each other stories.
They dared to imagine all this was true,
and they planned against it.
Laying the real trap not for you,
but for the wolf.
That wolf, there.
DOCTOR: Out! Out! Out! Out!
DOCTOR: Your Majesty!
We've got to get to the observatory!
(ROSE SCREAMING)
(WOLF BURNING)
DOCTOR: Good shot!
FLORA: It was mistletoe.
Isobel.
-ROBERT: Now get back downstairs.
-Keep yourself safe.
My love. Now, go.
Girls, come with me.
Down the back stairs
back to the kitchens, quickly.
Come on.
The observatory is this way.
No mistletoe on these doors,
'cause your father wanted
the wolf to get inside.
I just need time.
Is there any way of barricading this?
Do your work, and I'll defend it.
If we could bind them shut
with rope or something...
I said I'll find you time, sir.
Now, get inside.
Good man.
Your Majesty, the diamond.
-For what purpose?
-The purpose it was designed for.
(WOLF GROWLING)
Rose.
Lift it, come on.
-Not the right time for stargazing.
-Yes, it is.
(DOCTOR GROANING)
(WOLF GROWLING)
I committed treason for you,
but now my wife
will remember me with honour.
(ROBERT SCREAMING)
(BANGING AT DOOR)
I am the Defender of the Faith,
and that Faith shall defend me.
You said this thing doesn't work.
It doesn't work as a telescope,
"cause that's not what it is.
It's a light chamber.
It magnifies the light, like a weapon.
-We've just got to power it up.
-With what? There's no electricity.
Moonlight. But the wolf needs moonlight.
It's made by moonlight.
You're 70% water, you can still drown.
Come on!
Make it brighter. Let me go.
(HOWLING)
Your Majesty?
Did it bite you?
No, it's... It's a cut, that's all.
If that thing bit you...
It was a splinter of wood
when the door came apart. It's nothing.
-Let me see.
-It is nothing.
By the power invested in me
by the Church and the State,
I dub thee Sir Doctor of Tardis.
By the power invested in me
by the Church and the State,
I dub thee Dame Rose of the Powell Estate.
You may stand.
Many thanks, ma'am.
Thanks. They're never gonna believe this
back home.
Your Majesty, you said last night
about receiving no message
from the great beyond.
I think your husband cut that diamond
to save your life.
He's protecting you even now, ma'am,
from beyond the grave.
Indeed.
Then you may think on this also,
that I am not amused.
Yes!
Not remotely amused.
And henceforth, I banish you.
I'm sorry?
I have rewarded you, Sir Doctor,
and now you are exiled from this Empire,
never to return.
I don't know what you are, the two of you,
or where you're from,
but I know that you consort
with stars and magic, and think it fun.
But your world is steeped in terror
and blasphemy and death,
and I will not allow it.
You will leave these shores,
and you will reflect, I hope,
on how you came to stray so far
from all that is good,
and how much longer
you may survive this terrible life.
Now leave my world,
and never return.
-Whoa!
-Cheers!
-Walk on.
-No, but the funny thing is,
Queen Victoria actually did suffer
a mutation of the blood.
It's historical record.
She was haemophiliac.
They used to call it the Royal Disease,
but it's always been a mystery
because she didn't inherit it.
Her mum didn't have it.
Her dad didn't have it.
-It came from nowhere.
-What, and you're saying that's a wolf bite?
Well, maybe haemophilia is
just a Victorian euphemism.
-For werewolf?
-Could be.
-Queen Victoria's a werewolf?
And her children had the Royal Disease.
Maybe she gave them a quick nip.
-So the Royal Family are werewolves?
-Well, maybe not yet.
I mean, a single wolf cell could take
100 years to mature.
Might be ready by, oh, early 21st century.
No, that's just ridiculous.
-Mind you, Princess Anne.
-I'll say no more.
And if you think about it,
they're very private.
They plan everything in advance.
They could schedule themselves
around the moon. We'd never know.
And they like hunting.
They love blood sports.
(DOCTOR LAUGHING)
Oh, my God! They're werewolves!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BOTH HOWLING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
What will you do? Will you stay here?
I don't think I could.
I'd sell it, or pull this place down.
Although we may not speak of these events
in public, they will not be forgotten.
I promise you that.
Your husband's sacrifice,
the ingenuity of his father,
they will live on.
But how?
I saw, last night,
that Great Britain has enemies
beyond imagination,
and we must defend our borders
on all sides.
I propose an institute
to investigate these strange happenings
and to fight them.
I would call it Torchwood.
The Torchwood Institute.
And if this Doctor should return,
then he should beware,
because Torchwood will be waiting.
Good morning, class.
Are we sitting comfortably?
Three months ago, turns out
all the kitchen staff were replaced.
See? There's definitely something going on.
I was right to call you home.
May I introduce Miss Sarah Jane Smith.
-Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you!
Yes. Very nice.
You are not permitted to leave your station
during a sitting.
Boy in class this morning,
got knowledge way beyond planet Earth.
KO!
Our time has come, my brothers.
Today we shall become gods.