Karvanista took
whoever lived here.
Why would he do that?
- Every Lupar has a designated human.
- I'm not your human!
We have to save them
before it's too late.
What is it you're saving them from?
- The Flux.
- What's the Flux?
This is Serving Commander
Inston-Vee Vinder, leaving his post.
- They are without purpose.
- Your mind will boggle.
- Hello again, Doctor.
- Who are you?
Our final fight has begun.
The end of the universe.
I always wondered
what it would feel like!
End of the universe.
But we're still here.
- Wherever here is.
- Doctor!
Yaz! Is Dan with you?
I'm here. I just blacked out.
Last thing I remember,
we were on your TARDIS,
that Flux thing was coming at us
and then, nothing.
Me too. I think.
I was on the ground over there.
We must have been thrown out.
Must have been.
Where are we?
- Is she always like this?
- Pretty much.
If I had to call it,
we're back on Earth.
Which meant, the Lupari Shield worked,
but the TARDIS took a hit.
Looks like we're in the middle
of a battle field, which could mean...
Hey! Get away from him.
Show me your hands.
What did you take? Show me!
We didn't take anything.
I know what goes on out here.
Vultures!
Emptying the pockets of the dead.
But who are you? Where are you from?
I'm the Doctor.
This is Yaz, this is Dan.
Nice to meet you.
We were checking for signs of life.
Sure, Doctor is a man's term.
It's fluid.
Sentry Patrol, all of them dead.
It's too late for medical aid.
But you are too close to the front
to be with Mrs Nightingale.
She won't come this close to Sebastopol.
How long have you been here?
Sebastopol, 1850s. Oriented!
I know where we are.
Crimean War, 1855,
Ottoman Empire weakening,
British soldiers fighting Russians.
- What?
- We're in the middle of the Crimean War.
That would make you Mary Seacole.
Are you? You are, aren't you?
Mrs Seacole to you.
Doctress to the fallen.
Everybody, shush.
Listen.
- It's enemy soldiers. Back up, back up.
- Oh!
Where in the battle are we?
How many Russian troops
are the British fighting?
What's happening in Sebastopol?
What's this word you keep using,
"Russians"?
They're not fighting Russians.
They're fighting Sontarans.
Taste the victory, my soldiers.
Breathe in the rotting stench
of our vanquished foes.
Onwards, to domination. Sontar-Ha!
Sontar-Ha!
Sontar-Ha! Sontar-Ha!
Oh!
Ah!
Are you response? Can you repair?
- Can I what?
- Can you repair!?
- Wait, where am I?
- Can you repair? Respond!
I... I need to make contact
with my home planet.
There's been a mass extinction event
near where I was stationed.
We are aware. The Flux impacted
the inner temple. Can you repair?
Repair what?
Follow. Follow.
This was not foreseen.
Priest Triangles are only guardians.
We maintain and serve.
The impact of the Flux event
was too great.
The temple is compromised.
The Mouri must never be compromised.
Do you see, do you see the Mouri?
Whoa!
Thank you for getting us
out of there safely, Mrs Seacole.
I know every safe avenue
on and off of this battlefield.
I have to stay alive if I'm going to
nurse these men back to health.
- You're an army nurse?
- Oh, no.
I work for myself.
I am the closest nurse to the front.
And this is your hospital?
This is much more
than a hospital, child.
This is my British hotel.
So, let me just get this straight.
She's, like, a real person
from history.
You just talked to her,
didn't ya?
And those Sontaran things,
they're not part of history?
- Really?
- No. She should be here, they shouldn't.
Could this be connected to the Flux?
Is history being rewritten?
Dan, are you okay?
Are you seeing that?
Stay still, Dan.
What's happening to me?
Huh! Dan!
Doctor! You're fading.
A collision between
Flux and vortex energy.
You're falling through space and time.
Yaz, stay calm. I will find you.
- Promise?
- I promise!
- Where's the door? I need the door.
- Over there, Commander!
A voice. Another soldier
waiting to be obliterated.
Let me in! I have to find them.
Spread out
and locate the human scum!
I'm home?
Jim! Jim, it's me, Dan!
Sorry about the house, I can explain.
Jim!
Come on, Dad. Pick up, will ya?
What?
No way.
- What the hell is that?
- Curfew defier,
breach of curfew
will result in instant execution.
Soldiers, apprehend!
Divide and cover all escape routes.
Mam? Dad?
Where the hell have you been?
Doctor?
Dan?
I need a universal GPS, then I'd know
where I was, whenever this happens.
'Cause it just keeps happening.
This is intolerable!
Hi, I'm Yaz.
How am I to cope?
- Cope with what, sir?
- Well, any of it.
All of it, just...
It insists on shifting.
Why don't you take me
through it from the start?
From the start.
You mock me, madam. The start.
All right.
Can you tell me what's the year?
Why? Do you believe it to be
a matter of import?
- It might be.
- It is the year of our Lord 1820.
Do you reckon it differently?
Very differently.
Oh!
All our fears made true.
All is porous, all is broken.
I must retrace.
There's so much work to be done.
- I'll come with you.
- No. No, it's to no avail,
if my experience holds true.
Ah, this confounded situation.
- Can you repair?
- Can I what?
All assistance is required.
Can you repair?
Yeah. I can.
That's exactly why I'm here.
Oh, Mrs Seacole, I helped myself
to the rum, er, to aid planning.
It can go on your slate, General.
Your rapidly rising slate.
Good evening.
- Where are your friends?
- They were called away,
while I'm remaining here for now,
apparently.
Well, then, you are most welcome
to the British Hotel.
New arrival, Mrs Seacole.
Oh, yes. We met on the battlefield.
This is Lieutenant-General Logan
of the Light Division.
I'm the Doctor.
Oh, Mrs Seacole could certainly
do with your assistance.
Our advance tomorrow
is not without risk.
Please tell me you're not about
to engage Sontarans in battle.
That is why we're here.
You don't understand.
I've fought Sontarans before.
Ha! Somehow I doubt that.
Sontarans live for war.
They're a clone race.
It's what they're bred for.
It's their entire history.
And they're very, very good at it.
They also have weapons
beyond your imagination.
So even if you do have
numerical advantage,
I advise, at all costs, do not engage.
Then it's fortunate that I command these
divisions of Her Majesty's Army
and you do not.
- Madam, I'm at work.
- I know. I can smell the rum.
How long have they been here,
the Sontarans?
What, outside Sebastopol?
- No, on Earth.
- They've always been here.
Trust me, I know your history,
and that's not true.
Where are we? Britain there,
Jamaica here, still intact.
Er, Columbia there and Russia is...
Not there. No Russia, no China,
only Sontar.
- And you both think that's normal.
- War is the opposite of normal.
Er, that word you used, er, "Russia".
Where have I heard that before?
She said it earlier. I thought the same.
I heard it before in the past.
Like a memory. An echo of another time.
Yes.
Time has been disrupted.
But if you're still retaining
those memories of the truth,
then the disruption must be recent.
But how? Fall-out from the Flux?
Yeah, but that wouldn't be enough.
Oh, I mean, Sontarans are embedded
in maps, all of a sudden.
Are you expecting a response
to your musings?
How far away is their encampment?
You've gone very quiet, General.
The soldiers appear
from directions unknown.
See?
They're doing the basics
and you're already on the back foot.
You will lose every man if you face them
in the battlefield tomorrow.
You need my help.
I have Queen and country on my side,
that is all the help I need.
She here with you now then, the Queen?
Obviously not!
Then her influence may be limited.
Mrs Seacole, your new assistant
is putting me off my task.
You want to be helpful, Doctor?
Nursing rounds.
You have to get the General
to listen to me.
You think the Army take advice
from a Doctress?
I am here to nurse the wounded.
Sifting the battlefields
for injured soldiers,
setting up a sanctuary?
You just decided to come out here,
on your own?
If we all of us waited to be sent for,
we'd none of us find our purpose,
would we?
I paid for my own passage and I had
this place built from what I could find.
A proper pioneer.
Rice pudding
and hard liquor build morale.
They also pay for medicine.
But my time and my skills,
those I give for free to all comers.
Speaking of which, come over here.
The General does not approve.
More of you!
More to destroy when I free myself!
Which will be soon.
This is a surprise.
No wonder the General doesn't approve.
All life is sacred to me.
I use my remedies
to help whoever is in need.
Just as you did the Russian soldiers.
Although this one has refused
all treatment and healed himself.
He takes his rest in a regular rhythm.
Seven and a half minutes every 27 hours.
I recorded it.
I shall massacre you for revealing
privileged military information.
- The rest of the time, he yells.
- No wonder you're angry.
Capture, the ultimate shame
for any Sontaran.
How did he come to this?
I was dispatched
by my commanding officer
to assess the laughable strength
of the weak and pathetic
human resistance,
and was ambushed
by a circular propellant.
- Cannon ball in the back.
- Oh, I bet that hurt.
There is no such thing as pain.
- A little.
- You're lucky you survived at all.
You call this luck!
The gloried embrace of death
would have been luck.
I have questions for you, soldier.
I will answer nothing.
I am trained to resist
all interrogations.
Where's your encampment?
- I assert my rights to silence...
- Mmm.
...under section Cyan K-Z Nine Slothback
of the Shadow Proclamation.
Oh, you do, do ya?
But what if I have valuable
battle information for your commander?
What sort of information?
The Doctor.
Vanquisher and sworn enemy
of the Sontarans,
former President of Gallifrey,
is in the Crimea.
Where? Show me.
I will vanquish our despised nemesis
with my bare hands. Where is the Doctor?
Closer than you could possibly imagine.
But how can it have heard of...
I'd be prepared to give your commander
information on the Doctor's whereabouts
should he agree to parlay on my signal.
Now, if we release you,
will you relay this information?
I accept your offer
and pledge to end your life with
maximum suffering at our next encounter.
I'd expect no less.
May death rain down on you both.
Well, it's nice to meet you, too.
Hurry along.
Human scum! You will be stamped
beneath the boot of Sontar!
At a future point, to be determined.
Do not shoot!
You allowed an enemy combatant
to escape!
I discharged my patient.
The British Hotel
is my establishment, General.
And you are my guest.
Mrs Seacole, may I suggest
an evening constitutional? Come along.
What are we doing?
The thing about Sontaran soldiers is
they're not very bright,
but that means you can take advantage.
Miladdo's got a message for his General.
With any luck, he's gonna lead us
right to the location
of the Sontaran base camp.
- Pretty simple, right?
- Wait.
- Who are you?
- Me? I'm Mary Seacole's assistant.
Where did he go?
See, Mary?
- No.
- Exactly.
A conjuring trick?
In a manner of speaking,
basic camouflage shield.
But if you don't know it's there,
it's impossible to spot.
Want to give it a go with me?
Where are we now?
Soldiers!
Marching duty until sunrise!
Strategic base construction troops
report to Commander Strevs.
Security patrols must execute...
- There's so many of them.
- Yes. There are.
Mary, you're good at keeping
observation records, right?
Of course.
And you can survive
on very little sleep, I imagine.
- What are you asking of me?
- Monitor this encampment.
Keep a note of everything that happens.
But stay out of sight.
I can do that.
I think. Can't I?
You return to us wounded, humiliated
and no deaths to your credit.
I bring information, Commander Skaak.
The sworn enemy of Sontar,
the Doctor, is here on Earth.
The Doctor is here?
My source will request parlay
to discuss bringing the Doctor to you.
This is useful.
You have done adequately.
I am shamed, Commander.
Yes. The stench of your humiliation
infects us all.
I request mercy.
Request granted.
The mercy of immediate execution
be upon you.
For unanswerable shame upon Sontar.
Sontar-Ho.
So when did they turn up here,
these Sontarans?
Same day you vanished.
What's that, two days ago now?
Already feels like a month.
We had the Three-Minute Eclipse
and then, bang, they were here.
Three-Minute Eclipse?
Whole world went to blackout,
all at the same time.
Lasted three minutes.
Must have been the Karvanista's ships.
So, come on, where have you been?
It's a bit hard to explain.
Hey, lad, did someone nick your house?
Sort of.
Listen, how many of these are there?
Oh, millions.
All over the world in their ships,
soldiers pouring out and taking over.
But you can knock 'em out
with a frying pan?
They've got this thing on the back
of their neck, like a hole.
Probic something.
Yeah, all right, Eileen,
no need to get all medical.
But if you smack bang on it,
then they go down like ninepins.
Who found that out?
- Feller in Birkenhead.
- He was drunk with a mallet.
Birkenhead.
We've got to get rid of 'em.
That's what I said.
You said they'd be off
after the weekend.
- I never did.
- He does this to annoy me.
They were in Liverpool first.
Six hours before anywhere else.
Nobody believed us.
They went all round the world,
but they started here.
When you say here,
where exactly do you mean?
This is where they first appeared.
Took over the whole waterfront.
Let's go have a look.
Hey, where you going?
There's thousands of them.
They've got lasers.
Dad, this is our planet.
These are our docks.
What else are you gonna do?
Sit at home and complain?
It's what he normally does.
Oi, you! I'm not afraid of a scrap.
I was Wallasey's...
Junior Boxing Champion, 1996.
We've already heard of people trying
and then just disappearing.
Yeah, well, I've had some experience
of dealing with aliens
these last few days.
You two, get back to the house.
I'm going in.
What, by yourself?
It's better that way.
Take this, son.
In case you need it.
What happened to these two?
They're all burned out.
Can you repair?
I don't know what you mean.
Transmission received
from outer corridor priest triangle.
There is another. You will step aside.
Repair is here.
Hi, I'm Yaz.
Serving Commander Inston-Vee Vinder
of Kasto-Winfer-Foxfell at your service.
Oh, well, if we're going formal,
Serving Officer Khan,
Hallamshire Police. Earth Division.
At yours.
Repair! Repair!
You know how to fix this?
- Full disclosure, Inston-Vee Vinder.
- Just Vinder's fine.
I don't know how I got here, or why,
or where here is or how I get back home.
Same.
I don't wanna freak you out,
but there's something very wrong
with the universe right now.
I saw it for myself.
Me too. From my outpost.
Those objects, they called it The Flux.
What do they want repairing?
This.
Oh.
Well,
I was hoping
it was gonna be a bit smaller.
Less abstract.
More like a washing machine.
So, these are what are broken?
Like a before and after.
That's not all.
Step back.
Proximity activation, on all of them.
Not sure why.
Do you even know what this place is?
The triangle said
it's the Temple of Atropos.
- But it can't be.
- Why not?
Repair! You must repair!
I'm gonna need more information.
Take us through the basics.
Idiot's guide.
Repair
must not be undertaken by idiots.
Explain Mouri, explain Atropos,
and set context for repair.
We are the Guardian Priests.
We maintain the Temple of Atropos
on the planet of Time.
All time passes through the Mouri.
Must pass through the Mouri.
Before Atropos, Time ran wild.
To harness, the Mouri were assigned.
Assigned by who?
Information unavailable.
If the Mouri are broken,
Time shall run unstoppable.
Which is a problem, right?
Time is destruction.
The Mouri are controlled.
They must not break.
Time must not be unleashed.
You talk about Time
as if it was a force.
Time's evil.
And it will seek its own.
Human filth
has been discovered within the compound.
Commander Riskaw
requires an execution troop.
Immediate deployment.
Bring them here!
Place them in line.
I am Commander Riskaw
of Sontaran Temporal Command.
Spying is treason against Sontar.
If you have any words,
now is the moment
to keep them to yourselves.
Soldiers! Raise arms!
Execute!
Execution complete.
Our Temporal Offensive
is near, soldiers.
- Sontar-Ha!
Sontar-Ha!
Sontar-Ha! Sontar-Ha!
Enough!
Stay alert for intruders.
We will execute all who defy us!
Parlay.
Over here!
Let's be having you.
Take your hat off, mate.
Oh, on second thoughts, put it back on.
You have information regarding
the treacherous vermin
known as The Doctor.
You're talking to her.
What?
You deceived my soldier.
It wasn't difficult.
It is regrettable that our Flux strategy
did not foresee your presence
but we shall not falter.
You knew the Flux was coming?
So, what caused it? Is it you lot?
Are the Sontarans behind the Flux?
The Flux is neither of our making
or our control.
But our Psychic Command foresaw it.
We timed our attack on this feeble rock
in the fractions before
the Lupari Shield took effect.
While we were all looking the other way.
You must be very proud.
This planet has defied us
ever since the great Commander Lynx
first staked his claim
on the ground of its feeble soil.
We now assert that claim!
Earth shall be an outpost
of the Sontaran Empire.
No, it won't.
But why here? Why Sebastopol?
The Crimean skirmish
seems the perfect place to start.
So much conflict. So much opportunity.
And also...
I wanted to ride a horse.
Leave this planet now
and you get to leave alive.
Ugh.
You think your puny words
will stand me down?
There will be no battle.
I speak on behalf of all of humanity.
No, Doctor.
- You do not.
- What are you doing?
This woman does not speak
for the British Army.
We are ready.
I speak for more people
than you could possibly imagine!
Don't be a fool.
Call me that again, Doctor,
and see if you survive.
This is good sport!
Soldier,
escort this "Doctress"
back to the encampment.
Keep your weapon on her at all times.
- Don't do this.
- It's done!
Raise your arms above your head
or be shot as a traitor immediately.
Go!
You speak for no one, Doctor!
Not even your pitiful self.
I accept your offer
of a massacre.
Your blood shall soak our uniforms,
your bodies shall soften our steps.
Yes, this is as devastating
as you're imagining.
Be grateful you aren't there.
And I'm sorry.
Have a kip, it'll wear off in six hours.
And you'll still be alive.
Options blocked off.
Time to recalibrate.
I'm filming this for you,
Doctor.
They've turned Liverpool docks
into some sort of space shipyard.
I reckon I can get into one.
I remember this.
Passenger, we are three.
I'll lead.
Can you repair?
Yes.
That's why we're here.
Unsure.
Come here, little thing.
I said, come here.
- Closer.
- Identify.
Surplus of unauthorized
lifeform arrivals.
We're not the first here.
Identify.
I am Azure.
And I am your death.
It's as you said.
More powerful than before.
Why the wait will be worth it.
Now, Atropos,
where it all began
and will all begin again.
Fire!
You're still here,
on your watch. Thank you.
- Mary Seacole.
- What happened?
I couldn't stop them.
Now the soldiers are dying.
You're gonna be very busy
by day's end. I'm sorry.
I noted everything.
It's deserted down there now.
Excellent work, Mrs Seacole.
And just as I thought.
Now, given their absence,
it would be churlish
not to take advantage, don't you think?
Come on.
Where are we going?
Half a league onward.
That one looks good, Mary.
Let's have a squiz inside.
They built all of this?
I mean, it's good,
but it's no British Hotel.
Here we are.
Double top! Get in.
I've snuck on board.
Haven't seen
any of the potato heads yet.
I'm looking for the control centre
or whatever.
Ah.
That's more like it.
Now, Mrs Seacole, with your records,
and this data,
let's see what's really going on.
It is bad to just press things?
Hopefully they won't self-destruct.
Or let everyone know I'm here.
Dan! Dan!
Dan! Dan, it's me!
Doctor!
Where are you?
- Still in the Crimea!
- Back in Liverpool.
Where's Yaz?
I don't know.
You speak first.
How are you on a Sontaran ship?
I'm back home.
They've took over Liverpool dock.
They're building spaceships,
hundreds of them, all along the Mersey.
They're not just in the Crimea.
And they've got this
obsession with Japanese food.
I heard one of the chief Potato Heads
talking about Tempura Command.
Tempura Offensive.
What's that all about?
Could it have been "Temporal" Command?
Temporal as in time.
Oh, yeah.
That makes more sense.
Hey, I've been filming everything
if that helps.
Good lad! Very nice.
Hold your phone close to the screens.
I can access the Sontaran data banks,
plus everything that's on your phone.
What, including me photos?
Of course.
Temporal Offensive.
They're just about to launch
a huge wave of attacks throughout time.
They're building Time ships,
so they can invade Earth's history.
And the Crimea is the pilot scheme.
Earth will become a Sontaran outpost
from the dawn of time.
The whole history erased.
Well, you better make sure you stop it.
Is that Mary Seacole?
Hi, Mary.
Hello there.
I don't understand any of this.
We have to get the Sontarans
out of the Crimea.
But the rest is on you, Dan.
I was worried you were gonna say that.
The first wave of ships in the Sontaran
Temporal Offensive are about to launch.
You have to stop those ships leaving.
How am I supposed to do that?
What resources do you have?
- A wok.
- I'm sorry, what?
Why have you got a wok?
It's me Mam's. For hitting them
on the probic thingies.
Tracing rogue transmissions.
Who is using this frequency?
- Dan, get out of there, now!
- Disabling transmissions.
What about the plan?
...all rogue transmitters.
Doctor!
Good luck, Dan.
Right, Mrs Seacole,
we both have a lot of work to do.
Doctor!
Halt, intruder!
All right, mate. I'm a little bit lost.
I was just looking for the pier head.
This is an Imperial
Sontaran Time Carrier.
Unauthorised human presence
shall result in immediate
and enjoyably violent execution.
I'm just a tourist.
Ask your boss, your Commander, like.
There he is.
How'd you like that? Pan-fried Sontaran!
Now I'm gonna wok right out of here.
All right, lads. I was just looking
for the pier head.
How can we fix something
that can't be touched?
I have no idea.
But we do.
You can stand aside now.
We understand exactly
what's needed here.
- Can you repair?
- Yes.
Sure. You got identification?
Very good, Yasmin Khan.
Does the Doctor know
you're out this late by yourself?
I don't think we've met before.
Such linear creatures.
That message, in pen,
on the palm of your hand
that no one knows about.
W-W-T-D-D.
What would the Doctor do?
How could you know that?
How does she choose you?
Any of you?
So unremarkable.
Take your hands off me right now.
You heard her.
Commander Vinder.
Shamed, disgraced and rejected.
Were you hoping
this could be your redemption?
Try me.
Stop! It won't work.
- Who are you?
- I'm Azure.
This is Swarm.
Translations, but they'll do.
Now unless you want
to upset Passenger here,
take five steps to your left.
The proximity.
They've been quantum locked against us,
after last time.
It's a good thing you were here.
- Stay there.
- You are not repair!
You are identified!
You are forbidden from the temple.
It was...
You underestimated us,
you pathetic temporal hags.
Your deluded, pointless lives
have led you here,
to painful, powerless deaths.
Two already broken.
Shall I repair?
Stop! You don't know what you're doing.
Don't worry. I'm getting to you.
Spying is an act of treason
against Sontar.
Yeah, yeah. I've heard all this...
Troops! Prepare for execution.
Ready! Aim!
I don't think so!
I've still got a human in this fight.
You're welcome, idiot.
So many wounded.
We won't save them all.
All of the casualties were ours.
Soldiers pay the price
for their commanders' mistakes.
They'll attack again at first light.
I don't know what to do.
Help me.
I'm gonna need a pointy stick.
Sontarans! Project: Crimean Eviction.
Pay attention, sit up,
back straight, hands on heads.
Actually, forget about the last one.
So, here we go.
Sontarans need a rest cycle
of 7.5 minutes every 27 hours,
as detailed by Mrs Seacole
in her observations here
and at the Sontaran encampment.
During said rest cycle,
they all go back into their ships.
- Why?
- I...
I'll tell you why.
Because they cannot cope with Earth's
atmosphere over an extended period.
That's why they wear
the protective armoured suits.
The suits filter out harmful Earth gases
and substitute them with chemicals
and nutrients from their home planet.
But the suits only have
a limited capacity.
- They have to be refilled.
- From their ships.
Gold star and a sticker for Mrs Seacole.
Keep up, Lieutenant General.
The ships aren't just transport,
they hold their supplies.
So, for precisely 7.5 minutes
every 27 hours,
the Sontarans top up their suits
via the probic vents
in the back of their necks,
resting and refuelling like cars
refilling their petrol tanks.
- What...
- Wait, forget that one.
Um, like horses
replenishing their nose bags.
Right.
So, what we're going to do
is empty their ships of those supplies,
forcing a retreat out of the Crimea
back to the 21st century,
where my best person will be there
to deal with them. Hopefully.
Did you just say 21st century?
Shh! She's talking!
Now, if they're all
on the same timetable every day,
which I bet they are,
in 38 minutes' time,
they will all enter
their ships simultaneously.
While they're inside,
we will have exactly 7.5 minutes
to drain their supplies.
Might need some of your men to help.
Ah!
Right. Remember what I taught you.
Divert this gas into this chamber...
...and it will render the supply feed
inert and harmless to humans.
Then, rip off this
and let it all leak out into the air.
Got it? Come on, General.
Next ship, 6.9 minutes left.
What is happening?
Supply levels
dwindling to critical across the fleet.
Unable to refill armour.
What is that useless weapon you've got?
It's a wok.
You look ridiculous.
Says the bloke with the floppy ears.
What are you doing here?
We're still species-bonded.
Clearly, you're so inept,
you can't be on your own.
And, also, this is partially our fault.
The Sontaran attack force snuck through
in the second
before we sealed the shield.
It's our responsibility.
Well, my responsibility.
Because I got the blame. As usual.
Listen, they're about to launch
timeships into Earth's history.
- I know.
- I've got a plan.
- What do you mean you know?
- I intercepted the transmissions.
It's not your plan.
So, don't pretend you're clever.
Alright, keep your fur on!
What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
- I'm taking off.
- What...
I understand you're having a problem
with your supplies, Commander.
Sabotage!
I warned you this planet was protected.
Now, retreat.
That word shall never pass my lips!
We shall make a strategic withdrawal.
But we shall return.
Not while I'm around.
Now, hit the road, Skaak.
What's your plan?
Some clever sciency-spacey thing
I won't understand?
- We're gonna ram them.
- What?
We'll use this ship as a battering ram
to hit all the others,
creating a massive temporal reaction,
takes the ships and all of the Sontarans
on Earth out of existence.
- Huge temporal bang.
- Yeah, but... but we're on this ship!
There's an escape pod
down the corridor, you fool!
Come on! We're out of here.
- That was a great plan!
- Why did I have to get you to protect?
You could've killed me!
What are you doing?
Get down there! Hurry up!
This thing's about to crash!
Whoo!
This is Commander Riskaw, the fleet
is under attack from insurgents!
It worked! They're leaving.
And with no further bloodshed.
I must disabuse you of that.
What have you done?
I recommend you run.
Run, Doctor! Run!
This is for my men!
They were retreating.
It was done.
That was for the men I lost today.
For your guilt, you mean.
Sometimes men like you make me wonder
why I bother with humanity.
I... I am grateful that you do.
Whoever you are, Doctor.
I have to go and find my friends.
I hope we meet again, Mrs Seacole.
Where are you going?
I'm here.
What is this thing happening to you?
What was in that tube?
It was a waste tube.
You're kidding me!
They've gone.
It's all gone.
Temporal implosion.
You're welcome.
Oh, here she comes,
now the hard work's been done.
- You made it back
- And you got rid of the Sontarans.
It was pretty easy, really.
I worked it all out by myself,
until Scooby Doo here
tried to take all the credit.
I need your people to stay protecting
this planet while I'm away.
I have to find my friend.
You wanna come?
Okay.
I'm not done with you yet.
If you're going out into the universe,
you'd better understand,
it's in a bad way.
The Lupari will stay,
shielding the planet.
Until this is over.
If it is ever over.
I hope I never see you again.
Feeling's mutual.
That should not
be growing out the floor.
- Are these things new?
- Yeah.
They weren't here a second ago.
Something's corrupting the TARDIS.
- Did you just do that?
- No.
I can't make it work.
We're being hijacked.
Where are we?
I don't know.
But the spatio-temporal readings
are at zero, which is impossible.
This way.
I mean, this is obviously a trap.
And we're walking into it, are we?
I have to find Yaz. Stay close to me.
Do exactly as I say.
Ah! Doctor! At last.
Come.
It's been a long time.
I have something of yours.
Come.
Further.
Who are they?
These are the Mouri, Doctor.
The remnants of them, at least.
The Mouri...
in the Temple of Atropos.
On the planet Time.
There is no planet called Time.
Yet here we are.
The Temple of Atropos is broken.
And the Mouri are failing.
Creatures who hold time
in this universe together.
Broken.
Time is beginning to run wild.
Could really harm a TARDIS.
So I made a short-term repair.
- Yaz
- Doctor! Don't come near.
- I've seen what he can do.
- She's right.
Try to rescue them
and we'll reduce them to ash.
Her and her new friend.
- Will you count?
- Yes.
Five.
- What have you done to them?
- It's what I'm about to do, Doctor.
Four.
Poor placeholders.
Hardly equipped to be Mouri, are they?
- Three.
- When I click my fingers,
the full force of Time
will blast through them.
How many seconds will their bodies
be able to take before they die, Doctor?
Two.
Stop it.
You don't have to do this.
Tell me what you want.
One.
All in good time.
On my command.
Time is beginning to run wild.