Previously on Doctor Who...
C: Over the past week,
there's been a spate of attacks
on intelligence officers
worldwide,
of every nationality.
We need your help...Doctor.
SAY NAN: Die, die, die...
(SCREAMING)
YAZ: Daniel Barton.
Born in Bromsgrove,
now lives just north
of San Francisco.
- He's the founder of VOR.
- You can't entirely
trust everyone.
YAZ: Only 93% human.
- What's the other 7%?
- We're going to need
your best man on this.
- What do you call him?
- 0.
(WINDOW SHATTERS)
O...
(WINDOWS SHATTER)
What have you brought here,
Doctor?
Where are you from?
CREATURE: Far beyond.
(SCREAMS)
Ryan?!
If you really think they're
spies, we should be asking
who's the spymaster.
I'm really hard
to get rid of, Mr Barton.
Are you?
Should I say spy...Master?
You can't be.
Oh, I can be. I very much am.
Everything that you think
you know...
No, no, no, no, no.
...Is a lie.
DOCTOR: Hi, Doctor.
Oh! Hi.
How are you doing?
Good.
Just talking to myself
to prove I'm still alive.
I was wondering...
...what would you say to
the others if they were here?
"Don't panic.”
Yaz! Hold on!
(FRANTIC SHOUTING)
What?
DOCTOR: Of course,
I'm usually saying it as much
to myself as I am to them.
Always a good reminder
when you're alone...
...in the unknown...
...all hope lost.
(SHOUTING)
No way.
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- Won't work in here.
Why not? Could be a clue.
A clue to what?
What...
...was that?
Interesting. Useful. Maybe.
Another! Even better.
What are you?
Pathways?
Signals?
Synapses?
I could be inside something.
Oh, I hope it's not a liver.
I hate being inside livers.
People always get so offended.
"What are you doing
in my liver again?"
WOMAN: Hello?
DOCTOR: Hello?
"4C seat pocket."
No way.
(GROANS)
Hey! Hey!
I've got a plan.
Can you hear me?
I'm trying to find you...
somehow.
(DOCTOR CRIES OUT)
Please be assured
all this will pass.
I shall be recovered
momentarily.
- "Open panel in floor"!
- What does it say next?
"Connect the cable...
"...to your phone."
(STRAINS)
Welcome aboard.
You are kidding!
How's she doing that?!
I realise you have questions.
Where are you?!
We're going to die!
First of all,
you're not going to die.
Second of all
don't talk back to the screens.
Obviously, I'm a recording
and I can't hear you.
Third, don't panic.
Especially you, Graham.
I'm not panicking!
Yes, you were.
And I did just say don't
talk back to the screens.
Eh?!
Haven't got long. The bomb
in the cockpit knocked out
the signals from the computer
to the engines.
But the computers in this
aircraft aren't in the cockpit,
they're under the cabin floor.
Ryan, the app
should have opened.
What app? Eh?
How was this installed
on me phone?
Use it to communicate
with the engines
via the aircraft wiring.
By the way, you have shut
the cockpit door, haven't you?
That's vital.
Cockpit doors are designed
to be incredibly robust,
I'L do it!
Now pay attention.
Do this fast.
I'm worried you might lose me
if there's a power surge.
Lost her.
Press the cursor up!
We've got to stop this plane
- from going down!
- Up, up, up!
- Too many ups!
- Level out! Level out!
When you say "recovered”,
what do you mean?
The paralysis will fade.
You don't look paralysed.
Not in this...realm
but in my earthly aspect.
Right.
What's your name?
I am Ada.
And what do you think
this realm is, Ada?
I...believe it to be my mind.
Though I have not met
another here before.
Then what do you think I am?
I presume you are
a consequence of my thoughts.
No. I'm the Doctor,
and I'm very real.
But you've been here before?
Many times.
When the paralysis subsides,
I find myself
fully back in my body,
restored in the physical realm.
If you are real, do you have
your own solution
for egress from here?
No exit strategy.
(CRACKLING)
Before I leave, I need to
work out what this place is.
Oh!
Those fragments of light...
...or energy, why are they
surrounding you?
They are always here with me.
They place a word in my mind.
"Kasaavin"?
Ada...step away.
Do not be afraid.
This is my guardian.
This is their realm!
This is where they're from.
But how did you bring us here?
Unless...
You can't be.
But you must be.
What? Gateways?
We go through you
and arrive in your realm?
And I say "realm” - it's not
a planet, not really a void.
A separate dimension?
Are we beyond our...
...my universe?
Little of what you are saying
makes sense to me,
but I'm concerned
you'll be marooned here.
When my guardian
has returned...
- They're not your guardians.
- ...I can offer you my hand.
We may leave this place
together.
I don't think that will work.
How will you know
if you do not try?
Decide, Doctor.
You got us level, Ryan.
Good lad!
I can fly a plane!
Can't ride a bike,
but I can fly a plane.
Hey, look!
Barton must have programmed in
a flight pattern
before he left the cockpit.
Looks like this app's
keying into it.
- How did the Doctor do this?
- No idea.
But now we've got to stay
on a plane without a cockpit...
...till it decides
where to land.
You should've seen me!
I was great!
She did not have a clue.
This'd better work.
Final calibrations,
and then we'll be ready.
All our efforts
will come together
in a moment of beauty.
We'll all have what we want.
So you know, I don't appreciate
last-minute changes of plan
as I'm about to take off.
A little chaos
is a wonderful thing.
Allowed me to swat those flies.
(PHONE BEEPS)
I've just been notified.
My plane"s about to land
at its programmed destination.
- They can't have survived.
- You told me
everything was foolproof.
What's gone wrong?
Watch your tone...
...Mr Barton.
I'm not your employee.
(ALARM BLARES)
How has she got there?
What's happened?
Nothing I can't deal with.
I'll drop you at your plane.
You sort out her friends,
I'll deal with the Doctor.
Ah.
I'm getting...
...19th century?
Early...
...with a touch of mid.
Top notes...
...London.
Steam?
Why am I getting steam?
Nations shall cower in fear
as my steam gun fires
1,000 bearings per minute.
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- See the mouse survive
inside our revolutionary
diving bell!
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
- Touch the magneto.
- Powerful shocks.
- (AUDIENCE GASPS)
The perfect modern defence,
a grenade for the home.
Intruders repelled with force.
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
It worked!
Miss Gordon,
- are you recovered?
-I am.
- Thank you.
- Me too.
Thanks for asking.
Madam, this gallery
is full of
the extraordinary, but...
...your apparition just now
was...
...impossible.
How did you do it?
Er...
I am bound never
to reveal my secrets.
Go about your day,
knowing that you may tell
people you were
privileged to witness
the Marvellous Apparating Man!
Lady. Apparating Lady!
- Every time!
- (APPLAUSE)
The year, right now,
would be what?
The year, madam,
remains 1834.
Yes.
Marooned in the 19th century.
Hold on in there, fam.
And there was no-one on board?
No, sir. It appears the craft
landed itself via automation.
Sir, we have had
this conversation before.
If you're going to be testing
these sorts of systems,
we really need to be
kept fully in the loop.
I'm going to have to do
some tricky smoothing-over
with the Civil Aviation
Authority.
YAZ: How did he get here
so quick?
I dunno.
Where is "here", anyway?
Britain.
We're home.
Almost.
- Essex.
- Essex!
That is my manor!
We are golden!
What do we do, though?
Figure out what Barton and O
are planning.
That's what the Doctor
would do...
- Yeah.
- ...if she was here.
No, she'll be all right, Yaz.
Just got to believe.
You didn't see that place.
Eh?
Still got access
to Barton's diary.
He's giving a keynote speech
in London tomorrow night.
That is where
we have got to get to.
Yeah, without him
knowing we're still alive.
So let's get moving.
(KEYPAD BEEPS)
I need tracking intel
on three people.
As soon as you can!
These are their names.
ADA: Now we are safe,
Doctor, will you reveal
a little more concerning
how you came to be...
- Agh!
- ...in that place
and, indeed, who you are?
I'm a traveller
in space and time.
I was in the middle of dealing
with a planet-threatening
conspiracy two centuries
from now, when I was attacked
by an old enemy and exiled
to the place where I found you.
- Oh!
- I'm not a fool, Doctor.
And I'm not treating you
as one.
This conspiracy involves
those creatures you think
are your guardians.
They're in alliance with
a renegade from my home planet
and a 21st-century
tech inventor.
186 years from now,
they're assassinating spies,
and I am stuck here
without my TARDIS,
and I need to find
my way back before...
Ladies and gentlemen!
See the incredible
shrinking device!
Want to be smaller, ladies?
You can!
- (SCREAMING)
- Who's next? You, sir.
Go, Ada. You too.
Go!
Ah, the happy couple!
I said go!
Do not move!
Hands on heads.
Hands on heads!
(SCREAMING)
Let them go...
...and you can have me.
I've got you anyway.
Did you just move?
- Did you move?
- No!
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my mistake.
Sorry.
(SHRIEKING)
When I kill them, Doctor,
it gives me a little buzz.
Right here.
In the hearts. It's like...
How would I describe it?
It's like...
It's like knowing
I'm in the right place,
doing what I was made for.
What do you want?
Kneel.
Or they all die.
Call me by my name.
Master.
Beg your pardon?
Master!
Can't hear you, love.
Master.
When I arrange for your death,
I expect you to stay dead.
How did you escape?
How did you end up here?
You don't know!
You're not in control
of those creatures.
I bet you don't even know
what they are.
They're called the Kasaavin.
And we have interests
in common.
You, Barton...
...and a race you barely know?
That's one uneasy alliance.
Trust each other, do you?
Oh, completely.
By the way,
I bring news from home.
Down, Doctor!
(GUNFIRE)
This is not designed for use
- by a young lady!
- Nothing is.
And yet I find myself
more than capable.
All of you, out!
Ada, I really do not approve!
Run all you like, Doctor.
You won't get far
without a TARDIS!
DOCTOR: Don't have a TARDIS.
Do have an Ada.
It's hard not to stand out
in this gear.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- We've been on a night out.
We're just coming home, that's
all. Nothing weird about that.
- (PHONES RING)
- BARTON: Hello, friends.
Or should I say
"plane thieves"?
What, did you think I wouldn't
be able to track you?
We have your numbers, e-mails,
GPS. I even know how many
more stamps you need for
a free coffee. So close, Ryan.
Or should I say "Logan"?
Look up.
Your passports
have been revoked,
your bank cards are frozen.
We have a record of
everyone you know -
friends, family, colleagues,
everyone you ever followed
on social media.
Of course, we have
cameras everywhere, and now
you're wanted for hijacking.
Go on, go off-grid.
See how long you last.
Hey, smash your phones now.
Aw! Yasmin Khan
ls phoning her mum!
- He don't half go on.
- MUM: Yaz?
Hello. It's me. Listen, don't
listen to anything you hear.
- Ryan!
- Did you not hear him?
We have to go dark.
Run.
MR BABBAGE: Surely we must
alert the authorities.
DOCTOR: The authorities
won't be any help.
ADA: Besides, what would
we tell them, Mr Babbage?
I have no concept, Ada.
I cannot explain any
of what I have seen today.
Babbage? Charles Babbage?
Yes.
So this must be...
- My Difference Engine.
- ...your Difference Engine!
Oh. You...you know of it?
- Er, just in passing.
- As yet unfinished.
It will count and perform
quadratic equations.
If you're Charles Babbage,
then you're not just
any old Ada.
You're Ada Lovelace!
Daughter of Lord Byron
and Annabella Milbanke,
one of the great minds.
I am Ada Gordon, madam.
1834. Of course you are.
Well, maybe one day, who knows,
you might meet a nice earl.
This changes everything!
This isn't an accident.
Ada Lovelace
in Babbage's house?
You're clues.
- You're important.
-I'm...
...delighted to hear it, madam.
Yes, it's not good news.
What's that?
This is the Silver Lady...
...a revolutionary
piece of engineering.
But, like all great ladies,
she is as much for decoration
as for purpose.
- How did you come by this?
- It was a gift,
delivered by a young man
who said it was
a token of appreciation...
...from his master.
Was it?
What does it do?
It...moves...
...and, on occasion,
- projects.
- On occasion
projects something like this?
M-Mr Babbage, you have seen
the same form.
Madam, those are
my private notes.
The Master and the Kasaavin,
what are they doing?
Er... Do you understand her,
Miss Gordon?
Not in the least, Mr Babbage.
Ada, when was
your first paralysis?
I was 13 years old.
That is when I was first
transported to the place
where we met
and I first saw an apparition.
And over the years,
the paralysis recurs
with the same effect?
Yes! No doctor has ever been
able to diagnose the cause.
Well, this Doctor
may be able to.
An apparition...
from this machine.
- Correct.
- So,
they take you, Ada,
multiple times...
...from here and...
...they study you
in their dimension,
which means they can't be
in this dimension for long.
But maybe they gain an ally,
a mastermind who builds them
a machine which
stabilises them in this world
long enough for them to send
spies and to spread their work
and start a plan.
Cos I've seen the map!
In his hut. Multiple Earths.
Except not.
Not multiple Earths.
Multiple time periods.
These creatures aren't just
alien spies on Earth,
they're spies through time...
...through history...
- ...starting with you.
- (SONIC WHIRS)
What are you doing?
The man from the Adelaide
Gallery will be coming for me.
I need to get back
to where I came from, find
my friends and figure this out.
And I've only got
one way out of here,
the same way I came in.
If I use my sonic on the Silver
Lady, I might be able to force
this creature to throw me
back to the 21st century.
- I hope.
- If this is your plan,
it is fraught with risk.
Where there's risk,
there's hope.
Deep breath.
Ada, no!
GRAHAM: No-one living here yet,
no CCTV,
no neighbourhood watch.
The one on the end. Go on!
What if the Doctor
doesn't come back?
What if we never see her again?
We keep going...
...stop Barton...
...get rid of those creatures,
whatever they are.
Ryan's right.
We carry on doing what the Doc
would want us to do.
I'm sorry, did you just say,
"Ryan's right"?
Yes, I did!
Enjoy the moment, son.
You won't hear it often.
And that old guy...
...if the Doctor knew him,
how come she couldn't
recognise him?
In the outback...
...he said that he knew the Doc
when she was a man,
and that first night we met...
...she told me and Grace
that she'd been through, erm...
...something called...
...regeneration, like
her whole body had changed.
We've spent all this time
with her
and we don't even know
where she's from.
Yeah, not for want of asking,
though. Eh? I mean!
And we will ask...
...when we see her again...
...which we will...
...cos she is safe somewhere,
of course. Right?
- Right.
- RYAN: Right.
You know what she'd ask now?
"What do we have
at our disposal?”
Well...
...I've, er...got to admit...
...] did keep a couple of
those spy gadgety things.
Me too!
Hey, are you
- wearing the laser shoes?
- I might be.
Why didn't you use them
on the plane?!
What, in a confined space
like that?
You're having a laugh,
ain't ya?
That wouldn't have been
very smart, would it?
And besides which, I forgot
- to read the instructions.
- Graham!
Well, we was in a rush!
What could I do?
Rocket cuff links.
To be fair, I didn't read the
instructions on those either.
You doughnut!
- BOTH: "Doughnut"?
- Yeah, the pair of you.
Right couple of doughnuts!
But...
...there's no-one
I'd rather be on the run with.
(CRUNCHING)
What?
No.
(PLANE ROARS PAST)
Ada! Are you OK?
ADA: Are we safe?
- (BOMBS AND GUNFIRE)
- WOMAN: Don't move.
I said don't move!
We're not hostile.
We're here by accident.
What are you doing out here?
What are you wearing?
(BOMB WHISTLES OVERHEAD
AND EXPLODES)
ADA: What are those noises?
Where are we? And when?
Don't you know?
Just landed. Concussion.
Humour me.
Paris, 1943.
(MAN SHOUTS)
Oh, no!
It's a patrol.
Inside, quick.
We're not safe out here.
I know you're here!
I will find you!
(BEEPING)
Especially you, Doctor.
Coming, ready or not.
YAZ: Did you just hear
something?
Ryan, come on!
GRAHAM: Out this way.
Come on, out here!
YAZ: Quick, quick!
GRAHAM: Come on, quick!
Come on, Yaz!
- The shoe, Graham!
- What?
Just stomp your foot,
or something!
Again!
You've got to aim better.
What do you mean?
I didn't read the instructions!
Dance, Graham, dance!
Beautiful, isn't it?
Dates back to the 19th century.
What, not going
to say anything?
This cannot still be about
me moving to the States.
I text. I e-mail.
I tried to friend you
on Facebook, and you refused.
And trust me, I never use
Facebook unless forced.
Why am I here?
I'm in the country.
I thought it would be nice
for us to see each other.
- Thanks for coming.
- I didn't have a choice!
I keep wondering,
does she know?
Does she realise that I'm one
of the most successful men
on the planet?
I've changed the world.
What do I have to do
to get you to say, "Well done"?
Well done.
Are we finished?
No.
I wanted to see you...
...on the last day.
On the what?
So that you could be the first.
(SCREAMS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Yes?
(CLATTERING)
You're new.
(BREATHES RAPIDLY)
(FLOORBOARDS CREAK)
(THUDS CANE)
(GUNFIRE)
(GUNFIRE STOPS)
(THUDS CANE)
(DOOR CLOSES)
You are a life-saver.
Got some interesting stuff
under the floorboards here.
Wireless radio equipment.
As issued by the British
Special Operations Executive.
Very distinct, very large
and very difficult
to hide.
You're not Parisian.
You're a British spy.
I know that face.
Code name Madeleine.
Real name
Noor Inayat Khan.
First female wireless operator
to be dropped behind enemy
lines. Very nice to meet you.
I'm not where I wanted to be,
but I can work with this.
Ada, wait till you hear
about Noor.
She's as impressive as you.
You grabbing my hand must have
thrown us off course,
spat us out here.
I should like to come out
from the floor now.
Oh!
Who are you?
How do you know
so much about me?
And why are you both
wearing such strange clothes?
That soldier's voice - he was
in the Adelaide Gallery.
How can he be here?
He's in league
with the Kasaavin,
those creatures of light.
I'd hoped to get back to their
home dimension, where we met,
and then to the 21st century.
But we ended up here
instead, which is,
you know, 19th century
to 20th, it's progress.
But the Master tracked me down,
and now he wants me dead,
whereas I am a big fan
of being alive.
Ada? Are you all right?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
I have always wanted
to return to Paris.
NOOR: It's not at its best.
Nightly bombing raids.
Millions dead.
They promised us
war at this scale would never
happen again,
and yet here we are.
This isn't the first time?
Who are you people?
We're your allies, I promise.
This is the future.
A world on fire.
These are the dark times.
But they don't sustain.
Darkness never sustains...
...even though sometimes
it feels like it might.
I need to turn this
to our advantage
and get the Master
off my trail.
He's masquerading
as a German soldier.
That's a low, even for him.
Code name Madeleine, what
equipment do you have here?
Only my radio equipment.
No gun. No cyanide pill.
I'm a pacifist.
Snap! Strong position
to take during wartime.
Two pacifists
and a 19th-century
descendant of Byron
against the Nazis in Paris
and an alien invasion
across multiple dimensions.
That's a big to-do list.
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
I have an idea!
And you two brilliant people
are a big part of it.
(RINGING TONE)
Hello?
Sonya, it's me.
Where are you, idiot?
What sort of trouble have you
gone and got yourself into?
Shut up. I'm fine,
but I can't talk long.
Tell Mum and Dad not to worry.
SONYA: Oh, yeah,
cos that's going to work...
Your name's all over the news.
Have you gone rogue?
Shut up and listen.
I'm with Graham and Ryan.
We're fine. There's just been
a bit of a misunderstanding.
If anyone comes to the door
and wants you to go with them,
just refuse. Stay in the flat
and don't let anyone in.
Keep yourself safe.
I'm worried they'll come
for you. I've got to go.
(TYRES SCREECH)
Down! Get down!
Face down on the floor!
All right, all right.
Sorry, gents, it's you who's
getting down on the floor.
This is the most advanced
laser shoe known to man.
Ain't worth
the resistance, lads.
Guns down and on the floor.
Don't make me do
the ol' soft-shoe shuffle.
Your boss thinks we're stupid.
She made the call
knowing that you'd come for us.
And now we're taking
your phones
and we're going
to raid your GPS.
How's that for smart?
(CHUCKLES)
Ryan!
Don't tell them the plan!
Oh, yeah.
Sorry, I got a bit
carried away.
- Come on, let's go.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
(FOUR BEEPS)
That's not a code.
Not to you.
If this works, I'm going
to need you to find
something for me.
This is a very personal code.
(TWO SETS OF FOUR BEEPS)
The rhythm of two hearts.
(BEEPS CONTINUE)
That got his attention.
He's not so far.
I can sense him.
DOCTOR: Contact.
O: Contact.
O: Old-school.
You're not the only one
who can do classic.
So, how are you holding up
without a TARDIS
or your friends
or a hope...
...a fugitive in time?
All right.
You've come all this way.
You've got me cornered.
I'll meet you.
No troops.
No soldiers.
Just us.
Where?
Where do you think?
(AIR-RAID SIREN WAILS)
(PLANE ROARS PAST)
It's cold up here!
(WIND HOWLS)
It's worse than Jodrell Bank.
Did I ever apologise for that?
No.
Good.
How's the shoulder?
Painful.
I don't like
what you're wearing.
Or the company you keep.
How have you managed that?
You're not exactly
their Aryan archetype.
Tiny Teutonic
psychic perception filter.
Learned it at school.
Lets people see
what they want to see.
I'm assuming it was you
who hijacked the MI6 car.
That was fun.
And assassinated C.
Mandraffian laser rifle.
One shot.
I've still got an eye for it.
Why were the Kasaavin
assassinating spies?
Earth's intelligence services
started to realise
their presence.
So, what, you brought
the Kasaavin to Earth?
They were already here.
(CHUCKLES)
I just persuaded them
we had interests in common.
The Kasaavin are embedded
across the whole
of this universe,
spies from another dimension.
As I said to Mr Barton...
...think of them as Russia...
...but bigger.
Sleeper agents everywhere,
waiting to be activated,
amassing information
in case they need to attack.
And, I mean, you know me.
I can't help myself.
I have to stick my oar in.
What have you done?
Suggested a better plan.
(TYRES SCREECH)
YAZ: Over here!
Is she alive?
No.
What's she even doing here?
Where's Barton?
This is where his guys
were supposed to lead us,
and he's not here.
(BEEP)
Well done
overpowering my people.
But did you really think
they wouldn't tell me?
I have a significant
announcement to make,
and you, my friends,
are two steps behind.
- As usual.
- YAZ: We know all about you.
We know some of your DNA
isn't human.
So what are you, part alien?
You really don't understand
who I am.
I build things.
I test them.
So I let them test
a tiny part of me.
And now it's time
for the global roll-out.
I'm proof of concept.
What concept?
What did they try?
Look after my mum.
He killed his own mum.
And left her here.
That machine was
in Barton's office.
What are you doing?
Communicating a message
back to London,
just as the Doctor asked.
- Why are we trusting her?
- I have seen
extraordinary things with her.
She's wise and unafraid,
and I believe in her.
W-What is this...contraption
she's left us with?
I don't know. I've never seen
anything like that before.
So...
...are you ready
to brave the night?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE
AND EXPLOSIONS)
How does that fit here?
She did say,
"Look for something anomalous."
Use...the device.
(PHONE JINGLES)
(DIALLING)
(RINGING TONE)
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Oh! Must change the ringtone.
Sent it to voicemail.
Probably just asking
if I've had an accident
in the last five years.
They hate it when you give them
a list, though, don't they?
Why didn't you die when
the Kasaavin attacked you?
Me and Yaz,
both time travellers,
fizzing with artron energy,
and my DNA not matching
the rest of humanity,
we confused them.
And I don't think
they're as stable
in this dimension
as they'd like to be.
What deal have you made
with them?
I showed them and Barton
what was possible.
They helped me
lay a trap for you,
and I raised their ambitions.
Of course, ultimately...
...the Kasaavin are just
the mechanism.
They... They don't have
my vision. You know?
And what vision is that?
Maximum carnage.
I don't understand.
No, no, I know you don't.
But you will.
And of course,
the best thing is...
...everyone loses except me.
Barton and those creatures
do the dirty work,
and once they're done,
I get rid of them,
having destroyed your precious
human race in the process.
Win-win-win.
When does all this stop
for you?
The games?
The betrayals?
The killing?
Why would it stop?
I mean, how else
would I get your attention?
When did you last go home?
What do you mean?
I took a trip home.
To Gallifrey.
Hiding in its little
bubble universe.
Not sure how to describe
what I found.
"Pulverised"?
"Burned"?
"Nuked"?
All of the above.
Someone destroyed it.
Our home...
...razed to the ground.
Everyone killed.
Everything burned.
You're lying.
You should really take a look.
Oh, wait, you won't be able to.
I just thought
I'd let you know before I...
- (MEN SHOUT)
- Can you hear voices?
Why are there troops
coming up the stairs?!
Oh. That's me...
...and one of Blighty's
bravest radio operators.
Very good at sending messages,
particularly fake ones
designed to be intercepted.
Now, finish
what you were saying!
What have you done?!
Sent a message to the Brits...
...telling them how valuable
you've been...
...as a double agent...
...sending Nazi information
to the British.
Facial perception filter?
Very easy to jam.
Now they'll see the real you.
- Good luck.
- (LIFT BELL PINGS)
(SOLDIERS SHOUT)
I believe there's been
a misunderstanding.
Can we talk about this?
You've always struck me
as such reasonable people.
(CHATTER)
(PANTS HEAVILY)
NOOR: Over here.
Is this what you meant?
That wasn't here last week.
I bet it wasn't! So arrogant...
...didn't even change
the appearance.
OK, you two,
my best secret agents,
time to go lock-picking.
Why is this house so important?
This is not a house.
It's a machine
that travels in space and time.
This is my way back
to finding my friends
and saving humanity.
I know you think I'm mad,
but give me five minutes
and you'll think
I'm the sanest person alive.
OK, that was an overstatement.
I said the Master's arrogant,
but arrogance...
...can trip you up.
I know what this is!
A temporal map, showing
every significant person
in the development of computers
through history,
starting with you, Ada.
This is the plan!
See?
BOTH: No.
W-What is a computer?
Oh. Forget you heard that word.
Otherwise I've just disrupted
the whole of history. Again.
OK...
Ah, my brain's fizzing. Good.
The Kasaavin posted an agent
on every person on that map,
because that's what spies do,
what Barton does.
They gather all the data!
Where does the DNA fit in?
Kasaavin...
...technology, DNA...
How are they all connected?
Oh!
Human DNA.
That's what they were testing.
How much of that
did you understand?
Thank you.
Today, I'm here to say
thank you
to those of you
all around the world
who've made our achievements
possible,
to everyone who,
over the years,
has given us everything.
We gave you pieces of plastic
and circuitry and games...
...and you handed us -
me, my company -
total access to your lives -
what you buy, where you go,
who you text, what you text,
every thought and photo and
post, every credit-card number,
every birthday,
every memorable place
and all your mothers'
maiden names.
So thank you for carrying
our cameras in your pockets
and putting our microphones
in your bedrooms,
for signing up your kids,
handing them our devices.
We told you, "Of course
your lives are private,
"of course your data's safe.”
And you believed us.
You kept clicking "agree".
And now...
...we can do anything.
I can send a text
to every device on this planet.
(PHONE CHIMES)
(PHONES CHIME)
Go ahead.
Read it.
YAZ: "Humanity is over.
"You have three minutes
to prepare.”
Prepare for what?
(MURMURING AND LAUGHTER)
Funny, right?
Except...
...not a joke.
We are way past peak human.
We've created systems
that are smarter
and can run more efficiently
than we do.
So what's our purpose?
We must be useful
for something.
Well, the data tells us we are.
We can repurpose.
Well...
...you all can.
You know
the most efficient type
of hard drives on planet Earth?
Humans.
Human DNA can store
so much data.
We're the perfect
storage system,
which means there are
over seven billion
potentially incredibly useful
hard drives on this planet.
All that's needed is to
reformat the whole of humanity.
Luckily,
there's an app for that.
Anyone feel like this is
something we should be
worried about?
Mum?
I can't move!
A handful of us will remain
sentient in order to supervise,
maybe even rebuild.
But for the rest of you...
...welcome to
the end of your lives.
Use your shoe on the machine.
It doesn't make any difference.
Cuff links!
Move away.
Now!
I've just had
the most infuriating 77 years
of my life.
Have you any idea
how hard it is
to live through
the 20th century?
The places I've escaped from...
(INHALES DEEPLY) Still...
just in time to...
...watch you all pay.
What's the machine?
Conversion and transmission.
We're transmitting
Kasaavin energy
around the world all at once
into every device,
hitting every human being
and erasing all their DNA
simultaneously.
- Yaz!
- I can't let go of it.
First her. Then you.
Then you.
Don't do this.
(MURMURING)
Extraction team in.
Immediately!
Sorry. I think
that might have been me.
And I'll admit, it was close.
What was that?
What do I keep telling you?
Conspiracy!
- No.
- Two can play
at embedding things in history.
I knew the Silver Lady
was important
and that you built it
for a reason.
But I couldn't work out why.
So I traced its movements
through history.
And when I saw that
Barton now owned it,
we stopped by his office.
Middle of last year,
using your TARDIS, I built
a fail-safe into that machine,
planted a virus.
If it ever detected
the massing of a Kasaavin army
within its systems -
total shutdown.
You're going to have to explain
yourself to them, Doctor.
Am I?
Listen, you lot,
I've rigged the Silver Lady
to exile you back
to your own dimension.
This planet's off-limits.
Oh, and you know that deal
he made with you?
O: Barton and these creatures
do the dirty work,
and once they're done,
I get rid of them,
having destroyed your precious
human race in the process.
Win-win-win.
Oh...
That's your name.
Don't wear it out.
That's the trouble
with modern technology.
You never know
when you're being spied upon.
(KASAAVIN MURMUR THREATENINGLY)
Don't... Don't listen to her.
No.
Doctor...
Doctor!
What?
You have a lot of
explaining to do.
- Like what?
- Like...
Who are they?
And are we being replaced?
No!
This is Ada, this is Noor.
1834,
1943. They helped me out. I'm
dropping them back in a sec.
How did you manage
to save our lives on the plane?
The plane!
Oh! I forgot!
Come on!
You have shut the cockpit
doors, haven't you?
That's vital.
Cockpit doors are designed
to be incredibly robust.
I love a laminator.
Stick these in Barton's
plane as it's being built
then reclaim my own TARDIS.
This is where I leave you.
Answer me one question.
The fascists - do they win?
Never.
Not while there's people
like you.
It's all right.
I'm just removing me
from your mind.
Boone chance.
(VWORPING)
Doctor? Does this
have to be the end?
All the things I've learned,
the advances, the machines!
I would dearly love
to see more.
I'm afraid I need to do
something about that.
- What do you mean?
- I'm ever so sorry, Ada.
D-Doctor, what are you doing?
Wiping the things you shouldn't
have knowledge of.
Including me.
But I want that knowledge.
Don't take it away.
Please don't take it a...
Oh, Ada.
You don't need a preview.
You'll figure it out
before anyone.
The first to see the potential
in things like that,
to work out what could be...
...what they can really do.
Computers start with you.
Sweet dreams, Ada Lovelace.
(VWORPING)
0. When did you last go home?
You should really take a look.
(JINGLING)
O: Geo-activated.
If you're seeing this...
...you've been to Gallifrey.
When I said someone did that..
...obviously I meant...
.I did.
I had to make them pay
for what I discovered.
They lied to us...
...the founding fathers
of Gallifrey.
Everything we were told
was a lie.
We are not who we think,
you or 1.
The whole existence
of our species...
...built on the lie
of the timeless child.
REMNANTS:
Child...child...child...
O Do you see it?
It's buried deep
in all our memories...
...in our identity.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
I'd tell you more...
...but..
...but why would I make it
easy for you?
It wasn't for me.
(GROANS)
YAZ: You OK?
You're really quiet,
RYAN: Yeah. You have been
for days now.
They're right. Five planets,
you've barely said a word.
I'm fine!
Why don't you ever
share anything with us?
I share stuff!
GRAHAM:;
Not about yourself, though.
RYAN: Yeah, you know
everything about us.
YAZ: And we know
nothing about you.
GRAHAM: Mm.
Fine.
What do you want to know?
Who are you, Doc?
I mean, really.
I was born on a planet
called Gallifrey
in the constellation
of Kasterborous.
I'm a Time Lord.
I can regenerate my body.
I stole this TARDIS
and I ran away.
I've been travelling
ever since.
The Master was
one of my oldest friends.
We went very different ways.
Questions?
Loads.
Can we visit...your home?
Another time.
TANNOY: Welcome
to Tranquillity Spa.
Why would you need to defend
a holiday spa
with an ionic membrane?
I'm sure it's nothing
to worry about.
We're not safe out here.