(SEAGULLS CAWING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(BORS SIGHS)
How many days have I been here?
-About three hours.
-(SOFTLY) Three hours?
-Well, nearly.
-Maybe Clara's right.
She keeps telling me I've got
attention deficit, uh...
It's... It's something or other.
-What is your journey?
-(EXHALES)
Oh, you can't come with me, Bors.
I pledged to your service
ever since you saved my life.
I didn't save your life.
You had a splinter.
Where is it you go?
Why must you meditate first?
Someone I know is very sick.
He'll want to see me before...
While there's still time.
An old friend?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Someone I've known a very long time.
If there is danger,
let me ride at your side.
You can't help me.
Not where I'm going.
I have to get myself ready.
I have to be alone.
I have to think.
No more distractions.
As you wish, Sir Doctor.
Ugh! Hang on a minute.
The water.
-The water, sir?
-I don't like it.
I can't meditate properly
without decent water.
We're going to dig a well
right on, uh...
This spot. Very excellent water.
Right here.
-How do you know?
-(SCOFFS)
I'm very good at water.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
This is definitely a good spot
for water.
But this is the 12th place
you've made us dig.
-Well, 12 is my lucky number.
-(CROWD GROANS)
Here! No, here.
Look at this grass.
This is watery grass.
Follow the squelching.
(ROPE CREAKING)
Well, you've all the water you need now
and it's the finest in the land.
Your meditation can begin.
Yes, I suppose it can.
-Except...
-Sir?
Do you know what this well really needs?
-Nothing! It's perfect.
-A visitor's center.
-(SIGHS)
-(RATTLING)
(SPLASHING)
(MUMBLING)
(BLOWING SHARPLY)
I don't want to secrete onto your plan
for the throne room extension,
but we're not quite sure
what you mean by "a sunroof.”
-Look at this coin, you see it?
-I see it.
-Where is it now?
-There.
-No, it isn't.
-Yes, it is. I saw it.
Are you sure?
I'm really a very good magician.
What is it you dread?
Why would I dread anything?
You're always making jokes.
You never sit still.
You're like a man in fear
of days to come.
-I thought you were an idiot.
-I know, I thought that, too.
Good.
I was worried I would have to
break it to you.
(WIND HOWLING OUTSIDE)
Are you sure?
I've been avoiding it.
One last night.
Then I have to go.
-You wish to be alone?
-I have to prepare myself.
Why? You've never explained.
I did something wrong.
I let somebody down
when I should've been brave enough,
strong enough, to do better.
Tomorrow, I pay the price.
Tonight, I make myself ready.
Goodbye, magician.
You have widened my mind.
You do realize you're still an idiot?
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Good.
I have to be quiet now.
Quiet as the grave.
I do not believe
you are capable of silence.
Oh?
(STUTTERING) Oh, well we'll see
about that, shall we?
We shall, Sir Doctor.
No more distractions. Total focus.
No more distractions.
(YELLING) Bors!
-Are you any good with a broadsword?
-Yes.
(CLINKING)
-Fancy a friendly?
-Enough, magician!
I do not believe that you will meditate.
It is not in your nature.
If this is to be your last night here,
then we shall celebrate.
There shall be revelries.
-But first...
-First?
Tell me your story.
Tell me how you came to this place
and why now,
you're compelled to leave it.
(WIND CONTINUES HOWLING OUTSIDE)
I will not depart this room
until you do so.
-I suppose I do owe you.
-I've served you loyally, Sir Doctor.
Yes.
Yes, you have.
Then begin your tale.
(SIGHS) Well.
A little while ago,
a very long way from here,
I was looking for a bookshop.
Instead,
I found a battlefield.
Story of my life.
I've seen many battlefields.
(GUNFIRE IN BACKGROUND)
But this one will be different.
This one...
(MAN YELLING)
Will be my last.
(RAPID GUNFIRE)