(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Breathe slowly, son.
Well done, that's it.
Well done.
I'm alive.
We are alive, right?
As far as I can tell, yeah.
(GROANS)
Where are we?
On a spaceship.
WOMAN: My spaceship.
Who's that?
She says she's the pilot.
We were in space.
No way.
We were in that warehouse and then,
we were in space.
-Yeah.
-How were we in space?
-I've got no idea.
-And why are we not in space now?
I scooped you.
That was a very sneaky trick of his.
Especially coming out of hyper jump.
And you could've been killed.
Listen, I keep telling you,
we haven't got a clue
what you're talking about.
Oh, have it your own way.
Where in space are we?
Just off the Final Planet,
which is out of orbit.
Not where it should be.
But I still found it.
What do you mean, "final planet"?
How can a planet be final?
(CHUCKLING) You are
a very funny little bonus.
Where's Yaz and the Doctor?
-Are they here?
-No, I don't know where they are.
I've been trying to get her
to look for them.
I said there was four of us.
And I said I only saw the two of you.
I mean things were moving pretty fast,
speaking of which...
Landing ahead.
Lock yourselves back in.
We're not doing anything,
unless you turn this thing around
and go and look for our friends.
There'd be no point.
If they were still there,
they'd be dead.
They can't be dead.
Don't panic. We'll figure it out.
How? What happened to them?
-(DOCTOR SHOUTING)
-(WHOOSHING)
-(BEEPING)
-MAN: Stop insulting my ship.
-This is one of the best crafts around!
-DOCTOR: I'd hate to see the others!
MAN: I don't need your help.
DOCTOR: Yes you do.
The power's failing
across three sections.
This ship is on the verge
of total shutdown.
How can a planet be in the wrong place?
It should've been back there
where I scooped you up.
We should be
in its gravity belt by now.
-Well, we're not.
-I can see that.
Hi. I can smell burning.
You were right. She is still alive.
Yaz, you need to stay locked
in the medipod.
-Where's Ryan and Graham?
-There! The planet's there.
How can it be there?
Does it even have a name?
Only a symbol. Or a warning.
Closest word is...
Desolation.
Right.
I can do this.
I'm not going to be beaten. Move!
I've still got a few tricks
up my sleeve.
DOCTOR: Manual shield activation?
Wow, this thing should be on
Antiques Roadshow.
Right! Blast shield's up.
Don't know how long
they'll last for though.
Brilliant! We're about to crash-land on
Desolation. Real grounds for optimism.
Do you not understand anything?
I can't even get us there.
Because of the fuel I wasted...
Because of the fuel I've wasted
scooping you up.
I'm on a spaceship. Okay.
I can get us into the atmosphere.
If we jettison the rear section.
Listen to me.
Nobody is jettisoning anything.
This is the Cerebos. All right?
She's the envy of millions.
-Really?
-Yes.
People have written songs about her.
They'll be writing operas
about our pointless deaths
if we don't take drastic action
right now.
We're about to die?
Oh, sorry, Yaz. I forgot you were there.
All gonna be fine.
Five systems down!
Six minutes left on life support.
Are we doing this or what?
Oh, Rekk!
Let's do it.
Last stage anyway.
-Catch.
-Ah!
-And you.
-YASMIN: What's actually happening?
DOCTOR: No need to panic, Yaz.
We're just gonna blow the back
off this spaceship.
-What?
-Jettisoning.
-Do it.
-(RUMBLING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
RYAN: Whoa.
GRAHAM: I couldn't have put it better.
RYAN: Hey!
Where are you going?
I need to survey the atmospheric data.
-We're on an alien planet, Graham.
-Yeah.
Well, the three suns in the sky
are a bit of a giveaway.
Uh-huh.
What do we do?
Should we just follow her?
Yeah.
Maybe they're already here.
Yaz and the Doctor.
Maybe they're safe.
All systems offline.
We're not gonna make it.
Extra hand here.
You can be honest with me.
Are we gonna die?
One day, yes, comes to us all.
But not right now.
Not if I've got anything to do with it.
(MAN GRUNTING)
This ship is old school.
I'm good at old school.
Manual stabilisers.
Pull these two levers up,
they'll pull down and to the left,
pull them up and to the right
as strong as you can.
Got it.
That descent pattern won't work.
We're about to die
and you're still having a go?
Think you could do better?
Yes!
YASMIN: Doctor, these stabiliser
handles don't feel very stable.
By the way, level-3 shield hazing.
What? Seriously?
Power failure.
We're headed into the gravity belt.
Love, whoever you think we are,
we're not, all right?
Are you still pleading ignorance?
Do you guys hear that?
Finskad! How did he even make it?
It's another spaceship.
Another spaceship about to crash-land.
Oh!
Don't just stand there. Run!
It's coming. Run, run, run.
(RYAN GRUNTS)
(WIND HOWLING)
Brace!
(CRASHING)
-RYAN: Doctor.
-Sorry about the mess.
RYAN: Yaz, you're alive!
We thought you were dead.
Right. Quick update.
I made a terrible mistake,
we shouldn't be here.
I'm going to fix it
and get you guys home.
I promise.
-As soon I figure out where we are.
-How are you gonna do that?
Not sure. Treating it as a chance
to surprise myself.
Oh, by the way.
Welcome to what I presume
is your first alien planet.
Don't touch anything.
Come on, let's try this way.
Look at you, Epzo.
So you can't even control your own ship
now? You nearly killed us.
Yeah, well I'll try harder
next time, eh?
-Where's Kornlite and Fythen?
-Failed hyper jump.
Both of them.
It's just you and me left.
You're kidding me.
You have got so lucky.
How did you even make it
this far, Angstrom, eh?
You're nothing.
Still, makes the next bit easy.
(CHUCKLING) You would really love that,
wouldn't you?
But I've got two bonuses. Same as you.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
What's that?
ANGSTROM: Here we go.
DOCTOR: What do you mean, here we go?
Here we go where? To what?
RYAN: Yeah, where are we actually going?
DOCTOR: Come on. Oh, I forgot
I put stuff in these pockets.
GRAHAM: All this sand
is getting in my eyes something rotten.
Want to borrow my shades?
-Oh, ta!
-Like an old pair of mine.
I say mine - can't remember
who I borrowed them off now.
It was either Audrey Hepburn
or Pythagoras.
Eh? Pythagoras never wore shades.
Obviously never saw him with a hangover.
Do you two know what that is?
It's a tent.
(TUTS) Obviously it's a tent.
I meant... Oh, never mind.
Come on. No dawdling.
Losers first.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Be careful.
I don't know what's going on.
Could be dangerous.
Well, probably is dangerous.
Can I ask if we are on an alien planet,
with aliens,
how can we understand them?
Ain't they talking alien?
Let's have a look. Yeah. Medipods
have put implants into each of you.
Standard procedure.
Checks for a universal translator.
Implants one if you don't have one.
Eh? Well, can people and things
stop putting stuff inside me
without my permission!
If I had my TARDIS,
you wouldn't need them.
Anyway, shall we?
DOCTOR: This is lavish for a tent.
I'm the Doctor.
These are my new best friends.
Ryan, Graham, and Yaz. Now...
(BUZZING)
Ah, see. Hologram.
Thought it might be. Good one though.
I love a good hologram.
I was a hologram once.
For three weeks. The gossip I picked up.
What are you?
Projection reality or Al interface?
'Cause if you're interface,
those are excellent nose hairs.
Who are these people?
-Bonuses.
-No.
-What?
-I told you.
Bonuses and snake traps are over.
They were hanging in the star field
when we exited hyper.
Are you saying
we scooped them for nothing?
Yes.
I sacrificed my ship.
Yeah, sorry, some of this is my fault.
Hi, we were loads of solar systems away,
I was trying to find my own ship,
I got a fix on it here,
and then it all went
quite badly wrong actually.
These three have been very good
not going on about it.
Very grateful you came along.
Can I ask what is actually
going on here?
-'Cause I'm confused. Are you confused?
-Pretty confused.
-Proper confused.
-I'm way beyond confused.
You are intruding on the final stage
of the last ever
Rally Of The Twelve Galaxies.
What, like, a race?
Like Paris-Dhakar in space?
Are you two space-racing each other?
We are the finalists.
Four thousand entered. Two are left.
Only one will claim the prize.
-What's the prize?
-For the final ever race,
three point two trillion krin.
-Three point two trillion what?
-Krin.
How much is a krin?
-Two hundred kavlons.
-Ninety forvelars.
-No.
-Four thousand trynties.
-Oh, in old money.
-I'm a bit behind on my exchange rates,
Enough to provide a lifetime
of comfort on a safe world
for the winning pilot
and their entire clan.
-Are we eligible too?
-No.
You're irrelevant. Get on with it.
Tell us the task.
Final challenge
is to cross the terrain,
survive the planet.
Make your way to the other side
of the mountains,
and the first one
to get to the site marked
as the Ghost Monument
will be crowned the winner.
And transported off this planet.
The loser will not.
You can't leave one of us here.
The ships are out of fuel.
Don't tell me what I can and cannot do
with my own race.
You knew the risks when you joined.
Biggest ever prize. Biggest ever risk.
Wait. Hang on. What about us?
Shut up. You're not part of this.
Excuse me. We are human beings.
Show a bit of solidarity.
I'm Muxteran, she's Albarian.
Never even heard of Moomanbeans.
Beings. Human beings. Earth.
-No.
-Pretty cruel race.
Leaving the loser stranded.
The Rally is a test of survival.
How far will we go?
How will we react when challenged?
It's the ultimate test.
Interesting use of the word "we".
Seeing as though you're not here.
Projected in from a very long way away.
I started the Rally.
I competed, and I won.
And now I'm going to end it.
No sabotage, no injuries,
no killing each other.
Shame.
Instant disqualification applies.
Now take your meds.
Don't travel at night.
And don't drink the water.
In fact, don't even touch the water.
This entire planet has been made cruel.
Made cruel how? And by whom?
This stage must be completed
before one full solo rotation.
You have one single piece of assistance.
Transport. Provided by the water.
Get across the water, through the ruins,
and the site of the Ghost Monument
is on the other side of the mist swamps.
Mist what?
Your route trackers are over there.
Good luck.
I know you prefer to ignore me,
but what is it? This Ghost Monument?
The site was named
by the ancient settlers.
It appears in exactly the same place
every thousand rotations.
I've got my tracker. I'm good to go.
See you for the prize, in.
Finally get to light my Althusian cigar.
Saving it for the win.
What does it look like? This monument?
-What does it matter?
-Look at us.
Four people who barely know each other,
stranded on a planet called Desolation,
no route trackers,
no way off, and judging by
what you've just told us,
very little hope of survival.
I need all the information I can get.
Including, but not limited to,
what this Ghost Monument
actually looks like when it appears.
-That's an old police box.
-Yeah.
Yeah, like the one on Surrey Street.
Only the one in town's green.
This don't make any sense.
It makes sense to me.
Oh, thank you. Thank you so much.
That'll do.
Well, I'm sorry
I can't be of any more help.
I don't think you are.
You're right.
Oh, bye, then.
He was a bit full of himself.
I've got a couple of questions.
A couple? I got a book full.
But shouldn't we keep with up
with those two
before they get too far away?
Yes.
Now I know this is a bit of a shock.
Well, you could say that.
I mean, we have been dumped in space.
We got spaceships
crashing all around us.
Now we are marooned on a planet
that everyone else is racing
to get away from.
All right.
Anyone can focus on the negatives.
Well, what are the positives?
What he called the Ghost Monument,
that's my ship. It's here.
-What, the old police box?
-Didn't look all that.
Its very "all that",
thank you very much.
Don't you see, I got it mostly right.
I tracked my TARDIS here,
but the planet had fallen out of orbit.
We landed
where the planet should've been.
It looks like the engines
are stuck in a loop.
Phasing in and out of time and space.
If we get to it when it phases in,
I should be able to stabilise it,
then I can get you back home
Definitely?
If we get there,
you can get us off this planet alive?
Yaz, I promise. I will keep you alive.
And I will get you back home.
I'm really good in a tight spot.
At least I have been historically.
I'm sure I still am.
If we stick together, if you trust me,
we can get out of this.
Right. Let's get a shift on.
RYAN: Do you think
she's telling the truth?
Do you really think
she can get us off here?
YASMIN: She saved Karl.
She got the better of Tim Shaw.
And she did jump a crane.
Don't know what would've happened
if she hadn't have been there.
Yaz is right.
I mean, she's our best hope,
or only option
depending on your politics.
Guess so.
Don't argue with the wisdom
of Graham, eh?
So we're sticking with Graham, are we,
and not Granddad?
Yes, Graham.
EPZO: I said, stay away from the boat.
ANGSTROM: You don't get this
to yourself.
This blaster says I do.
Put the blaster down.
We all know you're not gonna use it.
No injuring, no killing, no sabotage.
Isn't that what What-his-face said?
Yeah, well,
maybe I don't play by the rules.
Did you practise
those lines in the mirror?
-See this?
-(GASPS)
-Nice move.
-Thanks.
Venusian Aikido.
Grand Master Pacifist.
Temporarily paralyses,
while also being fundamentally harmless.
Very clever, those Venusian nuns.
Shall I let go?
(GASPING AND COUGHING)
ANGSTROM: And this boat doesn't work.
-Oh, me and Ryan will take a look.
-Will we?
Well, those NVQ classes
must be good for something.
-An engine's an engine.
-Not a space engine.
You don't get to take charge here.
This is about me
and her fighting to win.
We're all going to the same place and
that boat is big enough for all of us.
Yaz is right. If we get it started,
we all get onboard.
Yeah, I know what this is.
You are all part of Ilin's game.
Saboteurs. Sent to throw us off.
You think the whole universe
is out to get you.
How's your family, Angstrom?
So that's why he said
don't touch the water.
Flesh eating microbes.
Millions of them living in there.
Toxic atmosphere. Killer water.
Very dangerous planet, Yaz.
You were right.
Not like any engine I've ever seen.
We ever gonna talk about your nan?
I mean, just because all this
is going on,
don't mean to say it didn't happen.
See, I cope myself
by asking the question "If Grace
was here what would she say?"
What do you reckon?
Well, right now she'd be going,
"What's the matter with you?
"You're on another planet.
How cool is that?"
-Yeah.
And it is. Right?
-I'm gonna look out for you, son.
-I'm not a kid.
Well, okay.
Well, I was hoping you'd say,
"I'm gonna look out for you, too".
-You talk about this stuff way too much.
-Mmm-hmm.
And you don't talk about it enough.
That's not an engine.
That's more like a massive battery.
-What if it's solar?
-Look at you boys.
Light years from home.
Figuring things out.
Yep, three suns in the sky.
Tri-solar engineering panels
on the outside powering that battery.
Well, if it won't start,
maybe the panels aren't lined up.
Or maybe they're not feeding
the battery properly.
Loving your work, boys.
Let's take a look.
I've never seen so much water.
You're Albarian, he said?
Yes, the planet of Albar.
It's tiny.
Crammed full of rusting high-rises.
Everyone wants to leave
any way they can. Even more so since...
Since what?
I don't know you.
Up and running. All aboard.
Hey, Yaz, can you believe it?
Alien planet, man.
I know.
This planet doesn't make any sense.
No other life forms except us
and the microbes in the water.
No people, no animals,
no insects, no nothing.
But he talked about the old settlements.
What happened here?
No one cares.
ANGSTROM: Don't take him personally.
He treats everyone like this.
I don't need other people.
We all need other people, mate.
We're all alone.
That's how we start and end.
And it's the natural state
of all points in between.
Were you born that miserable?
Or did you have to work at it?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You know, when I was four,
my mum told me to climb a tree.
She made me climb until I was too scared
to climb any higher.
Then she told me to jump into her arms.
"Don't worry,"” she said. "I'm your mum.
I'm here for you. I'll catch you."
So I jumped.
And she moved out of the way.
What?
Sorry.
Did you say your mum did this to you?
Smashed into the ground.
Broke this arm. Shattered that ankle.
And she stood over me, and she said,
"Now, you've learned.
"You can never trust anyone
in this life. "
That is messed up.
Best thing she ever did for me.
I loved my mum.
Yeah, she sounds terrific.
Your mum was wrong.
We're stronger together.
I see your mate's dropped off.
It's nice to see him quiet.
Yeah.
He can nap anywhere. Famous for it.
How many stages are there in the rally?
This time? 209 terrains, 94 planets.
We start the race with nothing
and barter our way up.
Is it worth it?
To ensure enough
for my family's safety? Yeah.
Albar is being systematically cleansed.
Half my family are in hiding.
The others are on the run.
This is my only chance
to bring us back together.
So you left your family to do this?
I left my family
to try and save my family.
They told me to.
If I win, I find them.
Rescue them.
If they're alive to be rescued.
And whatever happens here,
it's a better chance
than I have back home.
You're making me miss my family.
That's quite some achievement.
Considering my dad drives me bananas,
and my sister's trying to get me
to move out so she can have my bedroom.
And I only saw them yesterday.
Don't ever take them for granted.
Oh, you all look shattered.
You should all rest.
I'll wake you when we get there.
Ryan.
Ryan. Wake up, son.
I'm awake. I'm awake.
Are we home?
No. Time to get off the boat. Come on.
ANGSTROM: Have you seen yourself, Epzo?
I'd say you love that cigar
more than you've loved any person.
Have you any idea how rare
and expensive these are?
Takes half an Althusian lifetime
to make just one of these.
To make them, roll them,
age them, and then,
and this is the best bit,
they make them self-lighting.
Just one click of the finger
and it lights itself.
You want a sniff?
Closest you'll ever get to victory.
It's bad for your health.
ANGSTROM: Big set of ruins.
DOCTOR: Wonder who those were built for.
EPZO: Why do you even care?
Where are those people now?
And why are there so few signs of life?
What happened to everyone?
Bye.
Good luck.
EPZO: You're already lost, Angstrom.
GRAHAM: What, we're just
letting them go, are we?
How do we know what to do? Where to go?
First thing we have to do is make it
through those ruins safely.
Because these readings are all over
the place and I don't know why.
(PANTING)
(MECHANICAL BUZZING)
(BEEPING)
DOCTOR: Those suns are starting to set.
They're moving
way faster than I realised.
Well, back in the tent that bloke Ilin
said, "Do not travel by night."
We need to move. Fast.
GRAHAM: Whoa! They weren't there
when we came in.
RYAN: Where did they come from?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
YASMIN: Oh, my God! Doctor!
So much for no life forms
on this planet.
They're not alive. They're robot guards.
Why would you need robot guards
on a deserted planet?
Good news is they're not fully active.
So what we all need to do is
very slowly, totally unthreateningly,
back out of here.
-(WEAPON FIRING)
-(GRUNTS)
DOCTOR: They've been activated. Run!
GRAHAM: Move, move, everyone. Come on.
DOCTOR: Ahhh... Ha...
Don't run straight.
They're predicting your path.
Move! In here.
Well done, all of you. Nice running.
(GASPS) Oh! Okay. Come on.
Oh! What have we here?
YASMIN: Have you got
anything there, Doctor?
Information. Oh! That's bad.
They're SniperBots.
We just walked
into the middle of the shooting range.
Everything within the perimeter
is target practice.
Which would explain
all the targets in here.
And looking on the negative side,
they're human-shaped targets.
If that's the way it is,
time to stop messing about.
-What are you doing?
-Fighting back.
No. Guns, never use them.
-They're shooting at us.
-I know.
They're gonna kill us with their guns.
He's got a point, Doc.
-Put the gun down, Ryan.
-What's your better idea?
-Out-think them.
-You can't out-think bullets.
-I've been doing it all my life.
-Uh-uh. Sorry.
Call of Duty, man.
I've trained for this.
(YELLING)
(WEAPON FIRING)
Who's next?
See, that's what I'm talking about.
That's how you deal with things.
Taking out the aliens!
No. No. Where's the reload?
Where's the reload?
(SCREAMING)
(SNIPERBOTS' WEAPONS FIRING)
-Made it worse?
-Just a little bit, yeah.
Now do you see why I don't like guns?
-Don't go on about it.
-I will go on about it. A lot.
-DOCTOR: They're here.
-(WEAPON WHIRRING)
Take cover. Behind the pillars.
YASMIN: You know we're
completely surrounded.
-Yep.
-GRAHAM: With no way out whatsoever.
Here's a lesson.
The answer was on the floor.
You just reached for the wrong thing.
GRAHAM: What're you talking about?
DOCTOR: The best thing about robots is
they're powerful.
Literally packed with power.
Super-powered.
(BEEPING)
(BOOMING)
Okay, now that was impressive.
Thank you. I aim to please.
What exactly did you just do?
Electromagnetic pulse.
Basically fried their systems.
I reckon we've got about five minutes
before they reboot and recover.
See? Brains beat bullets.
Come on.
-(GROANING)
-Epzo. Is that you?
-Oh, my God! What happened?
-(GRUNTING)
-Do you need help?
-Not from you.
DOCTOR: Let's try through here.
EPZO: What just happened?
What do you care?
You don't care about anything.
-Oh, tracker. Thanks.
-How did you even do that?
Did I not mention? I am really smart.
Thank you.
You are very welcome.
Amazing what you can learn
from a SniperBot.
Like where their control commands
emanate from.
Also, maps.
Which leads us...
here.
(WHEEL GRINDING)
I want answers to this planet
and I think they're down there.
You sure about that?
No. Come on.
(EXHALES)
Why is it always ladders ?
See? Second nature now.
No, not really.
Thanks for waiting.
Always.
DOCTOR: These tunnels
run under half of the planet.
Think of the technology,
the civilisation required
to build all that.
Then ask yourselves where are they?
-(EPZO GROANS)
-How's the injury?
It's painful.
I hope it's made you reconsider
your entire philosophy.
No.
GRAHAM: Doctor.
Scorch marks all along the walls.
Not exactly encouraging, is it?
-No.
-Still, best feet forward.
Big locked door.
I love a big locked door.
(ZAPPING, DOOR OPENS)
Ominous.
DOCTOR: What happened in here?
There's another room next door.
-We'll take a look?
-Yeah.
I don't wanna be here.
We're off route. We need to move on.
You went into the ruins
without knowing what was there.
You want to keep going without knowing
why it's bad to travel at night?
Whatever happened here is in the past.
What does it matter to you?
This was a living,
breathing planet once.
With an ecosystem, organic life,
and a population.
There was a catastrophic event here.
And as hard as it is
for you to understand,
you are not the only life form
in this universe.
Some of us feel a duty
to others who might be in trouble.
So fix your wound,
take one of your heroic naps,
and we'll wake you when we leave,
if you're lucky.
Fine.
Now, do me a favour,
give me something that will finally
make sense of this planet.
(EPZO GROANS)
(HISSING)
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
That's more like it.
Angstrom, throw me
that route-mappy thing.
If we sync it,
it shows us
the whole network of tunnels.
Your friend Ilin warned us
not to travel at night.
We could use the tunnels
to keep moving while it's dark,
avoiding whatever's on the surface.
It's better than that, look.
There's the site of the Ghost Monument.
This network could help us
cut a diagonal through the route.
Then bypass
most of the mountain terrain.
We could cover the distance
in half the time.
Well, if you leave now,
you could get there
before Sleeping Beauty.
You could win.
GRAHAM: What was that?
DOCTOR: There's something
through there.
YASMIN: Ryan, have you seen this?
Surveillance footage.
RYAN: Look, they found the hatch.
DOCTOR: Inscriptions on the floor.
What is it?
Some sort of cave painting?
Almost.
Left by the people who worked here.
Can you read it? What does it say?
"We are scientists,
"abducted, tortured, and made to work,
"while our families are held hostage.
"We are forced to find
new ways of destruction.
"Poisons,
"weapons, creatures.
"We gave them our minds,
"and they made us the creators of death.
"This planet has been left scorched
and barren from our work.
"The atmosphere and water are toxic.
"Killing machines and creatures
inhabit every corner.
"We had no choice but to obey...
"...the Stenza.
"We are trying to destroy
all of our work
"before they use it against others."”
There's two words below that.
"They're coming."
That's how it ends.
The Stenza?
That's the thing we stopped
in Sheffield, right?
You know the Stenza too?
My wife died because of them.
Mine, too.
I'm sorry.
They took our planet.
Sent us into hiding.
Cleansed millions of us.
(FAINT CHANTING)
(EERIE WOOSHING AND WHISPERING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
DOCTOR: Epzo!
GRAHAM: Oh, my God.
DOCTOR: Nothing's working on it.
Doc, we've seen them before.
Like all over the planet,
like they were lying dormant.
Lying dormant till night.
Across the whole planet.
Clearing up the wounded.
Doctor, I've found you. The SniperBots
are on their way down after us!
We need to get out of here.
Everybody move fast!
(ELECTRIC WHIRRING)
YASMIN: Why have we stopped?
DOCTOR: Listen...
They've shut down the life-support
systems, depriving us of air.
A man could really
take against those robots.
We need to get out of the tunnels.
It's night.
This exit ladder will take us
up and out to the surface.
What's up there?
Acetylene fields.
Acetylene? Like the gas?
That doesn't sound good.
We're running out of air and options.
So let's go up.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRAHAM GRUNTS)
DOCTOR: You okay?
It's not my favourite thing.
Climbing ladders under pressure.
Can I just say? You are amazing.
Am I?
Think of what you've gone through
to be here.
And you're still going.
I'm proper impressed.
Thanks.
If it helps, focus on facts
about acetylene as you climb.
Did you cover it in NVQ?
I think I might have done, yeah.
Gotta be quick now, Ryan. Sorry.
(EXHALES)
YASMIN: That's some smell.
GRAHAM: What is it, garlic?
RYAN: Wait. Everyone stop.
Look. It's like the ground's moving.
(WHOOSHING)
WHISPERING VOICE:
Finally, a big feast of life...
DOCTOR: Nobody move.
EPZO: Don't let them touch you,
they'll squeeze the life out of you.
Yes, squeeze the life from all of you.
The talk is to distract you.
That's how they were designed
in that laboratory.
You can't save them.
We smell your fear, too.
The strongest of all.
You want fears?
I've got a dozen lifetimes' worth.
A dozen lives? We'll take you first.
You remember any facts, Ryan?
As we climbed?
It's lighter than air?
Yes. It smells like garlic
and lighter than air. That's right.
And one other thing about it.
But we'll all have to dig deep
for that, right?
What are you talking about?
What are you doing?
Shut up, and dig, Epzo.
You lead but you're scared too,
for yourself and for others.
Yeah, well. Who isn't?
Afraid of your own newness.
We see deeper, though, further back.
The Timeless Child.
What did you just say?
She doesn't know.
What are you talking about?
What can you see?
We see what's hidden,
even from yourself.
The outcast abandoned and unknown.
Get out of my head.
Now we crush those fears from you.
Enjoy your feast. Whatever it is.
You know what some people
like after a feast?
-Graham.
-Huh?
Not me. Some people.
EPZO: Do it.
Oh, yeah. A nice cigar.
-DOCTOR: Down!
-(YASMIN SCREAMS)
Third fact -
ignites very easily.
Good old acetylene.
See? Teamwork.
Now, move. Come on.
RYAN: We must be near now.
Says we're close.
There. Your finish line.
EPZO: Ah! We made it.
But where's your ship?
Where's the Ghost Monument?
It's not here.
I don't understand.
It should be here.
We did all this for nothing.
So you got here.
And now I'm going to claim my prize.
What? Your prize?
I saved your life.
You'd be dead without me.
And if I raced you now to that tent,
you'd be dust.
You're a wreck, Epzo.
Who had the cigar, eh?
Me. That was mine.
-The cigar saved us all.
-Seriously?
Don't even think
I'm going to lose to you now.
DOCTOR: Er, can I make a suggestion?
-Dead heat.
-ANGSTROM: Joint first.
Dual winners.
With witnesses.
What? No.
There's never been a joint winner
of the Rally.
-There has now.
-No.
I will declare the final race
null and void.
Ilin, you've made this
a living hell for us.
I promise you that whatever happens,
I will get off this planet.
And if we don't get what
we both fought for,
I will hunt you down,
and ensure that whatever time
you have left
is both short-lived and agonising.
Do we understand each other?
Now,
recognise your equal winners.
Pay the prize or pay the price.
I'm honoured to declare
a unique joint victory.
An equal split.
Now, get us off this rock.
Fine.
-And them.
-No.
ANGSTROM: No!
They're gone?
We're stuck here, are we?
I'm sorry.
I failed you.
I promised you and I let you down.
We can wait, can't we?
Yeah. We've got each other.
No, we'll be dead within one rotation.
Who says so?
We've come this far, haven't we?
Who says we're giving up? Any of us?
Really? Even you, Doc?
No, come on,
we ain't having that, are we?
-Nope.
-No.
(FAINT WHOOSHING)
Can you hear that noise?
Come on, please.
Give us this.
It's all right. It's me.
Stabilise.
Come to Daddy.
I mean Mummy.
I mean, I really need you right now.
(WHOOSHING)
My beautiful Ghost Monument.
Hello you. I've missed you.
Oh!
You've done yourself up!
Very nice.
I've lost my key.
Sorry.
But it's an old police box.
Sort of. Not really.
You expect us all to fit inside there?
-Yep.
-At the same time?
-Wanna try?
-RYAN: Okay.
Oh, word of warning.
I left it in a bit of a mess.
Oh!
You've redecorated.
I really like it.
This is my TARDIS.
Wow.
Yeah.
It was a police box.
It still is on the outside.
How do you fit all this stuff
inside a police box?
Dimensional engineering.
-You can't engineer dimensions.
-Maybe you can't.
-Can I press any of...
-No.
It's a spaceship?
And a times hip.
-Get out.
-Seriously.
This is proper...awesome.
I thought maybe you didn't believe me
that I'd get you home.
I thought you didn't believe yourself
for a second back there.
Who me? No. Never doubted.
Don't know what you mean.
Home then?
You can get us there? Really?
Start believing.
(RUMBLING)
(WHOOSHING)
(GASPS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: 1955, Montgomery, Alabama.
Parks, Rosa Parks.
No way!
RYAN: If she can live here all her life,
a couple of hours ain't gonna kill me.