(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(GUNFIRE)
(GRUNTS)
What's wrong?
Was that a child?
(PANTING)
KANZO: Oi!
You, there! Stop!
Stop running!
It's OK.
Not going to hurt you.
Just don't run.
-Kanzo?
-I'll catch up!
There are clam drones two miles away.
KANZO: I know. I'll be fine.
Just go.
What are you doing out here?
Huh? Did you get lost?
Stay still! Stay absolutely still.
(BEEPING)
I'm just scanning the ground.
I think we've got company.
Do you know what hand mines are?
(GASPS)
Well, in that case, you know you've got
to stand absolutely still, right?
Ever seen a hand mine?
Where?
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
OK.
It's OK.
Everything's going to be f...
(PANTING)
Help me!
Someone, please!
(ELECTRONIC PULSE)
DOCTOR: Your chances of survival
are about one in a thousand,
so here's what you do.
You forget the thousand and
you concentrate on the one.
Pick it up!
I said, pick it up!
(ELECTRONIC PULSE)
DOCTOR: I'm straight ahead of you,
about 50 feet. Can you see me?
The device in your hand is
creating an acoustic corridor,
so that we can talk. Do you understand?
Who are you?
DOCTOR: Oh, I'm just a passer-by.
I was looking for a bookshop.
How do you think I'm doing?
BOY: This isn't a bookshop.
DOCTOR: No, this is a war.
A very old one,
going by the mix of technology.
Which war is this?
I get them all muddled up.
Just "the war."”
Where am I? What planet is this?
I don't understand.
DOCTOR: Oh, well, neither do I.
I try never to understand.
It's called "an open mind."
Now you have got to make a choice.
A choice?
Yes, you have got to decide
that you're going to live.
Survival is just a choice.
Choose it now.
If I move, they'll get me.
I told you, you have
one chance in a thousand,
but one is all you ever need.
What's your name?
Come on. Faith in the future!
Introduce yourself!
Tell me the name of the boy
who isn't going to die today.
Davros.
My name is Davros.
DAVROS: Hello?
Are you still there?
Please, you've got to help me.
You said I could survive,
you said you'd help me!
Help me!
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CHATTER DIES DOWN)
(GROWLING)
We are Colony Sarff.
We bring harm.
Where is the Doctor?
(GROWLING)
(HISSING)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTS) Where is the Doctor?
SHADOW ARCHITECT: Deploy the
under-regiment, across both sectors.
That number of suicide moons
cannot be ignored.
Apparently, we have a security breach.
I won't ask how you got in here.
But I will demand to know your business,
Colony Sarff.
Where is the Doctor?
I've no idea.
He's not our concern,
and he's certainly not your employer's.
The Doctor is required.
SHADOW ARCHITECT: For what?
Colony Sarff,
you need to tell me
what does Davros want with the Doctor?
(HISSES)
(THUNDER)
OHILA: (ECHOING) Welcome, Colony Sarff.
We are the Sisterhood of Karn.
If you do not leave
our world immediately,
we will take your skin.
Where is the Doctor?
OHILA: Where he always is.
Right behind you,
and one step ahead.
Tread carefully when you seek the
Doctor, Colony Sarff,
or he will be the last thing you find.
Davros, creator of the Daleks,
Dark Lord of Skaro...
What of him?
Davros is dying.
Davros is ancient.
He should have been dust centuries ago.
He has a message for the Doctor.
Then you will give it to me.
(HISSING)
(GRUNTING)
OHILA: Your powers mean nothing here.
Give me the message and leave.
Tell the Doctor...
Davros knows.
Davros remembers.
Tell him
he must face Davros one last time.
(THUNDER)
Davros knows.
Davros remembers.
(THUNDER)
Doctor?
What have you done?
DAVROS: Doctor.
Doctor.
(BEEPING)
(FEEBLY) Doctor.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
COLONY SARFF:
You are dreaming, Lord Davros.
DAVROS: No.
I am anticipating.
He cannot be found.
DAVROS: Of course he can.
He has a weakness.
If you seek the Doctor,
first seek his friends.
RYAN: Will I get it back after school?
STUDENTS: Ew!
How will you know which one's yours?
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
Fine then.
Right, now where was I?
Jane Austen.
Amazing writer,
brilliant comic observer,
and strictly amongst ourselves,
a phenomenal kisser.
Miss?
ALISON: Miss?
RYAN: Miss?
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Everybody, turn on their phones.
News websites and Twitter.
-Twitter?
-Hashtag...
...Planes Have Stopped.
REPORTER: Reports of planes
hanging apparently
motionless in the sky...
Footage of passenger jets,
which have seemingly
come to a complete stand-still...
Miss Oswald,
there's a call at the office.
-That would probably be UNIT.
-They say you're needed.
They were going to put me
through to the Prime Minister.
Mr Dunlop, sorry.
I have to take the rest of the day off
owing to a, um, personal crisis.
Yes! Yes, yes, yes, I'm coming!
No, don't send a helicopter.
Think it through.
AMERICAN REPORTER: Attempts
at communications
with pilots, crew, passengers,
all have failed.
Family members have held
candlelight vigils around the world.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
REPORTER: Reports are coming in
from Caracas, Tel Aviv, Beijing.
It seems no corner
of the planet is unaffected.
The planes aren't responding.
No, none of them.
It's radio silence. I've got to go.
Tell the President I'll call him back.
He's not answering
his phone, have you tried?
We don't know enough yet.
He doesn't appreciate gossip.
Gossip?
How many planes?
4,165 aircraft currently airborne.
-That's a lot of passengers.
-That's a lot of fuel.
Oh, dear God. Yes, it is.
OK, so...
What could you do with
4,000 flying bombs?
Ah, well,
439 nuclear power stations
currently active.
What else?
I don't know, um, fault lines.
Earthquake. A tsunami?
Running simulations now.
So, if this is an attack...
What kind of attack advertises?
Why show somebody what you can do?
Why not just do it?
What's actually happened?
What are the pilots saying?
We can't contact them.
The planes haven't stopped,
they're actually frozen.
Like, frozen in time.
Pardon my sci-fi,
but this is beyond any human technology.
OK, so we need the Doctor.
Kate, we can't phone the Doctor
and bleat, he'll go Scottish.
Come on, what have we got,
what do we know?
It's not an attack,
it's not an invasion,
because, well, that doesn't
come with fair warning, so...
Somebody needs our attention.
Somebody who needs to put a gun to our
heads to make us listen. Oh!
KATE: Oh?
MIKE: We've got a message.
The Doctor channel.
Sorry, what?
He never uses it.
I doubt he remembers it even exists.
Then who is it?
MIKE: Decrypting...
-We're getting text through, I think.
-Texting? Definitely not the Doctor.
(BEEPING)
Have you got any more?
Coming.
Today, I shall be talking
to you out of...
-...the square window!
-What the hell was that?
How did she do that?
I dunno, some sort psychic
projection or something.
Oh, great, thanks.
OK, cutting to the chase, not dead.
Back. Big surprise, never mind.
I'm in a lovely little square
In one of your,
I don't know, hot countries,
and there's a light breeze
coming from the east,
and this coffee's
a buzz-monster in my brain
and I'm gonna need eight snipers.
Eight what?
MISSY: Three for each heart
and two for my brain stem.
You'll have to switch me off fast
before I can regenerate.
How fast can you get here?
Oh, I need to arrange
you a flight corridor.
Why do you need snipers?
Because it's the only way
she'll feel safe enough to talk to me.
Shall we say 4007?
(BELL TOLLING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Oh!
(CHUCKLING)
Saucy.
(INAUDIBLE)
Go on then.
How's your boyfriend?
Still tremendously dead, I expect.
Still dead, yeah.
How come you're still alive?
Death is for other people, dear.
Would you like to sit in the shade?
I know how you humans burn.
(BEEPING)
(JET ENGINES ROARING)
Better?
I expect you've tried
to contact him by now.
Well, you should know,
I can't find him either.
No one can.
That happens now and then.
MISSY: Not like this.
It's a confession dial.
A what?
MISSY: In your terms, a will.
The last Will and Testament
of the Time Lord known as the Doctor,
to be delivered, according
to ancient tradition,
to his closest friend
on the eve of his final day.
-(LOUD ZAP)
-Uh-uh!
What are you doing?
You said... I thought...
No, no, no!
It was delivered to me.
-You?
-Of course, it was sent to me.
What have you got to do with it?
You're just...
-I'm just what?
You see that couple over there?
You're the puppy.
Since when do you care about the Doctor?
MISSY: Since always.
Since the Cloister Wars.
Since the night he stole the moon
and the President's wife.
Since he was a little girl.
One of those was a lie.
Can you guess which one?
He's not your friend.
You keep trying to kill him.
He keeps trying to kill me.
It's sort of our texting.
We've been at it for ages.
Oh, it must be love.
Oh, don't be disgusting.
We're Time Lords, not animals!
Try, nano-brain, to rise above
the reproductive frenzy
of your noisy little food chain
and contemplate friendship.
A friendship older
than your civilisation
and infinitely more complex.
So the Doctor is your bezzie mate
and I'm supposed to believe
that you've turned good.
Good?
MAN: Man down!
Don't shoot her. Do not shoot her!
By the ring on his finger,
he was married,
and I think I detected some
baby leakage on his jacket,
so he had a family.
No, I've not turned good.
Nobody fire!
Oh, wow, I'm on a roll.
Thanks for bringing spares.
Stop it. Just stop it.
Don't shoot anybody else!
Oi, you, sweaty one, on your knees,
let's have a goodbye
selfie for your kids.
Missy! Nobody else!
(SIGHS)
Say something nice.
CLARA: No!
I'll kill everyone in this square.
Start with me.
Then what?
Hey? You came here for my help.
Because the Doctor is in danger.
-Make me believe you.
-How?
Release the planes.
The planes are keeping me alive.
I mean, there's, one,
two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight
naughty little snipers ready to kill me.
Yeah. On my command.
Your best friend is in danger,
show me how you care. Make me believe.
(BEEPING)
(JET ENGINES ROARING)
The planes! The planes
are all moving again.
It was only a basic Time Stop,
parlour trick.
I couldn't have done
anything with them anyway.
What does it say?
MISSY: What does what say?
His confession.
It will only open when he's dead.
Then it won't open, will it?
Question. If the Doctor
has one last night to live,
if he is certain he's facing
the end of his life,
where, in all of space and time,
would he go?
Here.
(CHEERING)
Yes, Earth, obviously, but where? When?
The algorithm generates
probabilities based on crisis points,
anomalies, anachronisms, key words.
KATE: Such as?
Blue box, Doctor...
BORS: Magician!
There we go. San Martino, Troy,
multiples for New York,
and three possible versions of Atlantis.
JAC: It's easier than you'd think.
The Doctor makes a lot of noise, and he
loves to make an entrance.
(CHEERING)
Which one is the one? Where is he now?
How is a Time Lord supposed to die?
MISSY: Meditation.
Repentance and acceptance.
Contemplation of the absolute.
Great thanks.
Change the algorithm.
Eliminate the crisis points.
Where is the Doctor making the most
noise, but there isn't any crisis?
(SIGHS) We're looking for a party.
(BEEPING)
There he is.
(PINGING)
"Do not go gentle into that good night."
You go, girl!
(WHOOPING)
Whoo! Mummy, do it again!
Vortex manipulators,
yours is slave to mine.
Cheap and nasty time travel.
Face me, Magician!
Face me!
Oh, you probably want
to throw up, don't you?
Pick a local.
According to you,
this is where the Doctor is.
How do we find him?
How do we know what we're looking for?
Anachronisms.
-The slightest, tiniest...
-(ELECTRIC GUITAR SQUEALING)
-Anachronisms.
-(ELECTRIC GUITAR PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GUITAR SQUEALS)
Dude!
What is that?
You said you wanted an axe fight.
(CHATTER)
Oh, come on,
in a few hundred years
that will be really funny.
It's a slow burner.
BORS: A musical instrument
is not an axe.
Yes, and a daffodil is not a broadsword,
but I still won the last round.
(CROWD CHEERING)
DOCTOR: What do you think of my tank?
Don't worry, it isn't loaded.
I don't like it.
No, neither do I.
I bought it for my fish.
BORS: Your fish?
I may have ordered online.
Oh, come on!
Fish, tank,
honestly, this stuff will be hilarious
in a very few hundred years,
do please stick around.
What's the matter with him?
He's never like this.
MISSY: Oh, you really are new,
aren't you?
Wait, hang on. Did he just hear that?
He doesn't know we're here, does he?
(PLAYING OH, PRETTY WOMAN)
Now, you lot.
I have been here all day,
and it's been a great day!
You've been here for three weeks!
Three weeks?
It must be nearly bedtime.
Well, we've partied.
-(CROWD CHEERING)
-Yes!
I helped you dig a well,
with a first class,
child-friendly visitor's centre.
I've given you some
top notch maths tuition
in a fun, but relevant way.
And I've also introduced the word "dude”
several centuries early.
Let me hear you!
ALL: Dude!
Are you a Renaissance...
DOCTOR: Are you a Medieval...
ALL: Dude!
I am a dragon slaying...
Where are all the young...
ALL: Dudes!
DOCTOR: I like it.
But I've got some sad news
for you, dudes.
Tonight, I'm going to have to leave you.
CROWD: No!
But before I do,
I'd like you to meet
a couple of friends of mine.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(APPLAUSE)
How did you know I was here?
Did you see me?
When do I not see you?
What, one face in all of that crowd?
There was a crowd, too?
Wow, we're doing charm
as well now, are we?
(CHUCKLING) Which one of us dying?
OK.
And we're doing hugging now too.
I can't keep up.
Well, you know what they say.
Hugging is a great way
to hide your face.
OK, look. I guessed a party,
but not like this.
What is this?
This isn't you.
I spent all day yesterday in a bow tie.
The day before in a long scarf.
It's my party and all of me is invited.
(PLAYING GUITAR)
What the hell are you up to, man?
It's the wicked stepmother.
Everyone, hiss.
-(STRUMMING GUITAR)
-(CROWD BOOING)
Apparently you think
you're going to die tomorrow.
Well, I've got some good news
about that.
-Oh, yeah?
-It's still today!
Oh, that's very good.
(CHOKING)
Bors.
Is it a marble again?
Did you swallow one
of the marbles I gave you?
Don't swallow marbles!
(CHOKING)
(SNAKE HISSING)
(CROWD GASPING)
Doctor.
Your friends have led me to you.
You will come.
Says you and whose army?
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(SNAKES HISSING)
Nobody dies here.
Not one person, not one of my
friends, do you understand?
Davros, creator of the Daleks,
Dark Lord of Skaro, is dying.
So I hear.
He would speak with you again
on the last night of his life.
Then you will harm nobody in this place.
Not one person. Are we very, very clear?
(HISSING)
(SNAKES HISSING)
Are you so dangerous, little man?
You want to know how dangerous I am?
Davros sent you.
You know how stupid you are?
(SCOFFS) You came!
(HISSES)
Is that supposed to frighten me?
Snake nest in a dress!
Now, explain politely.
Davros is my archenemy.
Why would I want to talk to him?
Hang on a minute.
Davros is your archenemy now?
-Hush!
-I'll scratch his eye out.
Davros knows.
Davros remembers.
That's yours.
Uh, it was.
Was?
I don't have a screwdriver any more.
Ooh!
Never seen that before.
Doctor, the look on your face.
What is that?
Shame.
You're ashamed.
Doctor?
What have you done?
YOUNG DAVROS:
Please, you've got to help me.
You said I could survive,
you said you'd help me!
Help me!
Is your ship in orbit?
It's a trap.
Prepare yourself for teleport.
Doctor, listen to me.
I know traps. Traps are my flirting.
This is a trap!
I am prepared.
You sent me your confession dial.
You threw yourself a three-week party.
You know what this is!
Yes.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Clara.
(HISSING)
We're coming with him.
Both of us, her and me.
No, no, no, no! Under no circumstances!
-What are you doing now?
-Voting.
We are a democracy.
It is agreed.
No, no, no! I forbid it. No!
No! No!
(BEEPING)
Inform high command. It is located.
The Tardis is located.
DALEX: The Tardis will be procured.
Procure the Tardis. Procure the Tardis.
Procure. Procure.
Davros is the child of war.
A war that wouldn't end,
a thousand years of fighting,
till nobody could remember why.
So, Davros, he created
a new kind of warrior,
one that wouldn't bother
with that question.
A mutant in a tank
that would never, ever stop.
And they never did.
The Daleks.
How scared must you be,
to seal every one of your own kind
inside a tank?
(BEEPING)
Davros made the Daleks.
But who made Davros?
OK, great. Coming out of hyperspace.
So that's where he ended up.
CLARA: What is that?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
A hospital?
(MISSY SINGING)
How long have we been waiting?
Who knows?
It's always the way with hospitals.
You will come.
You will stay.
Fair enough.
Doctor.
You sent Missy your confession dial.
Well, we've known
each other a long time.
She's one of my own people.
My point is, we both saw her
die on Earth, ages ago.
And obviously you knew that wasn't real,
or worse, hoped it wasn't.
Either way, I think you've been lying.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologise. Make it up to me.
There, see, ha!
Now you have to come back.
(HISSING)
Gravity.
I know.
-Gravity?
-Oh, yeah.
You know what's wrong
with the gravity in here?
-No.
-Nothing.
It's perfect.
But this is a space station,
so the gravity should be
artificial, all coppery-smelling
round the edges,
a tiny bit sexy.
But, this feels real, man.
Like a planet.
How can you and the Doctor be friends?
-Why shouldn't we be?
-You spend all your time fighting.
-Exactly.
-(HISSING)
MISSY: You know what this airlock is?
I'll tell you.
-It's pants.
-What do you mean?
I mean that today might be the day.
What day?
The day I kill you.
What are you doing? Are you opening it?
MISSY: Yeah, of course.
Missy, we'll get sucked out!
You and me together, off we go!
Let's make jam!
(ELECTRONIC PULSE)
(BEEPING)
Doctor?
Doctor!
Davros.
DAVROS: I approve of your new face,
Doctor.
So much more like mine.
Colony Sarff, untie our guest's hands.
(COLONY SARFF HISSING)
DAVROS: You may leave us.
You came, then?
Clearly.
Did you suspect a trap?
I still do.
Then why are you here?
Did you miss our conversations?
THE FOURTH DOCTOR: If you had created
a virus in your laboratory...
THE FIFTH DOCTOR:
I'm not here as your prisoner, Davros!
THE SEVENTH DOCTOR: Unimaginable
power, unlimited rice pudding...
THE TENTH DOCTOR:
Everything we saw, everything we lost...
THE SIXTH DOCTOR:
But did you bother to tell anyone
they might be eating
their own relatives?
Yes, yes, OK,
you've made your point.
Have I?
If someone who knew the future
pointed out a child to you
and told you that that child
would grow up totally evil,
to be a ruthless dictator
who would destroy millions of lives,
could you then kill that child?
I get the point.
Do you know why you came, Doctor?
You have a sense of duty.
Of guilt, perhaps.
And certainly of shame.
You flatter me.
A pity.
I intended to accuse.
I believe that
for the ultimate good of the universe
I was right to create the Daleks.
You were very wrong.
DAVROS: This is the argument
we've had since we met.
It ended in the Time War.
It survived the Time War,
but it will end tonight.
That is why you are here.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
It seems your friends
have gone exploring.
It's warm, isn't it?
For deep space, anyway.
CLARA: What are you doing?
MISSY: Treading softly.
Oh, there's a floor?
MISSY: No.
No, there's ground.
This is the ground.
We're on a planet!
And that is not a space station,
that is a building,
and the rest of the planet,
the whole thing, is invisible.
That's ridiculous.
MISSY: Well, yes, of course it is.
I mean, how would you
ever find your glasses,
or the little girls' room and...
What if you kissed an ugly?
Unless, when you're part of
the atmosphere,
you start syncing with the spectrum.
Why would anybody hide a whole planet?
That would rather depend
on the planet, dear.
No!
They've built it again.
They've brought it back.
No! No! No!
What? What is it? Where are we?
Skaro!
You brought me to Skaro!
Where does an old man go to die,
but with his children?
(PANTING)
What's Skaro?
MISSY: The beginning.
Where it all started.
This is the planet of the Daleks.
DALEK: Correct!
Clara!
You cannot help her now, Doctor.
(GRUNTS)
CLARA: The Tardis.
How did she get here?
It has been procured.
Yeah? Yeah, well, if you're
trying to get inside, you can't.
Nothing can enter the Tardis.
The Tardis will not be entered.
The Tardis will be destroyed.
(LAUGHS) Well, good luck,
because she's indestructible.
Did the Doctor tell you that?
'Cause you should never
believe a man about a vehicle.
What are they going to do?
Who can say?
You know what children are like.
MISSY: Daleks, pay attention!
Don't. Just don't.
You know what this is?
This thing you're about to destroy?
I'll tell you.
It's the dog's unmentionables.
And you know all about those, don't you?
This is a Tardis.
Now, with this you can
go anywhere, do anything,
kill anyone.
With this, the Daleks
can be more powerful than ever before.
You just need one thing.
No. Missy, no!
Me!
You need me!
A Time Lady to show you how it works.
With this and with me,
everything can be yours,
and you can burn it all,
forever and ever and ever.
Or would you rather just kill me?
Maximum extermination.
Exterminate!
Please!
(PANTING)
Please, I'm begging you, please!
Please. Please save Clara.
I gave the Daleks life.
I do not control them.
Oh, Clara.
Oh, my Clara.
See how they play with her.
See how they toy! They want her to run.
They need her to run.
Do you feel their need, Doctor?
Their blood is screaming.
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Hunter and prey,
held in the ecstasy of crisis.
Is this not life at its purest?
Exterminate! Exterminate!
(SCREAMS)
(SIGHS)
Why have I ever let you live?
Compassion, Doctor.
It has always been
your greatest indulgence.
Let this be my final victory.
Let me hear you say it, just once.
Compassion is wrong.
Destroy the Tardis!
DALEKS: Destroy! Destroy!
Destroy! Destroy!
YOUNG DAVROS: Help me!
You can't leave me, you promised.
You said I had a chance.
(CLICKING)
Who are you?
I don't get it.
How did you get there?
From the future.
Are you going to save me?
I'm going to save my friend,
the only way I can.
Exterminate!
DAVROS: Imagine to hold in your hand
the heartbeat of every Dalek.
Genocide, in a moment.
So many backs with a single knife.
DALEKS: Always Davros!
Are you ready to be a god?