BILL: So...
DOCTOR: So...
What do we do?
Do I have to to sit somewhere?
Are there seat belts? Like...
What? You've done this before.
This isn't your first trip.
Yeah, but it's proper this time.
Oh, that's a mistake.
What is?
BILL: Well, you can't reach the controls
from the seats,
what's the point in that?
Or do you have stretchy arms
like Mr Fantastic?
Oh, I stand. Like this.
You never thought of bringing
the seats a bit closer?
No, not so far, no.
(GASPS) Where's the steering wheel?
Well, you don't steer the TARDIS,
you negotiate with it.
Still point between where you want to go
and where you need to be.
That's where she takes you.
How much did it cost?
DOCTOR: Ah.
No idea.
Stole it.
-Seriously?
-Yeah.
(CHUCKLES) Why?
Well, actually, because I felt like it.
Oh, what if I steal it from you?
On you go, then.
(LAUGHS) Well,
I don't know how it works.
Oh, neither did I.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Who's that?
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
(WHISPERS) Mum.
-(CLEARS THROAT)
-NARDOLE: Excuse me.
Just what is the TARDIS doing down here?
I'm over 2,000 years old.
I don't always want to take the stairs.
Your oath, sir.
You're not supposed to go off-world
unless it's an emergency.
-I'm not off-world.
-Are you going off-world?
I'm going back to my office.
Could you put the kettle on, please?
Mmm.
Why's she here?
DOCTOR: Because she isn't
anywhere else.
Kettle.
(NARDOLE GRUMBLES)
I'm not making any for her.
She can make her own.
Not a slave for a human,
I can assure you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
So...
Back up to your office
for a cuppa, then?
Between here and my office,
before the kettle boils,
is everything that ever happened
or ever will.
-Make your choice.
-What choice?
Past or future.
Future.
(BEEPING)
Why?
Why do you think?
I want to see if it's happy.
(WHOOSHING)
GOODTHING: (ON INTERCOM)
Kezzia, where are you?
Hey, Goodthing. I'm coming back in.
GOODTHING: Kezzia,
don't come in just yet.
KEZZIA: I've been out
since second sunrise.
I'm hungry.
Round them up, big fella.
GOODTHING: Kezzia, please don't come in.
We're having a little tiny vard problem.
Me and my vardies have just pollinated
three miles of wheat.
GOODTHING: You've got to keep smiling.
KEZZIA: Got to what?
It's the vardies.
God, what's wrong with you?
Is that smile supposed to look real?
It's like you're standing
in a wind tunnel.
Hey, big smiles now.
Brace yourself.
Mum is dead.
Sorry?
Smile, smile, smile.
That's not even funny.
No, it's not a joke.
Mum is dead. Mum is dead.
And Hopeful, she's dead, too.
And her friend, Sunshine, she's dead.
And Eliza
and quite a few other people are dead.
KEZZIA: Why are you saying this?
You can't say things like that
grinning like an idiot.
GOODTHING: Smile, really. Try.
If you don't... (PANTING)
I shouldn't have told you. Please smile.
(BEEPS)
(FAKE LAUGHTER) You're on two tears now.
KEZZIA: Is it hugging me?
(VARDIES DRILLING)
Who programmed that?
GOODTHING: Please, give her a moment.
She'll be happy in a moment. (CHUCKLES)
-Kezzia!
-(KEZZIA SCREAMING)
No, look.
(SHUDDERING) I'm smiling.
(GASPS) Smiling!
(GOODTHING SCREAMING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
BILL: Which way is Earth?
DOCTOR: Ah, space is bent.
Earth is any way you choose to look.
Why? You're thinking about leaving?
Thinking? I'm not thinking.
My brain's overloading.
-Why a phone box?
-DOCTOR: I told you.
BILL: Yeah, well,
I get it's a cloaking device.
But why keep it that shape?
Why do you like it?
DOCTOR: Who said I like it?
BILL: You kept it.
DOCTOR: Come along.
This is one
of the Earth's first colonies.
They say the settlers have cracked
the secret of human happiness.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
BILL: One question.
Little fella said you made an oath?
You're not supposed to leave the planet.
DOCTOR: Okay, I suppose
I owe you an explanation.
(CLEARS THROAT)
A long time ago, a thing happened.
As a result of the thing,
I made a promise.
As a result of the promise,
I have to stay on Earth.
Guarding a vault?
Guarding a vault.
BILL: Well, you're not guarding
the vault right now.
Yes, I am. I have a time machine.
I can be back before we left.
But what if you get lost,
or stuck or something?
I've thought about that.
And?
Well, it would be a worry,
so best not to dwell on it.
Look at this building, look at it.
You know what I really like
about humanity?
-It's optimism.
-(BUZZING)
Do you know
what this building is made of?
Pure, soaring optimism.
What're they?
Alien birds?
Vardies.
Tiny robots.
Work in flocks.
They're versatile, hardworking.
Good at learning skills.
The worker bees
of the third industrial revolution.
Probably just checking us out
for security.
These are robots?
These are disappointing robots.
That's a very offensive remark.
Don't make personal remarks like that.
Er, you can't offend the machine.
DOCTOR: Typical, wet-brained
chauvinism.
-(BEEPING, STATIC)
-Oh, what just happened?
DOCTOR: Your ear's on fire.
Argh, your voice just came out
in my ear.
I mean, I know voices go into ears,
but this is like...
We have been fitted
with some kind of communication device.
It is using our own nervous system
as hardware.
We've just downloaded an upgrade
for our ears.
BILL: I'll never lose my phone again.
I'll never run out of battery again!
Welcome to paradise.
Hang on, is there a mute button though?
Like, what if we're in the loo?
Who needs loos?
There's probably an app for that.
So, where is everyone?
Don't tell me
we've come halfway across the universe
and they've all gone out.
Should have texted first or something.
-(WHIRRING)
-(GASPS)
BILL: What's that?
That is a robot.
That is not a disappointing robot.
DOCTOR: Technically,
this isn't a robot at all.
The tiny little things,
those are the robots.
This is the interface for them.
Does it speak?
Will we understand it?
DOCTOR: Well, depends upon
what aspect of your language
has survived
over so many thousands of years.
Emoji! It speaks emoji!
Of course, it does.
Aw, it's cute.
BILL: What's that?
DOCTOR: Blank patches.
BILL: Oh, yours isn't blank.
It's got a face on the back.
DOCTOR: Yours too.
Interesting.
BILL: It's never on the side
that you're looking at.
What's it doing now? What...
What face is it making?
Mmm, sort of puzzled. Me?
-Same.
-Hmm.
DOCTOR: Do you know what I think?
I think that this is some kind
of a mood indicator.
BILL: But you're never allowed
to see your own mood?
-Makes sense.
-Does it?
Well, seeing your own mood
might affect your own mood.
It's like a feedback loop,
interfering with
the information being collected.
Like a scale weighing itself.
Well, who's collecting the data?
It's the big question.
BILL: So, what do we do, then?
Well, if they're badges, then...
(BEEPS)
What? Where's...
-Where's it gone?
-BILL: Oh, it's on your back.
DOCTOR: Oh, yours too.
So, everyone you walk past
can see what you're thinking.
What if you really fancy someone?
Well, I suppose it means that you have
to maintain eye contact with them.
Oh, that's brilliant.
DOCTOR: Welcome to the future.
Emojis, verbal communications.
We're in the utopia of vacuous teens.
(EMOJIBOT ARMS WHIRRING)
BILL: Look at this!
It knew I was starving.
Food from another planet.
What? You gotta have it in.
(SNIFFS) Smells like fish.
I'm not that fond of fish.
Except socially,
which can complicate a meal like this.
Should we eat though?
I mean, what if they're not like us?
Well, the cutlery is human cutlery.
No other species
in the universe uses emojis.
Everything here is human.
Except...
No humans.
This is a perfect colony for humans, so,
where are all the colonists?
That's some sort of flavoured algae.
I haven't seen any livestock yet.
BILL: That's good, isn't it?
In the future, we don't eat
living things, we eat algae.
I met an emperor made of algae once.
He fancied me.
Why aren't you loving this?
Everything is here.
Everything is ready,
but there's no one here.
It's like the student union
first thing,
before the actual students arrive.
Two portions though.
DOCTOR: Well,
that's because that one is mine.
That's it.
That it! Of course!
The whole place is waiting.
We're just too early.
BILL: So, who's still in bed?
Two portions. One portion.
Is there going to be food sexism
even in the future?
Is this bloke utopia?
It's probably reading me as two people.
The heartbeats.
If you're going to travel
20 light years,
you're going to want to make sure
that you've got somewhere
to sleep at the end of it, aren't you?
So, what do you do?
Sorry. Two hearts?
You send a rocket load
of intelligent robots up ahead of you.
They build you a place to live,
so that when you arrive,
it's all waiting.
This is brilliant!
(STUTTERING) You've got two hearts.
Robots, they don't breathe.
They can fix the atmosphere for you,
send data back.
So, you know whether
to bring your waterproofs or not.
Working, huge robot flocks.
You just send them up ahead
and you leave them to it.
Yeah, hearts though, why two?
Oh, why one?
Does that mean
you've got really high blood pressure?
Really high.
BILL: So, since people aren't here yet.
What do we do?
Put a kettle on?
Or are we going to leave
before they arrive?
Is that what you're worried about?
I can see you're worried.
DOCTOR: Well, you never know
what's around the next corner.
Ah, of course.
Wheat fields outside,
now there's something else to eat
when they get here.
This is their crops.
Look, they're going to have orchards,
olive groves.
This is their nursery.
Look, little robots
are doing pollination work.
Oh, this plant!
There's one of these growing outside
the student union.
It smells amazing.
DOCTOR: Rosemary.
I'm smelling home.
Twenty light years from home.
(GIGGLES)
Thanks for bringing me.
This is a great day out.
I mean, come on,
admit it, you love it.
Did I say I didn't love it?
Yes, I do, it's very... Lovable.
You asked me where all the people were.
I theorised that
they hadn't got here yet.
Did I sound convincing?
-Yeah.
-And did I convince myself?
BILL: No.
DOCTOR: No.
No, and I'll tell you why,
because there should be somebody here.
There should be some kind of a...
A set up team.
A skeleton crew.
You're thinking.
Tell me what you're thinking about.
A magic haddock.
Obviously.
What is this stuff? Is it snow?
This is fertiliser.
Mineral fertiliser.
Calcium based. Now.
We don't have answers,
so let's put together two questions.
What is the source of this
mineral fertiliser?
(HISSING)
Where are all the people?
Ugh! (GASPS)
Here.
Right here.
In this garden.
Oh, my God.
(SCREAMING)
DOCTOR: Despite appearances,
they haven't been dead very long.
What? Those are the colonists?
The colonists aren't here yet.
This is the set up team.
The skeleton crew.
Well, why did the robots feed them
to the garden?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
Maybe they ran out of fertiliser.
Let's not ask them.
(MECHANICAL WARBLING)
-DOCTOR: Hello.
-(STAMMERS)
-Er, we were just admiring your garden.
-Yes!
We'll be gone now because there's
nothing of particular interest here.
Cheerio!
If he's chasing us,
he's moving very slowly.
Do you know what it means
if something chases you very slowly?
-What?
-It means,
there's a reason
that they don't have to run.
(GASPS)
Okay, they're slow
but the city's full of 'em.
So they catch you in the end.
And what do we do?
The question. We've been here for ages.
Why are they taking us now?
Does it matter?
Only if we want to live.
Smile for me.
Smile?
Use your whole face. Right now. Do it.
Er, what good's smiling?
Smiles aren't just smiles.
Psychologically, they have
a measurable effect on your mood states.
Yes!
These robots, they built this place,
they grew those trees.
Something went wrong, but they were
designed to make you happy.
How would massacring hundreds of people
make me happy?
"How would massacring hundreds of people
make me happy?” Smiley face.
Smiley face.
Magic haddock.
What magic haddock?
What's that all about?
The robots want you to be happy
but they got the wrong end of the stick.
I think we should give them
what they want.
(SIGHS)
Don't even try without smiling.
What a lovely place you have here!
Thank you so much for your hospitality.
We will come again. (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Doctor, I... I was thinking, maybe
next time we might go to Wiltshire,
perhaps. (CHUCKLES)
Or Aberdeen.
Ah, yes. Two thumbs up
for Wiltshire/Aberdeen.
(GASPS)
-Doctor!
-Smile!
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
(GASPING)
(BUZZING)
BILL: Where did they come from?
DOCTOR: Once we're out of the city,
we should be safe.
BILL: Are they coming after us?
I'm guessing that once we're out,
we're not their problem.
(PANTING)
Right. You'll be perfectly safe
in the TARDIS.
She'll look after you till I get back.
Where are you going?
There's a giant smiley abattoir
over there.
And I'm having this
really childish impulse to blow it up!
Be right back.
What, you're going back in?
We've only just escaped.
I thought we were going home.
Home?
Why would we be going home?
That place is a living death trap.
We can't just leave it
with its mouth wide open.
But they're all dead.
We saw them, it's too late.
We have to assume
that there is a colony ship on the way.
What do you think is gonna happen
when all those people arrive?
They're expecting
the new Garden of Eden.
What they are not expecting
is to be the fertiliser.
There's broadband in there.
Go and watch some movies or something.
Well, I get that
someone has to do something,
but why is it you?
Can't you phone the police?
Isn't there a helpline or something?
And stay away from my browser history!
(SIGHS)
A penguin with his arse on fire.
Huh.
(BEEPING)
Ah.
-(BEEPS)
-Good morning.
I'm happy.
Good morning. Look at me. I'm...
I'm happy, happy, happy, happy...
What a lovely, beautiful morning.
It makes me so happy.
I'm happy,
I hope that you are happy too.
See?
Happy.
(BEEPS)
(STAMP BEEPS)
-(BEEPS)
-Hello, is someone there?
I can hear you breathing.
Why are you Scottish?
I'm not Scottish. I'm just cross.
BILL: Is there a Scotland in space?
They are all over the place.
Demanding independence from every planet
that they land on.
Why are you here?
Because I figured out why you keep
your box as a phone box.
I told you, it's stuck.
"Advice and assistance
obtainable immediately."
-You like that.
-No, I don't.
See, this is the point.
You don't call the helpline
because you are the helpline.
Don't sentimentalise me.
I don't just fly around
helping people out.
What are you doing right now?
I happened to be passing by
so I'm mucking in.
You never passed by in your life.
You couldn't even leave me
serving chips.
So, I'm not gonna leave you.
Look at the wall.
-The wall?
-Closely.
Before, when the vardi, the little
microbots, were going to attack you,
you asked me where they came from.
Well, they didn't come from anywhere.
They were here all the time.
BILL: (STUTTERS) In the wall?
DOCTOR: No. Not in the wall.
They're not in the wall.
They are the wall.
-They're all the walls.
-(BUZZING)
These little robots
didn't build this place.
They became it.
They can be a part of a wall
one minute, flying around the next.
This whole structure is built
from interlocking microbots.
(BUZZING STOPS)
Smile. You're in the belly of the beast.
So what do we do?
Well, the obvious. We find a real wall.
Oh, you really are smiling, aren't you?
(CHUCKLES) Do you know why?
You're an awesome tutor.
When the Vikings invaded, they used to
pull the longboats out of the water,
turn them upside down
and live in them as houses
until they pillaged and looted enough
to build new ones.
So?
You didn't see
a spaceship outside, did you?
When the settlers first landed,
they must have lived in it
and built out from it,
so it's still here.
Somewhere inside this building.
Ah...
Bits of meteor damage.
Flakes of rust. Rivets.
Oh, I love rivets.
A wall. A real, honest wall. Not made of
tiny robots but made of any old iron.
Every spacecraft needs... A door!
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPS)
Not even locked.
(DOOR WHOOSHING)
They were expecting to live in peace.
Wicked.
We'll lock it after us, shall we?
(POWERING UP)
(ENGINES HUMMING)
It's life support systems
are starting up.
It knows we're here.
Whoever did
the interior decoration in here
needs to take lessons
from whoever did the out there.
Ah. This was built by humans.
That was built by vardi.
Wet brains, dry brains.
Ah...
(CHUCKLES)
Good old, universally-compatible
incorruptible maps.
You are here.
This is the engine room.
That's the target.
That's where I'm going.
-Where am I going?
-You are staying here.
And you will be guiding me to here
using this map.
I'll hear you through the thingamabob.
BILL: I'm on a spaceship.
Like, for real.
A proper one.
-DOCTOR: Left or right?
-Oh! Er...
Right.
Well, they were certainly planning
to make themselves at home here.
They brought
all their favourite knick-knacks.
Er, there should be a door
that leads on to a corridor.
-(CHUCKLES) I really am on a spaceship.
-DOCTOR: Yes...
Which we are about to blow up.
How are you allowed to do that?
Like, how are you allowed to blow
something up and not get into trouble.
I mean, blow something up,
get into trouble.
That is a standard sequence.
What do you mean "allowed"?
It's a moral imperative.
This is a murder machine.
Beautiful though.
I mean, the whole place.
Er, you should be able
to see a staircase.
All traps are beautiful.
That's how they work.
-Up or down?
-Down.
What... What's this big bit
in the middle?
There's a big, empty space
in the middle.
The engine is in the middle
of a big, empty space.
What's that for?
-WOMAN: (ON PA) Attention.
-(GASPS)
Attention. Error one systems initiated.
Ship's system's set to respond
to human presence.
It was sleeping. We walked in.
Now it's waking up.
-Er, there should be a ladder.
-Got it.
(GRUNTING)
-(AIR HISSING)
-(ALARM BLARING)
Pitiful.
Fleischman cold fusion engine.
AW I got to do is back the flow
into the calorimeter and run.
(CHUCKLES) It's like
it wants to get blown up.
Hang on, I'm being thick.
I can come with you.
DOCTOR: Took that long
to think of photographing it?
You'd already memorised it, hadn't you?
-Yep.
-Stop trying to keep me out of trouble.
There's no trouble. (GRUNTS)
This is going to be
a stroll in the park.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(BEEPS)
BILL: Doctor, why did people come here?
Did something terrible happen?
I can't hear you.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-(HISSING)
-Oh! Argh!
-This isn't as easy as it looks.
-I've got to know.
The people who came here.
Were they the last people?
Were they our last hope?
DOCTOR: Earth was evacuated.
But there were a number of ships.
I've bumped into a few of them
over the years.
(ENGINE HUMMING LOUDLY)
Right. I've rerouted the flow.
-(RATTLING)
-No. No. No. No. No.
That's not right. Bad noise.
That's not right... No. No! Er...
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
No. When the calorimeter
reaches its peak...
I could do with a hand here!
BILL: Okay. On my way.
(GASPING)
Oh.
Are we there yet?
(ALARM BLARING)
BILL: Doctor,
there's something you need to know.
I'm too busy! (GROANS)
(ALARM BLARING)
Oh!
-(EMOJIBOT WARBLING)
-(DOCTOR STRAINING)
(BOTH GASP)
BILL: Almost with you, Doctor.
You took your time.
When I let this go,
it's gonna spin back.
I want you to hold it tight
while I jam it shut.
(EMOJIBOT CLICKING)
(GRUNTS)
-Doctor? Doctor, can you hear me?
-(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING) Oh, don't worry about me.
I'm having the time of my life
making new friends!
Come on.
(YELLS)
(EMOJIBOT BLARES)
(EXPLODES)
-(GRUNTS)
-(ALARM BLARING)
Get ready to run. Run really fast!
(ALARM BLARING RAPIDLY)
What?
Where did you come from?
Where is everybody?
When you say everybody...
WOMAN: (ON PA) My very good people.
We will soon be beginning
an emergency disembarkation.
Good people,
please prepare for disembarkation.
(PODS ACTIVATING)
We wish you a happy new world.
Doctor?
Pods.
What is it? What's happening?
We can't blow up the city.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
BILL: Why?
Those pods, what's in them?
I got it wrong.
I got it very, very wrong.
The colony ship isn't on the way.
It's right here.
The colonists are all around us.
Cryogenically frozen.
What's in those pods, Bill,
is the surviving population
of Earth.
And I nearly killed all of them.
WOMAN: (ON PA)
Welcome to your new world.
Be happy.
BILL: 7hey're waking up, aren't they?
We must've triggered the process
when we came in.
So what happens now?
Now?
Now they're all gonna leave the ship
and find their friends and family
mulched in the garden.
And did Earth smile about that?
It's going to be the end
of the human race.
Argh. Oh, those pods, eh? (CHUCKLES)
Not much headroom.
Oh. Thought I'd be first up.
Steadfast. I'm at Tech one.
-What day is this?
-The end of the world.
Again? We've only just got here.
Bill, with me.
What's happening?
What's happening is nobody leaves
this ship until I tell you otherwise.
Clear? Nobody leaves.
-Where are we going?
-No idea.
But if I look purposeful,
they'll think I've got a plan.
If they think I've got a plan,
at least they won't try to
think of a plan themselves.
But you don't have a plan?
I don't know how to stop it
happening again.
Because I can't figure out
why it happened last time.
What made them do this?
I think I need to show you something.
WOMAN: (ON PA) Section A-34,
reanimation sequence commencing.
(PODS ACTIVATING)
DOCTOR: Spacecraft landed.
Most of the colonists were
kept in cryogenic suspension.
A few, the ones with skills...
The best ones. The brave ones.
They were woken
to shepherd the little flocks
of vardi robots.
She came here. She was happy.
It was all going well.
Those are the shepherds, aren't they?
And they're all dead.
If we rearrange this data
to reflect the time of death,
what do we get?
(BEEPING)
That's her.
This woman died.
There's no sign of violence.
So you know, she just died
the way that humans do.
Then a few more people died
all at the same time and then
a lot more died just after.
And then the rest.
Dozens.
A virus? A virus that went...
Well, viral?
Grief! Grief!
Grief as plague.
How?
The vardies, well, their job
was to maintain happiness.
At first that meant making sure
there was enough oxygen and water.
That's what the badges
are meant to communicate.
Satisfaction.
A positive mental state.
But the vardi are smart.
They learn.
Try to be good servants.
So they expand the definition
of happiness until...
She dies.
No one had ever died here
before this lady.
The vardies, they've never
heard of grief before.
This place is all about hope
and the future and happiness.
No one ever thought about the opposite.
The vardies didn't know
what to do with it.
They identified grief
as the enemy of happiness
and everyone who was experiencing grief
as a problem,
-as...
-Compost.
And all those dead people,
well, you know, they had friends
and family, too, so...
BILL: Even more compost.
And so on, and so on and so on
and what you get
is a whole, like, a grief tsunami.
And all this took how long?
One morning.
All of these people
were slaughtered in a day.
Slaughtered for their own good.
Because the vardi think different.
Like the magic haddock.
Not bad, not good, just different.
So what will happen when
the new people meet the robots?
BILL: That's the boy.
The first to wake up.
Where did you get this?
I think it's his mother's, don't you?
Yeah, or his nan's.
Well, you'll find her.
When she wakes up in her pod.
I found it in the fruit garden
when we first arrived.
Oh.
I would say that a lot of the colonists
had friends or family
who were working here as shepherds.
When they find out what happened...
They'll be grief-stricken.
And after that?
A massacre.
Okay, where are we going?
What's the opposite of a massacre?
-Okay, what?
-In my experience a lecture.
You brought the vardi here.
Microbots to make your life so easy.
But like every slave class in history,
the vardi are beginning to have
ideas of their own.
They wanted to eliminate unhappiness
but to a robot that meant
eliminating unhappy people.
They gave you monitors, badges,
so they'd know when you were
too unhappy to live.
(BEEPING)
(RATTLING)
-BILL: You need to listen.
- I did listen.
What did I miss?
The vardi have killed our families.
But you need to understand
why that happened.
I don't care why.
DOCTOR: Then you will die, too,
and so will everyone on your ship.
-The vardi are not your enemy.
-They want to kill us.
No, they want to help you.
-Killing you is just the side effect.
-Get out of my way.
You've got guns. You think that'll
help you against the whole living city?
That little boy, where did he go?
My mum was a gardener.
Have you seen her?
(EMOJIBOT GRUNTS)
She's supposed to be here.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
There he is.
Step away from the kid.
They're not armed.
You don't need to do this.
You just need to...
BOY: What's wrong?
What's going on? Where's my mum?
Where's everyone?
-Where's everyone?
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
Hey, hey...
Look, everything's gonna be okay.
Look.
This is your new house. Isn't it lovely?
I want Mummy.
Okay. Smile, smile, smile, smile.
Everything's gonna be fine
if you just keep smiling.
Get away from the kid!
(GUNS COCKING)
-(BOY GROANS)
-(BILL GASPS)
(CRACKLING)
(EMOJIBOT BEEPING RAPIDLY)
-What's that?
-(EMOJIBOT WARBLING)
Rage? Revenge?
It's one robot.
It's not one robot.
Doctor, what do we do?
(ALL GASPING)
Doctor, what's happening?
STEADFAST: Cover fire! Now!
-It's fascinating.
-What's fascinating?
The vardi are identifying as
under attack.
Which means they identify as a species.
They are self-aware. They...
They're alive!
They're going to kill us.
(MAN SCREAMS)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
-What are you doing?
-I really hope this doesn't hurt.
Do you know why I always win at chess?
-Because I have a secret move.
-(GUNS FIRING)
I kick over the board.
Here it comes.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(EXPLOSION)
DOCTOR: Once, long ago
a fisherman caught a magic haddock.
The haddock offered the fisherman
three wishes in return for his life.
The fisherman said,
"I'd like my son to come home
from the war
"and 100 pieces of gold."
The problem is magic haddock,
like robots,
don't think like people.
The fisherman's son came home
from the war in a coffin.
The king sent 100 gold pieces
in recognition of his heroic death.
The fisherman had one wish left.
What do you think he wished for?
Some people say he should've wished
for an infinite series of wishes.
But if your city proves anything,
it is that granting all your wishes
is not a good idea.
-(GRUNTS)
-BILL: It's okay.
It's not gonna hurt you.
Actually, he doesn't even know
who you are.
What happened? What have you done?
In fact, the fisherman wished that
he hadn't wished the first two wishes.
Thus, in a way,
pressed the reset button.
What the hell did you do?
Aren't you listening?
I pressed the reset button.
Every computer has one
and anyone can find it.
Especially if they happen to be
a scary, handsome, genius from space.
I re-initialised the entire
command structure
retaining all programmed abilities
but deleting the supplementary
preference architecture.
He turned it off and on again.
DOCTOR:
I turned it off and on again.
Course, I wiped their memories.
They no longer have the faintest idea
who you are.
And, in fact, they're wondering what
you're doing in their very nice city.
Their city?
Yes.
Their city.
It's made of them.
-It's our city.
-Oh.
-They're our robots.
-They were.
DOCTOR: Welcome to your new world.
Meet the vardi.
They are as of now
the indigenous life form.
You'd best make friends with them
because there's loads of them.
And they're the only ones who know
how anything works.
They killed our people.
Well, look.
They have forgotten about that.
They've forgotten about you.
They've forgotten that you even
made them in the first place.
Now, since they have absolute power
over this city
and since, I'm assuming, you all
don't want to sleep rough tonight,
I have a suggestion for you.
BOTH: Smile.
(CHUCKLES) You can't be serious.
I am serious.
In fact, I'm willing to be a negotiator.
-Are you now?
-Yes.
Watch.
(EMOJIBOT BEEPS)
Hello, I'm the Doctor.
A few hours ago, I made the mistake
of not recognising your status
as an emergent new life-form.
As recompense for my mistake, please
allow me to act as your negotiator
with the migratory conglomerate
known as the human race.
They're looking for a place to stay
and they've got their eye on your city.
(BEEPING)
Would you like me to discuss rent?
(TRILLING)
(CASH REGISTER DINGS)
BILL: So, ls it gonna work?
DOCTOR: That's up to them.
Did you just...
Well, did we just
jump start a new civilisation?
It's a dirty job,
but someone's gotta do it.
Did you do this all the time?
Do what?
Flying around sorting things out like
some kind of
intergalactic policeman? (CHUCKLES)
I don't sort things out.
I'm definitely not a policeman.
Well, you live in a police box.
-(SIGHS) It's a pure coincidence.
-Yeah, of course.
Back at the exact moment we left.
Kettle's boiling, and with
a vote to God,
and everything is exactly as we left it.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
Wasn't snowing when we left.
(GASPS)
Maybe I do need a steering wheel.
-BILL: Where are we?
-London.
And this is
the Thames.
(TRUMPETING)
(BELL TOLLING)
BILL: 7ravel into the past,
there's got to be rules.
If I step on a butterfly,
it could send ripples through time.
-(MAN GRUNTS)
-Yeah!
Regency England. Bit more black
than they show in the movies.
Are there any side effects
to time travel?
Sometimes you see lights under the ice.
-(ICE CRACKS)
-Stay back!
There's something frozen
under the Thames and it's eating people.
Plan, let's get eaten.
(YELLS)
(GROWLS)
MAN: The creature will be fed.
Have you ever killed anyone?