(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(# WOKE UP THIS MORNING
WITH MY MIND STAYED ON FREEDOM)
(SINGING STOPS ABRUPTLY)
Hey, you. You don't go that way.
That way is not for coloreds.
Get off, go around the back
and get on there.
That's your entrance. You know that.
I don't see the need...
for getting off, then back on there,
not when there is folks standing
in the stairwell.
How am I gonna squeeze on there?
If you ain't going
through that back door,
you're getting off my bus.
Sir, let me go.
Please don't do that, sir. Stop!
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
You better not hit me.
Get out that door!
Hey!
Hey, hold on. Stop!
(WHOOSHING)
Nearly.
-YASMIN: Sheffield?
-Almost. Really close.
So, not Sheffield then.
You're doing this deliberately,
aren't you?
Who are you talking to?
If it's me, I haven't touched anything.
I'm talking to the TARDIS.
'Cause this is our ninth attempt.
Fourteenth.
You can't control this thing, can you?
Excuse me? Yes, I can.
Most of the time.
Just sometimes, like now,
it has a mind of its own.
So, where are we, actually?
Earth. United States.
1955, Montgomery, Alabama,
if I'm reading this properly.
New displays.
Still figuring them out.
Elvis. Could we see Elvis?
I think he's in New York this week.
I could give him a call.
You haven't got Elvis's phone number?
Don't ever tell anyone
I lent him a mobile phone.
(BUZZING)
Whoa.
What's that?
Traces of Artron energy?
Should we know what Artron energy is?
It's the same type of energy
that TARDIS runs off.
There really shouldn't be traces
of Artron energy here.
Unless they are ours, which they're not.
And now you want to check it out?
Yeah, I should.
Quick look, but quietly.
History is very delicate.
We stick together.
Real life 1950s.
Time travel's awesome!
RYAN: Excuse me?
Excuse me?
You dropped this.
Get your filthy black hands off my wife.
-Stop it!
-Please, take a step back.
DOCTOR: Are you okay, Ryan?
I was just trying
to give her back her glove.
Is this your boy?
It's my grandson, actually.
-Your what?
-My grandson.
You ain't from around here.
We don't want any trouble.
I don't know how it goes
where you folks are from,
but your boy, he'll be swinging from
a tree with a noose for a neckerchief
if he touches a white woman
in Montgomery.
-What did you just...
-Is there a problem here, Mr Steele?
Step away now, go ahead.
Step away.
-Friends of yours?
-No, sir.
Just on my lunch break,
wondering if I can help out
with any misunderstanding.
I believe your suit
will be ready tomorrow.
The alterations are going
to make it look just right, sir.
Let's go, Lizzie.
-Are you crazy?
-He slapped me.
Do you read the newspapers?
You know what they did
to young Emmett Till.
-We're from out of town.
-So was Emmett Till.
On vacation from the north,
couple of words to...
a white woman in Mississippi,
and the next thing,
they find his body in the river.
You want that to be you?
No.
Did your mother raise you
with no manners?
I will take a "No, ma'am.”
No, ma'am.
-You all together?
-Yes, we're very grateful, Miss...
Mrs Parks. Rosa Parks.
No way.
-You kidding?
-Brilliant!
Rosa Parks?
Lovely to meet you, Rosa Parks. Big fan.
Excuse me?
Big fan of...
Montgomery.
I am... We are just visiting.
Recommend anything for tourists like us?
I recommend you get yourselves
the hell out of Alabama
before you find yourselves in trouble
you can't get out of.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Oh, my God.
Can you believe it? Actual Rosa Parks.
Amazing.
Also a problem.
Registering traces of Artron energy
all around her.
Why is that?
(DEVICE HUMMING)
(BEEPS)
No.
Force shields.
YASMIN:
We were in Rosa Parks class in primary.
Do you remember?
All the Year 4, 5 and 6 classes
were named after inspirational people.
She's the bus woman, right?
-You do remember what she did?
-Yeah.
First black woman to ever drive a bus.
-No, Ryan.
-RYAN: What?
Your nan would have a fit right now.
How could you have been in a class
named after the woman,
and not know who she is?
She's American.
She refused to give up her seat on
a segregated bus to a white passenger.
And got arrested for it.
Her arrest started a boycott
of the buses in Montgomery.
Or rather, will start.
Today is Wednesday, November 30th, 1955.
Tomorrow, Rosa refuses
to give up her seat.
And all this basically kicked off
the US civil rights movement
led by Martin Luther King.
See, I'm not totally ignorant.
I just got confused
by the whole bus thing.
Martin Luther King is a minister here
in Montgomery, right now.
-He and Rosa knew each other?
-Yeah.
Is it me, or has it gone
very quiet in here?
We don't serve Negroes.
Good.
Because I don't eat them.
Or Mexicans.
Is she talking to me?
WAITRESS: You all need to eat
somewhere else.
Come on.
Okay, listen, I can deal with this.
You guys go back to the TARDIS
and be safe.
-While you do what?
-Locate the source
of these energy anomalies.
We're one day out of a tipping point
in earth history,
I don't want anything disrupting that.
It's easy for me here.
It's more dangerous for you.
You can walk away from this.
-Rosa Parks can't.
-Rosa Parks doesn't.
If she can live here all her life,
a couple of hours ain't gonna kill me.
-It ain't gonna kill me, right?
-No.
Not if we look out for each other.
I'm cool with it.
What do you reckon, Mexican lady?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER HUMMING)
Oi, keep that up,
I'LL use you as a pinata.
Epicentre of the Artron region
is 1.2 miles that way.
-Come on.
-Hey, hey.
We will stop somewhere else to eat,
though, won't we?
No time, Graham.
Have you noticed that happens a lot?
I need regular food, that's all.
RYAN: We just got thrown out of a bar
and that's what you're worried about?
GRAHAM: Not just that.
YASMIN: Not sure your stomach"s
compatible with time travel, Graham.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
Can I help you?
There a problem here?
(AMERICAN ACCENT) No problem, ma"am.
No problem at all.
DOCTOR: This is where
the Artron signals converge.
YASMIN: At the bus company.
All roads lead to Rosa Parks.
DOCTOR: Yeah.
Bit of a worry.
Let's have a look around.
GRAHAM: I'm not sure about this.
(HUMMING)
RYAN: There's nothing in here.
YASMIN: Why padlock an empty room?
DOCTOR: Unless it's not empty.
GRAHAM: That wasn't there a second ago.
No kidding.
It was there. We just couldn't see it.
Perception filter.
Why would anybody do that to a suitcase?
Can we open it?
Is the right question.
Is anyone excited?
'Cause I'm really excited.
You won't be if it's a bomb.
Don't kill the vibe, Graham.
RYAN: Whoa. Not very '50s.
DOCTOR: I knew it.
See, now there is a problem.
We are not the only ones in Montgomery
who don't belong here.
Any clues what any of that is?
Information brick.
Multi-intercepting surveillance device.
All a bit knackered though.
Well, why has it been left in here?
(GASPS)
This explains the Artron signals.
This is very bad news.
Secondary charger for a...
(LOUD FIRING)
In here.
(WHISPERING) Stay here.
Oi, Brando. Looking for us?
I'm not armed.
Is that suppose
to make me not shoot you?
Ideally.
So,
temporal displacement weapon.
Horrible things. Can't stand them.
Thank you.
Not a compliment.
Takes a lot of power
to displace things in time.
I think you and I both know
your weapon is pretty much out of juice.
And I've got your spare battery.
You've been leaving traces
of residual Artron energy all over 1955.
What are you, the Artron police?
Maybe you are.
Blue box in the alley, is it a TARDIS?
Might be. What's it to you?
It could be worth a lot.
Nah, not that one.
Second hand, huge mileage.
One careless owner.
Mind you, it's better than
a Vortex Manipulator,
like the one on your wrist.
Cheap and nasty time travel.
So, what do you want with Rosa Parks?
Who?
(SIGHS) Now you're being annoying.
The feeling's mutual.
How long have you been here?
Get out of Montgomery.
You're not the first to say that to us.
If I see any of you again,
I will kill you.
Don't threaten me.
Chop chop, on your way now.
(HUMMING)
(LAUGHS) What are you doing?
Come on, gang.
Are we actually leaving?
Not in a million years.
I'm getting pretty sick
of seeing that sign.
So, how are we gonna do this?
(GROANS)
In you come before anyone sees.
Well, this is fun.
Last time I sneaked into someone's room
by a window was Danny Biswas in Year 10.
You just went right down
in my estimation.
All right!
Danny Biswas? He was punching
well above his weight.
Did you just accidentally
pay me a compliment?
Whatever.
GRAHAM: Why can't we just
stay in the TARDIS?
DOCTOR: Our friend with the temporal
displacement weapon has got eyes on it.
We go in and out of there,
we're gonna run into him again.
And I don't want to, just yet.
-Not until we figure this out.
-This is better?
Smuggling ourselves into crummy motels?
I just need a moment to work this out.
Yeah, like, what do we actually know?
Well, 1955, Montgomery.
One day away from Rosa Parks
refusing to give her seat up on a bus.
Meanwhile, we've got
an out of time impostor,
skulking in the bus works
with a temporal displacement weapon.
I understand "weapon,” but not sure
about "temporal displacement.”
Displaces you through time.
A blast hits you,
you're thrown through time
to wherever the user has set it.
He had it set for the very far future.
That's horrible.
Yes, and it uses Artron molecules.
That, plus his Vortex Manipulator
were presumably what the TARDIS detected
when it brought us here.
So, do we think he is trying
to kill Rosa Parks?
Or use that weapon on her?
He is been here a while.
Set up base at the bus works.
If he wanted to get rid of her,
why has he not done it already?
Besides, the sonic picked up
something else on him,
but I need to go back to make sure.
Right.
What do you remember
about Rosa from school?
Oi, whoa. What are you doing?
That is vandalism.
We'll have to pay for that!
Don't worry. Special pen.
No, pack it in. You ain't Banksy.
Or am I?
Rosa takes the bus
on the first of December, 1955.
What time of day?
Evening. She was coming home from work.
I remember because she said,
people thought she didn't stand
because she was tired from working,
but she wasn't.
Where did she work?
I think it was in a shop,
like a department store.
No, no, wait, earlier she told
that git that slapped Ryan,
"Your suit will be ready tomorrow."
That's it, she did clothes repairs.
She was a seamstress.
I mean, is a seamstress.
Can't get used to being in the past.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
-Bathroom.
-Seriously?
Very seriously.
No, Doc, the wall.
(HUMMING)
Banksy doesn't have one of those.
Or have I?
Oh, Officer. What can I do for you?
Can 1 come in, ma'am?
"Ma'am," I still can't get used to that.
Here we are, darling.
This police officer was
so keen to come in
he didn't feel the need
to introduce himself.
Is there a problem, Officer...
Mason. Montgomery police.
I'd offer you a cup but the refreshment
facilities are very poor.
I'll be leaving a note.
British?
(CHUCKLES) How can you tell?
You've been making folks uneasy.
How have we done that?
You don't happen to know
a couple of mongrels, hmm?
Negro boy. Mexican girl.
I don't recognise anyone
by that description.
They say that Negro
has been going around
picking fights with upstanding citizens.
You appreciate it's a...
It's an offence
to harbour coloreds in a room here.
We're not harbouring anyone who
doesn't have the right to be here.
Mmm-hmm.
MASON: What's your business here
in Montgomery?
We are here to pitch an invention.
Yeah, uh, it's a telephone.
That plays music and it's a camera,
also takes photos.
And it's a calendar.
And it sends letters.
-Sounds ridiculous.
-Yeah...
What's your name, sir?
Steve.
Jobs. Steve Jobs.
You being disrespectful with me,
Mr Jobs?
Steve Jobs would never disrespect
a Montgomery police officer, sir.
You get yourselves gone
as soon as your business is concluded.
Mmm-hmm.
I did not warm to him.
RYAN: I'm sick of this place already.
YASMIN: I know.
To be here just as history
is taking place.
This ain't history here, Yaz.
We're hiding behind bins.
(SIGHS)
I'm having to work so hard to keep
my temper, every second here.
I could have slapped that guy back there
as soon as we arrived.
Thank God, my nan taught me
how to keep my temper.
Never give them the excuse.
Yep.
-My dad tells me the same.
-Yeah, see.
It's not like Rosa Parks wipes out
racism from the world forever.
Otherwise, how come I get stopped way
more by the police than my white mates?
Oi, not this police.
Tell me you don't get hassle.
Of course, I do. Especially on the job.
I get called a Paki
when I'm sorting out a domestic,
or a terrorist on the way home
from the mosque.
Yeah, exactly.
But they don't win, those people.
I can be a police officer now
because people like Rosa Parks
fought those battles for me.
For us.
And in 53 years they'll have
a black president as leader.
Who knows where they'll be
50 years after that?
That's proper change.
(RYAN CHUCKLES)
-What?
-Were you born this positive?
Guess so.
Must be my Mexican blood.
(LAUGHS)
Yaz? Ryan?
(HUMMING)
Where were we? We need
as much intel as we can get.
If we're gonna protect Rosa,
we need to know the facts of her life.
Home address. Daily routine.
Where she works.
The route she takes
and the church she attends.
Also the name of the driver she refused.
I know that. It's James Blake.
How do you know that?
Well, your nan when she found out
I was a bus driver, said to me,
"You better not be like James Blake.
"Blake the snake."
That's what she called him.
And I had to ask her who he was,
and she just said he gave
all bus drivers a bad name.
She said that when you'd only just met?
-Yeah.
-That's pretty hard line.
That's my nan.
Yeah. She had a t-shirt that said,
"Spirit of Rosa."
And well, I wish that she was here.
I don't. She'd start a riot.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Right. Operation Rosa Parks.
YASMIN: I found out where she works.
Montgomery Fair Department store.
And if the phone book's right,
this is where she lives.
Right. So, these bus routes don't go
near Rosa's shop or house,
but these ones do.
Great. If we can find Rosa's route
and time today,
we can keep an eye on her tomorrow.
Who's up for a bus ride?
GRAHAM. Sir, excuse me.
Sorry.
Hey, Doc.
This route is one of three that goes
between Rosa's home and where she works.
I reckon this one's the most direct.
DOCTOR: So it's most likely she takes
this one tomorrow night.
But we can't be certain
exactly what time.
Unless we stalk her all day.
This is me. On the back of the bus.
I'm so ashamed.
You shouldn't have to do this.
I agree. I'm sorry, Ryan.
The driver let me on
at the front of the bus.
What does that mean for where I sit?
Obviously not a lot of
Pakistani heritage around here.
Does coloured just mean black in 19557
(SIGHS)
I guess I'll park
my South Asian Mexican backside
in the white section
and let's see what happens.
Riding the bus in Montgomery.
Good times.
(BELL DINGS)
That's where she works.
This must be her stop.
DOCTOR: Perfect. We can wait here,
then get on the bus with her
when she finishes work.
Have a little chat.
Hi. Nice to see you again.
Mrs Parks, right?
Yes.
You helped us out earlier today
with our little misunderstanding.
I remember. British.
Yes, funny thing.
You'll never believe this.
We're actually doing
market research for bus companies.
Looking at people's transport habits.
Answer the questions,
enter the raffle for a prize.
You get this bus this time every day?
Most days. Always this time.
And you live?
Cleveland Court. Next stop.
Ma'am, if you keep sitting there
we're all going to have to move.
What do you mean?
Well, if white folks need seats,
by law, I have to give mine up.
This middle section's only for coloreds
if white folk don't need it.
Well, that's not right.
Tell that to your company, sir.
If I win your raffle, will that give me
the right to sit anywhere
I want on this bus?
No.
I didn't think so.
This is my stop.
I'm gonna follow her.
See what I can find out.
Meet you back at the motel later.
DOCTOR: Ryan.
Be careful.
Yeah.
Do you think he'll be all right?
I hope so.
Graham, do you think you can find
James Blake, the driver?
Um, yeah, I'll just have a talk
with the bloke at the front
and find out where
they all drink.
Yaz, can you compile a timeline
of what happens,
this time tomorrow evening?
Okay. But what are you gonna do?
Talk to our friend.
Tell him to stay out of history's way.
Stalking Rosa Parks!
Don't know about this.
You better not be following me.
-I wanna help.
-With what?
The fight.
And how do I know you're not a spy
for the police or the FBI?
Because if they were gonna send a spy
they would send one who could actually
follow you without being spotted.
And that didn't have a British accent.
Also, don't think they know
any black guys.
(LAUGHS)
You any good at serving coffee?
(DOGS BARKING)
(HUMMING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GRUNTS)
Oops. Shame.
You just sent all your equipment
to goodness knows where.
79th century
judging by the weapon setting
which, by the way, overheat very easily.
(GRUNTS)
Cheap and nasty. Now we're even.
First things first.
Tell me about Stormcage.
-Storm what?
-Ah, rubbish liar.
On your wrist is a Stormcage identifier.
The most secure prison facility
this side of the universe.
Not in this time zone, of course.
But I guess that's where
the Vortex Manipulator comes in.
It's amazing what you can get
if you're prepared to work
and barter inside that prison.
Escape or release?
I did my time. I'm rehabilitated.
What were you there for
in the first place?
Oh, if I tell you,
it might colour your view of me.
I was young. Nobody got hurt.
Well, a few people got killed.
A few hundred people. Thousand tops.
Two thousand.
And it was nasty enough that Stormcage
placed a neural restrict or in your brain
before releasing you
back into the universe.
How can you know that?
-Who are you?
-Very good scanner, this.
I though I detected it
the first time we met.
And then it started to make sense
because we were wondering...
You've obviously got a problem
with Rosa, why don't you just kill her?
But the answer is, because you can't.
Neural restrict or means you can't kill
or injure any living thing.
It stops you from doing it,
no matter how much you wanna try.
So even if I do this,
smash your Vortex Manipulator...
(GASPING)
Yeah, there it is. Kicking in.
Tied to your brain chemistry.
You can't harm me.
As much as you want to.
Better be nice to me
because I'm your best shot
of getting out of this time zone now.
(GRUNTS)
Neutered criminal on release.
And you come here.
-Why?
-I'm allowed a hobby.
And yours is Rosa Parks?
This is where things
started to go wrong.
And you think you can put them right?
I had a lot of time to think
in Stormcage,
and I realised
tiny actions change the world.
What's your name?
-Krasko.
-Don't like it.
Listen, Krasko,
I will give you one warning.
Go somewhere else.
Find a beach, read a book.
Because you're a criminal
who's lost his kit.
Lost his weapons.
You think that makes a difference?
History changes
when tiny things don't go to plan.
You mean tomorrow.
Won't work.
Not while I'm here.
Well, let's see.
This is Ryan Sinclair.
He's from England.
I'm thinking he might be
a new recruit to our youth council.
I said he could listen in
and serve coffee.
Ah, this is my husband, Parks.
This is Mr Fred Gray.
And this is Dr King
from Dexter Avenue Baptist Church.
What?
-Martin Luther King?
-That's correct.
Oh, my days.
My nan loves you.
Your "nan"?
My gran. Grandma.
The elder ladies do love
your sermons, Martin.
You'll never be short for
a grey-haired wife in Alabama.
She attend Dexter Avenue?
No, she died recently.
I'm sorry for your loss, son.
Thank you.
Thank you, Martin Luther King.
She'd be chuffed to know
that you said that.
-Ryan.
-Excuse me, Dr King.
Yes, Rosa Parks? Whoa.
You want to serve that coffee now?
Yeah.
BLAKE: So you say you're a bus driver
too back in England?
It's a privilege, innit, eh?
Getting people where they want to go.
Being part of the community.
I'm figurin' you ain't got to deal with
keeping coloreds apart from whites.
No. No, we don't do that.
You approve of that, Jim?
Just the way it is.
No matter how much they complain.
Ain't going to change.
Back at it tomorrow, I suppose.
No, going fishing at Mill Creek.
You can't be. It's December the first.
What?
Well, 'cause it's a Thursday, innit?
You know, like a work day.
My rota got changed.
Fella from the depot just came by,
gave me the good news.
Get what you wanted from tonight?
I didn't know what I wanted.
But, yeah.
Meeting you guys. Listening to you
all talk. I can't believe it.
It'll get better, you know.
Not perfect but...
Better.
I hope so.
It's worth the fight.
Thank you.
From me and my nan.
I haven't done anything.
Good night, ma'am.
DOCTOR: Managed to get Krasko's
weapon off him, at least.
(DOOR CLOSES)
James Blake is taking the day off.
-What?
-But he can't.
That's what I said.
Strangely, he didn't listen.
Your mate is interfering.
He has reassigned Blake's route
to a driver called Elias Griffin Junior.
Tiny actions.
That's what Krasko is doing.
See, he's clever. I'll give him that.
He knows.
He is not planning on killing
or destroying or breaking history.
He's planning to nudge it
just enough so that it doesn't happen.
Enough of a stick in the spokes
to throw everything off the rails
and now I'm really mixing
my transport metaphors.
Well, he didn't reckon
with us keeping it in place.
YASMIN: And how do we do that then?
Now we know what our task is.
Keep history in order.
No changing it.
Just guarding it against someone
who wants to disrupt it.
Tomorrow we have to make sure
Rosa Parks gets on the bus
driven by James Blake
and that the bus is full,
so Rosa sits when she is asked
to stand for white passengers.
-(BEEP)
-Ryan, don't mess with that.
How does it even work?
Charger's here, this setting dials
the temporal destination.
Pretty simple, pretty deadly.
Now, can we concentrate?
How are we supposed
to keep history in order
if James Blake is going
to go fishing at Mill Creek
and another driver is lined up
to do his route?
-I've got an idea.
Same idea?
-Raffle winner.
-Fishing takedown.
Elias Griffin Junior?
-Yeah.
-Congratulations.
You are the lucky winner
of our Raffle of the Century.
I don't remembering entering no raffle.
You have won an all expenses paid trip
to Las Vegas.
Front row tickets to see Frank Sinatra
and a VIP pass to meet Frank himself.
My wife loves Sinatra.
Amazing, who would have guessed?
Only one condition,
you have to leave now.
Right now.
Oh, I can't. My work shift starts
in a couple of hours.
We've sorted that too.
Your company has already assigned
someone to cover you.
There's a taxi coming to pick you up
in 30 minutes
to take you to the airport.
-Thirty minutes?
-Unless you don't wanna go.
Oh, we'll be ready. We'll be ready.
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
Good job Elvis lent Frank that mobile
phone against everything I told him.
We need to stick tight to Rosa.
Oi, oi, Jim boy.
How you doing, cockle?
We've been looking for you
all along the creek.
Why?
Well, we thought we'd come and join you.
You saying last night how beautiful
and peaceful it was. Yeah.
This is my grandson, Ryan.
What in the hell?
Yo! Jimmy Blake. What's up, blud?
You can't be here!
Hey, how many have you caught?
Can I pick them up?
Ever seen a man juggle fish?
(SHOUTING) Stay out of my things.
You don't belong here.
And he ain't your grandson.
I reckon we'll be here all day.
Yeah, might as well.
Seeing as that bus sit-in
is kicking off.
-Mmm.
-Gonna be big trouble.
What you say, boy?
Oh, we heard that
a group of black passengers
were planning a sit-in across
all the bus routes tonight.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Not on my bus, they're not.
You gonna get out of my seat?
Out of my seat!
GRAHAM: All right. Settle down.
Have the damn creek.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-He was easy.
-Boom.
Don't do that.
DOCTOR: Mrs Parks,
enormous clothing emergency.
Can you help me?
That is one nasty tear.
Yes, it is.
And there is nothing us Brits hate
more than a clothing emergency.
Mrs Parks, I have to go out
in that coat this evening,
and if it's torn
I'll get in such trouble.
Can you take a look at it now?
Double time Christmas bonus.
Well, I don't have any collections
until tomorrow afternoon.
I guess I could fit you in.
Now, if you come back
just before we close...
I'll wait...while you work.
Keep you company.
-I don't need company.
-No, but my coat does.
It's very valuable.
I don't usually allow it
out of my sight.
Thank you.
You're gonna make a big difference.
Well, I best set to work then.
Don't let her out of your sight.
I'm gonna go meet Graham and Ryan.
Remember, get Rosa out of here
by 5:40, at the latest,
to be on that bus on time.
(TICKING)
BLAKE: I came back
from the creek for this?
Four flat tyres
and a smashed in windshield.
What the hell happened?
-Kids.
-Well, I can't drive that.
Oh, no, you go on home.
We'll cancel the route.
BLAKE: So much for that protest.
This bus ain't going nowhere.
GRAHAM: Did you hear that?
Everything we do,
Krasko's a step ahead.
He must have deliberately smashed up
that bus himself.
RYAN: We've got to fix this.
James Blake has got to drive
Rosa's bus home tonight.
(PANTING)
Right, well,
he ain't giving up that easily.
Well, neither are we.
Ryan, check every bus stop
along Blake's route.
Tell the waiting passengers that the
bus is coming, and they have to wait.
Okay.
Do not let any of the passengers walk.
The bus has to be full.
It has to be crowded enough
so that Rosa is expected to move.
Right, got it. Good luck.
-Now, Graham.
-Mmm-hmm?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
GRAHAM: Nicking and hot-wiring a bus
from right outside the depot?
Hope our friendly cop
don't hear about this.
What in the hell?
This is your replacement bus service.
-Jim boy.
-You again.
I know, I literally get everywhere.
Now, come on. Hop in and do your job.
You're already 18 minutes
behind schedule.
How do you know that? What's going on?
What happened to that damn sit-in?
Nobody else knew anything about it.
Love to explain all that to you
but you know us Brits. Very imperious.
Not prone on explaining ourselves
to anyone.
So no time to chat. Just get driving.
Lot of people need
to get on this bus tonight.
(SIGHS) Driver James Blake
behind the wheel, check.
"Bus services suspended.”
No, no, no. Krasko.
Have you always
wanted to be a seamstress?
No, I dreamed of being a teacher.
But my grandmother got sick,
then my mother,
-so that was the end of school.
-Sorry about that.
Oh, I got myself educated.
Just took longer than I thought.
-But you kept going.
-Always.
An education makes you unstoppable.
Everything here is a fight for you.
Don't you get tired?
What keeps you going?
The promise of tomorrow.
When today isn't working,
tomorrow is what you have.
You married? Got a job back home?
Not married and I'm a police officer.
-You're police?
-Yup. Just starting.
Not where I want to be.
-Mmm. Where is it you want to be?
-In charge.
(LAUGHS) Amen to that.
Shouldn't you be finishing up?
If a job is worth doing,
it is worth doing well.
But don't you have a bus to get?
I can always walk.
Hey, Doc, I don't want to be an alarmist
but this bus seems a bit emptier
than last night.
(SIGHS)
DOCTOR: No, that's bad.
We need the bus to be full.
Come on, Ryan.
Excuse me, excuse me. Old people.
The buses are still running.
We're gonna walk.
The buses are coming, I promise.
Please, just wait for the bus.
You don't tell me what to do, boy.
Oh, man. This place.
Passengers down, white passengers down.
Not good.
-I think that should just about...
-Love it.
Let's go. I'll walk you out.
Pay you on the way.
Ah, I might have known.
Pretty boy blocking the road.
Right then. This is on me.
Mate, move your car so the bus
gets through. Come on, out of the way.
No, you get out of my way.
Just give it up, will you?
Cut your losses.
You're not gonna win tonight.
I already have.
I know what should happen.
And even if it gets past here,
that bus is at least three passengers
short of what it should be by now.
Parks won't be asked to stand,
she won't protest
and your kind
won't get above themselves.
-My "kind"?
-Yeah, your kind.
Stay in your place.
Mate, you're living in the past.
In fact, you like the past that much,
-so why don't you stay there?
-(BEEP)
Oh! Oh, it worked.
Nice one, Ryan. Thanks, Ryan.
Move the car, clear the route,
find the bus,
and Rosa Parks will change the world.
Good, here we go.
DOCTOR: Yaz!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, how's it going?
Mrs Parks fixed your coat.
Oh, thank you, Mrs Parks.
Beautiful work. Much appreciated.
You're welcome, ma'am.
RYAN: Don't shut the door.
Don't drive off! One more coming on.
(PANTING) Found you.
I just got rid of Krasko.
-How??
-TI borrowed this.
I think I dialled the settings
as far back as it can go.
He's gone.
Use the door for coloreds.
Law's a law.
DOCTOR: Let's move back.
GRAHAM: Hey, Doc, Rosa's on board,
Blake's driving, we're good, right?
YASMIN: What's the matter?
What are you doing?
Counting seats.
YASMIN: Has it worked?
Have we done enough?
I don't know.
We get off at the next stop, right?
Empire Theatre, yeah.
Right, come on then. We can go.
Job done. History is safe.
-Well, come on then.
-Doctor?
Don't get off, Graham.
If we get off, there's enough
empty seats for white passengers.
Rosa won't be asked to move.
We have to stay on.
We were here. We're part of the story.
Part of history.
No, no. I don't want to be part of this.
We have to. I'm sorry.
We have to not help her.
I'm gonna need those seats back there.
You all better make it light on
yourselves and let me have those seats.
Stand up now.
I don't think I should have to.
(SHOUTING) Are you going to stand up?
No.
If you don't stand,
I'm gonna have you arrested.
You may do that.
# You're broken down and tired
# Of living life on a merry-go-round
# And you can't find the fighter
# But I see it in you
So we gonna walk it out
# And move mountains
# And I'll rise up
# I'll rise like the day
# I'll rise up
# I'll rise unafraid
# And I'll do it a thousand times again
# And I'll rise up
# High like the waves
# I'll rise up
# In spite of the ache
# And I'll do it a thousand times again
# For you, oh, oh, oh
# For you
# For you #
DOCTOR: On Monday, the boycotts begin.
Across Montgomery
people refuse to use the buses
as a response to Rosa's arrest.
And in just over a year,
on the 21st of December, 1956,
segregation on buses in Montgomery
was ended.
So it all worked out for her.
No, life's still hard for Rosa.
She loses her job, so does her husband.
It's a struggle. They keep fighting.
And in June 1999,
Rosa receives the Congressional Medal
from President Clinton.
The highest award given to any civilian,
recognising her as a living icon
for freedom.
It took so long, though. Her whole life.
Yes, it did.
But she changed the world.
In fact, she changed the universe.
Look at this.
Asteroid 284996.
Also known as Rosaparks.
# And we'll rise up
# Rise like the waves
# We'll rise up
# In spite of the ache
# And we'll do it
A thousand times again
# For you, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
# For you #
We're home!
Who are you?
How do you know my daughter?
WOMAN: Something's happening
with the spiders in this city.
Argh! Argh!