(FAINT GROWLING)
DOCTOR: Great work, guys.
- And sorry again.
- (CREATURE SCREECHES)
I did not know
it was their mating season.
Yes, Graham, my son!
I've got it!
Got what?
The sixth coupon
from the Bandohzi Herald.
Keeps getting delivered
by the coffee machine upstairs.
Or is it downstairs?
Anyway, don't matter.
I noticed they had an offer on.
Collect six coupons,
get a free holiday.
I'm up for a free holiday.
- Where is it?
- A place called Tranquillity.
Me too. So long as
there's plenty of sun
and absolutely
no deep-space squid.
Might get you
out of your mardy mood.
My mood's fine.
- That's you told.
- (WHIRRING)
DOCTOR: Hang on, Graham.
They're not
six perfect squares, are they?
No, don't put them together
yet!
- RYAN: Bit late for that.
- What's happening?
I hope you've packed.
They're not just coupons.
That's a teleport cube -
just activated.
We've got about four seconds.
No, no, no, no. I've got to go
and fetch my Speedos.
Only joking.
Already got 'em on. Ho-ho!
TANNOY:
Welcome to Tranquillity Spa.
Oh, guys! This is a bit
of all right, innit?
Welcome!
O'Brien party of four?
Bandohzi Herald coupons?
I'm Hyph3n with a 3,
your customer host here
at Tranquillity Spa.
And relax!
Hi, Hyph3n with a 3. Nice tail.
I'm a bit worried about
being separated from my ship.
Our system has saved
exactly where you came from.
You can return any time, but
you're booked in for two weeks,
all-inclusive.
Get in!
Your rooms
are just being prepared.
Take a moment to explore
and I'll come and find you
once they're ready.
I'm going to find the pool!
I'm seeing what they've got
inside the building.
And I am going to sit
over there for three hours,
then I'm going to get up
and sit somewhere else,
and then cocktails.
All-inclusive, Doc.
Got to get your coupons' worth.
Get in!
Come on, Graham, son!
I'll have a look round, then.
By myself.
Relax.
Our staff are being informed.
(ALARM BEEPS)
- Another system virus.
- Vorm, I don't care.
We've got a physical breach.
One of them's got in.
Find it, contain it,
and radio in.
Do not engage without me.
Look at that, Vilma.
Can you believe it?
Oh, it's perfect, Benni.
Thank you.
BENNI: I saw some newlyweds
up at reception.
Nice place to come
for a honeymoon.
We've had 46 years.
We never needed to be married.
You say that...
...but...
Wow!
- BENNI: Oh, hello.
- VILMA: Not bad, is it?
It's absolutely gorgeous.
Um...
YAZ: This place
has got everything.
Welcome to Tranquillity's bar
and refreshment zone.
We serve all your favourites,
all-inclusive.
Oh, free stuff!
- (NUMBER PAD BEEPS)
- Ooh
- (FIZZING)
- Ow! Ow!
Fighting with
the vending machine?
No, it just gave me
an electric shock.
That's not a shock.
It's a hopper virus.
This machine's sick,
and it just passed its virus on
to you.
How did I get a virus the same
as a vending machine?
I'm not a machine.
Hoppers are multi-platform.
They'll go for anything.
- Don't pick at it!
- Did it just go through me?
It's moving deeper inside you
to mutate
into your nervous system.
What?
Important not to panic.
Humans always have the same
reaction to a hopper virus.
First you get
the wiggly fingers,
which is a warning
the legs are about to go.
Luckily,
this is where my hopper
first-aid training kicks in.
Need to get rid of these.
Then pinch your ear.
- Then you're going to sneeze.
- Atchoo!
Yes! Now suck your thumb
until the hallucinations stop.
And remember,
they're not real bats.
- (RYAN SQUEALS)
- He's fine.
He's fine.
Make the bats go away!
Hotel perimeter breach.
Initiating guest
protection measures.
It's on the move again, Vorm.
Be careful.
I'm Vilma. Nice to meet you.
This is Benni.
Yaz. Just arrived.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to interrupt.
- Oh, you're all right...
- Well, you were a bit...
All guests, please assemble
at your nearest muster station.
Relax.
This is a routine
Tranquillity drill.
All guests, please assemble
at your nearest muster station.
If this is anything to do
with you, Doc...
Relax.
This is a routine
Tranquillity drill.
Stay here. I'll investigate.
It's probably nothing.
Usually nothing.
I say "usually”...
All guests, please assemble
at your nearest muster station.
The nearest muster station to
this zone is the teleport pad.
Hopper virus got you too?
I'm not sure about this place.
So...
...you here with family?
Hotel critic.
Mm.
You?
Oh, I'm here with my mates,
yeah.
I'm a pilot...surgeon...
pilot...surgeon...
I'm a surgeon for pilots.
So, do you come across
many hopper viruses?
Does this usually work?
- What?
- Pretending to be stupid
so girls have to answer
your questions?
Hey, look, I'm not
trying to chat you up.
Shame.
I'm Bella.
Oh...
VORM: Heading to the east zone.
I'll isolate it there.
If this is a drill,
what's he doing with a gun?
Do you want to find out?
Relax. This is a routine
Tranquillity drill.
Coming up to linen cupboard
now.
Hyph3n with a 3!
I just pulled this
out of a friend of mine.
Well, we do not make any
judgments on our guests
and fully support any way
you choose to enjoy yourself
here at Tranquillity Spa.
It wasn't recreational.
This is a weapon.
I'd say someone
is targeting you.
Now, why would they do that?
Also, why is that alarm
going off?
And why do you look
so concerned?
Also, where does the 3
come in "Hyphen"?
Never mind. That one can wait.
Also... Also,
what's behind that door?
Cos no linen cupboard
needs a key
with that many
security gradings.
I want to take a look.
Guests aren't permitted
in the...linen cupboard.
How about...
...Pan-galactic Standards
and Practices Officer?
Health and Safety?
Security and Hygiene?
Resort Inspector?
Now, are you
and your excellent tail
going to let me have a look,
or am I going to have
to bark at you? Cos I will.
(BEEP)
It's after the second H
and before the final N.
- The 3.
- Oh, yeah!
Course.
Deadlocked room
with its own armoury.
Don't tell me. Honeymoon suite?
Hyph3n, what the hell
are you doing?
Who's this?
I'm the Doctor, and you, madam,
are far too handsy.
Resort Inspector.
We've only just been inspected.
Well, we like to surprise.
Just like this hopper virus
I found
in your vending machine.
This will mutate any system
it hops into and wreck it.
This is part of a family set,
so there are other replications
out there, which might explain
why your ionic membrane's
failed.
why would you need
to defend a holiday spa
with an ionic membrane?
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
Power systems
in this zone of Tranquillity
are currently
experiencing challenges.
(CLATTERING)
(GROWLING)
Help me!
- Relax, and leave immediately.
- Please!
- Confirmed sighting.
It's on the loose inside.
(SNARLING)
It's attacking the guests.
What did he say?
What's attacking the guests?
Why do you need all this?
Tell me.
Do not engage. I'm en route.
We have to implement
teleport evacuation procedures.
Don't tell me about
the procedures, Hyph3n.
I wrote them.
You can forget
about evacuation.
The hopper virus
is in your teleport system.
Everything's down.
I need you here to help me
understand this place,
not out there
shooting at things.
This zone of Tranquillity
ls compromised.
If you can hear this message,
you shouldn't be here.
Leave immediately.
- (SNARLS)
- Stay back!
(ELECTRICAL FIZZING)
Kane, there's more than one.
I have to retreat!
(SNARLING)
- RYAN: Something's down there.
- BELLA: In here.
Good, here we go.
You're maintenance, right?
You're just the fella.
You are needed outside.
Some of the guests reckon that
the teleport on the terrace
ain't working.
Yeah, nothing's working,
mate, sorry.
Where's my snap hammer?
Sylas?
Snap hammer won't fix that.
You want a crash wrench.
Oi, you're not a mechanic.
You're a child.
Now pass me the snap hammer.
I'm Nevi. This is my boy Sylas.
All right, Sylas?
Yeah, he likes to show up
without warning.
This place is way better
than Mum's house.
How many people
have you got staying here?
23. This shows
all their positions.
- Guest offline.
- No, 21 now.
Guest online. Guest off...
- (SNARLING)
- (SCREAMS)
- 19.
- ...offline.
Guest offline. Guest offline.
Our friends are out there.
All guests
within the hotel building,
to the linen cupboard in
the north corridor immediately.
It's just a drill.
Not a drill.
Repeat, not a drill.
I'm sure it's nothing
to worry about.
(SNARLING AND SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS REVERBERATE)
We should probably
head to the linen cupboard.
Guest offline.
DOCTOR:
Where's your security team?
KANE: No team.
Just me and Vorm.
(SNARLING)
This zone of Tranquillity
ls compromised.
Please do not enter
the Tranquillity steam room
during this routine drill.
MAN: Help! Please, it's coming!
- RYAN: Hey, what's out there?
- It's seen me!
- What...?
- BELLA: Shut up!
Welcome to the Tranquillity
steam room.
Please leave immediately.
(SNARLING)
Hey.
- I'm not a surgeon for pilots.
- (FAINT SCREAMS)
I work in a warehouse.
I'm not a hotel critic.
I just... I didn't want to say
"unemployed nobody".
(SCREAMING)
(SNARLS)
An unauthorised life form
has entered the steam room.
This debug script should
neutralise the hopper viruses,
but they'll need time to work.
More urgently, I need to build
a new ionic membrane
to banish whatever is killing
your guests.
You can't build an ionic
membrane from scratch.
If I had crayons
and half a can of Spam,
I could build you from scratch.
Now, out of my way.
HYPH3N: They'll take
the bodies, won't they?
There you are. We heard the
Doctor's voice over the Tannoy.
Also gunfire.
And people screaming.
Yeah, I know.
I've been on better holidays.
All of you, in here.
That's a funny kind
of linen cupboard.
Hi, can't talk. Building.
Always the hat, Vilma.
(GROWLING)
KANE: I'm losing visuals
across the compound.
I don't know how many
of those creatures have got in.
Kane, I'm sorry.
I couldn't stop it.
It's your job to stop it, Vorm.
VORM: Those things are heading
for the guest teleport.
Benni, I dropped my hat.
Where's Benni?
And where's Ryan?
Shh!
(WHISPERS) Don't run.
Psst.
(PANTS)
- (SNARLS)
- (SCREAMS)
DOCTOR: I got it.
Ionic membrane.
Reinstated DNA filter.
It'll exile any life form
not pre-approved.
If I've built this right.
(THUDDING)
(GROWLS)
(BELLA WHIMPERS)
(SNARLS)
(ROARS)
DOCTOR: Yes. It worked!
Seal is secure.
Internal 02 level
restored to 20.5%.
The ionic membrane's
forced those things out.
Now, open the door.
Our friend's out there.
What are those red dots?
VORM: Casualties of the Dregs.
NEVI: Don't look, Sylas.
BELLA: Has it gone?
What just happened?
If I had to guess...
The Doctor.
GRAHAM: Can you show me Ryan?
Where's Ryan on there?
I'm so sorry.
VILMA: Yaz, I can't see Benni
on there either.
Where's Benni?
GRAHAM: Ryan!
Ryan!
Ryan! Ryan!
- Graham.
- Oh!
What's happening?
Oh, Ryan!
It ain't the aliens
that are gonna kill me,
it's worrying about you.
DOCTOR: What is it
that got in here?
KANE: A couple of the locals.
Dregs.
They're always trying
to attack.
That's why we have shields.
But the virus that brought
the shields down,
the Dregs couldn't have
done that.
Somebody hacked the system.
RYAN: Who'd sabotage a hotel?
KANE: Vorm, void panel SE9-13.
RYAN: What is happening
right now?
- (THUD)
- RYAN: Ooh.
Cor blimey! Right on me nut!
Am I having a stroke
or something?
- It's a fake-cation.
- GRAHAM: A what?
A really good one.
What? So none of this is real?
The hotel is, and the pool.
But you reach
a certain point...
(KNOCKS)
These are usually built in
cities so no-one has to travel.
Our guests now get
off-world holiday
for a fraction of the price.
If they survive.
You built this somewhere
you shouldn't,
thinking no-one'd notice
if you could only get
in and out by teleport.
I heard your little chat
about 02 levels.
That's a completely
different environment
out there. The native species
want you and your guests dead.
Doctor, you need to see this!
They've built a wall
all around this hotel.
Vilma said it's the first
off-world fake-cation.
Done that bit. Feel the lump
on my bonce. Do that.
- What?
- But my Benni is missing.
According to this,
he's outside the shields.
You can't just walk outside.
There's not enough oxygen.
He'd be dead
before we reach him.
He has an oxygen tank.
We have to find him.
He came here because of you.
If there's even the slightest
chance of finding him,
you need to do it. We'll help.
Get transport. I'll gather
everyone in the bar.
Now, Kane!
You get one 02 canister each.
Conserve it.
Green is good, orange is bad,
red's dead.
Oh...
The good news -
these are smart.
Tn an 02-rich environment,
They refill themselves.
Outside this dome,
he only 02-rich environment
on the planet
will be inside the truck.
Do not exit
without my permission.
Keep an eye on your readings.
They'll change colour if you
are running low on oxygen.
Nevi, cockle, my nose thingy
and this breathing apparatus,
is it on right?
Yeah, it's fine.
Dad, it-it's not right.
(BEEPING)
We'd better go
and fire up the truck.
- SYLAS: Yeah.
- I built it myself.
Good.
Tell me
you helped him build it.
KANE: We're moving out!
You owe me some answers.
This is my operation.
Well, it's clearly going well.
What planet is this?
Orphan 55.
You built a fake-cation on
an orphan planet? Are you mad?
The radiation's dropped.
It's safe in short spells.
Get in the truck.
Always remain
inside the vehicle.
This vehicle is the property
of Tranquillity Spa,
your home from home.
RYAN: Was we inside that?
YAZ: This whole planet
looks dead.
It is. It's an orphan planet.
It's a grading that means
it's become too toxic for life.
We're not safe out here.
GRAHAM: Well, we weren't
exactly safe in there.
Come on, Doc, explain. Why
is it called an orphan planet?
DOCTOR: Because it's
uninhabitable. In societies
that let this happen, there's
nearly always a ruling elite
that gets to evacuate, and then
signs off all responsibility
for whatever
they've left behind.
That's messed up.
Happens more than you think.
This is Orphan 55.
And if you can't evacuate?
You die.
All sentient life dies.
That's how it gets the grading.
Except on Orphan 55,
something clearly survived.
RYAN: The Dregs.
Why here, Kane?
Why build this hotel?
It doesn't make any sense.
The air's unbreathable,
but a few years
with the right terraforming,
we can reduce the CO2 and make
the whole planet habitable.
Terraforming
bankrolled by fake-cation.
Smart.
Today hotelier, tomorrow...
...the proud owner
of Orphan 55,
the best real estate
in the galaxy.
If you can sort out your
Dreg problem, you'll be rich.
(TRACKER BEEPS)
Hey, Doc.
Benni's changed direction.
VILMA: Why would he do that?
Maybe he's heading back
to the dome.
- Abort the mission.
- (BRAKES SCREECH)
He's alive!
We know where he is!
He's moving at
37 clicks an hour.
That doesn't
sound like my Benni.
The Dregs got him. We abort.
If those things have got Benni,
we're getting him back!
You want money, Kane?
That's worth a fortune!
BELLA: That would buy
a lot of terraforming.
Or don't you want to be Queen
of Orphan 55 any more, Kane?
DOCTOR: Never mind the money,
there's a man's life at stake.
Vorm, follow the tracker.
- (VEHICLE STARTS)
- Oh...
External oxygen levels 2%.
Current internal
oxygen levels 27 %.
Always remain in...
So what do you actually
know about the Dregs?
How many are there?
...Is the property
of Tranquillity Spa.
Don't want to talk to me? Fine.
I don't need a second person
for a conversation.
A lot of the time
they just get in the way. So...
A Dreg is a native species
that somehow lived
through the fallout.
That's generations.
There must be a few of them.
Hyph3n with a 3,
your face tells me I'm right.
But how did they survive?
And why is your gun fitted
with an exciplex modulator?
They randomise laser output.
You'd only need that
against a thing
that could adapt
to your attack.
Hang on.
That's what they do?
Adapt?
To guns and to nuclear winter?!
Apex predators! And we...
We are driving
straight into their territory!
(WIND HOWLS)
(SNARLS)
(ALL SNARL)
So, er...
...how long
have you been unemployed?
Is that the worst chat-up line
ever?
Yeah.
You just witnessed history.
I've been unemployed
for a month.
I was my dad's carer,
but...he died.
Oh. Sorry.
I lost my mum eight years back.
Have you got anyone else?
Is your mum around?
She died
when I was about Sylas's age.
She made Nevi look like
Parent of the Year.
So...guys...
...what's going on?
Just talking.
- Having a conversation.
- Great.
Where are we up to?
Yeah, Ryan.
What are you talking about?
Er, er, we both have
dead parents.
(BANG!)
This vehicle is experiencing
momentary difficulties.
(CRACKLING) 7his vehicle
ls compromised.
What the hell was that?
This vehicle is compromised.
Please stay inside the vehicle
and wait for assistance.
DOCTOR: This is a trap,
presumably set by the Dregs.
This mist is highly toxic,
and when it clears,
direct sunlight is worse.
We get ten minutes
of solar blistering and then...
...death.
Solar blistering?
What a lovely phrase.
Here's another one.
Completely knackered vehicle.
We're stranded.
KANE: I need to check
where we are.
(GROWLING)
KANE: There's a service tunnel
close by.
If we can make it to that,
we might live.
OK. Bad news is,
we have to leave the truck
and head out on foot.
Not ideal,
but basically our only option.
We can't leave! I paid you.
We came here for Benni!
Stay quiet, move fast.
VILMA: Kane! Kane!
RYAN: All right, let's go.
We'll find him, Vilma,
I promise.
KANE: Tunnel entrance
is just past this ridge.
Benni! Benni! Where are you?
- Shh, shh!
- Oh...
DOCTOR: You'll bring the Dregs.
They're massing
in the hills all around us.
(GROWLING)
GRAHAM:
Doc, we don't stand a chance.
(SNARLING)
Everyone,
back to the truck! Now!
Go, go!
(SNARLING)
NEVI: So what's the plan now?
KANE: Shut...up.
(GROWLING)
What are we going to do?
KANE: Vorm, we're going
to deal with the Dregs.
Doctor, get them out,
head east, look for a hatch.
We'll keep them busy.
- BENNI: Vilma.
- (GASPS)
(GROWLING)
BENNI: Are you in there?
Benni?
- Benni!
- Shh!
- Shh-shh.
GRAHAM: The Dregs have got him.
- (GROWLING)
- YAZ: Shh-shh-shh.
BENNI: Vilma!
I can't believe you came!
I'm not alone,
and I don't have long...
(GROWLING)
...but I-I have two questions.
I'm sorry to ask them together.
Will you marry me?
Oh, of course I will!
Yes!
What was the other one?
BENNTI: If anyone can,
will they please shoot me?
- (GROWLING)
- Oh, Benni!
What has it done to you?
(SNARLING)
We've got to get out of here.
We shouldn't
have left the dome.
(SCREAMS)
Vorm! This is it!
- This is the job!
- GRAHAM: Come on!
RYAN: Let's go!
DOCTOR: Sylas, now! Head
to the ridge. Don't look back!
Come on.
(GROWLING)
Hyph3n, hurry!
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARS)
Come on, come on.
- DOCTOR: Kane, what happened?
- It threw me.
- Are you OK?
- They've got Vorm!
(SNARLING AND SCREAMING)
Get me back up there!
You can't fight any more.
Vorm needs me.
We need you. You know this
planet. Get us to the tunnels.
(SNARLING)
GRAHAM: How can it be
even hotter down here?
DOCTOR: Oxygen check.
Dad, we're doing oxygen checks.
As green as the hair
on our heads, Sylas.
KANE: We're safe.
There's a short-range
maintenance teleport here,
which should just get us
back to base.
Stay close. There's only
enough power for one use.
Kane, when you were fighting
the Dreg,
did you see Benni?
Yeah.
Don't worry. I killed him.
Oh!
GRAHAM: What did you just say?
Benni?
He asked me to.
Oh!
How...? How could you?!
Come on. Come on, Vilma.
I got you.
What is wrong with you?
Why didn't the Dreg kill him?
He was having fun.
There's a room down there
where I stashed a medipack.
Fetch it
and we can get out of here.
You're not getting
out of anywhere.
Bella!
- What are you doing?
- Shut up! I will shoot you.
Where's the maintenance
teleport, Kane?
I'd rather die than tell you.
Oh, you're going to die.
It's just whether
I shoot and kill you now
or wound you
and leave you to the Dregs.
What is it you want?
To burn everything
you've built to the ground.
Who are you?
Me?
I'm no-one.
I was my dad's carer.
Bella...why are you
doing this?
My mum didn't really die.
She just never came
to any of my birthdays.
She didn't come to his funeral.
And she doesn't even
recognise me now.
Trixabelle...
Oh! And she gave me
the name Trixabelle.
The teleport's behind you.
DOCTOR: Oh!
Come on!
This is not the way
to resolve a family dispute.
How about good old-fashioned
passive-aggressive discussion?
(SNARLING)
Bella!
Tranquillity Spa
ls experiencing...
- I didn't ask you to do that!
- You're welcome.
We need to find a way
to help the others get back.
No. They can sort
themselves out.
Hey, hey, hey.
These people are my family.
We're finding a way.
Too late. I'm here
to burn this place down,
and if you're not with me,
you'll die here too.
Our staff are aware. Relax.
- Hang on, where's Ryan?
- With Bella.
Hopefully,
the maintenance teleport
has got them back to the hotel.
OK, listen up.
There's stairs just beyond here
that will take us down
and back.
Just one catch - the route
goes through a Dreg nest.
That's madness!
We'll never make it through!
(SNARLING)
Oxygen supply falling.
You talk too much.
Using up all your oxygen.
Consider urgently
refilling this canister.
(SNARLING)
Consider urgently
refilling this canister.
That daughter of yours, Kane -
real chip off the old block.
I didn't know she was here.
So you left her and her dad
and never got back in contact?
You don't get to judge me.
This project, Tranquillity Spa,
I was only doing it
to give to her.
YAZ: Maybe you should
have mentioned that
before you pulled a gun on her.
RYAN: OK, we're not really
going to burn this place down,
- are we?
- Nope.
We're blowing it up.
What?
You...built a bomb?
(SCOFFS) Oh, I've built
more than one.
Reminder.
Please locate breathable air
in order to recharge supply.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm slowing you down.
No, don't worry, don't worry.
(BEEPING)
We're using too much oxygen.
(GROWLING)
KANE: That's more of them.
They know where we are.
They'll be too fast for us.
Take cover.
I'll try and get a shot.
- YAZ: What is it?
- DOCTOR: Nothing. Keep moving.
GRAHAM: Hey,
what are you doing?
- I said it's nothing!
- No, let us see!
That looks like Russian.
Novosibirsk.
It's a Siberian
underground station.
This is Earth.
No, no, no. It can't be Earth.
This is nothing like Earth.
(GROWLING)
- DOCTOR: Hide. Hide!
- GRAHAM: Come on!
KANE: Get down.
I've got a shot.
DOCTOR: There's too many
of them!
You don't have
enough ammunition!
- We have to run for it.
- Vilma can't run.
(GROWLING)
Yaz, promise me...you'll run.
You can't hide by yourself.
Run.
Stay alive.
(GROWLING)
- Vilma!
- Hey!
- (SNARLING)
- Over here!
Which one of you
hurt my Benni?!
(SNARLING AND SCREAMING)
Don't tell me
that's another hopper virus.
Yep. And this time
I'll put it somewhere
the Doctor won't be able
to isolate...
You said you were with me!
You can't blow this place up!
I've spent my whole life
wondering about her,
and she's never thought once
about me!
I will shoot you.
Tranquillity Spa
ls experiencing
momentary
operational difficulties.
Go on, then.
(BANG!)
There was a smaller bomb
in the bar too.
I wasn't going to use it
when anyone was here!
(ALARM BEEPS)
But it just blew up
the mainframe.
KANE: This is a nest.
Watch out for dormant Dregs.
They sleep standing up.
The stairs are the other side.
We need to go through.
Silently.
We should have been able
to help her.
She died, bless her, so we can
get out of here. Come on.
- Tell us what you know.
- (BEEPING)
How can this be possible?
How did the Dregs get here?
When did the planet
get invaded?
Oxygen supply level 1%.
You must find breathable air
immediately.
Oxygen supply level 1%.
Immediate action required.
Refill oxygen canister.
Find breathable air.
Failure to do so
will result in threat to life.
NEVI: These stairs should
take us back to Tranquillity.
GRAHAM: Wait, where's the Doc?
Oxygen supply level 1%.
You must find breathable air
immediately.
Oxygen supply level 1%.
- Immediate action is required.
- Oh, do shut up.
- Refill oxygen canister.
- (GASPS FOR BREATH)
Find breathable air.
Failure to do so will result
in threat to life.
(DREG SNORES)
(INHALES)
(BEEPING)
Oxygen supply refilling.
Well, aren't you
full of surprises?
I need to understand
one more thing now.
Checking what's in here.
(GASPS)
That's what I was afraid of.
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
KANE: Doctor!
(ROARS)
Over here!
It's so strong without oxygen
because it doesn't need it.
It breathes carbon dioxide in
and oxygen out,
like a really angry tree!
Thank you, but you should
not have come back for me.
I didn't.
But I can buy you some time.
- No. You owe her!
- I owe you all.
For starting this.
Tell her I'm sorry.
She deserved better.
- (YELLS)
- (GUNFIRE)
Kane!
This is an emergency
announcement...
GRAHAM: Whoa, what happened
in here?
YAZ: I'm guessing Bella.
NEVI: If they think
I'm clearing all this up...
(GASPS FOR BREATH)
This is an emergency
announcement.
Come on. We need to close
this up. Secure the room.
Come on, give us a hand.
One, two, three!
(GROWLING)
NEVI: We need to block
this off.
The vending machine! Come on.
- NEVI: Good idea.
- SYLAS: Quick!
(YELLS)
GRAHAM: Drop it, drop it!
Come on, that's it.
- (SNARLING)
- Let's go, let's go!
- Hey! Doctor!
- Ryan! '
Bella, Sylas, Nevi,
to the command centre now.
We'll hold this off for as long
as we can - somehow.
(SNARLING)
"Made in China."
Hey, how did this get here?
It never left.
Orphan 55 - it's Earth.
Your future.
(SNARLING)
If this is Earth,
then what are the Dregs?
They're us. Mutated.
Yes. The few that didn't die.
Oh, no, they can't be.
How did Earth end up like this?
You had warnings
from every scientist alive.
- Global warming.
- Huh?
The food chain collapses.
Mass migration. And war.
(ROARING)
I can't hold this much longer.
We need to get out of here.
When I say run...run.
Run!
(ROARING)
(ROARS)
(ALL ROAR)
DOCTOR: Nevi, secure that door!
I'm trying! The autolocks
are playing up.
(ALARM BEEPS)
Wait, where's Kane?
She didn't make it back.
SYLAS: Dad,
you're doing it wrong.
It needs a passkey
to close it from the inside.
Not now, Sylas, OK?
I'm trying to concentrate.
You never listen to me!
Do it yourself, then!
Doctor, look! Outside the dome.
DOCTOR:
Dregs responding to the call.
They're massing for an attack.
And the ionic membrane's down,
so they can all get in.
We need to evacuate.
We are on phantom power
and the teleport is dead,
but it still knows where
each one of us came from.
Nevi, you need to fix
the teleport.
No way, no, I'm...
You're the only one who knows
how to fix that thing.
And if it doesn't work,
we're all going to be stuck
on this planet.
The bounce capacitor
is completely blown
and the only fuel
we've got left is syrillium 3,
which isn't enough to get us
off-planet.
For that we need syrillium 4.
Which is what...syrillium 3
mutates into
when it's attacked
by the hopper virus.
- Good luck with that, Dad!
- Autolocking linen cupboard.
(BANGS SHUT)
(GROWLING)
NEVI: Open the door!
Sylas is out there!
I can't get the autolocks open!
Where is he?!
DOCTOR: He's not in
the corridor. He must have run.
We're all going to die here.
Not if I've got anything
to do with it.
I know how we can survive this.
We have one advantage
over them.
Oxygen. We love it.
The Dregs hate it.
This whole dome
is air-conditioned.
If I can up the oxygen levels,
the Dregs will be weakened
and we'll get out of here.
Now, Nevi...
...get on it.
Yaz, Ryan,
the Dregs are going to attack
the one place where
the dome wall meets the hotel.
The steam room.
Keep them at bay and buy us
as much time as you can.
Graham, you're with Nevi.
Bella, we're going
to find Sylas.
I'll try and boost
the oxygen levels.
BELLA: Why should I take
orders from you?
You caused this mess.
And now you're going
to help fix it.
Everyone regroup
at the teleport.
Now, I'm going
to blitz these autolocks.
- NEVI: OK. While I do this...
- Yeah?
...you open the drive core
and isolate the syrillium 3.
Are you having a laugh, mate?
I'm... I'm a bus driver.
YAZ: We need to find
something to barricade
the breach in the wall,
stop the Dregs getting in!
RYAN: Sun loungers?
YAZ: Yep, sun loungers.
Last line of defence.
Sylas must be here somewhere.
(FAINT GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
DOCTOR: Ha! Found him!
One small problem...
You've got a plan, right?
Oh, it's brewing.
At least three-eighths
of a plan right here.
Two-eighths.
I'll be honest,
all I've got is the letter P,
but sometimes
that's all I need.
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
Hey, that's our oxygen supply!
It's our only weapon!
(SNARLS)
DOCTOR: Got a plan.
Sylas, stay there.
I'll distract it.
You grab Sylas and
I'll meet you at the teleport.
Oi! Wheezy!
Over here!
Yeah, I see you, Dreg leader,
the alpha dog
of the apex predators.
(SNARLS)
Get to the teleport. It's OK.
(SNARLING)
You call,
and your species responds.
But we need to isolate you, and
that CO2 has just shown me how.
Right, change of plan.
We need to keep it busy. Run!
This way, Wheezy! Follow us!
I can't do this!
Where's my boy?
He'd know what to do.
SYLAS: Whoa, that's a mess.
Graham, move over
for a real mechanic.
SYLAS: Gentlemen, let's make
some syrillium 4.
There's too many of them!
There's nothing we can do!
I've got an idea. Follow me!
(SNARLING)
DOCTOR: Get in the cage!
BELLA: What are you doing?
Isolating Wheezy.
It's the Dreg leader.
BELLA: Then why are we
in the cage?
Playing a hunch.
(SNARLS)
First we weakened it
with oxygen.
Now we deny it the carbon
dioxide it needs to breathe.
I know you can hear me.
I've been in your head.
- (SNARLS)
- This room is sealed.
You need carbon dioxide
to convert into oxygen
so you can breathe.
We need oxygen
to make carbon dioxide.
Right now we've got
a perfect ecosystem.
Kill us, and you die too.
Sorry. This was a trap and
you walked into it, Wheezy.
- Step back.
- (GROWLS)
And let us out of that door.
It's the only way
you're gonna live.
(ROARS)
The people who used to have
this planet could have changed,
but they didn't,
so they lost everything.
Be smarter than what made you.
(GROWLS)
Step away.
Good Dreg. Smart Dreg.
Ready?
(GROWLS)
The second you open that door,
it's going to kill us.
I'm not gonna open the door
until it's in the cage.
I'm hoping it understands that.
(GROWLS)
Run. Run, run, run, run, run!
(SNARLS)
YAZ: You let Bella
set this bomb?
RYAN: She had a lot of bombs
and a gun.
I wasn't gonna argue.
Bella's got
some serious issues.
Yeah, lucky for us.
(GROWLING)
YAZ: This way.
Add one hopper virus,
leave to simmer,
and we'll have
our syrillium 4.
- Well, hopefully.
- Oh, Sylas! Well played, boys.
Please wait
Teleport operations rebooting.
(EXPLOSION)
Did you both forget to mention
the massive bomb?!
It's going to take about
a minute to get to full power.
Nevi, we don't have a minute.
Teleport occupancy exceeded.
There's too many people
to transport.
(SNARLING)
Teleport occupancy exceeded.
- Get out of here.
- No, Bella, come back here!
This teleport
ls now fully operational.
Nevi, I've set the system.
You and Sylas can go.
Sylas, you've been brilliant.
Bye, Doctor.
(GROWLING)
- Bella!
- YAZ: Weapon failed on her!
Get away from her!
(SNARLS)
Got this.
(FIRING CONTINUES)
O'Brien, party of four. Return
teleport profile located.
Teleporting.
We made it.
She... She'll be OK.
She'll be fine.
She's with Kane.
How are they going to be OK?
No oxygen, no help.
When did you know...
that it was Earth?
Just before you did.
Look, I know
what you're thinking.
But it's one possible future.
It's one timeline.
You want me to tell you
that Earth's going to be OK?
Cos I can't.
In your time, humanity is busy
arguing over the washing-up
while the house burns down.
Unless people face facts
and change,
catastrophe is coming.
But it's not decided.
You know that.
The future is not fixed.
It depends on billions
of decisions, and actions,
and people stepping up.
Humans.
I think you forget
how powerful you are.
Lives change worlds.
People can save planets,
or wreck them.
That's the choice.
Be the best of humanity.
Or...
(SNARLS)
(ROARS)
DOCTOR: Gilded Age, New York.
This is when
the modern world begins.
It's only Nikola Tesla!
The Niagara generator
should be shut down.
You believe this is alien?