Salutations. This is Sally Calypso
with the traffic news at 70:175.
We've got reports of
a multiple stack-pile at Junction 509,
with a spate of carjackings reported
on New 5th Avenue.
So you take care now. Drive safely.
(CRASHING)
They're gonna get in.
There's no stopping them.
The police are on their way, I promise.
I've sounded the alarm.
Repeat, this is car 1-0-Hawk-5.
We have a problem,
require urgent assistance.
OPERATOR: Thank you for your call.
You have been placed on hold.
It's all your fault.
You lied to the computer.
You said there were three of us.
You told them three!
Repeat, urgent assistance.
Car 1-0-Hawk-5.
This is an emergency. Help us!
Oh, my God, I'm begging you!
Please, help us!
The weather is at 36 degrees,
and it's smooth skies all the way home.
This is Sally Calypso signing off.
Missing you already.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Just one trip, that's what I said.
One trip in the Tardis and then home.
Although, I suppose we could
stretch the definition.
Take one trip into the past,
one trip into the future.
-How do you fancy that?
-No complaints from me!
How about a different planet?
Can we go to yours?
No, there's plenty of other places.
Come on.
I mean, the planet of the Time Lords.
That's got to be worth a look.
What's it like?
It's beautiful, yeah.
Is it like, you know, outer space
cities, all spires and stuff?
I suppose it is.
Great big temples and cathedrals?
Yeah.
Lots of planets in the sky?
The sky's a burnt orange.
With a citadel enclosed
in a mighty glass dome,
shining under the twin suns.
Beyond that,
the mountains go on forever.
Slopes of deep red grass,
capped with snow.
Can we go there?
Nah! Where's the fun for me?
I don't want to go home.
Instead...
This is much better.
Year 5000000053. Planet New Earth.
Second home of mankind.
50,000 light years from your old world,
and we're slap-bang in the middle
of New New York.
Although, technically,
it's 15 New Yorks since the original,
so it's New New New New New New New New
New New New New New New New New York.
One of the most dazzling cities
ever built.
Oh, that's nice.
A Time Lord version of dazzling!
A bit of rain never hurt anyone.
Come on, let's get under cover.
He has arrived.
What should I do?
Find him before it's too late.
Well, it looks like the same old Earth
to me, on a Wednesday afternoon.
Hold on, hold on, let's have a look.
(POUNDING)
...and the driving should be
clear and easy,
with 15 extra lanes open for
the New New Jersey Expressway.
That's more like it!
That's the view we had last time.
This must be the lower levels.
Down at the base of the tower.
Some sort of under city.
You've brought me to the slums?
Much more interesting.
It's all cocktails and glitter up there.
-This is the real city.
-You'd enjoy anything.
That's me. Ah, the rain's stopping.
Better and better!
When you say last time,
was that you and Rose?
Um, yeah. Yeah, it was. Yeah.
You're taking me to the same planets
that you took her?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing. Just ever heard
the word "rebound”?
Oh, you should have said!
How long have you been there?
Happy. You want happy. Happy!
Customers, customers!
We've got customers!
We have business.
(WOMAN SHOUTING)
Happy, happy, lovely happy!
Anger. Buy some anger!
It's mellow, makes you feel
all bendy and soft all day long.
Don't go to them, they'll rip you off.
Do you want some happy?
-No, thanks.
-Are they selling drugs?
I think they're selling moods.
Same thing, isn't it?
-WOMAN: Over here, sweetheart!
-Hey, you, over here! Over here!
Come over here, yeah.
And what can I get you, my love?
-I want to buy forget.
-I've got forget, my darling.
What strength?
How much do you want forgetting?
It's my mother and father.
They went on the motorway.
Oh, that's a swine.
Try this. Forget 43. That's 2 credits.
Sorry, but hold on a minute.
What happened to your parents?
-They drove off.
-Yeah, but they might drive back.
Everyone goes to the motorway
in the end.
I've lost them.
But they can't have gone far.
You could find them.
No. No, no, don't!
-I'm sorry, what were you saying?
-Your parents.
Your mother and father.
They're on the motorway.
Are they?
That's nice.
I'm sorry, I won't keep you.
So that's the human race
five billion years in the future?
Off their heads on chemicals.
Sorry. I'm really sorry.
We just need three, that's all.
-Let her go! I'm warning you!
-It's not our fault!
Whatever you want, I can help.
We can help.
-But first you've got to let her go!
-Sorry.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(BUZZING)
The Doctor is so gonna kill you. Never
mind him, I'm gonna kill you myself!
-Let go of me!
-Give her some sleep.
Don't you dare! Don't put that near me.
It's just sleep. It won't do you
any harm if you don't fight it.
That's it, come on. That's it.
Get on board.
Engaging antigravs. Hold on.
Martha!
She's all right, she's breathing.
Pulse is fine.
No harm done.
She looks rich. She must have got lost.
Well, she's worth
her weight in gold to us.
This is car 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
We have three passengers, repeat, three.
-Request access to the fast lane.
-Access granted.
Oh, yes.
I thought you'd come back.
Do you want some happy-happy?
Those people, who were they?
Where did they take her?
They've taken her to the motorway.
Looked like carjackers to me.
I'd give up now, darling.
You won't see her again.
Used to be thriving, this place.
You couldn't move.
But they all go to the motorway
in the end.
He kept on saying three, we need three.
What did he mean, three?
It's the car-sharing policy,
to save fuel.
You get special access
if you're carrying three adults.
This motorway, how do I get there?
Straight down the alley, keep going
to the end. You cannae miss it.
Tell you what, buy some happy-happy.
Then you'll be smiling, my love.
A word of advice to all of you.
Cash up, close down and pack your bags.
Why is that, then?
Because as soon as
I've found her alive and well,
and I will find her alive and well,
then I'm coming back.
And this street is closing. Tonight!
(DISTANT VOICES)
MAN: Now you just settle back.
It's all gonna be worth it.
WOMAN: ...the view from the windows,
you can see all the way out to the...
Open sky. They say the air smells
like apple grass. Can you imagine?
MAN: The houses are made of wood.
There are jobs going in the foundries.
Everyone says so.
Take me back. Whoever you are,
just take me back to my friend.
That's all I want. I won't cause
any trouble, just take me back.
I'm sorry. That's not a real gun.
-Well, you would say that.
-Where do you get a gun from these days?
I wouldn't even know how to fire.
No, nor me.
Okay.
What's your name?
Martha. Martha Jones.
Well, I'm Cheen and this is Milo.
And I swear, we're sorry.
We're really, really sorry.
We just needed access to the fast lane,
but I promise as soon as we arrive,
we'll drop you off, and you can go back
and find your friend.
-Seriously?
-I swear. Look, honesty patch.
All the same, it's still kidnapping.
Where are we anyway?
-We're on the motorway.
-What's that then, fog?
It's exhaust fumes.
We're going out to Brooklyn. Everyone
says the air is so much cleaner.
And we couldn't stay
at Pharmacy Town because...
Well, "cause of me. I'm pregnant.
We only discovered it last week.
Scan says it's gonna be a boy.
Right. What do I do now,
congratulate my kidnappers?
We're not kidnappers. Not really.
No! You're idiots!
You're having a baby
and you're wearing that?
Not any more.
This will be as fast as we can.
We'll take the motorway
to the Brooklyn flyover
and then it's gonna take a while
"cause then there's no fast lane,
just ordinary roads,
but at least it's direct.
-It's only 10 miles.
-How long is it gonna take?
About six years.
What?
It'll be just in time for him
to start school.
No, sorry, hold on. Six years?
Ten miles in six years? How come?
(HORN HONKING)
(COUGHING)
(CARS HONKING)
Hey! You daft little street strut!
What are you doing standing there?
Either get out or get in. Come on!
-MAN: Did you ever see the like?
-Here you go.
He was just standing there,
breathing it in.
There's this story. It says
back in the old days, on Junction 47,
this woman stood in the exhaust fumes
for a solid 20 minutes.
By the time they found her,
her head had swollen to 50 feet.
-Oh, you're making it up!
-A 50-foot head. Just think of it.
-Imagine picking that nose.
-Oh, stop it. That's disgusting.
What, did you never pick your nose?
-Bran, we're moving.
-Right, I'm there. I'm on it.
(HORNS BLARING)
Twenty yards. We're having a good day.
And who might you be, sir?
Very well dressed for a hitchhiker.
Thanks. Sorry, I'm the Doctor.
Medical man?
My name's Thomas Kincade Brannigan,
and this is the bane of my life,
the lovely Valerie.
Nice to meet you.
And that's the rest of
the family behind you.
Oh, that's nice.
(MEOWING)
Hello.
-How old are they?
-Just two months.
Poor little souls. They've never known
the ground beneath their paws.
Children of the motorway.
-What, they were born in here?
-We couldn't stop.
We heard there were jobs going,
out in the laundries on Fire Island.
-Thought we'd take a chance.
-You've been driving for two months?
Do I look like a teenager?
We've been driving for 12 years now.
Sorry?
Yeah, started out as newlyweds.
Feels like yesterday.
-Feels like 12 years to me.
-Ah, sweetheart, but you still love me.
Twelve years? How far did you come?
Where did you start?
Battery Park. It's five miles back.
You travelled five miles in 12 years?
I think he's a bit slow.
-Where are you from?
-Never mind that. I've got to get out!
My friend's in one of these cars.
She was taken hostage.
I should get back to the Tardis.
You're too late for that.
We've passed the lay-by.
You're a passenger now, sonny Jim.
-When's the next lay-by?
-Oh, six months.
(HORNS BLARING)
-How many cars are out there?
-I don't think anyone knows.
Here we go. Hungry?
Oh, thanks.
How far down is it to this fast lane?
It's right at the bottom,
underneath the traffic jam.
Not many people can afford three
passengers, so it's empty down there.
Rumour has it
you can reach up to 30 miles per hour.
Wow, that's like, crazy.
But how are you supposed to
live inside this thing? It's tiny!
Oh, we stocked up.
We've got self-replicating fuel,
muscle stimulants for exercise,
there's a chemical toilet at the back
and all waste products
are recycled as food.
Okay.
Oh, now, a gap. This is brilliant!
Car 4-6-5-Diamond-6 on descent to
fast lane. Thank you very much.
I need to talk to the police.
Thank you for your call.
You have been placed on hold.
You're the police!
Thank you for your call.
You have been placed on hold.
Is there anyone else?
I once met the Duke of Manhattan.
Is there any way of
getting through to him?
-Oh, now, ain't you lordly?
-I've got to find my friend!
You can't make outside calls.
The motorway's completely enclosed.
What about the other cars?
We've got contact with them, yeah.
Well, some of them anyway.
They've got to be on your friends' list.
Now, let's see, who's near by?
Ah, the Cassini sisters!
Be still your hearts, my handsome girls.
It's Brannigan here.
Get off the line, Brannigan.
You're a pest and a menace.
Come on now, sisters, is that any way
to talk to an old friend?
You know full well we're not sisters.
We're married.
Ooh! Stop that modern talk,
I'm an old-fashioned cat.
Now, I've got a hitchhiker here,
calls himself the Doctor.
Hello. Sorry, I'm looking for someone
called Martha Jones.
She's been carjacked.
She's inside one of these vehicles,
but I don't know which one.
Wait a minute.
Could I ask what entrance did they use?
-Where were we?
-Pharmacy Town.
Pharmacy Town, about 20 minutes ago.
Let's have a look.
Just my luck to marry a car-spotter.
In the last half hour,
53 new cars joined from
the Pharmacy Town junction.
Anything more specific?
All in good time.
-Was she carjacked by two people?
-Yes, she was. Yeah.
There we are! Just one of those cars
was destined for the fast lane.
That means they had three on board.
And the car number is 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
That's it! So how do we find them?
Ah. Now there I'm afraid I can't help.
We can call them on this thing.
We've got their number, Diamond-6.
Not if they're designated fast lane.
It's a different class.
-You could try the police.
-They put me on hold.
You'll have to keep trying.
There's no one else.
Thank you.
(ALL HONKING)
See? Another ten layers to go,
and we're scorching.
(RUMBLING)
What's that?
It's coming from underneath.
It's that noise, isn't it? It's like
Kate said, the stories, they're true!
What stories?
It's the sound of the air vents,
that's all.
Exhaust fumes travel down,
so at the base of the tunnel
they've got air vents.
No, but the stories are much better.
They say people go missing
on the motorway.
Some cars just vanish,
never to be seen again,
'cause there's something
living down there in the smoke.
Something huge
and hungry.
And if you get lost on the road,
it's waiting for you.
(SNARLING)
Well, like I said, air vents.
Going down to the next layer.
Except, look out there. Does it look
like the air vents are working?
No.
(GROWLING)
So what's that, then?
Nah, kids' stuff.
Car 4-6-5-Diamond-6, on descent.
We've got to go to the fast lane.
Take me down.
Not in a million years.
-You've got three passengers.
-I'm still not going.
She's alone and she's lost.
She doesn't even belong on this planet,
and it's all my fault.
I'm asking you, Brannigan, take me down.
That's a no, and that's final.
I'm not risking the children down there.
Why not? What's the risk?
What happens down there?
We're not discussing it.
The conversation is closed.
-So we keep on driving?
-Yes, we do.
-For how long?
-Till the journey's end.
Mrs Cassini, this is the Doctor.
Tell me, how long have you been driving
on the motorway?
Oh, we were amongst the first.
It's been 23 years now.
And in all that time,
have you ever seen a police car?
I'm not sure.
Look at your notes. Any police?
-Not as such.
-Or an ambulance?
Rescue service? Anything official, ever?
I can't keep a note of everything.
What if there's no one out there?
Stop it.
The Cassinis were doing you a favour.
Someone's got to ask, 'cause you
might not talk about it, but it's there,
in your eyes.
What if the traffic jam never stops?
There's a whole city above us.
The mighty city-state of New New York.
-They wouldn't just leave us.
-In that case, where are they? Hmm?
What if there's no help coming,
not ever?
What if there's nothing?
Just the motorway?
With the cars going round and round
and round, never stopping? Forever!
Shut up! Just shut up!
This is Sally Calypso,
and it's that time again.
The sun is blazing high in the sky
over the New Atlantic.
The perfect setting for
the daily contemplation.
You think you know us so well, Doctor.
We are not abandoned.
Not while we have each other.
This is for all of you
out there on the roads.
We're so sorry.
Drive safe.
(OLD RUGGED CROSS PLAYING ON TV MONITOR)
# On a hill far away
# Stood an old rugged cross
# The emblem of suffering and shame
ALL: # And I love that old cross
# Where the dearest and best
# For a world of lost sinners was slain
# So I'll cherish the old rugged cross
# Rugged cross
# Till my trophies at last I lay down
# I will cling to the old rugged cross
# Rugged cross
# And exchange it some day for a crown #
Fast lane access. Please drive safely.
We made it. The fast lane.
If you won't take me,
I'll go there on my own.
What do you think you're doing?
Finding my own way. I usually do.
ELECTRONIC VOICE: Capsule open.
Here we go.
Look after this.
I love that coat.
Janis Joplin gave me that coat.
But you can't jump!
If it's any consolation, Valerie,
right now I'm having kittens.
This Martha,
she must mean an awful lot to you.
Hardly know her.
I was too busy showing off.
And I lied to her.
I couldn't help it, just lied.
Bye, then!
He's completely insane!
That, and a bit magnificent!
Capsule open.
Who the hell are you?
Sorry, motorway foot patrol.
I'm doing a survey.
How are you enjoying your motorway?
Well, not very much. Junction 5's
been closed for three years.
Thank you, your comments
have been noted. Have a nice day!
Capsule open.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Your comments have been noted.
Do you mind if I borrow this?
Not my colour, but thank you very much!
Capsule open.
Oh, don't mind me.
Try again.
Brooklyn turn off 1, closed.
Try the next one.
Brooklyn turn off 2, closed.
What do we do?
We keep going round,
we'll do the whole loop,
by the time we come back round,
they'll be open.
(GROWLING)
You still calling that air vents?
What else could it be?
(GROWLING)
-What the hell is that?
-It's just the hydraulics.
Sounds like it's alive!
It's all exhaust fumes out there.
Nothing could breathe in that.
WOMAN: Calling car 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
Repeat, calling car 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
This is 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
Who's that? Where are you?
I'm in the fast lane,
about 50 yards behind.
Can you get back up?
Can you get off the fast lane?
We only have permission to go down.
We need the Brooklyn Flyover.
-It's closed. Go back up.
-We can't. We'll just go round.
Don't you understand?
They're closed, they're always closed.
We're stuck down here. There's
something else out there in the fog.
Can't you hear it?
(ROARING)
-That's the air vents.
-Jehovah, what are you, some stupid kid?
Get out of here!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
What was that?
We can't move. It got us.
-What's happening?
-What's got you? What is it?
I don't know...
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
-Hello?
-Just drive, you idiots!
Get out of here!
-No/
-Can you hear me? Hello?
Just drive! Do what she said,
get us out of here!
-But where?
-Just straight ahead! And fast!
What is it? What's out there?
What's happening?
Capsule open.
Excuse me! Is that legal?
Sorry, motorway foot patrol.
Whatever. Have you got any water?
Certainly. Never let it be said
I've lost my manners.
Is this the last layer?
We're right at the bottom.
Nothing below us but the fast lane.
-Can we drive down?
-There's only two of us.
-You need three to go down.
-Couldn't we cheat?
I'd love to, but it's an automated
system. The wheel would lock.
Then excuse me.
You can't jump, it's 1,000 feet down!
No, I just want a look.
(ROARING)
What's that noise?
I try not to think about it.
What are those lights?
What's down there?
I just need to see.
There must be some sort of ventilation.
If I could just transmit a pulse through
this thing, I could trip the system.
Give us a bit of a breeze.
(DRILLING)
Just what we need! Pirates!
I'm calling the police!
The Doctor, where is he?
That's it! Might shift the fumes a bit,
give us a good look.
(SCREECHING)
What are those shapes?
They're alive.
What the hell are they?
Macra.
-Go faster!
-I'm at full speed!
No access above.
But this is an emergency!
Thank you for your call.
You have been placed on hold.
-Turn everything off!
-You've got to be joking!
Listen, it's all fog out there,
so how can they see us?
Maybe it's the engine, the sound,
or the heat or the light, I don't know.
But if you turn everything off,
they might not be able to find us.
What if you're wrong?
It can't be worse than this. Just do it!
(MACRA RETREATING)
CHEEN: They've stopped.
Yeah, but they're still out there.
How did you think of that?
I saw it in a film.
They used to do it in submarines.
Trouble is,
I can't remember what they did next.
Well, you'd better think of something,
"cause we've lost the air-con.
If we don't switch the engines back on,
we won't be able to breathe.
How long have we got?
Eight minutes maximum.
The Macra used to be
the scourge of this galaxy. Gas.
They fed off gas.
The filthier, the better.
They built up a small empire
using humans as slaves
and mining gas for food.
They don't exactly
look like empire-builders to me.
Well, that was billions of years ago.
Billions. They must have devolved
down the years. Now they're just beasts.
But they're still hungry,
and my friend's down there.
(BANGING)
It's like New Times Square in here!
For goodness sake!
DOCTOR: I've invented a sport!
Doctor! You're a hard man to find.
No guns! I'm not having guns!
I only brought this in case of pirates.
-Doctor, you've got to come with me.
-Do I know you?
You haven't aged at all.
Time has been less kind to me.
Novice Hame!
Whoa, hold on. Get off!
Last time we met, you were
breeding humans for experimentation.
I've sought forgiveness, Doctor,
for so many years under his guidance.
And if you come with me, I might
finally be able to redeem myself.
I'm not going anywhere. You've got Macra
living underneath this city. Macra!
If my friend's still alive,
she's stuck down there!
You've got to come with me right now!
No, you're coming with me.
We've got three passengers now.
I'm sorry, Doctor, but the situation
is even worse than you can imagine.
-Transport.
-Don't you dare! Don't you dare!
(DOCTOR GROANING)
Rough teleport. Ow!
You can go straight back down
and teleport people out,
-starting with Martha!
-I only had the power for one trip.
Then get some more! Where are we?
High above, in the Overcity.
Good, 'cause you can tell the senate
of New New York I'd like a word.
They have got thousands of people
trapped on the motorway! Millions!
But you're inside the senate, right now.
May the goddess Santori bless thee.
They died, Doctor.
The city died.
How long has it been like this?
24 years.
All of them? Everyone? What happened?
A new chemical. A new mood.
They called it "bliss".
Everyone tried it. They couldn't stop.
A virus mutated
inside the compound and became airborne.
Everything perished.
Even the virus in the end.
It killed the world
in seven minutes flat.
There was just enough time to close down
the walkways and the flyovers,
sealing off the Undercity.
Those people on the motorway
aren't lost, Doctor.
They were saved.
So the whole thing down there
is running on automatic.
There's not enough power
to get them out.
We did all we could
to stop the system from choking.
Who's we? How did you survive?
He protected me.
And he has waited for you
these long years.
Doctor.
The Face of Boe!
I knew you would come.
Back in the old days,
I was made his nurse
as penance for my sin.
Old friend, what happened to you?
A failing.
He protected me from the virus
by shrouding me in his smoke.
But with no one to maintain it,
the city's power died.
The Undercity would have fallen
into the sea.
So he saved them.
The Face of Boe wired himself
into the mainframe.
He's giving his life force
just to keep things running.
But there are planets out there.
You could have called for help.
The last act of the senate
was to declare New Earth unsafe.
The automatic quarantine
lasts for 100 years.
(THE FACE OF BOE GASPING)
So the two of you stayed here.
On your own for all these years.
We had no choice.
Yes, you did.
Save them, Doctor.
Save them.
How much air is left?
Two minutes.
There's always the Doctor.
That friend of mine.
He might think of something.
Martha, no one's coming.
He looked kind of nice.
-He's a bit more than that.
-Are you and him...
Sometimes I think he likes me,
but sometimes I just think
he needs someone with him.
I never even asked. Where's home?
A long way away.
I didn't really think.
I just followed the Doctor and...
They don't even know where I am.
My mum and dad.
If I died here, they'd never know.
So, um, who is he, then? This Doctor?
I don't know.
Well, not really.
There's so much he never says.
But that means that
the only hope right now is
a complete stranger.
-Well, that's no use!
-But it is, though.
Because you haven't seen
the things he can do.
Honestly, just trust me. Both of you.
You've got your faith,
you've got your songs and your hymns,
and I've got the Doctor.
Right.
Systems back online.
-Good luck.
-And you.
(GROWLING)
Car 4-6-5-Diamond-6, it still registers!
That's Martha.
I knew she was good.
Novice Hame, hold that in place.
Take the residual energy, convert it,
feed it through the electricity system.
-But there isn't enough power.
-Oh, you got power! You got me!
I'm brilliant with computers,
just you watch.
Hame, every switch
on that bank up to maximum!
I can't power up the city,
but all the city needs is people.
So what are you going to do?
This!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
The transformers are blocked.
The signal can't get through.
-Doctor.
-Yeah, hold on, not now.
I give you my last...
(GASPING)
Hame, look after him!
Don't you go dying on me,
you big old face.
You've got to see this.
The open road. Ha!
-What in Jehovah was that?
-It's coming from above!
What is it? What's happening?
Hold on, May.
Of all the cats in the kingdom.
What is it?
Yes!
It's the sun!
Oh, Brannigan!
Children, it's the sunlight!
Sorry, no Sally Calypso, she was just
a hologram. My name's the Doctor.
He's a magician.
And this is an order. Everyone drive up.
-Right now.
-Is he serious?
I've opened the roof of the motorway.
Come on.
Throttle those engines. Drive up.
All of you, the whole Undercity,
drive up.
-Here we go.
-Drive up. Drive up!
We've got to clear that fast lane.
-Drive up and get out of the way.
-BRANNIGAN: Here we go! Whoo!
Oi! Car 4-6-5-Diamond-6.
Martha! Drive up!
-That's the Doctor!
-We can't go up, we'll hit the lane!
Do as he says. Go up!
DOCTOR: You've got access above.
Now, go!
It's daylight.
Oh, my God, that's the sky.
The real sky!
He did it!
I told you. He did it!
Did I tell you, Doctor, you're
not bad, sir? You're not bad at all.
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
You keep driving, Brannigan.
All the way up.
'Cause it's here, just waiting for you.
The city of New New York,
and it's yours.
And don't forget, I want that coat back.
I reckon that's a fair bargain, sir.
Car 4-6-5-Diamond-6, I've sent you
a flight path, come to the senate.
MARTHA: On my way!
Quite a while since I saw you,
Martha Jones.
Doctor!
Doctor?
Over here.
Doctor! What happened out there?
What's that?
It's the Face of Boe.
It's all right, come say hello.
And this is Hame. She's a cat.
Don't worry.
He's the one that saved you, not me.
My lord gave his life to save the city.
And now he's dying.
No, don't say that.
Not old Boe, plenty of life left.
It's good to breathe the air once more.
Who is he?
I don't even know.
Legend says the Face of Boe
has lived for billions of years.
Isn't that right?
And you're not about to give up now.
Everything has its time.
You know that old friend,
better than most.
-The legend says more.
-Don't. There's no need for that.
It says that the Face of Boe
will speak his final secret
to a traveller.
Yeah, but not yet.
Who needs secrets, eh?
I have seen so much.
Perhaps too much.
I am the last of my kind,
as you are the last of yours, Doctor.
That's why we have to survive.
Both of us.
Don't go.
I must. But know this, Time Lord.
You are not alone.
(SOBBING)
All closed down.
Happy?
Happy-happy.
New New York can start again.
And they've got Novice Hame.
Just what every city needs, cats
in charge. Come on, time we were off.
But what did he mean, the Face of Boe?
You are not alone?
I don't know.
You've got me. Is that what he meant?
I don't think so.
Sorry.
Then what?
Doesn't matter.
Back to the Tardis, off we go.
-Right, are you staying?
-Till you talk to me properly, yes.
He said, "Last of your kind."
What does that mean?
-It really doesn't matter.
-You don't talk. You never say. Why not?
(CITIZENS SINGING OLD RUGGED CROSS)
It's the city.
They're singing.
I lied to you.
'Cause I liked it.
I could pretend.
Just for a bit,
I could imagine they were still alive.
Underneath a burnt orange sky.
I'm not just a Time Lord.
I'm the last of the Time Lords.
The Face of Boe was wrong,
there's no one else.
What happened?
There was a war.
A Time War.
The last great Time War.
My people fought
a race called the Daleks,
for the sake of all creation,
and they lost.
They lost. Everyone lost.
They're all gone now.
My family.
My friends. Even that sky.
You should have seen it,
that old planet.
The second sun would rise in the south
and the mountains would shine.
The leaves on the trees were silver.
When they caught the light
every morning,
it looked like a forest on fire.
When the autumn came,
a breeze would blow through
the branches. It sounded like a song...
MARTHA: It's the Statue of Liberty.
I've always wanted to go to New York.
(SQUEALING)
It's the Depression, sweetie. Your heart
might break, but the show goes on.
MARTHA: Hooverville mystery deepens.
Arm yourselves. Come on!
MAN 1: Who are we working for?
MAN 2: Behold your masters.
What do you mean, creatures?
(SQUEALING)
-What the hell was that?
-Doctor?
Run!
Hands in the air, and no funny business.
Where's Martha?
(SCREAMING)
It's insane, it's inhuman!
(SHUSHING)
DOCTOR: They always survive,
while I lose everything.