(THUNDER CRASHING)
DARLA: First there were the Daleks.
And then there was a man
who fought them.
And then, in time,
he died.
There are a few, of course,
who believe this man somehow survived
and that one day he will return.
For both our sakes, dearest Hannah,
we must hope these stories are true.
I got your message.
Not many people can do that,
send me messages.
I have a daughter,
Hannah.
She's in a Dalek prison camp.
They say you can help.
Do they? I wish they'd stop.
Hell of a choice of meeting place.
They said I'd have to intrigue you.
DOCTOR: Skaro.
The original planet of the Daleks.
Look at the state of it.
-Who told you about me?
-Does it matter?
Maybe not.
But you're very well-informed.
If Hannah's in a Dalek prison camp,
tell me, why aren't you?
-I escaped.
-(LAUGHING) No!
Nobody escapes the Dalek camps.
You're very cold.
What's wrong?
-It's a trap.
-What is?
-You are. And you don't even know it.
-(NECK CRACKING)
(SCREAMING)
DALEX: The Doctor is acquired!
(POP MUSIC PLAYING, CAMERA CLICKING)
I'll just be a minute.
-Um, your husband is here.
-Hmm. I don't have a husband.
Oh, well, apparently you still do.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
You have to sign these.
And then we're not married?
Just like magic.
-Can't chat, working.
-Really?
I thought you were just
pouting at a camera.
Rory...
(LIGHT BULB BUZZING)
Sorry, love. Was I interrupting?
No.
Gosh, look at you. You've gone so pale.
Come on. Take a seat.
We'll soon sort that out.
(BUZZING)
(NECK CRACKING)
Amelia Pond is acquired!
Cheers.
(NECK CRACKING)
Rory Williams is acquired!
(GASPS)
Where are we?
So how much trouble are we in?
(DOOR WHIRRING)
DOCTOR: How much trouble, Mr Pond?
Out of 107
11.
(HATCH WHIRRING)
(METALLIC CLANG)
Where are we? Spaceship, right?
Not just any spaceship.
The Parliament of the Daleks.
Be brave.
What do we do?
Make them remember you.
Well, come on, then.
You've got me.
What are you waiting for?
At long last, it's Christmas!
Here I am!
Save us.
You will save us.
I'll what?
You will save the Daleks.
-Save the Daleks!
ALL: Save the Daleks!/
Save the Daleks! Save the Daleks!
Well...
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
This is new.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(CARMEN SUITE NO. 2 PLAYING)
OSWIN: Day 3635.
-(HUMMING)
-The terror continues.
Also, made another souffle.
(BELL DINGS)
Very nearly.
Check defences.
They came again last night.
Still always at night.
Maybe they're vampires.
(GASPS) Oh! And it's my mum's birthday.
Happy birthday, Mum.
I did make you a souffle
but it was too beautiful to live.
DALEK: (BANGING) You will let us enter!
DALEKS: We will enter! We will enter!
(PLAYING CARMEN SUITE NO. 7 LOUDLY)
(DALEKS SHOUTING, INDISTINCT)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
RORY: What's he doing?
AMY: He's chosen the most
defendable area in the room,
counted all the Daleks,
counted all the exits
and now he's calculating
the exact distance we're standing apart
and he's starting to worry.
Oh! And look at him frowning now.
"Something's wrong with Amy and Rory
and who's going to fix it?"
And he straightens his bow tie.
DALEK: We have arrived.
Arrived where?
Doctor.
The Prime Minister
will speak with you now.
Do you remember who you were
before they emptied you out
and turned you into their puppet?
My memories are only reactivated
if they are required to facilitate
deep cover or disguise.
-You had a daughter.
-I know.
I've read my file.
Well?
What do you know of the Dalek asylum?
According to legend,
you have a dumping ground.
A planet where you lock up
all the Daleks that go wrong.
The battle-scarred, the insane,
the ones even you can't control.
Which never made any sense to me.
-Why not?
-Because you'd just kill them.
It is offensive to us
to extinguish such divine hatred.
Offensive?
Does it surprise you to know
that Daleks have a concept of beauty?
I thought you'd run out of ways
to make me sick.
But hello again.
You think hatred is beautiful?
Perhaps that is why
we have never been able to kill you.
(METALLIC CLANGING)
DARLA: The asylum.
It occupies the entire planet,
right to the core.
DOCTOR: How many Daleks are in there?
DARLA: A count has not been made.
Millions, certainly.
DOCTOR: All still alive?
DARLA: It has to be assumed.
The asylum is fully automated.
-Supervision is not required.
-Armed?
The Daleks are always armed.
What colour?
Sorry, there weren't
any good questions left.
(SIGNAL BLEEPING)
DARLA: This signal is being received
from the very heart of the asylum.
(BIZET'S CARMEN PLAYING)
What is the noise? Explain! Explain!
-It's me.
-Sorry, what?
It's me playing the triangle. (LAUGHS)
Okay, I got buried in the mix.
Carmen, lovely show.
Someone's transmitting this.
Have you considered tracking
back the signal and talking to them?
(OPERA CONTINUES PLAYING)
He asked the Daleks.
Hello? Hello, Carmen!
Hello!
-Hello?
-Come in, come in. Come in, Carmen.
Hello! Yes, yes! Sorry. Do you read me?
Yes! Reading you loud and clear.
Identify yourself
and report your status.
Hello.
Are you real?
Are you actually, properly real?
Yeah, confirmed.
Actually, properly real.
Oswin Oswald.
Junior Entertainment Manager,
Starship Alaska. Current status,
crashed and shipwrecked somewhere...
not nice.
Been here a year,
rest of the crew missing,
provision's good but keen to move on.
A year?
Are you okay? Are you under attack?
Some local life forms.
Been keeping them out.
Do you know what those life forms are?
I know a Dalek when I hear one, yeah.
What have you been doing
on your own against the Daleks
for a year?
Making souffles.
Souffles. Against the Daleks. (CHUCKLES)
Where do you get the milk?
This conversation is irrelevant.
No, it isn't!
-(SIGNAL WARBLING)
-Hello! Hello! Hello!
Because a star line has crashed
into your asylum and someone's got in.
And if someone can get in,
then everything can get out.
A tsunami of insane Daleks.
Even you don't want that.
-The asylum must be cleansed.
-Then why is it still here?
You've enough firepower on this ship
to blast it out of the sky.
The asylum force field is impenetrable.
Turn it off.
It can only be turned off
from within the asylum.
A small task force
could sneak through a force field.
Send in a couple of Daleks.
Oh!
Oh! Ah, that's good, that's brilliant.
You're all too scared to go down there.
Not one of you will go, so tell me.
What do the Daleks do
when they're too scared?
The Predator of the Daleks
will be deployed.
You don't have a predator.
And even if you did, why would
they turn off a force field for you?
Because you will have
no other means of escape.
May I clarify?
The Predator is a Dalek's word for you.
Me? Me?
You will need this.
It will protect you from the nanocloud.
The what? The nano what?
The gravity beam will convey you
close to the source of the transmission.
You must find a way to deactivate
the force field from there.
You're going to fire me at a planet?
That's your plan?
I get fired at a planet
and expected to fix it?
In fairness, that is slightly your MO.
Don't be fair to the Daleks
when they're firing me at a planet.
What do you want with them?
It is known
that the Doctor requires companions.
Oh, brilliant! Good-o!
DOCTOR: Don't worry.
We'll get through this, I promise.
Don't be scared.
Scared? Who's scared?
Geronimo.
-DOCTOR: Oi!
-(AMY AND RORY SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Wrong way up! Wrong way up!
Oh, God!
Rory!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
(AMY MUMBLING)
Hello.
-Hello. Who are you?
-(AMY GASPS)
-You okay?
-(GASPING)
Rory? (PANTING)
Doctor? (PANTING)
I'm Harvey. I'm Harv...
Who's Rory?
Where are you going?
(WHIRRING)
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS)
Hey! Huh?
(CARMEN PLAYING)
OSWIN: Sorry.
Sorry, pressed the wrong switch.
Souffle Girl?
You could always call me Oswin,
seeing as that's my name.
AR/
-You okay?
How are you doing that, eh?
This is Dalek technology.
-Well, it's very easy to hack.
-No, it isn't.
Where are you?
Ship broke up when it hit.
Somewhere underground, I think.
You coming to get me?
AMY: Doctor?
Hey! Oi, Souffle Girl!
-Come back.
-Damn!
Doctor!
Amy.
-Hey.
-(PANTING)
-Where's Rory?
-HARVEY: There was another beam.
There. Over there.
Are you the rescue team?
(TOGGLING SWITCHES, SIGNAL WARBLING)
Hello!
AMY: Rory?
Rory!
(WATER TRICKLING, RORY MOANING)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
Hmm.
We came down two days ago.
There's 12 other escape pods.
(LOCKS CLICKING)
(WHIRRING)
HARVEY: I don't know
what happened to them.
AMY: Alaska?
That's the same ship as Souffle Girl.
DOCTOR: Yeah.
Except she's been here a year.
Here, we should have some climbing rope
long enough for that hole.
Won't you introduce us to your crew?
Ah, yeah, sorry.
Guys, this is the Doctor and Amy.
Guys?
HARVEY: Oh, my God!
They're dead.
-All of them.
-That's not possible.
I just spoke to them.
Two hours ago,
we were doing engine repairs.
You're sure about that, are you?
'Cause I'd say they've all been dead
for a very long time.
Well, they can't be.
Well, they didn't get in this state
in two hours.
Oh, of course. Stupid me.
Of course what?
I died outside.
And the cold preserved my body.
I forgot about dying.
(SCREAMING)
-Amy, the door!
-Come on, come on!
Explain, that's what you're good at,
how did he get all Daleked?
Because he wasn't wearing one of these.
Oh, ho, ho!
That's clever! The nanocloud.
Microorganisms that automatically
process any organic matter,
living or dead, into a Dalek puppet.
(CHUCKLES) Anything attacks this place
it automatically becomes part
of the on-site security.
-Living or dead?
-These wristbands protect us.
The only thing stopping us
going exactly the way he did...
Doctor, shut up.
-Living or dead?
-Yes, exactly, living or-or-or...
(BONES CRACKING)
(CRACKING)
...dead.
Oh, dear.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Yeah.
(GRUNTING)
(AMY EXCLAIMING)
(SCREAMS) Doctor!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
-Is it bad that I've really missed this?
-Yes.
-It's good.
-I know.
(OVER PA) Unauthorised personnel
may not enter the cockpit.
-Shut up.
-What? Mr Grumpy.
Bad combo.
No sense of humour and that chin.
Is that her again, Souffleey Girl?
Yeah, she...
Oi, what is wrong with my chin?
Careful, dear.
You'll put someone's eye out.
I'm scanning you.
You're in another of the escape pods
from the Alaska,
it seems your power's on.
How can you hack into everything?
It should be impossible.
-You're in a crashed ship!
-Long story.
Is there a word for
"total screaming genius”
that sounds modest and a tiny bit sexy?
Doctor. You call me the Doctor.
-See what you did there.
-(BEEPING)
Check the floor.
I'm picking up a breach at floor level.
There could be a way out.
See you later.
A-ha! Hatch.
It looks like it's been used already
and they tried to block it off
behind them.
-(BANGING ON DOOR)
-Can't imagine why.
The lower part of the pod is buried,
so this must go
straight down to the asylum.
Where Rory is.
Yeah. Speaking of Rory... (GRUNTS)
Is there anything you want to tell me?
-Are we going to do this now?
-Well, what happened?
Oh, stuff, you know.
We split up. What can you do?
What can I do?
Nothing.
It's not one of those things you can fix
like you fix your bow tie.
And don't give me those big, wet eyes,
raggedy man. It's life.
Just life. That thing that goes on
when you're not there.
-(METAL CLANKS)
-Right...
(GRUNTING)
Okay, so someone else
got out this way, then.
-Yeah, let's go and find them.
-(POUNDING ON DOOR CONTINUES)
Whoa! Hello, hello, hello.
What are they up to?
What's that?
One of these. But where did they get it?
Oh, Doctor.
-They got it from me.
-Oh, Amy.
Doctor, what's going to happen to me,
seriously? Tell me. What?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Ah.
(METAL CLANKS)
Shh.
(METAL SCREECHING)
"Egg-egg-egg-egg-egg-egg-eggs...”
What?
Sorry, what?
"Egg-egg-egg-egg-egg-eggs...”
Eggs?
-You mean those things?
_IIEggs.-- FF
I don't... I don't know what you want.
Uh, those things...
Are those things eggs?
This?
You want this?
IIEggs.-- Fr
(SLOWLY) ...term...i...
...Nate.
-Exterminate!
(EXCLAIMS)
Exterminate!
(DALEKS CONTINUE SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
ALL: Exterminate! Exterminate!
OSWIN: (OVER PA)
Run! The door at the end. Run for it/
They're waking up but they're slow.
The door at the end. Just run.
Now, now, now!
DALEK: Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate!
(SCREAMING)
Exterminate! Extermin...
(EXHALING)
(SIGHING)
-So. Anyway.
-(GASPS)
-I'm Oswin. What do I call you?
-Uh...
I can't remember. Uh...
Rory.
Lovely name, Rory.
First boy I ever fancied
was called Rory.
-Okay.
-Actually, she was called Nina.
I was going through a phase.
Just flirting to keep you cheerful.
(LOUD BANGING)
DALEKS: (MUFFLED) Exterminate!
DALEKS: Exterminate!
Exterminate! Exterminate!
Ah, okay.
(WHISPERING) Anytime you want to start
flirting again is fine by me.
So tell me. What's going to happen
to me? And don't lie.
'Cause I know when you're lying to me
and I will definitely fall on you.
The air all around
is full of micro-machines,
robots the size of molecules.
Nanogenes.
Now that you're unprotected,
you're being...rewritten.
So what happens? I get one of those
things sticking out of my head?
-Physical changes come later.
-What comes first? How does it start?
With your mind.
Your feelings, your memories.
-And I'm sorry but it's started already.
-How do you know?
Because we've had this conversation
four times.
Okay, I'm scared now.
Hang on to scared. Scared isn't Dalek.
(WHIRRING)
OSWIN: Hey there, Binky boy.
If it's a straight choice,
I prefer Nina.
Loving this! The nose and the chin.
You two could fence.
There's a door behind you.
In there, quickly.
Okay. You're safe for now.
Pop your shirt off, quick as you like.
-Why?
-Does there have to be a reason?
(METAL CLANKING)
(SNIFFING)
(DALEKS SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
AMY: What's that?
(DALEKS SHOUTING, INDISTINCT)
Keep a look out, don't open this door.
Oswin!
Oswin, can you hear me?
Hello, The Chin, I have visual on you.
Why don't I have a visual on you?
Why can't I ever see you?
Limited power, bad hair, take your pick.
There's a door to your left, open it.
Going to send you a map to that screen.
I put your little friend somewhere safe,
I can get you to him.
Rory? You found Rory?
I call him Nina.
It's a personal thing. Hush, now.
(WHISPERING) Who are you?
Doctor...
(FEMALE HUMMING)
(MAN AND GIRL LAUGHING)
(BABY CRYING)
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
(APPLAUSE)
How many Daleks
directly ahead of me right now?
Ten, twenty? Hard to say.
Some of them are catatonic
but they do have firepower.
How do I get past them? Amy!
Hmm, it's okay. Shh, it's okay.
It's just people in here.
It's just people.
Amy, it's the nanocloud.
It's altering your perception.
Look again, look again.
Those aren't people.
-(GASPS)
-Come here.
Come on, Amy, take my hand. Run, run!
No, they're coming down.
Ah! Ah, yes, they are.
(AMY SCREAMS)
Intruder.
-DOCTOR: Back.
-Intruder.
(SLOWLY) Intruder.
(POWERING DOWN)
-It's damaged.
-Okay. But what do we do?
Identify me, access your files.
Who am I?
Come on!
-Who's your daddy?
-You are
the Predator.
Access your standing orders
concerning the Predator.
The Predator must be destroyed!
And how are you going to do that?
Dalek without a gun?
You're a tricycle with a roof.
How are you going to destroy me?
(ALARM BEEPING)
Self-destruct initiated.
AMY: What's it doing?
It's going to blow itself up
and us with it.
Only weapon it's got left.
DALEK:
Self-destruct cannot be countermanded!
DOCTOR:
I'm not looking for a countermand, dear.
I'm looking for reverse.
Forwards! Forwards! Forwards! Forwards/!
-Forwards/!
-Intruder! Intruder!
Whoa!
(GASPS)
Oswin, what was that? That was close.
Oswin! What happened?
Who killed all the Daleks?
Who do you think?
Will sleeping help her?
Will it slow down the process?
You'd better hope so.
Because pretty soon
she's going to try and kill you.
-(AMY GROANS)
-DOCTOR: Amy.
-Ow.
-You still with us?
-Amy, it's me.
Do you remember me?
-She remembers me.
-Same old Amy.
Do you know
how you make someone into a Dalek?
Subtract love, add anger.
Doesn't she seem a bit too angry to you?
Well, somebody's never been to Scotland.
What about you though, Oswin?
How come you're okay?
Why hasn't the nanocloud converted you?
I mentioned the genius thing, yeah?
Shielded in here.
Hmm. Clever of you. Now, this place.
The Daleks said it was fully automated.
But look at it, it's a wreck.
Well, I've had nearly a year
to mess with them. And...
not a lot else to do.
A junior entertainment manager
hiding out in a wrecked ship,
hacking the security systems
of the most advanced warrior race
the universe has ever seen.
But you know what really
gets me about you, Oswin?
The souffles.
-The souffles?
-Where do you get milk
for the souffles?
Seriously, is no one else
wondering about that?
No! Frankly, no. Twice.
OSWIN: So, Doctor.
I've been looking you up.
You're all over the database.
Why do the Daleks call you the Predator?
I'm not a predator.
I'm just a man with a plan.
You've got a plan?
We're all ears.
There's a nose joke going
if someone wants to pick that one off.
In no particular order,
we need to neutralise
all the Daleks in this asylum,
rescue Oswin from the wreckage,
escape from this planet
and fix Amy and Rory's marriage.
Okay, I'm counting three lost causes,
anyone else?
DOCTOR:
Oswin, there's a Dalek ship in orbit.
OSWIN: Yeah, got it on the sensors.
The asylum has a force field.
The Daleks upstairs
are waiting for me to turn it off.
As soon as I do, they'll burn
this whole world and us with it.
So, Oswin, my question is this,
how fast can you drop the force field?
-What?
-Pretty fast.
But why would I?
Because this is a teleport,
am I right, Oswin?
Yeah! Internal use only.
I can boost the power, you know,
once the force field is down.
And we can use this to beam us
right off this planet.
But you said
when the force field is down,
the Daleks will blow us up.
We'll have to be quick, yes.
Fine, we'll be quick,
but where do we beam to?
The only place within range.
The Dalek ship.
Where they'd exterminate us on the spot.
Oh, so this is the kind of escape plan
where you survive
about four seconds longer?
What's wrong with four seconds?
You can do loads in four seconds.
Oswin, how fast can you drop
the force field?
I can do it from here.
As soon as you come and get me.
DOCTOR: No, just drop the force field
and come to us.
There's enough power
in that teleport for one go.
Why would you wait for me?
Why wouldn't I?
No idea, never met you.
(TYPING)
Sending you a map
So you can come get me.
This place is crawling with Daleks.
Yeah! Kind of why I'm anxious to leave.
Come up and see me sometime.
(BEEPING)
So,
are we going to go get her?
I don't think that we have a choice.
(SIGHS)
DOCTOR: Okay, as soon as
the force field is down,
the Daleks will attack.
If it gets too explodey-wodey in here,
you go without me, okay?
-And leave you to die?
-Oh, don't worry about me.
You're the one beaming up to a
Dalek ship to get exterminated.
Fair point. Love this plan.
What about Amy?
Keep her remembering, keep her focused.
That'll hold back the conversion.
What do I do?
You heard what she said.
They're subtracting love.
Don't let them.
(DALEKS SHOUTING, MUFFLED)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
DALEK: Prepare to be annihilated!
(BANGING CONTINUES)
DALEK: We are the Daleks!
We are the Daleks!
(BEEPING)
Okay, look at me.
I'm going to be logical.
Cold and logical, okay?
For both of our sakes, for both of us,
I'm going to take this off my wrist
and put it on yours.
Why? Then I'll just start
converting you. That's not better.
Yeah, but it will buy us time
because it will take longer with me.
Sorry, what?
It subtracts love. That's what she said.
What's that got to do with it?
What does that even mean?
It's just arithmetic.
It will take longer with me
because, well, we both know,
we've both always known that...
Amy, basic fact of our relationship is
that I love you more than you love me.
Which today, is good news because
it might just save both of our lives.
How can you say that?
Two thousand years
waiting for you outside a box,
saying it because it's true.
And since you know it's true,
give me your arm.
Amy!
Don't you dare say that to me.
Don't you ever dare.
-Amy, you kicked me out!
-You want kids.
You have always wanted kids.
Ever since you were a kid.
And I can't have them.
-I know.
-Whatever they did to me at Demons Run,
I can't ever give you children.
I didn't kick you out,
I gave you up.
Amy, I don't...
Don't you dare talk to me
about waiting outside a box
because that is nothing, Rory, nothing
compared to giving you up.
-Give me your arm. Let me put this on.
-Get off!
-Just give me your arm!
-Don't touch me!
It's the Doctor's.
-When you were sleeping...
-A Time Lord.
What's the betting
he doesn't even need it?
Then why didn't he just tell us?
Oswin,
I think I'm close.
You are!
-Less than 20 feet away.
-(BEEPING)
Which is the good news.
Okay.
And the bad,
which I suddenly feel is coming?
You're about to pass
through Intensive Care.
(SOFTLY) What's so special
about this lot, then?
OSWIN: Don't know.
Survivors of particular wars.
Spiridon, Kembel, Aridius,
Vulcan, Exxilon.
Ringing any bells?
All of them.
OSWIN: Yeah?
How?
These are the Daleks who survived me.
DALEK: Doc...
-...tor!
-Doc...
-Doctor!
-...tor!
ALL: Doctor!
That's weird.
Those ones don't usually
wake up for anything.
Yeah, well, special visitor.
Okay.
Door,
but it won't open.
They can't be far away now.
Hang on, uh...
Not quite sure but there's
a release code. Let me just...
-Anything happening out there?
-No.
Hang on, I'm trying to think.
Doc...
...tor!
-Doctor!
Oswin, get this door open.
-Oswin, open this door!
-I can't!
-Oswin!
-ALL: Doctor!
DOCTOR: Please get this door open!
DALEKS: Doctor!
Oswin! Oswin, please get this door open!
Help me! Help!
(SILENCE)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
OSWIN: Oh, that is cool.
(OSWIN GIGGLING)
Tell me I'm cool, chin boy.
What did you do?
Hang on.
I think I found the door thingy.
No, tell me what you did.
OSWIN: The Daleks,
they have a hive mind.
Well they don't,
but they have a sort of telepathic web.
The path web, yes.
I hacked into it,
did a master delete on all the
information connected with the Doctor.
But you made them forget me.
Good, huh?
And here comes the door.
I've tried hacking into the path web,
even I couldn't do it.
Come and meet the girl who can.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey!
You're right outside. Come on in.
DOCTOR: Oswin, we have a problem.
No, we don't.
Don't even say that.
I joined the Alaska to see the universe,
ended up stuck in a shipwreck
first time out.
Rescue me, chin boy,
and show me the stars.
DOCTOR: Does it look real to you?
-Does what look real?
-Where you are right now?
Does it seem real?
-It is real.
-It's a dream, Oswin.
You dreamed it for yourself
because the truth was too terrible.
Where am I?
Because you are a Dalek.
I am not a...
...Dalek. I am not a Dalek/
I'm human.
You were human when you crashed here.
It was you who climbed out of the pod.
That was your ladder.
Where am I? Where am I?
Where am I?
I'm human.
Not any more.
Because you're right.
You're a genius.
And the Daleks need genius.
They didn't just make you a puppet.
They did a full conversion.
Where am I? Where am I?
Where am I?
Oswin, I am so sorry.
But you are a Dalek.
The milk Oswin.
The milk and the eggs for the souffles.
Where? Where did it all come from?
Eggs. I'm human.
I am not a Dalek.
I am human. I am not Dalek.
I am human!
IIEggs.-- Fr
It wasn't real.
It was never real.
I am a Dalek. I am a Dalek.
IIEggs.-- Fr
...term...
ed.. 1707,
-Oswin?
-Ex...
...ter...minate.
-Exterminate!
-Oswin.
-No, no, no, Oswin? Oswin.
-Exterminate! Exterminate!
Listen, Oswin.
You don't have to do this. Oswin?
Oswin!
(SPEECH GARBLED)
(SOBBING)
Why do they hate you...
...so much?
They hate you so much.
Why?
I have fought them
many, many times.
We have grown stronger
in fear of you.
I know.
I tried to stop.
Then run.
What did you say?
I've taken down the force field.
The Daleks above
have begun their attack. Run!
-Oswin, are you...
-I am Oswin Oswald.
I fought the Daleks and I am...
...human.
Remember me.
-Thank you.
-Run!
(EXPLOSION)
(SOFTLY) Run, you clever boy.
And remember.
(BOTH GASPING)
How long can we wait?
The rest of our lives.
Agreed.
Right! Let's go!
Let's go.
We're good. Let's go.
-For God's sake.
-(BEEPS)
DALEX: The asylum is destroyed.
Incoming teleport from asylum planet.
We are under attack.
DALEK SUPREME: Prepare to defend.
Defend! Defend!
Explain, Dalek Supreme.
DOCTOR: You know, you guys
should really have seen this coming.
The thing about me and teleport,
I've got a really good aim.
Pinpoint accurate, in fact.
Or, to put it another way...
Suckers!
DALEK: Identify yourself.
-Identify!
It's me. You know me, the Doctor.
The oncoming storm. The Predator.
DARLA: Titles are not meaningful
in this context.
Doctor who?
DALEK: Doctor who?
-Oh, Oswin.
-Doctor who?
Oh, you did it to them all.
You beauty.
DALEKS: Doctor who? Doctor who?
Fellas, you're never going to
stop asking.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Yes!
-I can see you.
-Okay.
Doctor Who!
Doctor... Who!
MAN: This ship contains
the most precious cargo.
WOMAN: The ship's coming
through the atmosphere.
The creatures on board this ship
are not objects to be sold or traded.
-Who sent you?
-That's my dad.
What's going on?
(CREATURE SCREECHING)
This ship's been boarded before.
You think I won't punish those
who get in my way?
WOMAN: I'm launching the missiles.
What was your name again?
Whatever's down there
is coming this way.
Queen Nefertiti of Egypt.
-What is it?
-Dinosaurs, on a spaceship!
(GROWLING)