First we have a note.
Then we have a tune.
Then we have a melody.
Beethoven wrote this when
he first discovered he was going deaf.
All that rage and fury,
out of which, something beautiful.
Am I boring you, Henry?
- It's just a bit stuffy.
Can't you play
something more exciting, sir?
There is one thing you might like.
It's called the Devil's chord.
Tell me more, sir.
It was banned by the church
in medieval times
in case it allows
the Devil to enter the room.
Makes you shiver, doesn't it?
Technically, it's known as a tritone,
but, uh, put it in context and, uh...
Oh! Gosh.
Oh, goodness me. Uh--
What?
Is someone playing a game?
Ta-da!
- Henry, get away from him.
Them.
What?
- Me.
- I'm them.
- You're who?
-"You're who?"
Nice to see you again, kiddo.
- You know each other?
That's my daddy.
Don't be ridiculous.
You didn't look at my name, sir.
Course I did.
It's Henry-- What was it? Henry...
"Henry Arbinger". That's it.
Harbinger.
Think of him as my prelude.
And now his song is sung.
Wh-- Who are you?
My notation is Maestro.
But what are you?
I am...
music.
And you, Mr Timothy Drake,
you're a genius.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're the greatest composer
who ever lived.
Clever enough to find the lost chord.
But it's so sad, Timothy.
You never had the luck.
You never got that break.
I did not.
You're right.
No-Nobody ever understood me.
All those melodies,
stifled and strangled inside you.
All those songs you never sang,
they sit there still,
wrapped around your heart, still beating.
Wrapped so tight.
Would you like me to set them free?
I would love that, yes. Yes.
Music, Maestro, please.
Now.
I wanna see
The Beatles
recording their very first album.
- Seriously?
- Well, you asked.
If I could go anywhere in time and space,
that's where I'd go because my mum,
she had a girlfriend, Claire.
And I loved Claire,
and she was dead into vinyl.
She had all The Beatles albums, so we
used to play 'em every day after school.
Ten years old, I was.
We had Revolver, the White Album--
So, yeah, if I could go anywhere
then that's where I'd go.
That is amazing.
- Oh! Wait, seriously?
- Oh!
- People always say the Titanic.
- Or Mars. Or Bethlehem.
- Oh!
- But The Beatles!
- Why have I never done that before?
- Come on!
- Oh!
- Oh.
February 11th, 1963.
No way. Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Whoo!
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
If we're in the '60s,
what about my clothes?
Good thinking.
Could give you go-go boots.
Oh, I've got eyeliner!
- Oh, eyeliner!
Oh, I want a beehive! I want a beehive!
I've got wigs galore!
♪ Like a sound you hear
That lingers in your ear ♪
♪ But you can't forget
From sundown to sunset, now, now ♪
♪ It's all in the air
You hear it everywhere ♪
♪ No matter what you do
It's gonna grab a hold on you ♪
♪ California soul ♪
1963.
Hey, hey, hey!
- Oh, no way!
It's like the album cover!
I am having the best time!
Look at the cars.
- G-- Oh, come on!
- Abbey Road Studios!
Not called Abbey Road yet.
Right now, in '63,
they are the EMI Recording Studios.
Huh.
And how do we get in?
- Won't they ask who we are?
Oh! Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Hi.
Janet said we could take over,
so you can have ten minutes off.
Oh, right. Thank you. Very kind.
Yep. There's always a Janet.
And everyone wants a cuppa.
- Brilliant.
Good morning.
Cuppa tea?
Uh, yeah.
Make it a strong one. Two sugars.
- Uh.
Boys, do you want anything?
I'm all right for now.
Maybe something stronger later on.
- What do you think, John?
- Now you're talking, Paul, lad.
I just want a good night's sleep.
You keep playing like that,
we'll all have a good kip.
All right. Let's take it from the top.
I thought the chorus--
Don't slide in the harmonies. Just hit it.
Whatever you say, boss.
Hurry up then, George.
Only getting paid seven quid a day.
Uh, good luck.
Thanks, love.
Roll to record.
And a three, two, one.
♪ I've got a dog ♪
♪ He's called Fred ♪
♪ My dog is alive ♪
♪ He's not dead ♪
♪ I love my dog ♪
♪ He loves me too ♪
♪ I haven't got a cat ♪
♪ Only a dog ♪
♪ My dog, my dog, my dog, my dog ♪
♪ I've got a dog ♪
♪ I love my dog ♪
♪ He's my dog ♪
♪ He's not your dog ♪
♪ If you want a dog
Get your own ♪
Hi. Don't mind us.
Just a cuppa tea.
Okay.
Going from the second chorus.
Playing in the last four bars
of the verse.
Good luck, Cilla.
Don't let me down, Cilla.
And a three, two, one.
♪ I love you ♪
♪ You love me ♪
♪ We are two ♪
♪ We are not three ♪
♪ 'Cause you love me ♪
♪ And I love you ♪
♪ We're quite happy ♪
♪ I think ♪
♪ Perhaps ♪
Oh, Cilla.
Don't mind us.
Roll to record.
Look at them.
Everything's gone dull.
No one hums. No one whistles.
No one taps their feet.
I don't get it though.
Music isn't...
Like, you can't lose it
or steal it or kill it.
It's just natural.
You get music
when the wind blows through the trees.
It's called aeolian tones.
The music--
Music is the highest form of thought.
If you take that away...
Finland? That never happened.
If music is gone,
that means everything is changing.
The whole human race
is taking a different path.
Okay, so what do we do?
You take John Lennon.
I'll take Paul McCartney.
Find out what happened
and when it happened.
- Two cups of tea, my darlings.
That's half a crown. Ta very much.
How much?
- That is outrageous.
- Outrageous.
Take it or leave it, sweetheart.
That is daylight robbery.
Ooh. That's me.
Margaret Lockwood in The Wicked Lady.
Now there was a woman.
Statuesque.
Uh, excuse me. Hold on, Paul.
Um, could I just have a word?
I've got a cup of tea for you.
Mr Epstein sent me.
Okay. Um--
Y-You are writing songs
for the band, yeah?
They're not very good, are they?
Oh. Uh.
No. No.
Great.
That's great, lad.
That's how it should be.
It's not like the old days when we had
waltzes and fandangoes and all that.
But waltzes used to exist.
When did they start becoming wrong?
Don't know. Way back. '20s? '30s?
Why? What happened?
We started seeing sense.
What we're doing here today
is the last gasp.
If I can make a bit of money
out of cheap, old rhymes,
then I can settle down
and get a proper job.
It's embarrassing, singing.
Just wanna finish the album, get back
to Liverpool and... [sighs] ...forget it.
But you can't do that.
Wh-- [chuckles] We need ya.
What for? I'm no good at anything.
But, Paul,
see when it's just you on your own,
don't you think
that there must be better songs?
You know, songs that lift you
and devastate you and-and make you soar.
Songs that are-are tucked away somewhere
in-in secret in the back of your mind?
How do you know that?
I-- I just wanna go home.
Forget this life.
Just have me tea and go to bed
with a woman of me own, you know?
It's all I want.
But then, why do I wake up crying?
It's like, sometimes, late at night,
I get this thought.
Like, it's so far away, but it's a note.
A single note.
And then a second.
And a third and fourth and fifth.
And you put them together, and it feels
like the most holy thing on this earth.
Like a G, then an E.
And a G, maybe twice.
And then C.
And if you put words to it,
words right from your heart...
♪ I love you so much ♪
Don't waste me time.
Do you know what you are
with your ideas, pal?
Disgusting. You are disgusting.
What the hell was that?
Yeah, that's it, Vinnie. Nice and safe.
I want that installed on the rooftop
like it is precious china.
Easy, boys. Don't hit the wall.
Right, let's head on up.
Thing is, without music,
dance must be gone.
No one dances anymore.
I mean, can you dance without music?
I mean, you can, but do you want to?
And think about it, Ruby. Love songs.
There are no more love songs anymore.
Oh, my God!
There's no more love songs
in the whole wide world.
- Ooh.
Old London Town!
- Oh, is that smog?
I thought they got rid of that
in the '50s.
We had really bad smog
in December '62, but this?
It's more like a darkening.
The world is darkening.
I live over there.
You do what?
- I live over there.
- What do you mean?
- Shoreditch.
I'm there right now.
Okay, you're gonna have to start again.
In the past, right now,
I live in a place called Totter's Lane.
1963, I parked the TARDIS in a junkyard,
and I live there
with my granddaughter, Susan.
- Ah. Wh--
- Okay?
- Your what?
- My granddaughter.
- Susan?
We could go and have a look but,
you know, timelines.
- Wh-- You-You've got children?
- I did have.
I will have.
Time Lords get a bit complicated.
Yeah, but you've got a granddaughter?
Like, now? Like, today?
Back in our time? My time.
Where is she?
- I don't know.
How do you not know?
The Time Lords were murdered.
Genocide rolled across time and space
like a great, big cellular explosion.
Maybe it killed her too.
Doctor. God.
There we go, Doc.
- Hey, Vinnie!
Thank you very much.
Come on.
Bit of luck,
I'll have you whistling by sundown.
Can't bear whistling, Doc.
All those horrible tunes. No, thanks!
Well, all right.
It's all yours, honey.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. I'm--
I'm not that good.
Uh, you are, sweet. I've seen you.
December '23. King's Arms.
You opened with "One More Sleep"?
Oh, I can't believe you were there.
Ah. It all comes back to Christmas
with you, doesn't it?
I need you to play again.
But what for?
At this moment in time, Ruby Sunday,
you are the only music in the world.
Let's see what happens
if you bring music back.
It's just-- No pressure.
Okay.
I wrote this for my friend Trudy
when a girl broke her heart.
Mmm.
No!
You called?
That was the Giggle!
- Hide!
Uh, do what?
We've gotta hide!
You never hide!
I can't fight this thing.
Okay.
I heard music!
♪ Where are you? ♪
- Who was playing that piano?
The chorus of ancient songs calls me...
...Maestro.
And who...
...are you?
Because I heard music.
And music...
...is mine!
What?
Sound and vision.
Music.
Wh-Who was that?
Were they inside the piano?
- How can they be inside the piano?
- Okay.
- The piano wouldn't work.
- Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
You're scaring me now.
That thing must be part of the Pantheon.
Oh, God.
Oh, Ruby, there are...
vast powers beyond the universe.
I told you, when we first met,
I said-I said, "The Toymaker",
and defeating him took everything.
- It ripped me in half.
- But you survived.
It literally-- It tore my soul in half.
I can't survive that again.
The Toy-- The Toymaker said-- He said--
He warned me.
He said, "My legions are coming."
"My legions are coming."
- He said, "My legions are coming."
- But you made that silence with the sonic.
- That worked, didn't it?
- Yeah.
One trick. Once. That's all you get
with the gods.
- Okay, so what do we do?
- I don't know.
I don't know, Ruby. That is the point.
- I don't know. I--
- No, but you always know.
- I don't.
The last time, I got lucky. Catch.
One trick. Once.
But this thing is stealing music.
I mean, how the--
How the hell is--
- I'm sorry.
But the power of these creatures
is so vast,
the whole world could slide into the pit.
Doctor.
I know you're clever.
I know that.
But I've got news for ya.
The world did not end in 1963.
- Right.
- No, but it didn't.
Okay? I'm living proof.
- I was born in 2004...
...and all my life,
I've had Beyoncé and Sam Fender
and Strictly and tap dancing
and raves and--
Oh, my mum sings "Danny Boy" at Christmas,
when she's drunk, to my gran.
- And don't you see, Doctor?
Music exists.
Come with me.
So when is it for you, back home?
What time are you?
June 2024?
Uh, it's hard to keep track.
But, yeah, I think so.
- June? July?
Well, have we done it? Are we back?
2024. I've brought you home.
This is what we're trying to stop.
But this isn't real.
This is--
- It's just like a parallel universe.
- This is your time.
This is your home
if Maestro isn't stopped.
Where's my mum?
I think without music,
the human race goes sour.
Without any way of expressing
a broken heart,
they go to war, without even knowing why.
Then how am I still alive?
Why don't I fade away?
Because of me.
- Boo!
What?
Maestro, the Doctor.
That was you in '63, wasn't it?
Sweet cheeks.
You stepped from one time to another...
...like the Lord Temporal,
who trapped my father
and bound him in salt.
- Yes?
- The child of the Toymaker?
I should thank you, Doctor.
Daddy was so bad to me.
♪ Daddy was so mean ♪
♪ Daddy was so tough ♪
♪ Daddy daddied me ♪
♪ And that was quite enough ♪
If he was a living game,
you are the essence of music itself?
But what's the point?
You've destroyed the world.
Music is gone. How is that a win?
Not gone!
Darling, hush!
The sound of a nuclear winter.
The purest music of all.
Aeolian tones.
Music without the need of people.
And every song that goes unsung feeds me.
I get stronger and stronger.
Until I can reach out...
...and steal the music of the spheres.
Then the universe will stop turning.
It'll keen in a minor key.
Aeolian tones
across the whole of creation.
And that lament will be
my symphony supreme.
With all of life extinguished.
I'm goin' solo.
How did you enter this world?
Oh.
That would be telling, babe.
No, babes!
Your father established
the rules of fair play!
One thing that he would never do is cheat.
So I have a right to know.
A genius.
A single, silly man
who found the lost chord.
Which means a different combination
of notes would banish you?
I said, "Genius".
And you might be bright.
And hot.
- And...
..."timey wimey".
But genius?
Oh, honey, I don't think so.
What are you doing?
- Everything resonates, Doctor, dear.
Every atom hums.
And anything that plays a tune is mine.
Sing along, Doctor.
Everybody!
What is it? What's hap--
- Maestro!
Controlling the TARDIS.
But I say never.
Never!
Ruby!
- Are we flying?
- Only just.
The only thing I can do
is take us back to 1963.
- Where's Maestro?
- Composing.
- And the next tune might be deadly.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Don't hate me.
Okay, come on.
Come on. Come on, come on, come on.
Come on. Okay.
Strange.
- Did you break it?
- No.
No, no, no, no, no. That's something else.
- Okay.
- Right.
Okay. If we can record the right tune on
the sonic, we can use this as a weapon.
- Right.
- Yeah?
- No, no, no, no.
- Oh. Oh, okay.
We need to find the Notes of Banishment.
Ah, John Lennon's guitar!
That's gotta be a good start.
Okay.
- Okay, but don't you need to be a genius?
Uh--
Oh, just-- No offence.
Just a musical genius.
- Sometimes genius is just hard work.
Yeah?
If I can find the right notes.
Wait a minute.
There's 66 billion trillion
different tunes out there, but...
No, but just wait.
Can you hear that? That music?
Whoa! No, no, no!
Doctor!
I thought that was non-diegetic.
No, no, don't--
Doctor!
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No, no, no, no!
Doctor!
Wait! No, no, no, no!
Put her down!
Can't trick me twice, honey!
- Then fight me!
Huh? Leave her alone!
But she's the only human left
with music in her heart!
Playing lovesick songs
for heartbroken lesbians,
and that just makes me hungry
for all those delicious songs.
Let me go!
- That's right, pretty girl! Sing!
Maestro.
- Maestro, I am asking you. Just--
What?
That's wrong.
What do you mean?
There's a hidden song
deep inside her soul.
- What is it?
What?
Ruby.
What is this?
Christmas.
The music that was playing
the night that she was born.
How could a song have so much power?
And power like him?
- Like who?
- The oldest one.
On the night of her birth,
he can't have been there.
- What for?
- What for? What for? What for?
Who was there?
Enough.
- Whoa!
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
- I've got you. I've got you.
- Okay, okay.
What was it? What happened?
- It's all right. All right? It's okay.
This creature is very wrong.
And this-- this is very, very, very right.
Do you know what this is?
This is the famous Abbey Road piano.
They call it the Mrs Mills Piano.
Oho!
Oh, she was a girl.
We had some adventures, me and Mrs Mills.
But this is the piano that The Beatles
will play on their greatest hits.
"Penny Lane".
"Lady Madonna". All from this.
So I know that this piano is rattling
with all the potential
to send you back to hell.
Hmm.
Music battle.
Go on then.
Do it.
Can you find it?
- The lost chord?
- Are you enough of a genius?
Oh, I would never call myself that,
Maestro.
But I have lived, and I have loved.
And I can only smile like this
because I have lost so much.
I've experienced everything.
Every single thing.
And if that's where music comes from...
...I can find the chord to banish you.
One more.
Just one more.
Bum note.
♪ Maestro ♪
Whoa!
Song time.
Ruby, get the piano!
Sorry to keep harping on.
No, no, no, no, no, no. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
You ain't no genius!
I just wanna go home.
But you can't do that.
We need ya.
What for? I'm no good at anything.
I can't breathe!
And then a second.
And a third and fourth and fifth.
And you put them together, and it feels
like the most holy thing on this earth.
♪ No ♪
Oh, no!
No!
The one who waits is almost here!
Listen.
Listen, listen, listen, listen.
- Here it comes.
- Everywhere!
♪ Music ♪
♪ Figaro, Figaro, Figaro, Figaro ♪
They're making music.
The whole city. The whole world.
- Yes. Yes. Yes.
But there is one thing
that I should warn you about, Ruby,
and this is really very serious.
With all my adventures
throughout time and space,
I have to tell you,
there's always a twist at the end.
♪ There's always a twist
There's always a twist ♪
♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ There's always a twist
There's always a twist ♪
♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ My friend, depend
Press send, let's bend ♪
♪ 'Cause there's always
There's always ♪
♪ Yes, there's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ Hey!
Hey, hey! ♪
♪ We got the bop
And the rock and the Lindy Hop ♪
♪ We got the jive, beehive
And the "Stayin' Alive" ♪
♪ We got the conga and the salsa
And the mighty Big Bopper ♪
♪ The waltz and the schmaltz
And no penalties for faults ♪
♪ There's always a twist
There's always a twist ♪
♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ There's always a twist
There's always a twist ♪
♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ Pretend, descend, Land's End
Make do and mend ♪
♪ 'Cause there's always
There's always ♪
♪ Yes, there's always a twist at the end ♪
- ♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ We ain't no fools from Liverpool ♪
♪ 'Cause there's always a twist
At the end ♪
♪ I always said
That it ends with a twist ♪
♪ That's one good thing
That can't be missed ♪
♪ Have a smashin' little dance
'Cause we know what's best ♪
♪ 'Cause we're the smart girls
From the north-west ♪
♪ Always, there's always
There's always, there's always ♪
♪ Sing along if you've got a twist
Sing along if you kiss the mist ♪
♪ There's a special little dance
You're on the list ♪
♪ There's always, always ♪
- ♪ Always a twist ♪
- ♪ Always, there's always ♪
♪ Always, there's always ♪
♪ Always, there's always
There's always, there's always ♪
♪ There's always a twist at the end ♪
♪ I said, "There's always
A twist at the end" ♪
♪ What you intend I can't defend ♪
♪ I think this song will never end ♪
♪ 'Cause there's always ♪
♪ Always, always a twist at the end ♪
Whew!
Where are we?
In the middle of a war.
One wrong move, and boom...
Doctor!