What in the name of the saints?
But what is it
you are saving them from?
- The Flux.
- What's the Flux?
This is Serving Commander
Inston-Vee Vinder
- leaving his post.
- Five.
So, we still on for Halloween drinks?
- Eight o'clock?
- Don't keep me waiting, you.
Diane. Come on in.
Four.
Hello again, Doctor.
- Who are you?
- Three.
Explain Mouri.
Explain Atropos.
Before Atropos,
Time ran wild.
All time passes through the Mouri.
If the Mouri are broken,
Time shall run unstoppable.
- Two.
- The Temple of Atropos is broken.
You know how to fix this?
So, I made a short-term repair.
Yaz! Tell me what you want?
- One!
- All in good time.
What I learned,
in the immediate aftermath of The Flux,
seems obvious now.
But, it's only obvious
once you've lived it.
The biggest changes to our lives
start small.
Catastrophes creeping in quietly.
And by the time you realise,
the life you once had
is already behind you.
The Dalek Sector is growing.
I thought I made it out.
But, they just keep spreading.
Because, since what some people
keep calling 'the beginning of the end',
who is there left to stop them?
Of course, I call it the Dalek Sector.
I don't know for certain.
But, it helps me understand.
Because the maps definitely don't make
any sense any more.
Or the days.
Everything is disrupted.
But, this isn't about Daleks.
For once, they're not what worries me.
At least we understand them,
you and me, my love.
We've fought them.
It's the other things.
Whatever they are.
Appearing from nowhere.
Feasting on the wreckage.
Coming for survivors of The Flux.
I must admit, some days I feel like
they want to stop me
from getting to you.
But, nothing is going to stop me
I spend my life
walking into new places
and weighing things up fast.
Who's who? Who has the power?
Who is in danger?
How fast danger is coming?
Also, how likely my friends are to die?
I've got good at figuring
all of that out at speed.
- Three.
- Right now, big danger.
No obvious solutions.
Well, one solution.
One massive risk.
- You don't mess with Time.
- All in good time.
You don't put yourself
and your friends
in the midst of a time storm.
Unless there's no alternative.
John Burroughs once said to me,
"Leap and the net will appear."
He was talking metaphorically.
Whereas right now...
I'm sorry!
Had to buy us Time, literally.
We're in the heart of the time storm.
We're sheltering, in broken time,
while I...
No! Yaz...
Dan!
Time is pulling you back.
I'm coming to get you! No!
How did you get in here?
Broken disrupted time.
Everything is corrupted.
Have to rescue them.
No!
- Not me as well!
- I've too much to do...
What's the update, boss?
Trubial monument is down.
Only the central Temple left.
Where are the hostages?
We don't know. No traces.
The only information we have is,
five passenger forms in main Temple.
- Where are we on aerial?
- Aerial shelling now complete.
Should've weakened primary defences
to give us a way in.
Just give the word.
Enough equipment remaining
to breach the entrance?
You said come prepared.
We also have temporal eraser options.
Should we require them.
Where is this?
Why are you... What are you wearing?
- Temporal hazing?
- Happens to the best of us.
When is this?
Ow! What'd you do that for?
She loves doing that.
She so loves doing that.
I do love doing that.
Should block the temporal hazing.
You back with us?
We need to get this job done
and end the siege of Atropos.
Atropos.
That's where I found you.
Tell psy-ops to alert the Mouri skeins,
they should be on standby,
tell the fleet to ramp up second wave
of aerial shelling.
We all know why we're here.
We rescue those hostages,
end the siege, reset Time,
so the universe can function again.
The only way in is through the front...
risking our lives to save others.
The usual.
On my command.
The universe is relying on us.
What you doing here?
Seem to have two coffees
and one of them is a skinny latte
- with an extra shot.
- Weird.
- That's the way I have it.
- Is it?
That's lucky.
You all right?
Yeah, sorry.
Lost my bearings.
So, how was your date?
It wasn't a date.
All right, how was your thing
that wasn't a date?
I fell asleep in front of him.
I thought you were going for pizza.
I fell asleep in my pizza
in front of him.
He was so boring.
I woke up with him picking
bits of mozzarella off my cheek
and asking the waiter
to call an ambulance.
I had to lie and tell him
I was narcoleptic.
I mean, I obviously am,
in reaction to him.
Am I boring you?
No. Just thought I saw...
Doesn't matter.
Why aren't you married?
You're taking
no prisoners tonight, are you?
You're not a kid.
And you're not the ugliest feller
in the city.
So, what's wrong with you?
Why aren't you married with triplets?
It nearly happened, once.
Fifteen years ago? Lost count, now.
I was engaged to get married.
Two days before, she changed her mind.
Ouch.
Said she'd been thinking
about it properly.
Couldn't bear spending
the rest of her life with me. So...
- thought she could do better.
- Oh, my God! Brutal.
It's life, innit?
Nobody gets by without some bruises.
God, I loved her.
When is this?
What?
Did we move? Have we...
Have we done this before?
Why am I here?
I was waiting.
You didn't come. Where were you, Dan?
Where were you, Dan?
- Found you!
- Doctor, what are you doing?
I can't hold on to everything.
Uh...
But, if you go
three doors down,
they've got them half the price.
I was like, "You seen
what they're charging there?"
And they were like, "No, we don't care."
So, I said, "Well, why would I buy them
here for this price
when they're half the price
three doors down."
And she said, and she was so snotty,
"It's up to you, isn't it?"
I said, "Yes."
And I've never stepped foot
inside that shop since,
Who's the loser now?
It's not even like I'm that bothered
about satsumas.
Doctor?
You all right?
Yeah.
What is that?
Oh, you've got a bit of salad dressing.
Yaz, trying to break through
into your timestream,
but there is a barrier,
like something's trying to keep me out.
There we are.
All gone now.
Qualified highest in all streams.
Exceptional honours award.
And a commendation for saving the life
of three colleagues
on your most recent mission.
Any pilot would have done the same.
No. Because they didn't.
You were the only one
to fly into the blaze.
Your training craft received
fatal damage.
You were lucky to escape with your life.
Yes and no.
Yes, the damage to the craft was bad.
No, I don't believe I was lucky.
I made a judgement call and it came off.
That's what we train for.
I remember this.
But, it wasn't you.
You weren't here.
Commander!
Yes. Sorry.
No record of post traumatic
psycho disturbance.
I've taken all offers of counselling
and term-coming.
No problems.
Don't mind me.
I'm trying not to be distracting.
Let me just...
Did you...
Did I...
what?
Nothing.
You do realise
this is a prestigious posting.
With the highest level
of security clearance.
- I understand.
- You'll be permanently at the side
of the Grand Serpent.
It will be arduous.
The Grand Serpent is...
- demanding.
- Yes.
Absolute discretion
and absolute fidelity
- are the minimum expected.
- I understand.
Don't make me regret this.
Meaning?
The posting is yours.
Thank you, Sir, it's an honour.
It is. Make sure you remember that.
Do not let the Grand Serpent down.
Blow the doors in.
I got about 11 Nitros of Reducer left.
I'll use it when the doors go.
Keeps us at the normal speed,
but slows down
the rest of the environment.
We've gotta make the most of it.
Our entire focus is,
locate the Ravagers.
Oh, wow! Supersized Mouri.
Wait, where was I?
That wasn't my timestream.
And why were Dan, Yaz
and that lad there?
You have put yourself
at risk in here, Doctor.
Time is playing games with you all.
You understand what I'm trying to do,
by throwing myself in here.
The pressure of the time storm
will be too much even for you.
I will not let them die.
I can do this.
I can absorb it.
Help me with it and I can help you.
Time resists,
it is pulling you back.
Listen up, Ravagers.
You're intruders in
the Temple of Atropos.
The Temple is surrounded!
There's no way out of here
and no way off this planet.
We've come to reclaim what you took.
You do not belong here.
So, you might as well surrender
to save matters getting too unpleasant.
I know you can hear me!
Tell your remaining troops
to surrender now
or they'll have me to answer to.
Who the hell are you?
And what are you doing in my reflection?
What are you doing here?
Is this the Atropos defence systems?
I'm you. Which means...
this is my past.
I'm in a memory.
What do you mean you're me?
Nah, I don't think so.
I'm your future.
I threw myself into a time storm,
here in the future,
to protect myself and my friends.
But, it threw me down
into my own timestream
in the middle of a memory I've lost.
I'm losing control of it all!
No time
to admire yourself, boss.
Bit of praise for the effective Reducer
wouldn't go amiss.
Yeah, you're pretty smart for a dog.
Oy, language!
What did you call him?
Tell me who you are. All of you!
If this temporal hazing gets any worse,
we'll have to relieve her of command.
We can't risk the mission.
We're your team.
My team?
You talk to her. We'll cover.
It's all right, boss.
We understand the pressure.
Final push.
- We do this, you're clear.
- Clear?
They promised they'll stick to it.
Final attack. Retake the chamber.
Retake the planet.
You'll be free of all this.
That's the point, isn't it?
If you say so.
Why don't I know?
Why don't I remember how this ends?
If you've thrown yourself into
a time storm,
and that storm's thrown you in here,
you might never get back.
And my friends will die,
submerged in their own timestream.
Then you've got
a lot to figure out.
- What am I running from?
- The gun!
Don't shoot!
Why are you dallying here?
I'm not dallying. I'm trying to get out.
Last I knew, I was somewhere else.
Now, I'm not. Again.
Why do you disobey the task?
What task?
Back, vile demons!
I spite you all.
Now, what is this?
Has your mind deserted you?
Are you now a fool?
It really beginning to feel that way.
So, where've you just come from?
Well, Mason Street, clearly.
Mason Street, Edge Hill?
Well, of course Edge Hill! Where else?
That's right by where I live.
Are we there now?
No, sir.
Very far.
Very, very far.
- Is that what you were firing at?
- No.
Those mites,
I've seen them remove people
and objects from this mortal plane.
Wait! Wait! They return...
Right, stay put.
Don't move.
I'm coming in.
Quantum disruption, not exactly helping.
But, you should be safe
from those particles here.
I'm trying to hide you but you keep
fidgeting out of your timestream!
I'm over here, hang on.
Pushing through, wait.
It's not me! The world keeps moving.
I'm hiding you here,
in your own timestream,
while I try and get
the Mouri into place.
But, it's hard.
I mean, borderline impossible.
Time is breaking,
hunting down anomalies.
Which means, there's a problem.
Another problem. A lot of problems.
Not that I want to worry you,
'cos I don't.
But, I have, so sorry.
I'll fix this, just don't disappear.
Good news. I found a ship.
One lone ship.
The last relic of the Lupari,
who seem to have just vanished from
their home galaxy.
Do you think the Flux got them too?
Anyway, we got out the Space port
before it blew up.
Made it through the outer barriers
of the Dalek sector,
without being exterminated. Just.
There are bodies
and wreckage everywhere.
It feels like the last days
of the universe.
And here I am
still doing what I do best,
piloting a ship.
Only now,
I'm watching planets crumble,
and Space lanes fill with debris.
Who'd have thought one thing
could do so much damage?
And anytime I think
we found a brief sanctuary,
life proves me wrong.
Because apparently,
this is the Cyber sector now.
Cyber armies ransacking what's left,
converting the few who remain.
And in the dark moments, I think...
the bad guys won.
I know what you'd say.
Challenges are temporary.
Life is constant.
Don't over think it.
Just move forward.
And I can still hear you
telling me that.
So, I am.
We are, me and Tigmi,
moving forward.
Hoping that you're right.
Hoping we'll see you soon.
And I'm ignoring the creature in a bar,
who told me Atropos is falling,
the Mouri are compromised,
and Time is beginning to run wild.
Because if the Flux is eroding Space,
and Time is breaking down,
then what hope do we ever have
of finding each other again?
Take in that view.
You know who'd never get in here?
Frey Sampor.
'Cos, they don't let losers in.
You've two tasks as guardian
of the Grand Serpent.
Protect me and record the meeting,
so there's no...
misunderstandings later.
Our guests today come seeking a deal.
The Alforia want an alliance
where we shelter them under
our security protocols.
In return,
they provide our population
with food safety
for generations to come.
Everybody wins.
What did you say?
I mean, I can see
that there are benefits for both sides.
Oh. You can see that?
You understand this?
I... Supremacy, I didn't mean...
You want my seat?
Do you want to be me?
Hmm?
I was only expressing solidarity,
Supremacy, my apologies.
I don't need solidarity from a grunt.
What I need is for you to be silent
and do as you're ordered.
Understood.
They've docked.
Be ready.
I don't want to relive this.
I don't want to relive this!
Yaz, again, what are you doing here?
Come on, you're so bad at this.
I don't even
like playing video games.
Nobody calls them video games.
Whatever you wanna call them.
I'm not good at them.
You're helping me,
'cos this lad ain't gonna look at me
if I don't know my way around
a controller.
I'm gonna learn to be ace at this.
Next time I'm in a room with him,
he's gonna look at me and think,
who's the sexy girl
with the nimble fingers?
No human being is ever going
to look at you and think those words.
All right, super freaking out now.
To save you and that lad on Atropos,
who I've not even met yet,
from being overwhelmed by Time,
I took it upon myself to jump into one
of the burnt out Mouri's places.
To divert you from having
to absorb the timeforce.
But, if Time would've overwhelmed me,
what's it gonna do to you?
Well, I've got bit more practice.
Not to mention,
an entirely different biology.
Me and the Mouri are connected.
We're hiding you, all of you,
in your own timestreams.
In your own memories.
Past, present or even future.
What you looking
at me like that for?
Oh, sorry.
I'm split across multiple events,
multiple timestreams.
I can't be constant, multiple crisis.
I'm still trying to work out the plan.
You're camouflaged here.
Because this is where you belong.
The best place to hide you all
is in your own lives.
Except it's not.
These things haven't happened to me.
This isn't my house.
The details are wrong.
Yes, I think there's something is wrong
with your timestream.
Yaz?
Don't blink!
There are angels disrupting
your timestream.
It's stalking me.
- What is it?
- Quit the game.
What's that word?
You've to keep your eyes on it.
If the angels gets to you,
it will propel you back in time.
I won't know where you are.
You could be lost forever
and I won't able to find you.
Yaz! Yaz, I'm being pulled away...
Do you want me to be single forever?
No. Come on, Doctor.
You're in here for a reason.
Fix the future. Fix Atropos.
Protect Yaz and that lad.
Ah, I'm being pulled away again.
Dragged back to Atropos in the past.
Of course, you've made yourself thrones.
You've no shame.
Only pride. You should know that by now.
Surrender now
and your sentences will be merciful.
Banishment or execution?
Surrender to the four of you?
Don't underestimate me.
It's a difficult moral high ground
you occupy.
If you don't stop killing things,
we'll kill you.
If there's further death or bloodshed,
your punishments will be worse.
Erasure of identity.
Isolation prison terms
for the infinite duration
of the universe.
Working for the Division
must be so compromising.
You've already lost.
I'm just trying to reason with you.
How can we have lost
with so many hostages?
You understand what Passenger is?
The Passenger is a long, forbidden form.
Barred from this dimension
for good reason.
A thing of beauty,
A holding entity,
able to store
what it has captured within.
A living prison
with endless capacity.
Hundreds of thousands of life forms
locked away within each Passenger.
Five Passengers.
Millions of lives.
Kept a list, have you? Kept the numbers?
One Passenger destroyed.
- We need the Mouri now.
- I'm trying.
You think we would cower
before the Division
when we have taken control
of its dirty secret?
A planet called Time.
Thinking this could bring
the dark times to an end.
Time is not controllable, Doctor.
It will not do as other beings bid.
It will.
It must.
Here we are still engaged
in the founding conflict.
There is no greater battle than this,
the battle between Time and Space.
And Time shall not lose.
Time shall never surrender to Space.
No planetary mass,
however sophisticated,
can imprison the force of Time.
This planet, this construction,
is not just a fallacy,
not just futile hubris.
It is heresy.
And see how many lives
it has cost.
Keep away from it.
That's a second.
It's a massacre in there.
We can't let her lose anymore.
The Mouri are ready.
The Mouri are connected.
Oh.
Is that Passenger
meant to glow like that?
Mauri.
Tell me you did not bring them here.
- You were warned.
- They shall not have this!
You know the thing
about a Passenger form,
you'd better be sure
you know where they've been
or everything that's held inside them.
Maybe even hidden.
Ready to be summoned.
Because that one's ours.
Infiltrated your Temple.
Substituted for one of yours.
And inside waiting for my command.
Out you come, Mouri.
- This is your time.
- No!
The Mouri must be not allowed back in.
They are banished!
Time is not their prisoner!
Stasis fields now!
We shall not be contained!
Get them transported out of here now!
Mission accomplished, boss.
Yes!
Need your help.
You and me together,
we save my friends in the future
by replicating
what happened in the past.
Same problem, same solution.
Embed yourselves in the Temple
as you did before.
The Passenger is there.
We need four of you
to replace the burned out Mouri.
Let four be waiting.
You have to do this
or Time will fracture
across all of Space. Please!
Come on!
Come on, make hyper for me.
Whoa.
I missed that rush.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How are you doing, Tigmi? Huh?
Slightly elevated,
but that's to be expected, right?
Right. I'm hoping
the nav charts up-to-date.
They are, but they're not good.
Dalek Empire expanding over here.
Sontaran sector spread over here.
And us exiting the Cyber Zone
as fast as we can.
Wait, what's that?
Did we make it out or...
- Guess not.
- Prepare to convert organic lifeforms.
Yeah? Convert this.
How many Cybermen
in this part of the galaxy?
Seven billion,
three hundred and thirteen thousand,
four hundred and nine.
I like our odds, Tigmi.
So, what is happening to Time?
I mean, I get what happened
with the Flux,
but something has started
affecting Time.
Correct. Flux event
affected the Planet Time.
Temporal centre cannot hold...
I have no idea what that means,
but it doesn't sound good.
Okay, so what is the strategic aim
of the Cyber race post flux?
Secure territorial advance.
Convert all organic lifeforms remaining.
- And then what?
- We shall command. We shall rule.
Over what?
There is barely anything left.
The universe is disappearing.
All that is left shall be ours.
The Cyber victory shall be ultimate.
It shall be hollow. Pointless.
So, you guys, Daleks and Sontarans,
all fighting for the spoils,
as if nothing has changed.
In the end, you'll come down
to fighting each other.
Wiping each other out.
Actually, it's quite a good thing.
What is your mission?
- What?
- What is your mission?
I'm one person
out here in a broken universe.
My mission doesn't impinge on you.
I must record.
Fine.
Just put...
love.
Incorrect.
What?
Love is not a mission.
Love is an emotion.
Emotions are not missions.
And that's why you're dead on the floor,
and I put you there.
Love is the only mission.
Idiot.
Right?
I'm gonna get us to where we need to be
and who we need to be with.
That's my promise to you.
Thank you,
my valued Alforian friends.
Well, it looks like
we've come to an agreement.
On one condition.
You can stop the recording now, Vinder.
- Supremacy, I'm duty-bound.
- Shut it off.
Was my order unclear?
Stopping recording, sir.
You're sheltering a number of dissidents
on Alforus Extant.
I'm going to give you
a list of nine people.
Five of them are be returned to us
to face justice.
They must face the consequences
for their treasonous actions.
The other four...
The other four are family members
of my dear opponent
and vocal critic, Frey Sampor.
They need to have an accident.
It's important they're involved
in an unexpected tragedy.
Natural disaster.
Landslide, hunting accident. You decide.
You don't need to tell me.
But, they have to die.
And those are my final conditions.
And you want to make this official?
They're dead. You saw the reports.
An accident on the Lunar range.
You want to report that
the Grand Serpent is responsible.
It was his condition for the alliance.
There's no evidence on the recording.
No. He asked me to stop the recording.
What do you want to achieve here,
Commander Vinder?
He needs to be held to account.
You understand this report
will reach him if filed?
There are processes though, right?
Other people see it.
There are whistle-blower protocols.
Established by the Grand Serpent.
Have you spoken to your family
about any of this?
No. You're the first
as my commanding officer.
I took an oath.
I swore my loyalty to our constitution.
Not to any one person.
Something bigger, more important.
So... here's a choice.
I can submit this.
Or I cannot submit this.
Don't make me relive this bit.
People need to know the truth.
Submit it.
Sit down, Commander!
Hi, it's me.
I won't be coming back off tour
when I expected.
It may be a lot longer
before I see you again.
I don't want you to worry,
but there was an incident.
I was immediately reposted.
I can't say any more because...
I'm sorry.
I was doing the right thing.
I'm permitted one message.
I hope it gets to you.
I love you.
Time's correcting.
I'll file the report for Division.
I've seen that before.
Oy!
You know the rules.
Don't touch what you can't afford.
We know each other.
Temporal hazing getting to
the boss again.
Time to move.
Bring the Passengers.
We'll extract the hostages
back on-board the ship.
We have done
as you asked, Doctor.
We have returned
four Mouri to your time.
Now, you must return.
You must not linger
in your own timestream.
Not yet.
Not just yet.
The course of Time
will break you.
But, this is my only chance
- to find out more.
- More?
Who I was. Who I am.
It's all in here,
if I can just find it.
Your body is breaking, Doctor.
We can sense it. You must leave.
One more memory!
One more piece of my past.
Let me have some...
some explanation.
You will die in here.
Just give me something!
Give me the end,
give me the end of what I was in.
- No.
- You can't force me out!
Stop fighting now, Doctor.
Who are you?
Where am I?
You think you can navigate
all those timestreams
without anyone noticing?
You're fighting a lost cause.
You need to stop.
Lost causes are my specialty.
Not this time.
There'll be no glory
awaiting you on this one.
You seem to think
you're very well-informed.
I'm telling you,
the damage to Time is already done.
As intended.
- Intended?
- Hm.
The Flux event was spatial,
but it was possible
it wouldn't be enough.
The Ravagers, Swarm and Azure,
are rare and useful creatures.
Now, they have been reintroduced.
Think of them as a temporal poison
or contagion.
I'm sorry, I'm normally very good
at keeping up with things,
but you lost me quite early on.
Where are we?
And how do you know me
and I don't know you?
Always the wrong questions.
This universe is over, Doctor. Hm?
And you get to call it, do you?
Everything has its time.
Nothing is forever. Nothing is certain.
Not you
and not this universe
you seem to love so much.
This universe is home
to innumerable species and lifeforms.
Don't lecture me, Doctor.
Not when you should look to yourself.
The Flux wasn't an accident.
It wasn't a naturally occurring event.
It was made. It was placed.
- What?
- Because of you.
What are you talking about?
All is ending.
And don't come looking for this.
You can go.
I will not go!
No, no, no! Put me back, put me back.
I want to go back in.
I have to get back in.
- Doctor, it's okay...
- It's not okay!
Not for me!
- You don't understand anything.
- All right.
I had a chance while it was broken...
Well, it's not now.
The Mouri, they're all back.
You saved our lives.
Well done, Doctor.
Did you have fun in there?
Discovering the past you've lost?
You may have forgotten, but we did not.
We brought you here
knowing what you would do.
This is only the beginning.
I've seen this stuff before.
Particles of the Time force.
Tiny fragments of temporal destruction
which will erode whatever they touch.
You may have repaired,
but Time is unleashed for long enough.
The damage is done.
And if the Flux wrecked Space...
then we have disrupted the flow of Time.
- However briefly.
- No, you haven't.
And we're going to stop you, right?
Right, Doctor?
Dan Lewis.
We have something of yours.
You're not the only one
who can hide things
in Passenger, Doctor.
- Where am I now?
- Di!
Dan! I can't get to you.
What happened to you?
What're you doing here?
- Stay there, Dan.
- I've gotta get her.
You can't, you mustn't.
- Course I can. Get off me!
- Do as you're told.
You have no idea
what you're dealing with, I do.
Stay there!
I'll help you get her back.
Promise.
No, she's our toy now.
What do you want?
To reign in hell.
Sorry. What is this?
Stick your head in.
Go on.
What!
Is this a TARDIS?
It is, isn't it?
I didn't even think these were real.
Wait.
This can get me home.
After all this time.
Can I pilot it? Will you show me?
No. Get in.
Doctor, seriously.
We can't leave here without her.
She's not here, Dan.
We'll get her back. I promise.
We'll get Vinder home,
we'll rescue Diane,
we'll find out who's behind the Flux,
and what it's got to do with me.
Why would it have anything
to do with you?
Does everything have to be a discussion?
Go on.
In.
Did you repair?
Can you repair?
I really hope so.
I'm sorry.
I was doing the right thing.
I'm only permitted one message.
I hope it gets to you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Don't we Tigmi?
You know, we'll break it
if we watch it too many more times.
I wonder if he looks different.
We're coming, Vinder.
We waited.
And now we're looking and we're close.
We'll be there soon.
Me and your beautiful
as yet unborn child.
This is your home?
It was.
Looks like the Flux
went through here too.
I can take you anywhere.
No. I have to find someone.
Mate...
it's a lost cause.
No, I know she would have been here.
I need to find her.
Stay in touch.
Whenever you need us, press '0',
it's a direct line to us.
Be safe.
I'm back home.
I came looking for you.
But, there's no home left.
The Flux took that, too.
But, I'm not giving up.
I'll find you.
Whatever it takes.
Doctor!
Oh, no.
- That you yelling?
- What's the matter?
- What's that?
- A Weeping Angel.
- Don't blink.
- Why not?
Keep your eyes on the Angel.
Stay behind me.
I think...
I think I just blinked.
It's at the controls, Doctor.
What's it doing?
The Angel has the TARDIS.
Can you state
your name, please?
Claire Brown.
We're missing a little girl,
- ten years old.
- Maggie!
Maggie!
It's happening again.
Was that scarecrow there
a minute ago?
Everyone
in the village disappears
on the 28th of November, 1967.
Tonight.
Gerald, what's going on?
Jericho, wait!
I'm not blinking!