No! No, no, no.
So, if we can't get home,
and if the TARDIS isn't broken,
then it means what?
Planet Earth is broken or 2025 is broken?
Have we been invaded or hit by
a meteor or swatted by a giant moth?
Oh.
Imagine a moth that big!
But really?
'Cause my parents are back home.
And if this is Friday,
then they go to this bar with their mates
and my dad sings and everyone laughs
and then the whole room ends up singing.
Is that still happening, Doctor?
Are they safe?
I hope so.
You hope?
Come here.
I will meet your mum and dad.
And I will make your dad laugh.
And your mum can whistle at my behind.
And I will sing. I will do the singing.
That is a promise.
You can't promise.
Look at me.
I can.
I will.
I do.
Oh. [chuckles]
Right. Right.
Belinda Chandra, we go out there,
we take another Vindicator reading,
because each single reading
brings us closer to home.
Where have we landed?
Uh…
Oh.
500,000 years in the future.
We have jumped, baby.
But that's massive.
Do we still exist?
I mean… I mean me, I mean human beings.
Is there still a human race
in 500,000 years?
There is always a human race.
You voyage out there and own it.
Far and wide, across the stars.
-Come and see?
-W-Wait.
Do they still speak English?
The TARDIS translates.
Try it.
Do we get to change our clothes?
Girl, you are beginning to enjoy this!
At last. Come on!
[♪ "Toxic" playing]
[both chuckling]
What, what, what, what, what.
-Okay!
-Come on.
That looks good.
[alarm blaring]
Hiya. I hope you don't mind.
My name is the Doctor, this is Belinda.
We're just popping in, really.
Helmets!
Attach!
-Better had.
-[leader] Auto-seals on!
-And jump, jump, jump!
-[both] What?
What do you mean jump? But we're not--
[both screaming]
[♪ theme song playing]
[Belinda screams]
It's okay. It's okay.
Look.
[Belinda grunts]
[Doctor panting]
[Belinda panting] Oh, my God.
Life with you.
I know. I know, I know.
But…
look.
[Belinda exclaims]
Explain yourselves.
Immediately.
My name is the Doctor.
This is Nurse Belinda Chandra.
Who's your commanding
officer back at base?
Squadron Leader Chinchappa.
Well, I'm higher than Chinchappa.
See?
Apologies.
I am Platoon Leader Shaya Costallion.
I was not informed of your presence.
Well, that's the point.
We're like mystery shoppers.
Now, we just need to vindicate--
Done. Babes, we're vindicated.
And now you can return us to our blue box
which is in your ship thing in the sky.
-Immediately.
-But how do we do that?
This is a test?
-Yes.
-Yes. Yes.
-[Belinda] Yes.
This is Planet 6-7-6-7 and the atmosphere
is charged with Galvanic Radiation.
It would strip the engines bare.
The ship needs to
slide down at retrograde velocity.
Which will take how long?
Five hours.
So,
we've got five hours?
Can we breathe for five hours?
You can breathe in
that suit for five months.
Correct answer. Good.
So, imagine I don't know
anything about this mission.
Tell me, from scratch,
what the hell are you doing here?
Because Galvanic Radiation is tough.
Nothing can live on a rock like this,
but you've travelled all this way.
What for?
Colony Base 15.
Basic mining operation with
a mercury drop-line,
stripping a layer of Carbon 46.
Fifteen days ago all contact was lost.
Base went silent.
-How many colonists?
-Thirty-five.
Trooper 3, any signs of life?
Nothing. No movement.
No damage to the dome.
We can't scan for heartbeats because
of the radiation, so there's still hope.
Hope is irrelevant.
Thank you.
Troopers, advance.
The airlock only takes six.
Doctor and Belinda with me,
plus Troopers 1 to 3.
Troopers 4 to 9, follow us in.
10, maintain exterior guard.
[Trooper 1] Internal team, unmask.
[Shaya] Discard flight packs.
Trooper 2, sortie, take Walkway One.
Any threat to life,
you have permission, shoot to kill.
I keep thinking,
this planet's uninhabited,
but they're mining.
-Could something live underground?
-Impossible.
That radiation,
it soaks through everything.
Right down to the core.
This whole world is cold,
lifeless and dead.
You should stay suited.
Oh, I'm just not loving the look, babes.
I come in peace.
It's not appropriate to call me babes.
Okay, hon.
We have a body.
-Don't touch them!
-No, but they might still be alive.
Okay, no. Sorry, that's…
They've been dead for a while.
[Doctor] I'd say that
he's broken his neck.
Or…
broken everything.
Oh, my gosh.
This one has been shot in the back.
Laser fire.
There must've been a fight.
But why?
[Belinda pants]
Nothing in here.
This one's got a broken neck.
[Doctor] This one is laser fire.
"Chalona Rosani."
I'm sorry, Chalona.
We will find out what happened to you.
They broke all the mirrors.
Every single room. There's no mirrors.
[Shaya] You're right. Same in here.
Whatever did this was strong.
Half of them have been shot,
half of them have been assaulted.
What sort of fight is that?
[Belinda] What if no one's alive?
What do we do then?
What we should've done in the first place.
Nuke this site from orbit.
[device beeping]
There's a heartbeat!
Weapons up.
Single heartbeat, inside that room.
-It could be a survivor.
-It could be the killer.
It could be both.
[beeping continues]
[Shaya] Squadron, keep a safe distance.
Can you take me home?
Honey, we can do whatever you want.
-Do not approach.
-Doctor, be careful.
I have a daughter on Monpasso.
And she's with her grandad
and she's two years old.
And I just want to see her.
That's Sal.
I shot her, all right. I did it.
But she were gonna kill me.
You, do not move.
Eyes on me at all times.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Who are you?
My name is Aliss Fenly
and I just want to go home.
Confirmed on the manifest.
Aliss Pabba Fenly, 28.
Citizen of Monpasso.
One daughter, Pelody.
I need you to keep everything audible.
No private conversations.
-[Doctor] Okay. Gotcha.
-Yes.
It doesn't matter the year.
Signing still makes some people paranoid.
Hi. My name is the Doctor.
I don't need a doctor.
I just want to go home.
Aliss, tell us exactly what happened.
Why did you kill this woman?
But they all…
They all went mad.
Every single person
just went mad and it all happened so fast.
But not you?
But that's Sal and she was my friend.
But she was gonna kill me
with her bare hands.
I have never fired a gun in my life,
but what else could I do?
I'm just a cook.
I've been here for 12 months
and I cooked for them and that's all.
But it's not even cooking.
I just open a flat-pack protein
and add some salt.
And that's what I do every single day.
But I had to kill my best friend.
Are you hurt?
I'm sorry, I don't know how to sign.
But your arm, does it hurt?
I ran and I fell.
Everyone was panicking.
-Can I--
-Do not approach.
Oh, come on.
Do I just clip it on?
Yeah. Just… There you go.
Just talk.
Hi.
It's okay.
I'm a nurse.
A nurse who can't sign?
That's against the law.
Well, we have different laws.
But you're right, it should be the law.
Aliss. Can I ask?
You've been on your own for a long time?
Fifteen days.
[Doctor] Hmm.
What happened? Do you know?
They all went crazy.
Was there noise?
A gas?
This mineshaft operates as a mercury drop.
Was there any mercury that escaped?
-I don't know.
-Why did they smash all the mirrors?
It's okay. It's okay.
Is there a medical pack or something?
So we just abandon all protocol,
is that it, ma'am?
Well, she doesn't look like she could
break the necks of half the crew.
You hope. And hope is irrelevant.
Okay.
Doctor, we need to get to Central Control.
Stay here if you want--
Oh, I gotta see that.
I won't be long. Belinda's got you. Yeah?
Bel, be careful of her.
I can still lip-read.
Troopers, 2 to 6, stay on guard.
Clear the body.
Fifteen foot radius round
Aliss Fenly at all times.
Any sign of trouble, shoot to kill.
Sorry it's only a basic pack.
Um, thanks, but I don't know
what any of this is.
You're a funny sort of nurse.
Well, that has been said.
I suppose it's common sense.
Bandages, swabs.
Simolin!
It's just a graze.
I'm gonna clean it
and then it will stop stinging.
I know you've had a terrible time.
But we're gonna do
everything we can to help.
That's so kind.
All clear, safe to proceed.
No bodies.
Maybe they ran from this place first.
That's a nice thought.
So, what? This is the seed-well, yeah?
This is where they first dropped
the mercury-lines and drilled down.
Capable of hauling up two
blades of Carbon 46 every day.
[Doctor] Hello!
No one home.
A well that runs five miles deep
beneath the planet's crust.
Where light has never been before.
Nothing's responding.
Someone's put a good old-fashioned
restraining bolt on the system.
There.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa. Don't hit the roof.
Careful, boss.
Good shot.
I was brought up in the wildlands.
Shooting drought-sharks
from the age of six.
I could run faster than a snake-lighter.
That's how I got into the forces.
Fourteen years old.
That's a bit young.
The fight began the day I was born.
I'm a citizen of Lombardo.
Oh.
Tough.
Brutal.
So in this century Lombardo's
a joint foundation with Planet Earth.
-Belinda's from Earth.
-From where?
Planet Earth.
-Never heard of it.
-Stupid name for a planet.
But the human race, you've heard of that?
Not in these parts.
But Earth is part of
the foundation right now, that's a fact.
Your tests are very strange.
Now, see if you can revive
the Base Log Stats and Index File.
Let's find out what happened here.
[Belinda] It's bad luck,
me and the Doctor coming along.
'Cause you were a squad of 11
and we made it 13.
[chuckles] You both say funny things.
What does that mean?
Oh, has that gone?
Thirteen is unlucky,
is that an old Earth thing?
An old what thing?
Earth.
The human race?
What's that then?
Have you ever heard of--
[gasps]
What?
-[Trooper 3] What is it?
-What is it? What happened?
I thought I saw…
[sighs]
I'm getting paranoid.
-What did you see?
-I didn't.
Anyone there?
Honestly, there's nothing.
It's just me.
Sorry, Aliss.
I want to go home.
Is it ready?
Yeah.
Just paste that on.
Here I am, teaching the nursing staff.
You're amazing. Thanks, Mo.
Okay.
I'm just going to paste this
onto the wound.
I was saying,
traditions of the human race.
Have you ever met any? Humans, I mean.
I never heard of you.
They've wiped all the video chains.
Why would they do that?
Everything's been erased.
Everything…
has been restored.
-What's that thing?
-Magic.
Can you find the last entry?
Troop Leader,
does this doctor have authority over me?
Right now, he does. Yes.
[Trooper 1] It's still corrupted.
-We have fragments, hold on.
-[distorted shouting]
Base Commander's final statement.
It came from the well.
It came out of the well
and we don't know how to stop it!
[Trooper 8] Ma'am.
-Not now. Thank you.
-[Trooper 8] It's just…
We checked the walkways.
We found the rest of them dead.
Which confirms,
Aliss Fenly is the only one left alive.
[Belinda] It's so strange.
'Cause the Doctor said,
and I should mention, I hardly know him.
Isn't that strange?
But he's the expert
and he said to me that everyone--
[screams]
What? What is it? What's…
-What's happened?
-What is it? What did she do?
No, she didn't do anything.
Um…
I'm st… I'm stupid.
There's nothing there.
-Sorry.
-Yeah, but that's twice now.
What did you see?
Please, can you tell me
what you're saying?
I'm sorry, Aliss.
I… I didn't mean to scare you.
I just…
I thought I saw something behind you.
But there isn't, isn't there?
Look at me.
I'm all clean.
It's just me.
-What did it look like?
-Well, it didn't.
It's an empty room, there's no one there.
You thought you saw a person?
Well, I… I didn't, did I?
Now, I-I've got this dirty.
All the same.
-Stay where you are, Aliss Fenly.
-Where exactly am I gonna go?
[Trooper 2] Keep it calm, thank you.
What?
Nothing.
-Did you see something?
-No.
Then what was that?
Nothing.
It's a great big empty room.
There can't be anything, can there?
Aliss.
Sorry. Cast to Trooper 2.
Aliss, turn to your right.
I don't know what you're trying to prove.
[sighs] Leave her alone, Mo.
-Come on.
-No, but…
Whoa!
There's nothing there. Look.
I can see there's not anything.
There's literally nothing.
I saw something.
And you saw it before,
you did, you saw it.
-But there's nothing there.
-Yeah, but I saw something.
[stammers] I know what you're saying.
And I've seen it before.
This is how it started.
This is how I ended up killing my friend
before she killed me.
There is absolutely nothing behind me.
There's nothing there. Nothing.
Okay.
Let's prove it.
Hanno, I'll keep guard.
I want you to correspond.
Establish Aliss Fenly as a centre point
and execute a full circle.
Ple… Please, leave me alone.
Look, she's terrified.
You will be quiet or you will be
considered a threat to life.
You will stay looking at me.
Do not look away.
Hanno, execute the move.
Yes, sir.
Him. Isolate him.
Can you isolate his sound?
There's no coverage, he's too deep.
We don't know what it is!
We don't know what it is.
Like…
Like… [stammers, groans]
Oh, my old, old head.
This planet is flooded
with Galvanic Radiation.
Where does it come from?
The sun. But it's just a Grey Star now.
Nothing special.
But a Grey Star is
a star that's collapsed.
-What was it before?
-It was an Xtonic star.
But that's ancient history,
400,000 years ago.
The sun burnt out, the wars came,
they stripped all the carbon
off the surface and left it ruined.
When you say Carbon…
Carbon 46.
And the definition of that is?
Diamonds. This is a diamond mine.
The entire surface of this planet
was once made out of diamonds.
What?
Please stop.
Or what?
What is this planet called?
6-7-6-7.
The old name.
400,000 years ago,
what was the planet called?
It was called Midnight.
I've been here before.
[shrieks]
[gasps]
-What did you do?
-It wasn't me.
-I didn't do anything!
-She was just standing there!
Stop, stop, stop. Get back! Get back.
-What happened?
-She threw her across the room.
[Belinda] She did not.
[breathes heavily]
No, Mo, don't!
Come back!
-What did you do?
-It wasn't me.
It wasn't her. Mo, come back!
Just listen to me. Come back here!
-She's dead.
-Mo, don't go behind Aliss!
Don't go anywhere behind her!
Come here! Don't you see?
[stammers] What do you mean?
There is something behind her.
Hold your positions. What happened?
Everyone, stay where you are.
-Report, Trooper 2.
-Is she dead?
-I don't know, ma'am.
-She's dead.
-I trained with her brother.
-[Mo] It was so fast.
-Did you do this?
-Just try and stay calm.
I do not take orders from you!
-Did you kill her?
-No!
Then who did?
There's something behind me.
All right?
There's something behind me!
I don't know what it is.
No one knows what it is.
But it can't be seen
and it can't be stopped.
There's something behind me all the time.
Now please, help me.
Aliss…
explain what you mean.
Something came out of the well.
That's what they said.
It came out the well,
and they said it was laughing.
Now it's behind me.
Just look. Look, behind her.
Please, all of you, look!
[stammers] It doesn't make sense,
there can't be something behind her,
not from every angle.
Try telling it that.
Look.
No!
This is just an illusion or a trick.
We saw what happened to the base,
they all went mad.
No! Hold on! Listen--
Permission to override
the orders of this civilian, ma'am.
-Permission not given.
-Hanno was my friend.
Permission not given.
-Now listen to the Doctor.
-No, no.
Listen to Belinda.
Bel, what do you mean?
Why can't we go behind Aliss?
It's like…
It's like this.
If this is Aliss,
and this is us facing her now,
there is something behind her.
And if you go behind it,
you die.
If it was a clock-face,
you die at midnight.
[Belinda] That's what happened.
That is what I saw.
That's why I keep telling you stand back.
Don't go behind her.
Don't go directly behind her
or you're dead.
[Trooper 1] In that case…
if something is standing behind,
then why don't we get rid of you?
Because if you kill me,
it goes behind you.
What?
You think it went for me first?
You think it crawled its way
out of hell to get to me?
You idiot.
I'm nothing.
I'm just the only one left.
Half of them broken, half of them shot.
They killed each other to get rid of it.
But if you kill the host,
it jumps over to you.
It hides behind your back
and it stays there forever.
Cassio, step away.
Cassio, that's an order.
Doctor, you said you'd been here before.
When was that?
A different life.
Back when the world was made of diamonds.
[chuckles]
And I met something…
so vile.
It had no face.
No name.
No self.
I had never been so scared in my life.
-What did it do?
-It had fun.
Oh. [chuckles]
It played games.
Uh-huh.
[Doctor] I think it was learning.
[Cassio] You saw this 400,000 years ago?
And you're listening to him?
He might have information.
-[scoffs] Then I'm declaring a Red Code.
-Wait, you can't do that.
This is exactly what a Red Code is for.
When the leader is incompetent.
Am I seconded?
Yes, sir.
[Cassio] Then it's done.
Until such time as we reach
a disciplinary court,
the Red Code stands.
You will stand down,
Shaya Costallion, right now.
I think that we should all just calm down.
And you will be silent
or you will be shot!
Clearly, there is something at work here.
Clearly, bodies have been broken
by some kinetic force
manipulated either by Fenly,
or by something in collusion with,
or in control of her.
-And I maintain--
-No, don't.
If it exists,
we will bring this entity into the open.
We will examine it.
And if necessary, we will destroy it.
Trooper 2?
-Yes, sir?
-[Cassio] Do you volunteer to engage?
-Yes, sir.
-I'm telling you.
-Do not--
-One more word.
Either we disprove this story
or we meet the enemy.
Prepare to engage.
-Don't look. Don't look!
-Shut up!
Please.
-[shrieks]
-[gasps]
[grunts]
[both gasp]
Cassio, stop!
-Don't move! No, no!
-[screams]
[Belinda] No! No!
Don't move!
[Doctor] Stop! Do not move! Stop!
[screams]
-[screams]
-[Cassio pants]
-No way.
-[Doctor] All of you, look down!
Do not move!
[shrieks]
-[shrieks]
-[whimpers]
[Doctor] Cassio, stay where you are!
Stay where you are!
Cassio, turn away!
-[Trooper 7] Cassio, no!
-Cast to Trooper 1.
Aliss…
-turn 180.
-Mm-hmm.
[Cassio shrieks]
-[gasps]
-[both scream]
[Belinda gasps]
I had to.
-I had to. He was out of control.
-That's what it turns us into.
Shaya, gun down.
But it's not my fault.
I know.
I really know.
What do we do?
We leave this place.
The mission has failed. We retreat.
I'm sorry.
You're contaminated.
[whimpering] But…
my daughter. [sobbing]
We can't leave Aliss behind.
Can't we move her?
Okay, we can't step behind her,
but can't we manoeuvre her?
Somehow? Back to the ship?
She's not leaving this planet.
Not with that thing.
That's what it wants.
To get out.
-But we can't abandon her.
-That's not what I said.
Don't turn your back on me.
Please, don't turn your back on me.
Doctor, stay where you are.
Too many people have died.
And now it stops.
I am now addressing
the thing behind Aliss Fenly.
What?
My old friend.
You have waited 400,000 years.
But who are you?
Are you there?
What are you?
[distorted whispering]
-What was that?
-Did it say something?
Oh.
Aliss.
Maybe that's how you survived.
You can't hear it.
[whispering continues]
[stammers] What is it saying?
What is it? What's it saying?
[inhales shakily]
It knows my name.
[breathing shakily]
Oh, yes.
What?
There it is.
[Doctor gasps, chuckles]
It's behind you.
I know.
No, no.
I'm talking to the thing behind you.
And behind that…
What is… What did you see?
The way out.
[chuckles]
Oh, and I'm an idiot, because I forgot
what type of mine this is. Oh!
Everybody, get ready to run.
And I mean run!
Belinda, we should have
never unsuited, babes.
We are gonna have to work really,
really fast.
Shaya, how many in the airlock at once?
-Six.
-Six?
Okay, there's seven of us.
-Shaya, get ready with that pistol.
-For what?
'Cause you are the best shot in the land,
yeah?
And I need you to fire twice.
Aliss Fenly, get ready.
And now I am talking to
that thing behind Aliss Fenly.
You stone-cold murderer.
If the thing behind you
always gets destroyed,
what if the thing behind you is you?
Shaya, left hand pipe vent.
Right hand pipe vent.
Mercury.
This mine operates
a line drop of Mercury 16.
It's going to reflect it.
It broke all the mirrors.
[Shaya] It will see itself.
What will it do to me?
Aliss, whatever it does to you, yeah,
you have got us, okay?
We are with you, okay?
Everybody, eyes on Aliss. Yeah.
Are we gonna see it?
Do we look?
-Do we look away?
-I don't know.
[shrieks]
[grunts]
Okay, run.
Run, run, run, run.
[Belinda] We can't stop.
[Doctor] I wanna see it.
[gasps]
[Shaya] Troopers 7 and 9, you go first.
Get Aliss out.
-Come on.
-You should've got out.
I'm not leaving you behind.
Your flight packs are dead.
Just run as far as you can.
Hurry up. Hurry up!
Helmets!
What was that?
Are we okay?
But what happened?
Was that the thing?
[breathing heavily] Doctor, what happened?
[beeps]
-Airlock's clear.
-I am sorry.
I'm sorry, but we are not going anywhere.
We can't.
You don't think?
It's here.
It's not me.
Well, it's not me.
[breathing shakily]
I swear, it's not me.
It really isn't me, it really isn't.
I don't think it's me.
-No.
-Belinda.
-No. No, no. [crying]
-[Doctor] No, Belinda, it might not be.
[distorted whispering]
It's whispering.
Oh, Bel.
Is it behind me?
I'm so sorry.
It is not your fault.
Take me.
No.
Whatever you are.
Stand behind me.
Doctor.
I promised that I would keep you safe.
And I'm telling that thing behind you…
Whatever you are.
You can walk the universe on my back
if you just set her free.
Doctor, the physical construction of this
human race, is it similar to Lombardic?
-What?
-Is the torso constructed the same?
-Basically.
-[Shaya] Then a shot fired
three millimetres above the superior
vena cava of the heart could mean death,
or it could mean
the narrowest of survival.
-No. No.
-No, no.
-No.
All you need…
is a very good shot.
But it'll go to you.
This is my job.
[sighs]
I got you. I got you.
[Mo] Med-lines. Out of the way.
-[Doctor breathing heavily]
-[med-line charges, pulses]
-[grunts]
Power up to 60
and apply to the heart five times!
[Shaya] Serving Officer Shaya
Costallion squadron 775.
I ran as a child.
I ran from the wildlands.
I ran from those monsters
and never looked back.
And I ran across the galaxy with one aim.
To do my duty.
To help. To protect.
To bring hope.
No!
[panting]
[breathing heavily]
Simolin.
[grunts]
[Doctor] It's all right.
It's okay, it's okay.
I've got you. I've got you, Bel.
-My… My heart…
-Is fine.
-Okay, okay.
-We got it just in time.
Super-skin-stitch. All mending.
-Okay. Okay, okay.
-Okay?
What happened?
It's gone.
And Shaya?
I'm sorry.
I couldn't. I tried.
Did it work?
Are we safe?
Yes.
Doctor…
they'd never heard of the Earth.
What's happened to the Earth?
I don't know.
How could the Earth not exist?
And Troop Leader Shaya should be
recommended for posthumous recognition.
Bravery in the face of impossible odds.
And Cassio.
He tried his best.
The Doctor gave orders
to follow his advice.
Nuke the site from orbit, never to return.
[person on screen] And this doctor,
what do we know about him?
We thought he was sent by you.
He's got this sort of cargo on the ship.
A big, tall, blue box.
Was he carrying this?
Um, yes. He was, yes.
Well, that's exactly
what I needed to know.
Just as I predicted.
A Vindicator in action.
That's very good news.
Thank you.
[TARDIS warbling]
Excuse me.
[warbling stops]
What was the noise?
Do you know what, Val?
I've got absolutely no idea.
I don't think I know anything anymore.
You okay?
-Sounds like a nightmare down there.
-That's the word, yeah.
I've got to write the report
and I couldn't even begin
to tell you what happened.
[sighs]
What?
Nothing.
What is it?
[♪ theme song playing]
-My name is Ruby Sunday.
-[Carla] You haven't had
a boyfriend for ages.
The pheromones marks you as future prey.
[Ruby] No, they're after you.
[person] There's something out there.
We're a team, like you and the Doctor.
-[growling]
-[Ruby] What the hell is going on?
[♪ theme song continues]