(SCREAMING)
We are under attack. There are creatures.
I don't even think they're human.
We can't stop them.
The clock is broken. He's coming.
Did you hear what I said?
Listen to me.
There is a man coming to Versailles.
He has watched over me my whole life
and he will not desert me tonight.
What are you talking about? What man?
The only man, save you, I have ever loved.
No, don't look like that. There's no time.
You have your duties.
I am your mistress. Go to your queen.
Are you there? Can you hear me?
I need you now, you promised.
The clock on the mantel is broken.
It is time.
Doctor! Doctor!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(WHOOSHING)
It's a spaceship. Brilliant!
I got a spaceship on my first go.
ROSE: Looks kind of abandoned.
Anyone on board?
Nah, nothing here.
Well, nothing dangerous.
Well, not that dangerous.
You know what? I'll just have a quick scan.
In case there's anything dangerous.
So, what's the date? How far have we gone?
About 3,000 years into your future,
give or take.
(ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
DOCTOR: 51st century.
The Dagmar Cluster,
you're a long way from home, Mickey!
Two and a half galaxies.
Mickey Smith, meet the universe.
See anything you like?
It's so realistic!
Dear me, had some cowboys in here.
Been a ton of repair work going on.
Now that's odd, look at that.
All the warp engines are going.
Full capacity.
There's enough power running through
this ship to punch a hole in the universe
and we're not moving.
So where's all that power going?
Where'd all the crew go?
Good question. No life readings on board.
Well, we're in deep space.
They didn't just nip out for a quick fag.
No, I've checked all the smoking pods.
-You smell that?
-Yeah. Someone's cooking.
Sunday roast, definitely.
Now, there's something you don't see
in your average spaceship.
18th century. French.
Nice mantel.
Not a hologram.
Not even a reproduction. This actually is
an 18th-century French fireplace.
Double-sided.
There's another room through there.
It can't be. That's the outer hull
of the ship. Look.
-Hello.
-Hello?
-What's your name?
-Reinette.
Reinette. That's a lovely name.
Can you tell me where you are
at the moment, Reinette?
In my bedroom.
And where's your bedroom?
Where do you live, Reinette?
-Paris of course.
-Paris. Right.
Monsieur, what are you doing
in my fireplace?
Oh, it's just a routine...fire check.
Can you tell me what year it is?
Of course I can. 1727.
Right, lovely, one of my favourites.
August is rubbish, though. Stay indoors.
Okay, that's all for now.
Thanks for your help.
Hope you enjoy the rest of the fire.
Night-night.
Good night, monsieur.
You said this was the 51st century.
I also said this ship was generating enough
power to punch a hole in the universe.
I think we just found the hole.
-Must be a spatio-temporal hyperlink.
-What's that?
No idea, just made it up.
Didn't want to say "magic door".
And on the other side of the "magic door"
it's France in 17277
Well, she was speaking French.
Right period French, too.
She was speaking English, I heard her.
That's the Tardis, translates for you.
-Even French?
-Yep.
-Got you.
-ROSE: Doctor!
(HORSES TROTTING)
(GASPS)
It's okay. Don't scream.
It's me. It's the fireplace man, look.
We were talking. Just a moment ago.
I was in your fireplace.
Monsieur, that was weeks ago.
That was months.
Really? Hmm.
Must be a loose connection.
Need to get a man in.
Who are you and what are you doing here?
(TICKING)
-Okay. That's scary.
-You're scared of a broken clock?
Just a bit scared, yeah. Just a little tiny bit.
'Cause, you see, if this clock's broken,
and it's the only clock in the room,
then what's that?
(TICKING)
'Cause, you see, that's not a clock.
You can tell by the resonance. Too big.
Six feet, I'd say. Size of a man.
What is it?
Now let's think.
If you were a thing that ticked
and you were hiding in someone's bedroom,
first thing you do, break the clock.
No one notices the sound
of one clock ticking, but two?
You might start to wonder
if you're really alone.
Stay on the bed. Right in the middle.
Don't put your hands or feet over the edge.
Reinette, don't look round.
You stay exactly where you are.
Hold still, let me look.
You've been scanning her brain!
You've crossed two galaxies
and thousands of years
just to scan a child's brain?
What could there be in a little girl's mind
worth blowing a hole in the universe?
I don't understand.
It wants me?
You want me?
Not yet. You are incomplete.
Incomplete?
What does that mean, incomplete?
You can answer her, you can answer me.
What do you mean, incomplete?
Monsieur, be careful!
It's just a nightmare, Reinette.
Don't worry about it.
Everyone has nightmares.
Even monsters from under the bed
have nightmares. Don't you, Monster?
What do monsters have nightmares about?
Me. Ha!
Doctor!
Excellent. Ice gun.
Fire extinguisher.
-Where did that thing come from?
-Here.
MICKEY: So why is it dressed like that?
Field trip to France.
Some kind of basic camouflage protocol.
Nice needlework. Shame about the face.
Oh, you are beautiful!
No, really, you are. You're gorgeous.
Look at that!
Space age clockwork. I love it.
I've got chills!
Listen, seriously,
I mean this from the heart,
and by the way, count those,
it would be a crime,
it would be an act of vandalism,
to disassemble you.
But that won't stop me.
(CREAKING)
Short-range teleport.
Can't have got far. Could still be on board.
-What is it?
-Don't go looking for it.
-Where are you going?
-Back in a sec.
-He said not to look for it.
-Yeah, he did.
Now you're getting it.
Reinette?
Just checking you're okay.
(PLAYING HARP)
(CLEARING THROAT)
Oh. Hello!
I was just looking for Reinette.
This is still her room, isn't it?
I've been away, not sure how long.
WOMAN: Reinette? We're ready to go!
Go to the carriage, Mother,
I will join you there.
It is customary, I think,
to have an imaginary friend
only during one's childhood.
You are to be congratulated
on your persistence.
Reinette.
Well...
Goodness, how you've grown.
And you do not appear
to have aged a single day.
That is tremendously impolite of you.
Right, yes, sorry. Um...
Listen, lovely to catch up
but better be off, eh?
Don't want your mother finding you
up here with a strange man, do we?
Strange?
How could you be a stranger to me?
I have known you
since I was seven years old.
Yeah, I suppose you have.
I came the quick route.
You seem to be flesh and blood at any rate,
but this is absurd.
Reason tells me you cannot be real.
Oh, you never want to listen to reason.
MAN: Mademoiselle?
Your mother grows impatient.
A moment!
So many questions. So little time.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
MAN: Mademoiselle Poisson!
Poisson?
Reinette Poisson. No!
No, no, no, no! No way! Reinette Poisson.
Later Madame d'Etioles.
Later still, mistress of Louis XV,
uncrowned Queen of France!
Actress, artist, musician, dancer, courtesan.
Fantastic gardener.
Who the hell are you?
I'm the Doctor.
And I just snogged Madame de Pompadour.
(LAUGHS GLEEFULLY)
Rose!
Mickey! Every time. Every time!
It's rule one. Don't wander off.
I tell them, I do. Rule one.
There could be anything on this ship!
(NEIGHING)
Are you looking at me?
(EXCLAIMS)
Look! Look at this!
That's an eye in there. That's a real eye.
(RHYTHMIC BEATING)
What is that?
What's that in the middle there?
Looks like it's wired in.
It's a heart, Mickey.
It's a human heart.
Rose?
Will you stop following me?
I'm not your mother.
So this is where you came from,
eh, horsey?
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
Oh, Katherine, you are too wicked.
Oh, speaking of wicked,
I hear Madame de Chateauroux is ill
and close to death.
-Yes, I am devastated.
-Oh, indeed.
I, myself, am frequently inconsolable.
KATHERINE: The King will therefore
be requiring a new mistress.
You love the King, of course.
He is the King
and I love him with all my heart.
And I look forward to meeting him.
(BIRD CALLING IN DISTANCE)
Is something wrong, my dear?
Not wrong, no.
KATHERINE: Every woman in Paris
knows your ambitions.
REINETTE: Every woman in Paris
shares them.
You know, of course, that the King
is to attend the Yew Tree Ball...
-Maybe it wasn't a real heart.
-Of course it was a real heart.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
Is this, like, normal for you?
Is this an average day?
Life with the Doctor, Mickey,
no more average days.
It's France again. We can see France.
I think we're looking through a mirror.
Blimey, look at this guy!
-Who does he think he is?
-King of France.
-Oh, here's trouble. What you been up to?
-Oh, this and that.
Became the imaginary friend
of a future French aristocrat,
picked a fight with a clockwork man.
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Oh, and I met a horse.
What's a horse doing on a spaceship?
Mickey, what's pre-revolutionary France
doing on a spaceship?
Get a little perspective.
See these?
They're all over the place, on every deck.
Gateways to history.
But not just any old history. Hers.
Time window.
Deliberately arranged
along the life of one particular woman.
A spaceship from the 51st century
stalking a woman from the 18th.
-Why?
-Who is she?
Jean-Antoinette Poisson.
Known to her friends as Reinette.
One of the most accomplished women
who ever lived.
So has she got plans
for being the queen, then?
No, he's already got a queen.
She's got plans on being his mistress.
Oh, I get it. Camilla!
I think this is the night they met.
The night of the Yew Tree Ball.
In no time flat, she'll get herself
established as his official mistress
with her own rooms at the palace,
even her own title.
Madame de Pompadour.
The Queen must have loved her.
No, she did. They got on very well.
The King's wife and the King's girlfriend?
France. It's a different planet.
(TICKING)
How long have you been standing there?
Show yourself!
Hello, Reinette, hasn't time flown!
Fireplace man!
(CREAKING)
-What's it doing?
-Switching back on. Melting the ice.
-And then what?
-Then it kills everyone in the room.
Focuses the mind, doesn't it?
Who are you? Identify yourself.
Order it to answer me.
Why should it listen to me?
I don't know,
but it did when you were a child.
Let's see if you've still got it.
Answer his question.
Answer any and all questions put to you.
I am Repair Droid 7.
And what happened to the ship, then?
There was a lot of damage.
Ion storm. 82% systems failure.
That ship hasn't moved in over a year.
What's taken you so long?
We did not have the parts.
Always comes down to that, doesn't it?
The parts.
What's happened to the crew?
Where are they?
We did not have the parts.
There should've been over 50 people
on your ship. Where did they go?
We did not have the parts.
Fifty people don't just disappear, where...
Oh.
You didn't have the parts
so you used the crew.
The crew?
We found a camera with an eye in it.
And there was a heart
wired into machinery.
It's just doing what it was programmed to.
Repairing the ship any way it can
with whatever it can find.
No one told it
the crew weren't on the menu.
What did you say
the flight deck smelled of?
Someone cooking.
Flesh plus heat.
Barbecue.
But what are you doing here?
You've opened up time windows,
that takes colossal energy.
Why come here?
You could've gone to your repair yard.
Instead you come to 18th-century France?
Why?
One more part is required.
(CREAKING)
Then why haven't you taken it?
She is incomplete.
What? So that's the plan, then?
Just keep opening up
more and more time windows,
scanning her brain,
checking to see if she's done yet?
Why her?
You've got all of history to choose from,
why specifically her?
We are the same.
We're not the same.
We are in no sense the same!
-We are the same.
-Get out of here.
-Get out of here this instant.
-Reinette, no.
It's back on the ship! Rose, take Mickey
and Arthur, get after it, follow it.
Don't approach it, just watch what it does.
-Arthur?
-Good name for a horse.
-No, you're not keeping the horse.
-I let you keep Mickey. Now go, go, go!
You're going to have to trust me.
I need to find out what they're looking for.
There's only one way I can do that.
Won't hurt a bit.
Fireplace man.
You are inside my mind.
Oh, dear, Reinette.
You've had some cowboys in here.
-So, that Doctor, eh?
-What are you talking about?
Well! Madame de Pompadour,
Sarah Jane Smith.
-Cleopatra...
-Cleopatra! He mentioned her once!
-Yeah, but he called her Cleo.
-Mickey!
You are in my memories.
You walk among them.
If there's anything
you don't want me to see,
just imagine a door and close it.
I won't look.
Oh, actually, there's a door just there,
you might want to close...
Oh. Actually, several.
To walk among the memories
of another living soul.
-Do you ever get used to this?
-I don't make a habit of it.
-How can you resist?
-What age are you?
So impertinent a question
so early in the conversation.
-How promising.
-Not my question. Theirs.
You're 23. And for some reason
that means you're not old enough.
Sorry. You might find old memories
reawakening. Side effect.
Oh, such a lonely childhood.
It'll pass. Stay with me.
Oh, Doctor. So lonely. So very, very alone.
What do you mean, alone?
You've never been alone in your life.
When did you start calling me Doctor?
Such a lonely little boy.
Lonely then and lonelier now.
-How can you bear it?
-How did you do that?
A door once opened
may be stepped through in either direction.
Oh, Doctor.
My lonely Doctor.
Dance with me.
I can't.
This is the night you dance with the King.
Then first I shall make him jealous.
-I can't.
-Doctor.
Doctor who?
It's more than just a secret, isn't it?
What did you see?
That there comes a time, Time Lord,
when every lonely little boy
must learn how to dance.
(TICKING)
What is this? What's going on? Doctor?
MICKEY: Rose?
They're going to chop us up.
Just like the crew!
They're going to chop us up and stick us
all over their stupid spaceship.
And where's the Doctor?
Where's your precious Doctor now?
He's been gone for flipping hours,
that's where he is!
You are compatible.
Well, you might want to think about that.
You really, really might
because me and Mickey,
we didn't come here alone, no, no.
And trust me, you wouldn't want to mess
with our designated driver.
Ever heard of the Daleks? Remember them?
They had a name for our friend.
They had myths about him and a name.
They called him the...
DOCTOR: # I could have danced all night
(STUTTERING) They called him...
# And still have begged for more
# I could have spread my wings
And done a... #
Have you met the French?
My God, they know how to party!
Oh, look at what the cat dragged in.
The Oncoming Storm.
You sound just like your mother.
What have you been doing?
Where have you been?
Well, among other things,
I think I just invented the banana daiquiri
a couple of centuries early.
Do you know,
they'd never even seen a banana before?
Always take a banana to a party, Rose.
Bananas are good. Oh, brilliant.
It's you!
You're my favourite, you are.
You are the best. Do you know why?
'Cause you're so thick.
You're Mr Thick Thick Thicketty Thick-face
from Thick-town, Thickania.
And so is your dad.
Do you know what they were scanning
Reinette's brain for?
Her milometer.
They want to know how old she is.
Know why? 'Cause this ship is 37 years old.
And they think when Reinette is 37,
when she's complete,
then her brain will be compatible.
'Cause that's what you're missing,
isn't it, hmm?
Command circuit, your computer.
Your ship needs a brain.
And for some reason, God knows what,
only the brain
of Madame de Pompadour will do.
The brain is compatible.
Compatible?
If you believe that,
you probably believe this is a glass of wine.
Multi-grade anti-oil. If it moves, it doesn't.
Right, you two, that's enough lying about.
Time we got the rest of the ship turned off.
-Those things safe?
-Yep, safe.
Safe and thick. The way I like them.
Okay, all the time windows
are controlled from here.
Need to close them all down.
Zeus plugs. Where are my Zeus plugs?
Had them a minute ago.
I was using them as castanets.
Why didn't they just open a time window
to when she was 377
Amount of damage to these circuits,
they did well to hit the right century.
Trial and error after that.
The windows aren't closing.
Why won't they close?
(CHIMING)
-What's that?
-I don't know.
-Incoming message?
-MICKEY: From who?
Report from the field.
One of them must still be out there
with Reinette.
That's why I can't close the windows.
There's an override.
(CREAKING)
That was a bit clever.
DOCTOR: Right.
Many things about this are not good.
(CHIMING)
Message from one of your little friends?
Anything interesting?
She is complete. It begins.
What's happening?
One of them must have found
the right time window.
It's time to send in the troops.
And this time
they're bringing back her head.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
ROSE: Madame de Pompadour.
Please don't scream or anything,
we haven't got a lot of time.
We've come to warn you
that they'll be here in five years.
Five years?
Sometime after your 37th birthday.
I, um, I can't give you an exact date,
it's a bit random.
But they're coming. It's gonna happen.
In a way, for us, it's already happening.
I'm sorry, it's hard to explain.
The Doctor does this better.
Then be exact and I will be attentive.
-There isn't time.
-There are five years.
For you. I haven't got five minutes.
Then also be concise.
Um...
There's a vessel.
A ship. A sort of sky ship. And it's full of...
Well, you.
Different bits of your life
in different rooms. All jumbled up.
I told you it was complicated, sorry.
There is a vessel in your world
where the days of my life
are pressed together
like the chapters of a book
so that he may step from one to the other
without increase of age
while I, weary traveller,
must always take the slower path.
He was right about you.
So in five years these creatures will return.
What can be done?
The Doctor says keep them talking.
They're kind of programmed
to respond to you now.
You won't be able to stop them,
but you might be able to delay them a bit.
-Until?
-Until the Doctor can get there.
-He's coming, then?
-He promises.
But he cannot make his promises
in person?
He'll be there when you need him.
That's the way it's got to be.
It's the way it's always been.
The monsters and the Doctor.
It seems you cannot have one
without the other.
Tell me about it.
The thing is,
you weren't supposed to have either.
Those creatures are messing with history.
None of this was ever
supposed to happen to you.
Supposed to happen?
What does that mean?
It happened, child.
And I would not have it any other way.
One may tolerate a world of demons
for the sake of an angel.
MICKEY: Rose? Rose!
Rose!
The time window where she's 37.
We've found it, right under our noses.
No, you can't go in there.
The Doctor will go mad.
So this is his world.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
What was that?
The time window.
The Doctor fixed an audio link.
Those screams. Is that my future?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Then I must take the slower path.
REINETTE: Are you there? Can you hear me?
I need you now. You promised. The clock
on the mantel is broken. It is time!
That's my voice.
Rose, come on, we've got to go.
There's a problem.
Give me a moment.
-You okay?
-No.
I'm very afraid.
But you and I both know, don't we, Rose?
The Doctor is worth the monsters.
REINETTE: Doctor! Doctor!
(SCREAMING)
(CREAKING)
Doctor!
We must go! No one is coming to help us.
You are complete. You will come.
(SCREAMING)
You found it, then?
They knew I was coming,
they've blocked it off.
-Where are we going?
-The teleport has limited range.
We must have proximity to the time portal.
Your words mean nothing. You are nothing.
-How come they got in there?
-They teleported.
As long as the ship
and the ballroom are linked,
their short-range teleports will do the trick.
-We'll go in the Tardis.
-We can't. We're part of events now.
Can't we just smash through?
Hyperplex this side, plate glass the other.
We'd need a truck.
-We don't have a truck.
-I know!
We've got to try something!
No. Smash the glass,
smash the time windows.
There'd be no way back.
Could everyone just calm down!
Please!
Such a commotion. Such distressing noise.
Kindly remember that this is Versailles.
This is the Royal Court and we are French.
I have made a decision.
And my decision is no.
I shall not be going with you today.
I have seen your world and
I have no desire to set foot there again.
We do not require your feet.
(ALL GASPING)
You think I fear you,
but I do not fear you even now.
You are merely
the nightmare of my childhood,
the monster from under my bed.
And if my nightmare
can return to plague me,
then rest assured, so will yours.
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(HORSE GALLOPING)
(SCREAMING)
Madame de Pompadour.
You look younger every day.
What the hell is going on?
Oh. This is my lover, the King of France.
Yeah? Well, I'm the Lord of Time.
And I'm here to fix the clock.
(ALL GASPING)
Forget it. It's over.
For you and for me.
Talk about seven years' bad luck.
Try 3,000.
(CREAKING)
MICKEY: What happened?
Where did the time window go?
How's he gonna get back?
The link with the ship is broken.
No way back.
You don't have the parts.
How many ticks left
in that clockwork heart, huh?
A day? An hour?
It's over. Accept that.
I'm not winding you up.
Are you all right?
What's happened to them?
They've stopped.
They have no purpose now.
We can't fly the Tardis without him.
How's he gonna get back?
You know all their names, don't you?
I saw that in your mind.
The name of every star.
What's in a name?
Names are just titles.
Titles don't tell you anything.
Like "the Doctor"?
Like "Madame de Pompadour”.
I have often wished to see those stars
a little closer.
Just as you have, I think.
From time to time.
In saving me, you trapped yourself.
Did you know that would happen?
Hmm, pretty much.
Yet still you came.
Yeah, I did, didn't I?
Catch me doing that again.
There were many doors
between my world and yours.
Can you not use one of the others?
When the mirror broke,
the shock would've severed
all the links with the ship.
There'll be a few more broken mirrors
and torn tapestries around here I'm afraid,
wherever there was a time window.
(STAMMERING) I'll pay for any damage.
That's a thought, I'm gonna need money.
I've always been a bit vague about money.
Where do you get money?
So here you are.
My lonely angel.
Stuck on the slow path with me.
Yep. The slow path.
Here's to the slow path.
(REINETTE LAUGHS)
It's a pity.
I think I would have enjoyed the slow path.
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
Oh, aren't you?
Take my hand.
It's not a copy. It's the original.
I had it moved here
and was exact in every detail.
The fireplace.
The fireplace from your bedroom.
-When did you do this?
-Many years ago.
In the hope that a door once opened
may someday open again.
One never quite knows
when one needs one's doctor.
It appears undamaged.
Do you think it will still work?
You broke the bond with the ship
when you moved it.
Which means it was off-line
when the mirror broke.
That's what saved it.
But...
the link is basically physical
and it's still physically here,
which might just mean, if I'm lucky,
if I'm very, very, very, very, very lucky...
-Aha!
-What?
Loose connection!
Need to get a man in!
-Wish me luck.
-No.
Madame de Pompadour!
Still wanna see those stars?
-More than anything.
-Give me two minutes. Pack a bag.
Am I going somewhere?
Go to the window. Pick a star. Any star.
-How long did you wait?
-Five and half hours.
Great! Always wait five and half hours.
Where've you been?
Explain later. Into the Tardis.
With you in a sec!
DOCTOR: Reinette.
Are you there, Reinette?
Reinette?
Oh, hello.
You just missed her.
-She'll be in Paris by 6:00.
-Oh.
Good Lord!
She was right.
She said you never looked a day older.
So many years since I saw you last,
but not a day of it on your face.
She spoke of you many times.
Often wished you'd visit again.
You know how women are.
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(CARRIAGE DEPARTING)
And there she goes.
Leaving Versailles for the last time.
Only 43 when she died.
Too young.
Illness took her in the end.
She always did work too hard.
What does she say?
Of course.
Quite right.
ROSE: Why her?
Why did they think
they could repair the ship
with the head of Madame de Pompadour?
We'll probably never know.
There's massive damage
in the computer memory decks.
Probably got confused.
The Tardis can close down
the time windows
now the droids have gone.
Should stop it causing any more trouble.
You all right?
I'm always all right.
Come on, Rose, it's time you showed me
round the rest of this place.
REINETTE: "My dear Doctor,
“the path has never seemed more slow
and yet I fear I am nearing its end.
"Reason tells me that you and I
are unlikely to meet again,
"but I think I shall not listen to reason.
"I have seen the world inside your head
and know that all things are possible.
"Hurry, though, my love.
"My days grow shorter now
and I am so very weak.
"Godspeed, my lonely angel.”
(WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: So this is London.
An alternative to our world
where everything's the same
but a little bit different.
We're in some sort of no place.
All those people
disappearing off the streets,
it's been going on for months.
-What are they all doing?
-DOCTOR: It's the earpieces.
MAN: The prototype
has passed every test, sir.
It's working.
I've seen them before.
ROSE: What are they?
Skin of metal and
a body that will never age.
Cybers.