Patrol B returning to base,
following Grade 1 encounter.
Two survivors, one injury.
ETA, 20 minutes.
Have you done your teeth?
Yes.
Well,
I need to smell your minty breath.
Oh, you little liar.
Teeth, now.
How can you smell my breath over the comm?
Dad skills, that's how.
- Wait a mo.
How are we doing?
Less than a mile from base camp.
But we're right in the middle
of a minefield.
And there were no mines here yesterday.
All right, then.
They must have migrated again.
Fog's bad too.
It's just fog.
Some of the men think
the Kastarions are in the fog.
Like they're made of fog.
That's why we never see them.
Carson, the fog's been analysed,
and it's just fog.
- Oh.
Hey. I'm really close.
Find Mundy and get her to put you to bed.
And do your teeth.
All right. Kiss kiss.
Kiss kiss.
- Carson.
Due north's our best bet.
But...
I think there might be an ambulance.
I'll be fine.
- Come on.
I'm just asking you
to switch patrols with me.
It's not exactly loaves and fishes, is it?
Uh, I'm not a bishop.
- I'm not allowed.
- You're a verger.
I don't have the divinity.
- Mundy.
Give us a minute, love.
Hey, Canto!
Listen, seriously.
As God is my witness, on my soul eternal...
I'll let you see my tattoo.
Your tattoo?
It's not on general view,
which makes it more exciting given
the romantic tension between us.
Look, I'm only doing this
because I want you to stop annoying me.
Great. Thank you.
Thanks. Thanks a million.
- What's up, Splice?
- Oi!
What?
Tattoo?
Sorry. It's on Posh Graham.
I finished it yesterday.
You'll love it.
You should be nice to Canto. He likes you.
No, he doesn't.
- I was just joking about that.
- He's not joking.
Where's your dad?
What's wrong?
Ambulance. Dead ahead.
Okay.
Sir, respectfully, your eyes.
- It might detect the injury.
- Yeah. Well, it might help me then.
- Sir, the algorithm is haywire right now.
You know what happened to Wilson.
The algorithm's been upgraded.
No. They ran out of money.
Look, it doesn't matter.
We have to keep moving.
We don't have a choice.
Okay, okay. Hold there.
I guess it could be dormant.
It's a long way from the fighting.
Well, they're combat activated.
They power down when there's nothing
going on, but their sensors stay active.
You know,
I'm not even sure it's--
Carson! Carson, where are you?
It's--
- Are you okay?
- It's fine. It's fine. I'm okay.
I'm not injured.
Just stay where you are.
I'll just--
Carson!
Combat detected. Combat detected.
Combat detected.
Patient acquired.
Sharp scratch.
- You're doing very well.
Patient name: John Francis Vater.
Calendar age: 42 years.
Vital signs in normal range.
Blood pressure: high.
Cardiac function: good.
Liver mildly inflamed.
-blind.
I'm not blind.
My vision is temporarily impaired.
Eyesight recovery time estimated...
- ...four weeks.
unacceptable.
Combat medical: failed.
Listen to me. I have a child at base camp.
Check my records!
My next of kin, Splice, she's my daughter,
and I'm exclusively responsible for her.
Please! Check my records.
Leave a message at the tone.
Kiss kiss.
- Next of kin: informed.
The Villengard Corporation would like
to extend its deepest condolences
on your upcoming loss.
Thoughts and prayers.
Sharp scratch.
Did you hear that?
Give me a sec.
Someone's in trouble.
Stay there!
Okay, coming.
Doctor?
Doctor!
♪ Speed, bonny boat
Like a bird on the wing ♪
Doctor?
♪ Onward, the sailors cry ♪
♪ Carry the lad that's born to be king ♪
Doctor.
♪ Over the sea to Skye ♪
Doctor, is that you?
Everything's fine.
Who said it wasn't?
Completely fine.
Come toward my voice.
And watch where you put your feet.
♪ Loud the wind howls
Loud the waves roar ♪
♪ Thunderclaps rend the air ♪
Why are you singing?
It's "The Skye Boat Song".
Like it?
I didn't ask what you were singing.
I asked why.
I'm getting my zen on.
My landmine zen.
I need you to describe to me
what I'm standing on.
Fairly sure I know,
but details are important,
and I can't risk looking down.
The sensors are on hair trigger.
Why hasn't it set off already
when you stepped on it?
Impact activates the sensors.
Now it's confirming
if there's a live target on it.
One wrong move, and boom...
...I go all food mixer.
Mmm. Where are we?
In the middle of a war.
Oh, I was kind of hoping for a beach.
Yeah, what do you think this is?
It's not a beach.
Ah, give it time.
Everywhere is a beach eventually.
Okay. I'm down.
I'm about ten feet directly behind you.
Look at my right foot.
Describe what I'm standing on.
It's a sort of disc.
A white disc. It's really thin.
It's got lights around the edge,
round the rim. Green lights.
Okay.
Okay, very slowly,
very carefully, move around me,
and tell me if there's a gap in the light.
It's not gone off yet.
So I think there's a gap.
Hoping for quite a big one.
Why does a landmine have lights on it?
Capitalism.
Excuse me?
Flashy lights play well in a showroom.
Modern warfare. Death by salesman.
I found the gap.
It's right under your foot,
in front of ya.
How big is it?
Four fingers.
Okay.
Well, that's, um-- that's better
than two fingers, for instance.
Is there a V on it?
Yeah.
V for victory?
Villengard.
V for Villengard. Biggest weapons
manufacturer in recorded history.
Supplied all sides in all conflicts
for the past two centuries in the sector.
Had to deactivate one of these once.
At a lesbian gymkhana.
Underwater, for a bet.
Except it wasn't live,
and I wasn't standing on it.
And I lost that bet.
Sorry. Wrong moment for this story.
First things first.
Someone was screaming.
It came from directly up there.
Can you check
and see if anyone needs help?
- You need help.
- I'm not even screaming yet.
Priorities.
- You'll need to go the long way round.
And watch your step.
While you're up there,
see if you can see anything heavy.
A good-sized rock or something.
I cannot keep standing on one leg.
But if I put my other foot down
on the ground, it will shift my weight.
I need to counterbalance.
I need to increase the weight on the mine
at the exact moment I decrease it.
Well, it's gonna be tricky.
It's gonna be a moment, yeah.
Anyone there?
Uh... [stammers] ...no.
Nothing. Just a flashy light thing.
Hang on.
Found something?
A weird thing.
If it's a heavy weird thing, bring it.
It's okay! It's okay!
You're fine. Don't worry.
Just vacuum drones, that's all.
Hoovering up the smoke
so that nobody can choke to death
before they are safely shot.
Oh. Okay, I suppose that's--
What's wrong?
Ruby, have you seen something?
Oh.
Oh, Ruby, I'm sorry. I forgot.
- Your first time on a new planet.
It flips your stomach,
doesn't it?
A brand-new sky.
We're on Kastarion 3,
going by the rings next door.
- Decent enough. Seven out of ten.
Good trees. Great mountains.
Rainbow crystal.
Ah, wait until you see the dawn.
Mind you, this place is basically empty.
Who'd pick a fight round here?
Okay, I've got a heavy thing.
I think this is an urn or something.
But it's kind of gross.
- What is it?
- Never mind.
What do you mean, "never mind"?
Tell me what you're not telling me.
Okay.
Okay, that isn't an urn.
There isn't a body inside of that.
That is a body.
That is a dead body.
Compressed somehow.
Like it's been, I don't know, smelted.
Seriously?
I heard a scream. I guess it was that.
He was being smelted?
It's a good word, smelted, isn't it?
Not at the moment.
I never used the word "smelted" before.
It's never come up.
New planet, new word, landmine.
Ooh, I am having a day.
Are you getting scared?
'Cause you're just babbling now.
Toss it in your hand.
That thing,
toss it in your hand and catch it, please.
- Okay, that's about the right weight.
- About?
Okay, it's exactly 6.732217 kilograms.
I was trying not to show off.
Throw it to me.
- No.
- Throw it to my right hand.
I need to use it to counterbalance.
I'm gonna catch it at the exact moment
I put my left foot down on the ground.
I understand, but it's too unstable.
- Let me give it to you.
- No.
You'll have a much better chance
if I just put it in your hand.
If it goes wrong,
you will be caught in the blast.
Well, let's get it right then.
Ruby, I forbid this.
Yeah, good luck with that.
You don't understand.
This is a smart-mine.
It is monitoring anything,
any significant change.
I get too worried about you,
and my blood pressure goes up,
and I don't know how much leeway I have.
Best not to worry then.
So how are we gonna do this?
Count of three?
- Please listen to me.
- No arguing, Doctor.
Blood pressure.
Ruby, if this doesn't work...
You are brave.
Mmm.
- And you are wonderful.
And I forgive you
for being incredibly stupid.
Good then.
And if it does work,
I'm gonna be very cross at you
for a very, very long time.
Not that long, babes.
- You're standing on a landmine.
- Count of three?
- Okay, no, wait.
Um...
I n-need something more rhythmic.
Um, I need a beat, like-- like a song.
Sing the song.
- The song? The song.
- The song.
"Over the sea to Skye."
That's the last line. On the word "Skye"--
I love that song.
It's about Bonnie Prince Charlie.
- I know, it's sweet. Let's go.
- It's sweet, and it's sad.
And it's about soldiers fighting.
But it's sad, like a lullaby.
And that's right, isn't it?
Songs about soldiers should be sad,
don't you think?
Okay, Doctor. I'm ready. Stop babbling.
- Okay.
Okay, Ruby, shall we dance?
♪ Speed, bonny boat
Like a bird on the wing ♪
♪ Onward, the sailors cry ♪
♪ Carry the lad that's born to be king ♪
♪ Over the sea to Skye ♪
Okay, okay.
- Okay.
Okay, okay. The lights are moving.
That's okay. That's all right. It's fine.
It's the after-effect. It's my adrenaline.
I just need to focus.
- I just need to relax.
- They're still moving.
Maybe don't keep mentioning that.
I went down to the beach
and there she stood,
dark and tall, at the edge of the wood.
"The sky's too big. I'm scared," I cried.
She replied, "Young man,
don't you know there's more to life
than the moon and the president's wife?"
Okay. Okay. I think that's it.
That was close.
No margin for error.
You know what's really great
about no margin for error?
- No more errors.
Thank you, "John Francis Vater".
Hello. I'm John Francis Vater, deceased.
Apologies for your loss.
Oh, voice-activated.
These are my mortal remains.
At your convenience,
please return them to my parents,
Agnes and Millicent Vater.
Address will be supplied on request.
Hey, John. Am I talking to an AI?
I'm an approximate AI reconstruction
of the deceased John Vater.
Signature elements
of my former personality
have been incorporated
into this interface.
Kiss kiss.
What happened to you, John?
I was humanely terminated on the discovery
of the fatal condition, blindness.
Blindness isn't fatal.
You literally just said that
to a dead blind guy.
Who terminated you, John?
I was spared further suffering
by a Villengard Automated Ambulance Unit.
My recovery was estimated
as beyond acceptable parameters
for a conflict as budgeted.
- Sorry. Killed by an ambulance?
Life is cheap.
Patients are expensive.
- The Villengard algorithm.
- The what?
Villengard battle products
are fitted with AI.
The algorithm maintains a fighting force
at just above the acceptable
number of casualties.
Keeps you fighting,
keeps you dying, keeps you buying.
Medical services optimise
the casualty rate for continued conflict.
War is business, and business is booming.
Good to meet you, John.
- Kiss kiss.
Daddy?
- Is my daddy there? I heard him.
H-Hello. [chuckles] Hello, up there.
You okay? You need help?
I'm looking for my daddy.
How did you--
- Why did you come here?
He sent me a message.
I can read a geo-stamp.
Where is he? Where's my daddy?
I heard him.
Shouldn't you be tucked up in bed?
What's a little kid like you
doing out in a nasty war like this?
My dad got special permission to bring me.
Oh, that's good, isn't it?
'Cause my mummy got gathered up.
She got what? G-Gathered?
She got gathered up by God.
He loved her so much
that he gathered her up early
so she can be in heaven with him
like an angel.
We'll see her again one day,
Daddy explained.
Where is Daddy?
Uh, this is Ruby.
- And my name is the Doctor.
- The Doctor isn't a name.
Yeah.
And I'm not even a doctor.
People don't usually bring that up.
You're good already.
- I'm Splice.
- Great name. I love it!
- Just Splice or--
- Splice Alison Vater.
Splice Alison Vater,
you have been identified
- as the next of kin of John Francis Vater.
- Daddy!
I am an AI reconstruction
of your deceased parent.
- Apologies for your loss.
No.
- Let's grieve together. Come to--
- No. Wait!
- Dad!
Wait!
Daddy!
Let go of me! Get off me!
No, no! Please, Splice.
- If I'm causing distress...
Ruby.
Please! No.
- ...perhaps I should come back later.
- Kiss kiss.
Dad!
Let go of me!
- Ruby.
- Look at his foot!
- Look at what he's standing on.
You see that?
See what he's standing on?
Okay?
Doctor, you okay?
It's just an adrenaline rush.
Just gotta control it.
It's going down.
Down, let's move it down.
Down, down, down, down, down.
Slide it down.
Doctor. What's happening?
Me.
I'm happening.
I'm the explosive.
You are in my sights!
- I can drop you where you stand.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Do you understand?
Signal your understanding.
- Signal your understanding!
- I understand!
Please! I understand.
He's on a landmine.
He's standing right on one.
Ma'am, I'm fully apprised
of what he's standing on.
- Splice, you okay down there?
- I'm here, Mundy.
I'm trying to find Daddy.
I saw him. He was a hologram. Where is he?
Sir, my name is Mundy Flynn.
I'm an ordained Anglican Marine.
What are you doing out here?
Are you
civilians?
- Anglican what?
- Great name, Mundy Flynn.
You should marry Ruby.
Then you'll be Mundy Sunday.
Go on, get married. I'd laugh every day.
What's an Anglican Marine?
Since when was the Church an army?
Since most of your history.
You've been living in a blip.
Sir, the casket in your right hand.
Are you aware those are the sacred remains
- of an ordained Anglican?
Are you aware your face is ringing?
Did you like the tattoo?
What? I geo-stamped you.
I know where you are.
Get back to the compound.
- You're giving me orders now?
- What? I'm not giving you orders.
I'm worried. Fog drones have been out.
The Kastarions could
be planning an attack.
Shut up, you're worried.
You don't even like me.
- Of course I--
Okay, this idiot little war.
Who are you fighting?
The Kastarions.
Yeah? The Kastarions?
Go on.
Tell me about the Kastarions.
- We've never seen them.
- Excuse me?
They're in the mud.
Well, that's what we think.
Some of us.
- Or the fog.
- What, sentient mud?
- Sir, I do not have time for this.
- Seriously?
Do you know how ridiculous you sound?
I've met sentient mud. Lovely girls.
Grumpy, yeah, but you try laying around
with your face full of mammals all day.
- Sir, I'm gonna have to ask you...
...to let go of that casket.
- Just let it fall.
No!
If he drops the casket,
it'll trigger the landmine.
- It'll kill him!
- He's dead already.
Sir, when you stepped on that mine,
you triggered a countdown.
It's now trying to assess
whether it's acquired a viable target.
If it can't within a specified time,
it fails safe.
It blows anyway.
Drop the casket.
Immolation. How does it work?
There's no explosive
in this landmine, right?
Immolation triggers a quantum-level
chain reaction in the subject's DNA.
You are the explosive.
I'm a Time Lord.
- Not a human, I'm a Time Lord--
Doctor!
I am a higher-dimension life form.
I am a complex space-time event.
I'm Anglican.
No, no! Stop it!
I'm a much bigger bang
than you bargained for.
I'm a lot more explosive than I look,
and, honey,
I know how I look.
Put a quantum chain reaction through me,
and I will shatter this silly
little battlefield of yours into dust.
All of it.
In a heartbeat, into dust.
- That's not possible.
- Everything is possible.
Everything is possible.
Everywhere is a beach eventually.
Scan me.
Scan me. See for yourself.
You could blow up half of this planet.
- Combat detected. Combat detected.
Shoot it!
- Combat detected.
The algorithm won't let me!
- What is that thing?
- Combat detected.
- Is it a robot? Doctor, what is that?
It's an ambulance.
- Combat detected.
It's a what?
How is that an ambulance?
- Stop it.
- Patient acquired.
- Please, stop it.
- You've got to stop that thing.
Patient acquired. Hold still.
- Daddy!
- Hello, Daughter Splice,
can I assist you
with any persistent regrets?
Sharp scratch.
- Daddy!
Would you like to look at some old
photographs to remember the good times?
Patient name.
Patient name unknown. Unidentified.
- Vital signs. Vital signs. Vi-Vital signs.
- No, he's not human!
Get it off me!
- Vi-Vital signs.
- Combat!
"Combat is detected."
That's what she said!
- Give me the gun.
- What are you doing?
Combat! Can't you hear that lovely combat?
Combat, right this way! Combat!
- Combat! Combat!
Stay right here, okay?
Look! That's when we saw the antelope!
Combat detected. Combat detected.
Combat detected.
Wait!
Shoot me. It needs to detect an injury,
or it won't triage.
- Shoot me.
- No, I can't!
It's fine. I put it on setting one.
- Just do my arm or something.
- I can't.
You really have to. Come on!
You can do it!
Shoot me a little bit. Just do my arm.
- Left one, please.
- Yeah, sorry.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
Patient acquired.
- Patient acquired.
- Ruby. Ruby, can you hear me?
Doctor, what's happening?
Sharp scratch.
She was gonna shoot you. I saw her.
Patient identified.
Ruby Sunday.
Calendar age: 3082 years.
Next of kin.
Next of kin-- Next of-- Next of kin.
- Next of kin. Next of kin. Next of kin.
- Who-- Who is my next of kin?
Next of kin. Next of kin. Next of kin.
Next of kin. Next of kin.
- Next of kin.
- That's not possible.
- It doesn't snow here. It never snows.
No, it's Ruby. This has happened before.
Next of-- Next of kin.
Just please tell me who it is.
It's good, it's good. The snow is good.
While there's snow, there's ho--
It stopped. How can it do that?
How can it just stop?
Vital signs failing.
Mortality estimate: 432 seconds.
Patient non-ordained.
- Treatment withheld.
She was gonna shoot you.
I don't understand.
It doesn't matter. Look at the readings.
If that mine blows, it blows everything.
I went down to the beach,
there she stood,
dark and tall, edge of the wood.
"The sky's too big. I'm scared," I cried.
She replied, "Young man,
don't you know there's more to life
- than the moon and the president's wife?"
Sir.
Sir, please.
I've scanned the device.
I've ran the numbers. You're right.
You're gonna blow
a really big hole in everything.
You could wipe out every Anglican here.
Please, what do we do?
Ruby.
We're doing everything we can.
I'm reconfiguring
the ambulance protocols.
It could revive her,
but it's not programmed
to assist non-believers.
Sir, the mine is cycling down
to the end of the countdown.
We've got five minutes.
Probably less. Please.
What can we do?
Surrender.
- Excuse me?
- Surrender.
Lose.
Give in.
Even if that were possible,
which it isn't,
even if I had the divinity to authorise
that, it wouldn't switch off the landmine.
Yes, it would.
Why?
Because it's your landmine.
Patient death imminent.
Thoughts and prayers.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Ruby, stop that. Hang on in there.
I still need you.
I can't think unless I'm talking,
and I can only talk to you.
Mundy thinks that she's fighting
the Kastarions. What do you think?
You figured it out yet?
I don't think Mundy's figured it out.
Figured what out?
So this lot, Ruby, they came here,
what, six months ago?
They set up their defences and
fired their warning shots into the air.
"Watch out. We come in peace."
Yeah?
We advertised our presence.
It's standard procedure.
Do you hear that, Ruby?
They advertised their presence.
And do you know what that does?
Ruby, that-that activates
the Villengard algorithm.
The acceptable casualty rate algorithm.
Keeps you dying, keeps you buying. Huh?
Do you get it? Huh, do you get it?
Do you get-- Do you get it?
Do you get it?
Do you get-get-get it?
There's nobody else here.
You declared war on an empty planet.
There are no Kastarions in the mud.
They're not in the fog.
There are no Kastarions.
Just the algorithm
maintaining an acceptable casualty rate
in the face of nothing at all.
You are fighting your own hardware.
And it is killing you at just
the right amount to keep you buying more.
I mean, most armies would notice
that they were fighting smoke and shadows,
but not this lot, Ruby.
You know why? 'Cause they have faith.
- Shut up!
- Faith!
The magic word that keeps you
never having to think for yourself.
Just surrender, Mundy.
Just stop...
and it's all over.
Prove it.
What, seriously?
Now you need proof, faith girl?
Only the bishop can declare a surrender,
and the bishop will need proof.
- Oh. John Francis Vater, father and AI.
- Yes, sir.
I need you to download yourself
into the Villengard battle computer
and find proof
that the planet is uninhabited
and that the casualty rate
is hardware driven.
Send it to the scanner
in Mundy Flynn's hand.
Apologies. That is not possible.
I am not connected to the network.
No, but the ambulance is.
And the ambulance is connected to me.
And I am connected to you.
Shut up and google.
That is against my digital protocol, sir.
Listen to me.
However little is left of you,
you are still a father.
Dad to dad,
you never let them down, right?
Ever.
To the end, right?
Dad to dad, dust to dust. Am I right?
Sir, he can't. He's just an AI simulant.
I'll be back. Do your teeth.
How much of the countdown left?
Three minutes maybe.
Thoughts and prayers.
That will do that.
- How's it going?
- There are safeguards. Hush.
I saw your tattoo.
- What?
- The-- The one you did on Posh Graham.
It was beautiful.
- You checked out my tattoo on Posh Graham?
- Of course.
- Why?
- I wanted to see it.
But why?
Why did you even come out here?
Why were you looking for me?
Canto.
Do you like me?
Of course, I like you.
Everyone knows that I like you.
Except Posh Graham,
who now thinks I like him.
It was on his upper thigh.
You could've warned me.
Hang on.
Does that mean you like me?
Defences. Defences.
What is it? What is happening?
Canto, talk to me.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. How are you?
Where are you? I can't-- Are you injured?
I'm okay.
Just shock.
Canto.
You are identified as Mundy Flynn,
my designated favourite person.
Here's a personal message
recorded just for you.
If anything happens to me,
I want you to know that
I love you.
And honestly, it's okay that...
...you don't love me back.
Sorry. Yeah.
I'm sorry about your friend.
It was my fault.
I distracted him.
It was nothing to do with you.
It was the algorithm breach.
The Villengard algorithm
is protecting itself.
The ambulance killed him.
Thoughts and prayers.
We sent Daddy in there,
and it's fighting back. Look.
Of course. Of course, there's security.
There's a firewall.
Why didn't I think of that?
What's happening?
The algorithm will do anything it can
to protect itself.
- Anything at all.
Antelope.
- Ante-- Antelope.
- John.
Antelope. I saw antelope. We saw antelope.
We saw the antelope together.
I-I remember! I remember, Daddy!
Antelope. We saw antelope.
Antelope. Sorry.
Tell her to run, John!
Tell your daughter to run now!
- Dad to dad.
- I'm safe with Daddy.
Safe-- Safe-- Antelope--
Safe-- Can't-- Can't-- Ante--
A--
Dad--
A-Any attempt to interfere
with the Villengard algorithm
will be met with severe fines.
Where is John Francis Vater?
The AI known as John Francis Vater has
been identified as a hostile data virus
and permanently deleted.
Thoughts and prayers.
Attention.
This landmine will induce
fail-safe immolation shortly.
If you are not the selected target,
please stand clear.
- Run. Start running.
- There's no point.
Final countdown commencing.
- Both of you! Run!
Ten, nine...
- We'd never get far enough.
- ...eight...
- Where's my daddy?
- ...seven...
- I'm not leaving without my daddy.
- And I'm not leaving you, munchkin.
- ...six...
- I'm so sorry, then. This is it.
- ...five, four...
I'm so sorry, Ruby.
- ...three...
- I am so, so sorry.
...two,
one.
Kiss kiss.
Antelope-- Dad to dad--
Dust to dust-- Dust--
Kiss kiss.
- Virus alert. Virus a--
- Kiss kiss.
Kiss kiss. Kiss kiss. Kiss kiss.
Patient acquired.
Sharp scratch.
Revivification protocol initiated.
Kiss kiss.
- Kiss kiss.
- How?
Ruby, Ruby.
- You okay? Yeah?
- What's happening?
Your father, who art in heaven.
- A kind of heaven anyway.
Antelope-- Do your teeth-- Antelope.
The Villengard algorithm.
The whole Villengard arms industry,
all of it,
just got beaten up
by this little kid's dad!
- Doctor.
- Ah! Ruby! Ruby!
Ah, why are you lying around
missing all the good stuff?
A war just got switched off and very
possibly sent to bed without its supper.
I don't-- What happened?
Well, it's, uh--
It's kind of hard to sum up.
I think if I had a diary, it would be
a little bit too exciting for words.
I think I could write it with drums.
Can you write a diary in drums?
I bet I could.
- Uh, wait--
October the 5th!
I sent this girl's dad into the software
just for a look around.
Just looking for proof,
and he must have been very cross.
Because now,
the whole Villengard mainframe
has been taken down by parent power.
Basically, Villengard--
Basically, just wait till Daddy gets home.
Right, enough of that.
Moving on. Come on, Ruby.
No. Hang on. We've had, like,
two minutes of the awesome.
Yeah, two minutes. No lingering.
Plenty more universe to see.
And quite frankly, your lifespan sucks.
All right. Come here, Splice.
Splice, I'm so sorry about your dad.
Why are you sorry?
Because he's gone now.
But I know that Mundy is gonna
take really good care of you.
Silly, he's not gone.
He's just dead.
He's not gone.
That is right.
That is exactly right.
You keep the faith, Splice.
I thought you didn't
like faith much, Doctor.
Just because I don't like it,
doesn't mean I don't need it, Mundy.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye, goodbye.
I will be popping in every now and then.
Fish fingers and custard is my favourite.
- Okay, come on, Ruby.
Yes, yes.
Sorry we gotta rush off like this.
But he probably needs changing. Bye!
- Do you think she'll be all right?
Splice?
I reckon future president
of something.
Till then, she's got Mundy and her dad.
But her dad's dead.
No, I know. I know he's not gone,
and that's sweet and everything.
It's just he is--
He's really, actually, he's dead.
We're all dead eventually.
There's hardly any time
that we're not dead.
It's a good thing too.
We gotta keep the pace up.
Otherwise, nothing would get done.
Dying defines us.
Snow isn't snow until it falls.
Snow.
Yeah, snow.
We all melt away in the end.
But something stays.
Maybe the best part.
A sad, old man once told me,
"What survives of us is love."
- We are in Wales! Spectacular!
- Who's she?
Doctor.
Where is the Doctor? Where is he?
There's this woman following me.
- Who is she?
- I don't know!
- Mad Jack is unbound.
What the hell have you done?