Davros. My name is Davros.
DOCTOR: Davros created
a new kind of warrior.
Davros made the Daleks.
But who made Davros?
DAVROS: You said you'd help me!
Shame. You're ashamed.
COLONY SARFF: Davros is dying.
He has a message for the Doctor.
This is a trap!
(HISSING)
You brought me to Skaro!
MISSY: This is the planet of the Daleks.
Clara!
You cannot help her now, Doctor.
Compassion is wrong.
(ROPE CREAKING)
Consider the Doctor.
The Doctor, trapped. The Doctor, alone.
-You all right there, dear?
-Where are we?
-How did we...
-MISSY: Shh, now, Mummy's talking.
OK, I'm going to tell you
a story of the Doctor.
It's classic.
On the run, no Tardis.
No friends, no help.
In other words, the Doctor happy.
It was a long time ago.
Doesn't matter which
face he was wearing,
they're all the Doctor to me.
So let's give it to the eyebrows.
But the Daleks?
Yes, I'm coming to that.
Shouldn't we be, um...
-I don't want to say dead?
-Hush!
-He's travelling by teleporter.
-(BEEPING)
Unfortunately, his teleporter
ls out of power.
Also unfortunate, he's being stalked by,
oh, say about 50 android assassins.
I may be rounding up.
Ow!
Fifty invisible, indestructible
android assassins.
All exclusively programmed to kill him.
Why are you sharpening that stick?
Well, I have no idea how long we're
going to be stuck out here,
might have to go hunting.
So why am I tied up?
In case there is nothing to hunt.
(CHUCKLES)
The Doctor then, surrounded,
outnumbered, outgunned.
And freeze.
Nanoseconds to live.
Four, I'd say, being generous.
Now, my question is this,
how did he survive?
Oh, come on, Clara.
You know him.
Consider the Doctor.
(CHUCKLES)
(BEEPS)
Where did he get that teleport thingy?
Oh, good. Good!
He stole one from an android.
So, I'm guessing
he uses the same energy
as the android weapons, right?
Excellent!
-Not seeing you as sandwiches now.
-OK then.
He uses the energy wave
from the android weapons
to recharge the teleport bracelet,
and at the exact moment
he's supposed to disintegrate,
he actually teleports.
Hang on! That's how you did it.
(SCREAMS)
That's how we escaped the Daleks.
I modified the same principles
for our vortex manipulators, yes.
Blew them off, I'm afraid.
But the Doctor, he improvised it.
He must have got through
several thousand calculations
in the time it takes
to fire up a disintegrator.
Seriously, what a swot!
CLARA: So the androids think he's dead
and the Doctor escapes.
MISSY: No, he's the Doctor.
He fell into a nest of vampire monkeys.
(MONKEYS SCREACHING)
But that's another story.
(GRUNTS)
Why does the Doctor always survive?
Because he's clever!
Yes, but there's lots of
clever dead people.
I love killing clever-clogs.
They make the best faces.
Because he always assumes
he's gonna win.
He always knows
there is a way to survive,
he just has to go and find it.
Yes, except this time, he made a will,
and threw himself a goodbye party.
Now, if the Doctor assumes
he is going to die,
what happens then?
We do.
He's trapped at the heart
of the Dalek empire.
He's a prisoner of the creatures
who hate him most in the universe.
Between us and him is everything
the deadliest race in all
of history can throw at us.
We, on the other hand,
have a pointy stick.
How do we start?
We assume we're gonna win.
Oh, pity really.
I was actually quite peckish.
-Can I have a stick, too?
-Make your own stick.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DAVROS: It took me so long
to realise it was you,
standing at the gates of my beginning.
And here you are at the end.
But this time, I have you at my mercy.
Exterminate!
Doctor?
Ancient, inoperable.
(GUN POWERS UP)
Genius.
You would threaten a dying man?
Have I not suffered enough?
Get out.
I cannot leave this chamber.
It sustains me.
Get out!
DALEK 1: Alert! Alert!
The infirmary is breached.
SUPREME DALEK: Protect Davros.
Davros must be assisted.
DALEK 1: Davros is
leaving the infirmary.
SUPREME DALEK: Davros must remain.
Davros cannot leave.
DAVROS: My children, help me!
SUPREME DALEK: You
must return to the infirmary.
DAVROS: The Doctor is escaping.
Find him! Find the Doctor!
SUPREME DALEK: Find the Doctor.
Seek, locate, destroy.
DALEX 2: Locate.
DALEK 3: Destroy.
DALEK 4: Seek.
DALEX 2: Locate.
DALEK 5: Exterminate the Doctor.
DALEK 6: Exterminate the Doctor.
Exterminate.
CLARA: What's happening?
MISSY: What do you think?
He's in the middle of that.
Ah, that's what we need!
DALEKS: Exterminate! Exterminate!
DAVROS: Assist me.
DALEK 1: Davros approaches.
SUPREME DALEK: Admit Davros.
Admit the creator.
DAVROS: (STRAINING) Help me!
SUPREME DALEK: Assist Davros! Assist!
(DAVROS WHEEZING)
Admit it. You've all had
this exact nightmare.
Get me Sarff!
COLONY SARFF: I am here.
So, anyone for dodgems?
SUPREME DALEK: Exterminate!
DALEKS: Exterminate!
Daleks have sewers?
With one significant difference.
Being?
They are ever so slightly alive.
They're what?
How much of a drop
would you say that is?
Can you see the bottom?
It's too dark. Um...
We could chuck a stone down,
or something.
Oh, yeah, good idea.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
-(THUDS)
-Twenty feet.
Of course, the real question is,
where did I get the cup of tea?
Answer, I'm the Doctor, just accept it.
SUPREME DALEK: You are unharmed.
Proposition,
Davros is an insane, paranoid genius
who has survived among several billion
trigger-happy mini tanks for centuries.
Conclusion, I'm definitely
having his chair.
SUPREME DALEK:
You cannot escape, Doctor.
(GUN COCKING)
I am guessing that
his personal force field
only works in one direction.
SUPREME DALEK:
The Doctor does not use weapons.
DOCTOR: Doesn't he?
Ah, listen to your little hearts beat!
What?
Hello.
Oh, poppet.
Do you really think you could?
First chance I get.
MISSY: You won't survive
down here on your own.
You won't survive turning your back.
Oh, how exciting!
God, you're dull!
In future, if you're
gonna take my stick,
do me the courtesy
of actually killing me.
Teamwork is all about respect.
-We're not a team.
-Of course we are.
Every miner needs a canary.
Now hush, look around.
Bit of a mess, isn't it?
Well, you said it was a sewer.
The Daleks don't generate
much in the way of waste.
So what is it all, then?
Decaying Daleks.
Daleks can't die.
Genetically hard-wired
to keep on living,
whatever happens.
Well...
But they still age, poor loves.
Over time the body breaks down,
rots, liquefies.
Interestingly, the Dalek word for sewer
is the same as their word...
-(DECAYING DALEK SQUEALS)
-...for graveyard.
(DECAYING DALEKS SQUEALING)
Ask me what I want.
SUPREME DALEK: Irrelevant.
You will not prevail.
You will not succeed.
I've been at the heart
of your empire for 42 minutes,
and I own it,
and I haven't even
got out of my chair.
Ask me what I want.
SUPREME DALEK: What do you want?
Clara Oswald.
(OVER LOUD SPEAKER)
I want Clara Oswald.
Safe, alive,
and returned to me immediately.
You bring her back! You do that!
You do that now!
Unharmed.
Unhurt. Alive.
SUPREME DALEK: Your associate...
I saw what happened. I was there.
And I am hoping, for all of our sakes,
that it was trick.
SUPREME DALEK: It was not a deception.
Because if Clara Oswald is really dead,
then you better be very,
very careful how you tell me.
Listen to that.
The Doctor without hope.
DOCTOR: Who's going to tell me?
Who's gonna go first?
Nobody is safe now.
DOCTOR: All the power
Davros had is mine.
Everything he had, I have.
Who is going to tell me
Clara Oswald is really dead?
He'll burn everything. Us, too.
SUPREME DALEK:
Clara Oswald is not alive.
DAVROS: Doctor,
this urge for conquest...
It is gratifying to see you learn.
Davros! You're up.
Sorry, this seat's taken.
Indeed. Oh, but not by you.
-(SNAKES HISSING)
-(SHUDDERING)
You've met my head
of personal security, I think.
Colony Sarff.
-His agents are everywhere.
-(GRUNTS)
DAVROS: Are you ready?
COLONY SARFF: Of course.
Be subtle, Colony Sarff.
Tonight we entrap the Time Lord.
What is that? A lift?
What? Never mind the Llift.
See that thing on the wall?
-What about it?
-Take a look.
-What is it?
-Closer.
-What am I even looking for?
-Nothing.
I'm giving it a good look at you.
DALEK: Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
-Intruder alert!
CLARA: Why the hell did you do that?
-Ever ring a doorbell and run away?
-Humanoid detected in lower level!
But not this time.
Daleks to lower level 13.
What the hell did you do that for?
We need to trap and kill a Dalek.
You are the bait, I am the hook.
Dark star alloy,
goes through arm our plating
like a knife through people.
Missy. Missy.
Missy, uncuff me now!
It's pretty, though, isn't it?
Got it in the olden days of Gallifrey,
and the Doctor gave it to me
when my daughter...
(LIFT OPENING)
Keep it talking. We need
to draw it out of the lift.
You can't kill a Dalek with a brooch.
Yes, you can.
DALEK: Humanoid detected.
Remain still. Do not move.
Scan in progress.
Humanoid unauthorised
in restricted area.
Sterilisation proceeding.
MISSY: Hey, you!
Guess what? I just put a hole in you.
And another. And another. And another.
What are you doing?
Murdering a Dalek.
I'm a Time Lady. It's our golf.
DALEK: Damage levels insignificant.
MISSY: Oh, really?
I think you're forgetting
you're surrounded
by a bunch of very old,
very angry Daleks.
(DECAYING DALEKS SQUEALING)
MISSY: (IN US ACCENT) You just got
a puncture in a bad neighbourhood.
Meet the locals,
all blind and squelchy,
and out of their tiny minds,
but they can still smell!
Nobody hates like a Dalek.
Here they come!
I think they want to steal your motor.
DALEK: (GURGLING) Emergency! Emergency!
My vision is impaired!
Exterminate! Exterminate!
MISSY: Oh, here comes
the older generation.
Oh, young folks today are so tetchy!
Emergency! Emergency!
(EXPLOSION)
YOUNG DAVROS: Help me.
You can't leave me.
You promised. You did!
You said I could survive,
you said you'd help me!
Help me!
(BEEPING)
DAVROS: I hope you are grateful.
It wasn't easy to procure.
And very nearly unique, of course.
You should feel privileged.
The only other chair on Skaro.
-Don't get up.
-You neither.
The chamber is sealed,
and I believe you are not
carrying your sonic device.
Gave it up. Bad memories.
I am dying, Doctor.
DOCTOR: You keep saying that.
You keep not dying.
Can you give it some welly?
Come on!
And it is time for us to conclude
our business together.
We have no business.
DAVROS: We have nothing but.
Look again at the cables, Doctor.
Understand what they are.
What they can do.
Just step a little closer.
(SNIFFING)
Get in.
They don't have much
respect for you, do they,
your kids?
Have you seen the state of this place?
I mean, this is exactly where you'd dump
a smelly old uncle,
slash family pet,
slash genius scientist
who couldn't even invent legs.
Seriously, how do your boys take it
when everybody else has got two eyes?
You know what it is, of course.
Oh, yes, it's a hyperspace relay
with some kind of a genetic component.
I am connected to the life force
of every Dalek on this planet.
It is what has kept me alive.
As their hearts beat, so does mine.
Ooh!
Nice!
Vampiring off your own creations,
just to eke out your days.
I'm surprised that the Daleks allow it.
Oh, they have no choice.
My Daleks are afflicted
with a genetic defect.
What defect?
Respect.
Mercy for their father.
Design flaws I was unable to eliminate.
And now he sees it.
Now he understands.
The cables, Doctor, touch them.
Imagine, to hold in your hand
the heartbeat of every Dalek on Skaro.
They send me life.
Is it beyond the wit of a Time Lord
to send them death?
A little work, and it could be done.
Now, why would you be telling me this?
Genocide in a moment.
Such slaughter, not in self-defence,
not as a simple act of war,
genocide as a choice.
Are you ready, Doctor?
So many backs with a single knife.
(DOCTOR SHUDDERING)
DAVROS: Are you ready to be a god?
Why do you hesitate?
No one would know.
Clara Oswald is dead.
Is this the conscience of
the Doctor or his shame?
The shame that brought you here.
There's no such thing as the Doctor.
I'm just a bloke in a box,
telling stories.
And I didn't come here
because I'm ashamed.
A bit of shame never hurt anyone.
I came...
...because you're sick and you asked.
And because sometimes, on a good day,
if I try very hard,
I'm not some old Time Lord who ran away.
I'm the Doctor.
Compassion, then.
Always.
It grows strong and fierce in you,
like a cancer.
I hope so.
It will kill you in the end.
I wouldn't die of anything else.
You may rely on it.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(BEEPING)
How am I supposed to
make it go without pedals?
Telepathic control. Open wide.
I meant your skull. Never mind.
-(STATIC WHISTLING)
-Ow!
-Shh. Now, don't worry.
There's loads of nanotech repairing any
damage as the feed goes in.
-What about when it comes out?
-I've no idea. Nobody knows.
Anyway, to control the unit
you just have to think.
A novel idea for you, but let's try it.
Move forwards.
I don't know how to... (GASPS)
-You see?
-Huh!
How did I do that?
-Circle right.
-I can't.
Circle left.
There you go.
All right, this won't hurt a bit.
Hang on. No, Missy.
No, no, no, no.
No, Missy. Missy, no, no, no.
Please, don't!
Don't, don't, don't, please!
You OK?
Fine, I think.
(DALEK VOICE) Fine, I think.
-OK.
-(DALEK VOICE) OK.
That's a bit weird.
(CHUCKLING) Just a bit.
OK. All right, shh, say your name.
-(DALEK VOICE) why?
-Just... Just say it.
Clara.
(DALEK VOICE) Dalek.
Say it again.
-Clara Oswald.
-Dalek. Dalek.
MISSY: One more time.
I am Clara Oswald.
-I'm Clara Oswald.
-(DALEK VOICE) I am a Dalek.
I am a Dalek.
I am a Dalek! I am a Dalek!
(MISSY EXCLAIMS)
MISSY: Just...
Just don't get emotional.
Emotion fires the gun.
OK?
-I don't understand.
-(DALEK VOICE) I do not understand.
Say...
"I love you."
Those exact words.
Don't ask me why, just say it.
I love you.
-(DALEK VOICE) Exterminate.
-(CACKLING)
Say, "You are different from me."
-You are different from me.
-(DALEK VOICE) Exterminate!
Exterminate!
Say, "Exterminate.”
-Exterminate.
-(DALEK VOICE) Exterminate.
Exterminate! Exterminate!
(MISSY LAUGHING)
-Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate!
Cybermen supress emotion.
Daleks channel it through a gun.
That's why they keep
yelling "Exterminate,”
it's how they reload.
So let's go and kill them. Come on.
There is a question, Doctor,
one I have longed to ask.
Yeah, well, if you're gonna put your
hand on my knee, it isn't gonna go well.
Why did you leave Gallifrey?
Well, because I did.
You stole a Tardis and ran and ran.
Why?
It was a boring place, Gallifrey.
I was going out of my mind.
Yet you long to return.
Ah, well, I'm inconsistent.
But it is always the same lie.
-What lie?
-You weren't bored.
No one runs the way you have
run for so a small reason.
I do.
No, you don't.
Colony Sarff confiscated
these items on your arrival.
A Time Lord confession dial, I believe.
Your confession.
Tell me.
Send me to my grave
with this precious knowledge.
What is the Doctor's confession?
Don't you dare!
Is it possible I have touched a nerve?
Some things matter
to me, Davros. Not many, but a few.
And you don't put your
fingers anywhere near them.
And they better not be scratched.
These are my best ones.
DAVROS: Still you play the fool.
Well, by now,
that should make you nervous.
DALEK 1: Halt!
Report!
Humanoid intruder...
(DARLEK VOICE) Humanoid intruder
found on lower levels.
DARLEK 1: Why has the intruder
not been exterminated?
Explain!
Explain! Explain!
I'm a prisoner of special significance.
Count the hearts.
You are a Time Lord.
Time Lady, thank you.
Some of us can afford the upgrade.
Is it still the same old
Supreme Dalek these days?
I fought him once on
the slopes of the netherworld.
Tell him the bitch is back.
DAVROS: Make your confession, Doctor.
Why did you really leave Gallifrey?
How long has it been, you and I?
Long enough.
Galaxies have burned.
And now you ask me a personal question?
You have slaughtered
billions of my children,
as I have slaughtered
billions of your race.
We have exhausted
the conventional means of communication.
My people are alive.
They didn't die.
I brought them back. I found a way.
Is this true?
Gallifrey is back in the sky.
I don't know where, I may never know.
But Gallifrey is back and it is safe.
From both of us.
DAVROS: Doctor,
my most sincere congratulations.
(SCOFFS) I'm sorry?
This is wonderful news.
Beyond all hope.
I congratulate you.
Why are you saying that?
A man should have a race,
a people, an allegiance.
A man should belong.
Doctor, believe me, please...
I am happy for you.
So happy.
I don't... I don't understand this.
Why are you...
DAVROS: Come closer again.
Let me see your face.
You've seen it often enough.
Let me see it again,
with my own eyes.
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Closer.
Please.
If you have redeemed
the Time Lords from the fire,
do not lose them again.
Take the darkest path
into the deepest hell,
but protect your own,
as I have sought to protect mine.
Did I do right, Doctor?
Tell me.
Was I right?
I need to know,
before the end,
am I a good man?
You really are dying, aren't you?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Look at me.
Did you doubt it?
Yes.
Then we have established one thing only.
What?
You are not a good doctor.
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
Pity.
I had hoped to see the sun
one last time,
with the eyes of my true self.
Oh, hello! (SCOFFS)
Look at you all,
with your nice shiny domes.
Oh! I am loving this.
You're my secret favourite,
don't tell the others.
SUPREME DARLEK: You are an enemy
of the Daleks.
Yes, well anyone who's not a Dalek
is an enemy of the Daleks,
so that was an easy guess.
You will be exterminated.
Please, please do because
I have been on my feet all day.
But before you get all 'exterminatey',
two things.
One, I want to see Davros.
Two, I have a lovely
little gift for you all,
if you take me to him right now.
We do not negotiate.
Clara Oswald.
I've brought you complete control
of the Doctor, gift-wrapped.
Better!
Canned.
DAVROS: It is beautiful,
my world, is it not?
DOCTOR: How did you get it back?
The Daleks remade it.
(CLEARING THROAT) Like you,
they have a strong concept of home.
No, like you.
Everything you are, they are.
Hmm, like both of us, perhaps.
How far we have come to go home again.
I'm trying to pep this up,
but you've been gone a long time.
Every Dalek on Skaro
isn't enough any more.
It is so good of you to help me.
I'm not helping you.
I'm helping a little boy
I abandoned on a battlefield.
I think I owe him a sunrise.
-Come on, chin up.
-(GROANS)
Any minute now.
I have always admired you, Doctor.
Here it comes.
I wish,
just once,
we had been on the same side.
Look, the sun's coming up.
We're on the same side now.
I regret...
I cannot...
Open my eyes.
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
OK.
Don't ever tell anyone that I did this.
A little bit of regeneration energy.
Probably cost me an arm
or a leg somewhere down the line.
Or I'll just be really little.
(CHUCKLES)
(DAVROS LAUGHS)
Should be enough, just to...
(SCREAMING)
Hold him firm, Colony Sarff.
He is precious to us now.
(GROANING)
DOCTOR: What are you doing?
Regeneration energy,
the ancient magic of the Time Lords.
I thought I would have to tear you apart
to take it from you,
but as always,
your compassion is your downfall.
(GROANING)
No, please, no!
You have opened your veins
of your own free will,
and all Daleks shall
drink the blood of Gallifrey.
They shall rise stronger than ever.
(SCREAMING)
Where is Clara Oswald?
You will tell us! You will tell us/
You will tell us/
(DARLEKS POWER DOWN)
I'm sorry, was I, um...
Was I boring you?
No, no, no, no, Doctor,
what have you done?
-What's happening?
-(IN DALEK VOICE) What is happening?
I have to find the Doctor.
-No! No!
-(IN DALEK VOICE) Exterminate!
Exterminate!
-You can't just leave me here.
There was a prophecy, Doctor,
on your own world.
(PANTING) I must... I must stop this.
I must stop this!
It spoke of a hybrid creature.
Two great warrior races
forced together
to create a warrior greater than either.
Is that what you ran from, Doctor?
Your part in the coming of the Hybrid?
Half Dalek,
half Time Lord.
-(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
-Give me your gun!
Stop!
(SCREAMING)
(HISSING)
We are renewed.
We are more powerful.
The experiment has succeeded.
All praise Davros!
DALEKS: (CHANTING) All praise Davros!
Morning.
-Where's Clara?
-MISSY: Oh, hello to you, too.
You're alive, so she is too,
where is she?
I'm fine, thanks for asking.
Oh, you are not fine.
Thanks to you, Doctor,
my creations shall grow
to yet greater supremacy,
and my own life is prolonged.
This is the final defeat
of the Time Lords.
Have you nothing to say, Doctor?
Three!
Do you understand what has happened?
Hear my children sing.
Two!
Ooh, I know that face.
All praise Davros!
Creator, and saviour, of the Daleks.
-One!
-(CRASH)
What is that?
(CRASH)
What's happening?
We are under attack/
Explain!
I knew exactly what you were doing,
and I let you do it.
You transmitted regeneration energy
into every Dalek on this planet.
Every single one.
What have you done?
One word. No, two words
actually. Uh, first word...
Moron.
(SNIGGERS)
Second word. Sewers.
DALEK: We have emergency!
What is happening?
Our power is fluctuating!
No!
This cannot be correct!
How can this be?
Generations of Daleks
just woke up, very cross
and they are coming up the pipes!
Or to put it another way, bye!
Doctor, you must help me!
Can I just say it's been an
absolute pleasure to finally meet you.
(GROANS)
Doctor!
DALEK 1: My vision is impaired.
I cannot see.
DALEK 2: Alert! I cannot control.
DALEK: Doctor!
This city is about to be
sucked into the ground.
Your own sewer is about to consume you.
There's no way you can win,
there is nothing you can do.
So just tell me, where is Clara Oswald?
I am a Dalek.
Yes, you're a Dalek. Where is Clara?
Yes, I know that you're a Dalek.
Where is Clara Oswald?
It's me! I'm right here, it's me!
I'm in here, it's Clara!
(DALEK VOICE) I am a Dalek.
I am a Dalek.
Doctor, stop!
MISSY: It's you, isn't it?
No, I mean, no offence,
you all look alike, but it is you?
Yes, it's me, it's me. I'm right here.
Affirmative.
Clara's dead, Doctor.
This is the one that killed her.
Do not listen to her.
I am a Dalek. I am a Dalek.
I got her out of the city, but this one
caught us and shot her down.
There was nothing
I could do, I'm afraid.
I am a Dalek.
She ran. She screamed.
I'm so glad you didn't have to see that.
I am a Dalek. I am a Dalek.
This one's mad one, isn't it?
I mean it's almost, like,
like it's proud.
I am a Dalek. I am a Dalek.
I am a Dalek.
Kill it, Doctor.
They're all going to die anyway.
Indulge yourself., go on.
Kill the Dalek.
Do not kill me! Do not kill me!
Is Clara dead?
No!
Doctor, no. I'm not dead,
I'm in here! Can you hear me?
I am a Dalek.
I am alive.
I'm your friend. I'm your friend!
I am your enemy. Your enemy...
No, please, don't.
DALEK: Mercy. Mercy.
You shouldn't be able to say that.
Mercy.
That word shouldn't exist
in your vocabulary.
-How did Davros teach you to say that?
-Mercy.
Why aren't you trying to kill me?
Mercy.
Because I would never kill you.
You are the last person
I would ever kill.
I show mercy.
I'm putting the gun down.
Open your casing.
-How?
Just think the word "open,” it'll work.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Ah, look at that.
Now, there's a surprise.
Missy, run!
Doctor.
In a way, this is why I gave her to you
in the first place,
to make you see.
The friend inside the enemy.
The enemy inside the friend.
I'm sorry, Clara. I'm so sorry.
MISSY: Everyone's a bit of both.
Everyone's a hybrid.
I said run!
It wasn't me who ran, Doctor.
That was always you.
(DECAYING DALEKS SQUEALING)
Emergency!
Dalek control is compromised.
Where was the Tardis?
It was over there somewhere, wasn't it?
SUPREME DALEK: What is happening?
Explain! Explain!
Dalek Supreme,
your sewers are revolting.
You will assist or you
will be exterminated.
Ah, well, go on then, exterminate away!
Doctor!
Oops, sorry.
Tardis force field's still here.
We get in, you don't.
The Tardis has been destroyed!
Oh, don't be silly, of course it hasn't.
It's just redistributed
itself for a moment.
Hostile Action Dispersal System.
I'll just give it a quick
blast from my sonic,
and the real time envelope
will reassemble right here.
Doctor, you don't have your screwdriver.
Oh, yeah, I'm over screwdrivers.
They spoil the line of your jacket.
These days, I'm all about
wearable technology.
CLARA: No!
No.
Seriously?
SUPREME DALEK: What is happening?
Ah, same old, same old.
Just the Doctor
and Clara Oswald in the Tardis.
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
Humanoid detected.
Remain still.
Do not move. Do not move.
You are a Time Lord!
(GRUNTING)
You know what?
I've just had a very clever idea.
(EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE)
No chance you're going to tell me what's
in that confession dial, I suppose?
(CLARA CHUCKLES)
Doesn't make sense.
What doesn't?
When you were in the Dalek,
you made it say "mercy."
It shouldn't have
understood the concept.
It shouldn't have been able to say it.
How did a tiny piece of mercy
get into the DNA of the Daleks?
Doctor?
YOUNG DAVROS: Help me!
You can't leave me, you promised.
You said I had a chance.
(WHOOSHING)
Who are you?
I don't get it.
How did you get there?
From the future.
Are you going to save me?
I'm going to save my friend,
the only way I can.
-(COCKS GUN)
-Exterminate!
Come on.
I'll take you home.
DAVROS: Which side are you on?
Are you the enemy?
I'm not sure that any of that matters,
friends, enemies.
So long as there's mercy.
Always mercy.
CLARA: I want another adventure.
Monsters, things blowing up.
DOCTOR: Be careful what you wish for.
We are fighting
an unknown homicidal force.
Underwater, in a nuclear reactor.
Everything I think it couldn't
get more extraordinary, it surprises me.
They can walk through walls.
They only come out at night.
It's impossible. I hate it!
It's evil. It's astonishing.
-Who the hell are you?
-The Doctor!
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)