Out of my way!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Doctor!
Where's the Doctor?
Doctor who?
(DOCTOR SNEEZING)
(GROWLING)
You know, this isn't nearly
as bad as it looks.
"At the personal intervention
of the King,
"the unnamed Doctor was incarcerated
"without trial in the Tower of London."
Okay, but it doesn't have to be him.
"According to contemporary accounts,
two nights later, a magical sphere,
"some 20 feet across,
was seen floating away from the Tower,
-"bearing the mysterious Doctor aloft."
-Okay, it's him.
AMY: There's more.
Doctor. Doctor, what can you see?
Is the commandant's office
painted a sort of green colour
with a big flag on the wall?
(ALARM SOUNDING)
-I think the answer is probably "yes".
-(DOGS BARKING)
-Get him up!
-Ow!
It's like he's being
deliberately ridiculous,
trying to attract our attention.
Are you watching this again?
-(DOORBELL RINGS)
-Yeah, I've explained the jokes.
So what are you saying?
Do you really think he's back there
trying to wave to us
out of history books?
Hey, it's the sort of thing he'd do.
Thanks.
Yeah, but why?
Well, he said he'd be in touch.
-Two months ago.
-Two months is nothing.
He's up to something.
I know he is. I know him.
What is it?
Amy?
A date, a time, a map reference.
I think it's an invitation.
-From who?
-It's not signed.
Look, Tardis blue.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
You'd better get down here, sir.
She's doing it again.
Dr Song, sir.
She's packing.
Says she's going to
some planet called America.
-Thanks!
-DRIVER: You're very welcome!
This is it, yeah? The right place?
Uh, nowhere, middle of?
Yeah, this it.
Howdy.
-Doctor!
-(LAUGHS)
It's the Pond!
-Hey!
-Come on, Pond. Hello, Pond! Come here!
So someone's been a busy boy, then, eh?
-Did you see me?
-Of course.
-Stalker.
-Flirt.
-Husband.
-Rory the Roman! Oh, come here!
Ooh, ah.
Hey, nice hat.
I wear a Stetson now. Stetsons are cool.
(GUN FIRES)
Hello, sweetie.
Right, then, where are we?
-Have we done Easter Island yet?
-Um...
Yes! I've got Easter Island.
They worshipped you there.
Have you seen the statues?
Jim the Fish.
Oh! Jim the Fish.
How is he?
Still building his dam.
Sorry, what are you two doing?
They're both time travellers,
so they never meet in the right order.
They're syncing their diaries.
So what's happening, then?
Because you've been up to something.
I've been running,
faster than I've ever run,
and I've been running my whole life.
Now it's time for me to stop.
And tonight, I'm going to
need you all with me.
Okay.
We're here. What's up?
A picnic.
And then a trip.
Somewhere different,
somewhere brand new.
Where?
Space.
1969.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
DOCTOR: Salud!
ALL: Salud!
So when are we going to 19697
And since when do you drink wine?
I'm 1103. I must've drunk it sometime.
Oh, why, it's horrid!
I thought it would taste
more like the gums.
11037 You were 908
the last time we saw you.
And you've put on a couple of pounds.
I wasn't going to mention it.
Who's that?
Hmm? Who's who?
Sorry, what?
What did you see?
You said you saw something.
No, I didn't.
Ah! The moon.
Look at it.
Of course, you lot did a lot
more than look, didn't you?
A big silvery thing in the sky.
You couldn't resist it.
Quite right.
The moon landing was in '69.
Is that where we're going?
Oh, well, a lot more happens in '69
than anyone remembers.
Human beings.
I thought I'd never get done saving you.
Who's he?
Oh, my God!
DOCTOR: You all need to stay back.
Whatever happens now,
you do not interfere.
Clear?
RORY: That's an astronaut.
That's an Apollo astronaut in the lake.
Look.
Hello.
It's okay. I know it's you.
Well, then.
What's he doing?
-(GUN FIRES)
-Doctor!
Amy, stay back!
-(GUN FIRES)
-The Doctor said stay back!
-We have to stay back!
-No! No!
AMY: Doctor!
I'm sorry.
(GUN FIRES)
RIVER: No! Doctor!
AMY: Doctor, please!
AMY: River. River!
(DEVICE BEEPS)
No. No.
(RIVER FIRING GUN)
(CLICKS)
Of course not.
AMY: River, he can't be dead.
This isn't possible.
Whatever that was, it killed him
in the middle of his regeneration cycle.
His body was already dead.
He didn't make it to the next one.
AMY: But maybe he's a clone
or a duplicate or something.
I believe I can save you some time.
That most certainly is the Doctor.
And he is most certainly dead.
He said you'd need this.
Gasoline?
A Time Lord's body is a miracle,
even a dead one.
There are whole empires out there
who'd rip this world apart
for just one cell.
We can't leave him here.
Or anywhere.
Wake up.
Go on, wake up!
You stupid, bloody idiot.
What do we do, Rory?
We're his friends.
We do what the Doctor's
friends always do.
As we're told.
There's a boat.
If we're going to do this,
let's do it properly.
Who are you?
Why did you come?
The same reason as you.
Dr Song,
Amy,
Rory.
I'm Canton Everett Delaware III.
I won't be seeing you again,
but you'll be seeing me.
Four.
Sorry, what?
The Doctor numbered the envelopes.
You got 3, I was 2, Mr Delaware was 4.
So?
So where's 1?
What, you think he invited someone else?
Well, he must have.
RIVER: He planned all of this,
to the last detail.
Will you two shut up? It doesn't matter.
-RIVER: He was up to something.
-He's dead.
"Space 1969." What did he mean?
You're still talking,
but it doesn't matter.
-Hey, it mattered to him.
-So it matters to us.
-He's dead.
-But he still needs us.
I know.
Amy, I know.
But right now, we have to focus.
Look.
Excuse me, who was sitting over there?
Some guy.
The Doctor knew
he was going to his death,
so he sent out messages.
When you know it's the end,
who do you call?
Uh, your friends, people you trust.
Number 1.
Who did the Doctor trust the most?
This is cold.
Even by your standards, this is cold.
Or "hello", as people used to say.
Doctor?
I just popped out
to get my special straw.
It adds more fizz.
You're okay. How can you be okay?
Hey, of course I'm okay.
I'm always okay. I'm the king of okay.
Oh, that's a rubbish title.
Forget that title.
Rory the Roman!
That's a good title. Hello, Rory.
And Dr River Song.
Oh, you bad, bad girl.
What trouble have you got
for me this time?
Okay.
I'm assuming that's for
something I haven't done yet.
Yes, it is.
Good. Looking forward to that.
I don't understand.
How can you be here?
I was invited.
Date, map reference.
Same as you lot, I assume. Otherwise,
it's a hell of a coincidence.
River, what's going on?
Amy, ask him what age he is.
-That's a bit personal.
-Tell her.
-Tell her what age you are.
-909.
-Yeah, but you said you were...
-So where does that leave us, huh?
Jim the Fish?
Have we done Jim the Fish yet?
Who's Jim the Fish?
I don't understand.
Yeah, you do.
I don't! What are we all doing here?
We've been recruited.
Something to do with space, 1969,
and a man called
Canton Everett Delaware III.
Recruited by who?
Someone who trusts you
more than anybody else in the universe.
And who's that?
Spoilers.
1969, that's an easy one!
Funny how some years are easy.
Now, 1482, full of glitches.
Now, then, Canton Everett Delaware III.
That was his name, yeah?
How many of those can there be?
Well, three, I suppose.
Rory, is everybody cross with me
for some reason?
I'LL find out.
Explain it again?
The Doctor we saw on the beach
is a future version,
200 years older than the one up there.
But all that's still going to happen,
he's still going to die?
We're all going to do that, Amy.
We're not all going to arrange
our own wake and invite ourselves.
So, the Doctor, in the future,
knowing he's going to die,
recruits his younger self
and all of us to...to what, exactly?
Avenge him?
-Mmm-mmm. Avenging's not his style.
-Save him.
RORY: Yeah, that's not really
his style, either.
Well, we have to tell him.
We've told him all we can.
We can't even tell him
we've seen his future self.
He's interacted with his own past.
It could rip a hole in the universe.
Except he's done it before.
And, in fairness,
the universe did blow up.
-But he'd want to know!
-Would he? Would anyone?
I'm being extremely clever up here
and there's no one to stand around
looking impressed!
What's the point in having you all?
Couldn't you just slap him sometimes?
River, we can't just let him die.
We have to stop it.
How can you be okay with this?
The Doctor's death doesn't frighten me,
nor does my own.
There's a far worse day coming for me.
Time isn't a straight line.
It's all bumpy-wumpy.
There's loads of boring stuff,
like Sundays and Tuesdays
and Thursday afternoons.
But now and then, there are Saturdays,
big, temporal tipping points
when anything's possible.
The Tardis can't resist them,
like a moth to a flame.
She loves a party,
so I gave her 1969 and NASA,
because that's space in the '60s,
and Canton Everett Delaware III,
and this is where she's pointing.
Washington, DC. April the 8th, 1969.
So why haven't we landed?
-Because that's not where we're going.
-Oh.
-Where are we going?
-Home! Well, you two are.
Off you pop and make babies.
And you, Dr Song, back to prison.
And me?
I'm late for a biplane lesson in 1911.
Or it could be knitting.
Knitting or biplanes, one or the other.
What?
A mysterious summons.
You think I'm just going to go?
Who sent those messages?
I know you know,
I can see it in your faces.
Don't play games with me.
Don't ever, ever think
you're capable of that.
You're going to have to trust us
this time.
DOCTOR: Trust you? Sure.
But first of all, Dr Song,
just one thing.
Who are you?
You're someone from my future,
getting that, but who?
Okay.
Why are you in prison?
Who did you kill?
Hmm?
Now, I love a bad girl, me,
but trust you?
Seriously?
Trust me.
Okay.
You have to do this
and you can't ask why.
Are you being threatened?
Is someone making you say that?
No.
-You're lying.
-I'm not lying.
Swear to me.
Swear to me, on something that matters.
Fish fingers and custard.
My life in your hands,
Amelia Pond.
Thank you.
So! Canton Everett Delaware III.
Who's he?
-Who wants to know?
-Your boss.
I don't have a boss any more.
Maybe you want to tell that
to the President of the United States.
-Ex-FBI. Got kicked out.
-Why?
PRESIDENT: (ON PHONE) I understand
you have a problem with authority.
-Thank you.
-That's not a compliment, son.
Six weeks after he left the Bureau,
the President contacted him
for a private meeting.
Yeah, 1969. Who's President?
This is a personal matter.
I need someone on the outside,
someone with FBI training,
but who's not in contact with them.
I'm flattered.
You were my second choice
for this, Mr Delaware.
That's okay.
You were my second choice
for President, Mr Nixon.
RIVER: Richard Milhous Nixon.
Vietnam, Watergate.
-There's some good stuff, too.
-Not enough.
-Hippie!
-Archaeologist.
Every day, wherever I am,
I get a phone call.
People can't just call you,
Mr President.
It's a direct call every time.
Every day for the last two weeks,
usually late at night.
Man or woman?
Neither.
Listen.
Okay, since I don't know
what I'm getting into this time,
for once, I'm being discreet,
putting the engines on silent.
Did you do something?
No, just watching.
Putting the outer shell on "invisible".
Haven't done this in a while.
Big drain on the power.
-You can turn the Tardis invisible?
-Ha!
Very nearly.
Uh, did you touch something?
Just admiring your skills, sweetie.
Good. You might learn something.
Okay.
Now, I can't check the scanner, it
doesn't work when we're cloaked. Um...
Just give us a mo...
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You lot, wait a moment.
We're in the middle
of the most powerful city
in the most powerful country on Earth.
Let's take it slow.
(PHONE RINGING ON TAPE)
NIXON: Hello?
Who is this?
This is President Nixon. Who's calling?
Is this you again?
-CHILD: Mr President?
-A child.
This is the President, yes.
I'm scared, Mr President.
I'm scared of the spaceman.
-A little girl?
-Boy.
How can you be sure?
NIXON: What spaceman?
Where are you phoning from?
Where are you right now?
Who are you?
CHILD: Jefferson Adams Hamilton.
NIXON: Jefferson, listen to me.
(HANGS UP, DIALLING TONE DRONES)
Surely this is something
the Bureau could handle, sir.
These calls happen wherever I am.
How do I know the Bureau isn't involved?
I can't trust anyone...
Oh!
Hello.
Bad moment.
Oh, look, this is the Oval Office.
I was looking for the, er, Oblong Room.
I'll just be off, then,
shall I?
Every time.
Don't worry!
It always does that when its cloaked.
No! Stop that.
-He said the scanner wouldn't work.
-I know.
Bless.
-Ow, ow...
-Lockdown! Lockdown!
Stop that! Ow!
River, have you got
my scanner working yet?
Oh, I hate him.
-No, you don't!
-AGENT: Get the President out of here!
Sir, you have to go with them now!
River, make her blue again!
What the hell is that?
Mr President, that child just told you
everything you need to know,
but you weren't listening.
Never mind, though,
because the answer's yes.
I'll take the case.
Fellas, the guns, really?
I just walked into the highest security
office in the United States,
parked a big, blue box on the rug.
Do you think you can just shoot me?
They're Americans!
Don't shoot. Definitely no shooting.
RORY: No need to shoot us, either.
Very much not in need of getting shot.
Look, we've got our hands up.
-Who the hell are you?
-Sir, you need to stay back.
But who are they and what is that box?
It's a police box. Can't you read?
I'm your new undercover agent,
on loan from Scotland Yard.
Codename: The Doctor.
These are my top operatives:
The Legs, The Nose
and Mrs Robinson.
-I hate you.
-No, you don't.
-AGENT: Who are you?
-Nah, a boring question.
"Who's phoning you?" That's interesting.
Because Canton III is right,
that was definitely a girl's voice,
which means there's only one place
in America she can be phoning from.
Where?
Do not engage with the intruder,
Mr Delaware.
You heard everything I heard.
It's simple enough.
Give me five minutes, I'll explain.
On the other hand, lay a finger on me
or my friends
and you'll never, ever know.
How did you get it in here?
I mean, you didn't carry it in.
-Clever, eh?
-Love it.
Do not compliment the intruder!
-Five minutes?
-Five.
Mr President, that man is
a clear and present danger to...
Mr President, that man walked in here
with a big, blue box
and three of his friends
and that's the man he walked past.
One of them's worth listening to.
I say we give him five minutes,
see if he delivers.
Thanks, Canton.
If he doesn't, I'll shoot him myself.
Not so thanks.
-Sir, I cannot recommend...
-Shut up, Mr Peterson!
All right.
Five minutes.
I'm going to need a SWAT team,
ready to mobilise,
street-level maps
covering all of Florida,
a pot of coffee,
12 Jammie Dodgers and a fez.
Get him his maps.
-Why Florida?
-That's where NASA is.
She mentioned a spaceman.
NASA's where the spacemen live.
Also, there's another lead
I'm following.
A spaceman,
like the one we saw at the lake.
Maybe.
Probably.
(ALIEN CHITTERING)
Who's that?
I remember.
Amy?
What do you remember?
I don't know. I just...
Amy, what's wrong?
Amy?
-You all right?
-Yeah, no, I'm fine.
I'm just feeling a little sick.
Excuse me,
is there a toilet or something?
Sorry, ma"am,
while this procedure's ongoing,
you must remain within the Oval Office.
Shut up and take her to the restroom.
-This way, ma'am.
-Thanks.
Your five minutes are up.
Yeah? And where's my fez?
Actually, I can usually
manage this alone.
(ALIEN CHITTERING)
I saw you before, at the lake.
And here.
But then I forgot.
How did I forget?
What are you?
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Get back! Stay back from it.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, my God!
What is that? Is that a mask?
Is that a Star Trekthing?
Ben, is that you?
Get back from it, now!
Back from what, honey?
That.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, my God! Look at that.
Is that a Star Trek mask?
Ben, that's got to be you.
Hang on, did I just say all that?
No, please, you've got to stay back.
Back, honey? Back from what?
Oh, those lights. They never fix them.
Look behind you.
Honey, there is nothing...
(SCREAMING)
(AMY PANTING)
You didn't have to kill her.
She couldn't even remember you.
How does that work?
We can only remember you
while we're seeing you, is that it?
Why did you have to kill her?
Joy.
Her name was joy.
Your name is Amelia.
You will tell the Doctor.
Tell him what?
What he must know.
And what he must never know.
How do you know about that?
Tell him.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Much better, thanks.
What's that?
It's my phone.
Your phone?
I have to tell the Doctor.
Tell him what, ma'am?
Sorry, I don't know why I said that.
This way, ma'am.
(PHONE RINGING)
The kid?
-Should I answer it?
-Here!
The only place in the United States
that call could be coming from.
See? Obvious, when you think about it.
(PHONE RINGING)
-You, sir, are a genius.
-It's a hobby.
Mr President, answer the phone.
Hello?
This is President Nixon.
GIRL: It's here!
The spaceman's here!
It's going to get me!
It's going to eat me!
There's no time for
a SWAT team, let's go.
Mr President,
tell her help's on the way.
Canton, on no account
follow me into this box
-and close the door behind you.
-What the hell are you doing?
(WHOOSHING)
GIRL: Mr President! Please help.
Please help me!
Jefferson, it's all right.
I'm sending my best people.
DOCTOR: Jefferson isn't a girl's
name. It's not her name, either.
Jefferson, Adams, Hamilton. River?
Surnames of three of
America's founding fathers.
Lovely fellows. Two of them fancied me.
Are you okay, coping?
You see, the President
asked the child two questions,
"Where are you?" and "Who are you?"
She was answering "where".
It's bigger on the inside.
Ah, you get used to it.
DOCTOR: Now, where would you find
three big historical names
in a row like that?
-Where?
-Here.
Come on!
It's, uh...
Are you taking care of this?
Why is it always my turn?
Because you're the newest.
AMY: Where are we?
About five miles
from Cape Kennedy Space Center.
It's 1969, the year of the moon.
Interesting, don't you think?
But why would a little girl be here?
I don't know. Lost me a bit.
The President asked the girl
where she was
and she did what any lost
little girl would do.
She looked out of the window.
Streets! Of course, street names.
The only place in Florida,
probably all of America,
with those three street names
on the same junction.
And Dr Song,
you've got that face on again.
What face?
The "he's hot when he's clever" face.
-This is my normal face.
-Yes, it is.
-Oh, shut up.
-Not a chance.
We've moved.
How can we have moved?
You haven't even got
to space travel yet?
I was going to cover it
with time travel.
-Time travel?
-Braveheart Canton, come on.
So we're in a box
that's bigger on the inside
-and it travels through time and space?
-Yeah, basically.
How long have Scotland Yard had this?
RIVER: It's a warehouse
of some kind, disused.
DOCTOR: You realise this is
almost certainly a trap, of course?
I noticed the phone, yes.
AMY: What about it?
RIVER: It was cut off.
So how did the child phone from here?
AMY: Okay, but why would
anyone want to trap us?
DOCTOR: Dunno. Let's see if anyone
tries to kill us and work backwards.
(RHYTHMIC DEEP BREATHING)
Now, why would a little girl be here?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
Let's find her and ask her.
RIVER: It's non terrestrial.
Definitely alien.
Probably not even from this time zone.
Which is odd, because look at this!
It's earth tech, contemporary.
Very contemporary, cutting-edge.
This is from the space programme!
-RIVER: Stolen?
-What, by aliens?
Apparently.
But why? I mean, if you can
make it all the way to Earth,
why steal technology that
can barely make it to the moon?
Maybe 'cause it's cooler!
Look how cool this stuff is!
Cool aliens?
Well, what would you call me?
-An alien.
-Oi!
I, uh... I think he's okay now.
DOCTOR: Ah! Back with us, Canton?
-I like your wheels.
-That's my boy.
So come on. Little girl, let's find her.
-River...
-I know what you're thinking.
No, you don't.
You're thinking, "If we can find
the spaceman in 1969 and neutralise it,
"then it won't be around
in 2011 to kill the Doctor."
Okay, lucky guess.
It's only because
I was thinking it, too.
So let's do it.
It doesn't work like that.
We came here because of
what we saw in the future.
If we try and prevent the future
from happening, we create a paradox.
Time can be rewritten.
-Not all of it.
-Says who?
Who do you think?
What's this?
-We can still save him...
-Doctor, look at this.
So where does that go?
RIVER: There's a network of
tunnels running under here.
-Life signs?
-No, nothing that's showing up.
Those are the worst kind.
Be careful!
Careful? I tried that once.
Ever so dull.
-Shout if you get in trouble.
-Don't worry, I'm quite the screamer.
Now, there's a spoiler for you.
So what's going on here?
Uh, nothing. She's just a friend.
I think he's talking about
the possible alien incursion.
Okay.
(ALIENS CHITTERING)
So,
I was in a bar, having a drink.
Tell me honestly, am I still there?
Afraid not.
(PANTING)
All clear.
Just tunnels.
Nothing down there I can see.
Uh, give me five minutes.
I want to take another look around.
Stupidly dangerous!
Yep! I like it, too.
Amy, look after him.
Rory, would you mind going with her?
Yeah, a bit.
Then I appreciate it all the more.
Hang on, River.
I'm coming, too.
You okay?
Ah, yes, yes.
I just felt a bit sick.
It's the prison food, probably.
Okay, this way?
What do you think?
I keep thinking I hear things.
It's interesting. These tunnels are old.
Really old.
How can they be really old
and nobody notice them?
It's a maintenance hatch.
It's locked.
Oh, why do people always lock things?
What's through there?
-RIVER: I've no idea.
-Something bad?
Almost definitely.
You're going to open it, aren't you?
Well, it's locked.
How's a girl supposed to resist?
-Is this sensible?
-God, I hope not.
Yeah, you and the Doctor,
I can kind of picture it.
Keep a look out.
What did you mean?
What you said to Amy,
there's a worse day coming for you?
When I first met the Doctor,
a long, long time ago,
he knew all about me.
Think about that.
Impressionable young girl and suddenly,
this man just drops out of the sky.
And he's clever and mad and wonderful
and knows every last thing about her.
Imagine what that does to a girl.
I don't really have to.
Trouble is it's all back-to-front.
My past is his future.
We're travelling in opposite directions.
Every time we meet, I know him more,
he knows me less.
I live for the days when I see him,
but I know that every time I do,
he'll be one step further away.
And the day is coming
when I'll look into that man's eyes,
my Doctor,
and he won't have
the faintest idea who I am.
(WHIRRS)
And I think it's going to kill me.
What is this place?
That's an alarm.
Check if anything's coming.
(CHITTERING)
There's nothing out there.
These tunnels, they're not just here,
they're everywhere.
They're running under the surface
of the entire planet.
They've been here for centuries.
Rory!
So,
you were kicked out of the FBI
because you had attitude problems?
No, I just wanted to get married.
-Is that a crime?
-Yes.
Doctor who, exactly?
Ah...
That's classified.
-Classified by whom?
-God knows.
Do you work for him?
He's my friend,
if friend is the right word.
I haven't seen him in a while.
I had something I wanted to tell him,
but stuff always gets in the way.
Stuff does that.
GIRL: Help me!
-Help! Help me!
-That's her.
-(GROANING)
-Amy?
-GIRL: Help me, please!
-What's wrong?
I need to tell you something.
It's important.
-Doctor!
-It's really, really important.
-Doctor, quickly!
-What, now?
Canton! Canton! Are you okay?
Is he all right?
Just unconscious. Got a proper whack.
Doctor, I need to tell you something.
-I have to tell you it now.
-Not a great moment.
No, it's important. It has to be now.
GIRL: Help! Help me!
-Help me!
-Doctor,
I'm pregnant.
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
That's it, the astronaut.
-Help me!
-Get down!
-What are you doing?
-Saving your life!
-No!
-(GUN FIRING)
(SCREAMING)
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to shoot you.
MISSION CONTROL:
Thirty seconds and counting.
We are still go with Apollo 11.
DOCTOR: They are everywhere.
RORY: It's like they edit themselves
out of your memory
-as soon as you look away.
- Twenty seconds and counting.
AMY: We still don't know
what they look like.
DOCTOR: As long as there's been
something in the corner of your eye
or creaking in your house
or breathing under your bed
or voices through a wall.
MISSION CONTROL: 7 minus 10...
DOCTOR: We are not fighting an
alien invasion.
-We're leading a revolution.
-MISSION CONTROL: Five, four, three,
-two, one...
-(SCREAMING)
MISSION CONTROL: Good luck and godspeed.