WOMAN: No! Just back off!
(GRUNTS)
MAN 1: Come on!
You're going to regret this.
Completely ridiculous!
Get your hand off me.
(GRUNTS)
I think that makes my answer clear.
Don't you?
Oh, and, uh...
If you're going to go to print,
spell my name right.
Rattigan, with two Ts.
Oh, this goes way beyond the newspapers.
This thing's worldwide.
I'm telling you, Atmos is dangerous.
But if you had proof,
then you wouldn't be here.
Fine.
If you won't listen,
I'll find someone else who will.
ATMOS: Welcome.
What is your destination?
You're the last thing I need.
Atmos cannot be disabled.
(GRUNTS)
Right then.
Take me to UNIT headquarters,
Tower Bridge, London.
UNIT headquarters.
Her name's Jo Nakashima,
a freelance journalist.
Clever by the sound of it,
not as clever as me,
but that goes without saying.
I'd recommend termination.
ATMOS: Remember your status, boy.
We do not take orders from humans.
I said, "Recommend".
Then your advice shows military wisdom.
She will be terminated.
Cool.
RECORDED VOICE:
This is UNIT, extension 2217...
Don't put me through to answerphone.
(BEEP)
Yes, this is a message
for Colonel Mace from Jo, Jo Nakashima.
Look, you should've got my e-mail.
I've been investigating a number
of deaths related to Atmos systems.
SATNAV: Go straight on.
Now I can't prove anything,
but there's got to be a link.
I need you to check out all the people
who died in Atmos cars yesterday.
-And then, check out the time.
-Turn right.
-I don't believe this.
-This is your final destination.
I said, take me to UNIT.
(BEEPS)
Go straight on.
I don't think so.
I'll find my own way, thanks.
(ENGINE REVVING)
This is your final destination.
-This is your final destination.
-No!
-No! Help!
-This is your final destination.
-No, no, no! No!
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-I can't believe I'm doing this.
-No. Neither can I.
Whoa, whoa, careful.
Left hand down. Left hand down.
Getting a bit too close to the 1980s.
What am I going to do?
Put a dent in them?
Someone did.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Hold on.
That's a phone.
-You've got a mobile? Since when?
-It's not mine.
Hello.
Doctor, it's Martha.
And I'm bringing you back to Earth.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(WHOOSHING)
-Martha Jones.
-Doctor.
-You haven't changed a bit.
-Neither have you.
-How's the family?
-You know, not so bad. Recovering.
What about you?
Right. I should've known.
Didn't take you long to replace me then.
-Now, don't start fighting.
-Martha, Donna. Donna, Martha.
Please don't fight.
I can't bear fighting.
(CHUCKLING) You wish.
I've heard all about you.
He talks about you all the time.
-I dread to think.
-No, no, no.
No. He says nice things, good things.
Nice things. Really good things.
Oh, my God! He's told you everything.
Didn't take you long
to get over it, though.
Who's the lucky man?
-What man? The lucky what?
-She's engaged, you prawn.
-Really? Who to?
-Tom. That Tom Milligan.
He's in paediatrics.
Working out in Africa right now,
and yes, I know,
I've got a doctor who disappears off
to distant places. Tell me about it.
-Is he skinny?
-No. He's sort of strong.
He is too skinny for words.
You give him a hug, you get a paper cut.
-Oh, I thought you were fighting.
-No. Speaking of which...
WOMAN ON WALKIE-TALKIE:
Dr Jones, report to base, please. Over.
This is Dr Jones.
Operation Blue Sky is go, go, go.
I repeat, this is a go.
SOLDIER: Unified Intelligence
Task Force. Raise that barrier now.
Leave your safeties on, lads.
It's non-hostiles.
OVER LOUDSPEAKER: All workers,
lay down your tools and surrender.
MARTHA: Greyhound 16 to Trap One,
B Section. Go, go, go!
Search the ground floor.
Grid pattern Delta.
-What are you searching for?
-Illegal aliens.
SOLDIER: 7his is a UNIT operation.
All workers lay down your tools
and surrender immediately.
B Section mobilised.
E Section, F Section, on my command.
Is that what you did to her?
Turned her into a soldier?
SKORR: As predicted, the UNIT forces
have moved to the penultimate stage.
STAAL: Observe their troops.
Thin fabrics, exposed skin,
feeble weapons.
These are toy soldiers,
the playthings of children.
-A Section, in position.
-We are on standby, sir.
You're qualified now?
You're a proper doctor?
UNIT rushed it through,
given my experience in the field.
Here we go. We're establishing
a field base on site.
-They're dying to meet you.
-Wish I could say the same.
Operation Blue Sky complete, sir.
Thanks for letting me take the lead.
And this is the Doctor.
-Doctor, Colonel Mace.
-Sir.
-Oh, don't salute.
-But it's an honour, sir.
I've read all the files on you.
Technically speaking,
you're still on staff.
You never resigned.
-What? You used to work for them?
-Yeah, a long time ago.
Back in the '70s.
Or was it the '80s? But it was all
a bit more homespun back then.
-Times have changed, sir.
-Yeah, that's enough of the "sir".
Come on now, Doctor. You've seen it.
You've been on board the Valiant.
We've got massive funding
from the United Nations,
-all in the name of Homeworld Security.
-A modern UNIT for the modern world.
What, and that means arresting
ordinary factory workers,
in the streets in broad daylight?
It's more like Guantanamo Bay out there.
Donna. By the way, Donna Noble,
since you didn't ask.
I'lLl have a salute.
-Ma'am.
-Thank you.
So tell me,
what's going on in that factory?
Yesterday, 52 people died
in identical circumstances,
right across the world,
in 11 different time zones.
(BEEPING)
05:00 in the UK, 06:00 in France,
08:00 in Moscow, 13:00 in China...
-You mean they died simultaneously?
-Exactly.
52 deaths at the exact
same moment worldwide.
-How did they die?
-They were all inside their cars.
They were poisoned.
I checked the biopsies, no toxins.
Whatever it is
left the system immediately.
-What have the cars got in common?
-Completely different makes.
They're all fitted with Atmos.
And that is the Atmos factory.
-What is Atmos?
-Well, come on, even I know that.
Everyone's got Atmos.
It stands for
Atmospheric Omission System.
The Atmos in your car
reduces CO2 emissions to zero.
-Zero? No carbon, none at all?
-And you get Sat Nav thrown in,
plus 20 quid in shopping vouchers
if you introduce a friend. Bargain.
And this is where they make it, Doctor.
Shipping worldwide.
17 factories across the globe,
but this is the central depot,
sending Atmos to every country on Earth.
And you think Atmos is alien?
It's our job to investigate
that possibility. Doctor?
And here it is, laid bare.
Atmos can be threaded through
any and every make of car.
You must have checked it
before it went on sale.
We did. We found nothing.
That's why I thought
we needed an expert.
Really? Who'd you get?
Oh, right! Me, yes. Good.
Okay, so why would aliens be so keen
on cleaning up our atmosphere?
A very good question.
Maybe they want to help,
get rid of pollution and stuff.
Do you know how many cars
there are on planet Earth?
800 million. Imagine that.
If you could control them,
you'd have 800 million weapons.
We should head back.
There's not much down there.
There should be just oil rooms,
generators.
Aye, aye. What's this then?
You two, all personnel
have been ordered to evacuate.
Building's under UNIT control.
-This area is out of bounds.
-Excuse me, sunshine?
I think you'll find we're in charge.
We can do this the easy way...
(SNIFFING)
...or the hard way.
-SKORR: General Staal, they're close.
-STAAL: Excellent.
And like a good warrior,
I shall enter the fray myself.
Let them pass.
It's open.
Come on.
What the hell?
Greyhound 16 to Trap One.
We've found something.
Basement corridor, north side, grid 36.
Request backup, over.
It's like something boiling inside.
-Well, don't touch it.
-Come on, Steve.
We get first rights on this.
-That means promotion.
-Just leave it alone.
Wait for backup.
(THUDDING)
What was that?
-It came from inside.
-It could just be the machinery.
(THUDDING)
(COCKS GUN)
Is there someone in there? Hello?
(KNOCKING)
We've got to get this open.
-We should wait for the others.
-You could suffocate in there.
Greyhound 16 to Trap One.
Request immediate assistance.
Repeat, immediate assistance. Over.
How do you work this thing? Come on.
(ALARM BUZZING)
(COUGHING)
Oh, God! It stinks.
What the hell is that stuff?
Identify yourself. Identify.
Greyhound 16
declaring absolute emergency, sir.
Repeat, absolute emergency. Over.
Can you hear me? Can you understand me?
Look at his neck.
It's looks like an umbilical cord.
-Well, don't get too close.
-I think it's harmless.
I don't think it's properly alive.
-It's going to drown.
-No.
I think it breathes this stuff.
-It's some kind of embryo.
-What do you mean, "an embryo"?
Someone's growing a body. A human body.
Excellent skills of deduction.
I would rate you above average, soldier.
Well done.
Whereas you,
you smell of sweat and fear.
Yeah?
We're not the ones
who got out of school early, sonny.
And stop playing Humpty Dumpty
and tell us who you are.
Is that a reference to my height?
-Short answer. Yes.
-A pity.
Words are the weapons of womenfolk.
I must judge you unfit.
What are you going to do?
Bite our ankles?
(SCREAMS)
-I'm warning you.
-A proper soldier gives no warning.
Fire. I order you. Fire.
The room is contained within
a Cordolaine signal
exciting the copper surface
of the bullet
and causing expansion within the barrel,
rendering your guns useless.
And your radio signals
have been blocked.
My legs. I can't feel my legs.
I apologise for disabling you.
Death has more honour,
but you are needed for the stratagem.
Prepare them for processing.
You spoke of promotion,
now you will serve a greater cause.
-Who are you?
-Indeed. Know your enemy.
I am General Staal
of the 10th Sontaran Battle Fleet,
known as Staal the Undefeated.
Oh, my God! Help us.
Ionising nano-membrane
carbon dioxide converter,
which means that Atmos works,
filters the CO2 at a molecular level.
We know all that.
But what's its origin? Is it alien?
No, but it's decades ahead of its time.
Look, do you mind?
Could you stand back a bit?
-Sorry. Have I done something wrong?
-You're carrying a gun.
I don't like people with guns
hanging around me, all right?
If you insist.
Tetchy.
-Well, it's true.
-He's a good man.
People with guns are usually the enemy
in my books. You seem quite at home.
If anyone got me used to fighting,
it's you.
Oh, right. So it's my fault.
Well, you got me the job.
Besides, look at me.
-Am I carrying a gun?
-I suppose not.
It's all right for you.
You can just come and go,
but some of us have got to stay behind.
So I've got to work from the inside.
And by staying inside, maybe I stand
a chance of making them better.
Yeah.
That's more like Martha Jones.
-I learnt from the best.
-Well...
Oi, you lot.
All your storm troopers and your sonics,
rubbish.
-You should've come with me.
-Oh, where have you been?
Personnel. That's where
the weird stuff's happening.
In the paperwork.
'Cause I spent years working as a temp,
I can find my way
around an office blindfold.
And the first thing I noticed
is an empty file.
Why, what's inside it?
Or what's not inside it?
Sick days.
There aren't any. Hundreds of people
working here and no one's sick.
Not one hangover, man 'flu,
sneaky little shopping trip.
Nothing. Not ever. They don't get ill.
That can't be right.
You've been checking out the building,
you should've been checking out
the workforce.
I can see why he likes you.
-You are good.
-Super temp.
Dr Jones, set up a medical post.
Start examining the workers.
-I'll get them sent through.
-Come on, Donna. Give me a hand.
So this Atmos thing,
where did it come from?
-Luke Rattigan himself.
-That himself would be?
A child genius.
Invented the Fountain Six search engine
when he was 12 years old.
Millionaire overnight.
Now runs the Rattigan Academy,
a private school educating students
hand-picked from all over the world.
A hothouse for geniuses.
I won't mind going there.
I get lonely.
Do you think I should warn my mum?
About the Atmos in her car.
-Better safe than sorry.
-I'll give her a call.
Donna, do they know where you are?
Your family?
I mean, that you're travelling
with the Doctor?
Not really. Although my grandad
sort of waved us off.
-But I didn't have time to explain.
-You just left him behind?
Yeah.
I didn't tell my family.
I kept it all so secret.
It almost destroyed them.
In what way?
They ended up imprisoned.
They were tortured.
My mum, my dad, my sister.
It wasn't the Doctor's fault,
but you need to be careful.
'Cause you know the Doctor.
He's wonderful, he's brilliant,
but he's like fire.
Stand too close and people get burnt.
Conditioning is complete.
Now do your duty
and advance the conquest.
BOTH: Yes, sir.
General Staal returning.
The stratagem advances.
The last days of planet Earth.
(OSCILLATING DRONE)
You're not coming with me.
I want to talk to this Luke Rattigan,
not point a gun at him.
It's 10 miles outside London.
How are you going to get there?
Well, then, get me a jeep.
According to the records,
you travel by Tardis.
If there is a danger of hostile aliens,
I think it's best to keep
a super-duper time machine
away from the front lines.
I see, then you do have weapons,
but you choose to keep them hidden.
-Jenkins.
-Sir.
You will accompany the Doctor
and take orders from him.
Yeah. I don't do orders.
Any sign of trouble,
get Jenkins to declare a Code Red.
-And good luck, sir.
-I said, "No salutes".
Now you're giving orders.
-Getting a bit cheeky, you are.
-Doctor.
Oh, just in time. Come on.
Come on, we're going to the country.
Fresh air and geniuses.
What more could you ask?
I'm not coming with you.
I've been thinking. I'm sorry.
I'm going home.
-Really?
-I've got to.
Well, if that's what you want.
I mean, it's a bit soon.
I had so many places
I wanted to take you.
The Fifteenth Broken Moon
of the Medusa Cascade.
The lightning skies
of Cotter Palluni's world.
The Diamond Coral Reefs
of Kataa Flo Ko.
Thank you.
Thank you, Donna Noble.
It's been brilliant. You've...
You saved my life in so many ways.
You're...
You're just popping home for a visit,
that's what you mean.
-You dumbo.
-And then you're coming back.
Do you know what you are?
A great big outer-space dunce.
-Yeah.
-Ready when you are, sir.
What's more, you can give me a lift.
Come on.
-Broken Moon of what?
-I know. I know.
And your name's Treppa, yeah?
Is that Polish?
Listen, we're not checking passports.
It's not about that, but...
Did you come across
from Poland just to work?
-I came to do my job.
-Okay.
I need to listen to your heartbeat.
This might be a bit cold.
Lift.
(HEART BEATING FAST)
-Are you on any medication?
-I'm here to work.
-How many hours a day do you work?
-24,
You work 24 hours a day?
Down.
Mr Treppa, have you ever had
any form of hypnosis?
-I'm here to work.
-Okay.
If you could just wait here.
MAN: Take those to the stores.
-Dr Jones.
-Not now. I'm busy.
Just one question.
Do you have security clearance
level one?
-Yes, I do. Why?
-Colonel Mace wants to see you.
Oh, good, 'cause I want to see him.
Where is he?
Come with us.
DONNA: I'll walk the rest of the way.
I'll see you back at the factory, yeah?
DOCTOR: Bye.
DONNA: And you be careful.
-Haven't seen you for days.
-Been away.
Help!
-Hold on!
-I am!
I'm waving at fat.
What's he doing down here?
-He asked to see you.
-Why? Has he found something?
(MARTHA SCREAMING)
I said so, didn't I?
Aliens! I said, they was real.
I just didn't expect them
in a little blue box.
-It's bigger on the inside.
-Yeah, but is it safe?
This Doctor. Are you safe with him?
He's amazing, gramps.
He's just dazzling.
-And never tell him I said that.
-No.
-But I trust him with my life.
-Hold up. I thought that was my job.
You still come first.
-For God's sake, don't tell your mother.
-I don't know.
I mean, this is massive.
It's sort of not fair
if she doesn't know.
Doesn't know what?
And who's she? The cat's mother?
And where have you been
these past few days, lady?
After that silly little trick
with the car keys,
I phoned Veena and she said
she hadn't seen hide nor hair.
I've just been travelling.
Oh, hark at her, Michael Palin.
Are you staying for tea?
'Cause I haven't got anything in.
I've been trying to keep your grandad
on that macrobiotic diet,
but he sneaks off and gets pork pies
at the petrol station.
Don't deny it.
I've seen the wrappers in the car.
Oh, I don't miss a trick.
Now then,
what were you going to tell me?
What don't I know?
Nothing.
-Just nothing.
-Good.
Right, then. You can sit there
and cut out those coupons.
Every penny helps.
This new mortgage
doesn't pay for itself.
-Dad, kettle on.
-Yeah. Kettle on.
UNIT's been watching
the Rattigan Academy for ages.
It's all a bit Hitler Youth.
Exercise at dawn
and classes and special diets.
-SAT NAV: Turn left.
-Ross, one question.
If UNIT think that Atmos is dodgy...
How come we've got it in the jeeps?
Tell me about it.
They're fitted as standard
on all government vehicles.
We can't get rid of them till
we can prove there's something wrong.
-Turn right.
-Drives me around the bend.
-Oh, nice one.
-I timed that perfectly.
Yeah. Yeah, you did.
This is your final destination.
Is it PE? Wouldn't mind a kick around.
I've got my daps on.
-I suppose you're the Doctor.
-Hello.
-Your Commanding Officer phoned ahead.
-Oh, I haven't got a Commanding Officer.
Have you?
-Oh, this is Ross. Say hello, Ross.
-Good afternoon, sir.
Let's have a look, then.
I can smell genius...in a good way.
Oh, now!
That's clever, look.
A single-molecule fabric.
How thin is that?
You could pack a tent in a thimble.
Ooh! Gravity simulators.
Terraforming, biospheres,
nano-tech steel construction.
(CHUCKLES) This is brilliant.
Do you know, with equipment like this
you could, ooh, I don't know,
move to another planet or something?
-If only that was possible.
-If only that were possible.
Conditional clause.
I think you'd better come with me.
You're smarter than
the usual UNIT grunts.
-I'll give you that.
-He called you a grunt.
Don't call Ross a grunt. He's nice.
We like Ross. Look at this place.
What exactly do you want?
I was just thinking,
what a responsible 18 year old.
Inventing zero-carbon cars.
Saving the world.
-It takes a man with vision.
-Hmm! Blinkered vision.
'Cause Atmos means
more people driving.
More cars, more petrol.
End result, the oil's going
to run out faster than ever.
The Atmos system
could make things worse.
Yeah. Well, see, that's a tautology.
You can't say Atmos system
because it stands for
"Atmospheric Omission System".
So you're saying Atmospheric Omission
System System.
Do you see Mr Conditional Clause?
It's been a long time since
anyone said no to you, isn't it?
-I'm still right though.
-Not easy, is it? Being clever?
You look at the world
and you connect things,
random things, and think,
why can't anyone else see it?
-The rest of the world is so slow.
-Yeah.
-You're on your own.
-I know.
But not with this. 'Cause there's no way
you invented this single-handedly.
Might be Earth technology,
but that's like finding
a mobile phone in the Middle Ages.
No. No. I'll tell you what it's like.
It's like finding this
in the middle of someone's front room,
albeit a very big front room.
-Why, what is it?
-Nah!
This looks like a thing, doesn't it?
People don't question things.
You say, "It's a thing."
-Leave it alone.
-Me, I make these connections,
and this, to me,
looks like a teleport pod.
(OSCILLATING DRONE)
-TANNOY: Orbit now holding at 556. 3.
-Oh.
Sector two, 7-0.
We have an intruder.
DOCTOR: How did he get in?
Intruder window?
Bye, bye.
(OSCILLATING DRONE)
Ross, get out!
Luke, you'd better come with me.
Sontaran!
That's your name, isn't it?
You're a Sontaran.
How did I know that, eh?
Fascinating, isn't it?
Isn't that worth keeping me alive?
I order you to surrender in the name
of the Unified Intelligence Task Force.
That's not going to work.
Cordolaine signal, am I right?
Copper excitations stopping the bullets.
-How do you know so much?
-Well...
-Who is he?
-He didn't give his name.
Now this isn't typical
Sontaran behaviour, is it? Hiding.
Using teenagers? Stopping bullets?
A Sontaran should face bullets
with dignity. Shame on you.
-You dish on our me, sir.
-Yeah? Then show yourself.
I will look into my enemy's eyes.
-Oh, my God.
-And your name?
General Staal,
of the 10th Sontaran Fleet.
Staal the Undefeated.
Oh, that's not a very good nickname.
What if you do get defeated?
Staal the not-so-quite-undefeated
any more, but never mind?
He looks like a potato, a baked potato,
a talking baked potato.
Now, Ross, don't be rude.
You look like a pink weasel to him.
The Sontarans are
the finest soldiers in the galaxy.
Dedicated to a life of warfare.
A clone race.
Grown in batches of millions
with only one weakness.
-Sontarans have no weakness.
-No. It's a good weakness.
Thought you were meant to be clever.
Only an idiot would provoke him.
No, but the Sontarans are fed by
a Probic Vent in the back of their neck.
That's their weak spot, which means
they always have to face their enemies
in battle. Isn't that lovely?
-They can never turn their back.
-We stare into the face of death.
Yeah, well stare at this.
(GENERAL STAAL SCREAMING)
What have you done? What have you done?
Don't touch me.
A Sontaran would rather be
court-martial led than show pain.
-I must return.
-But he broke the teleport.
Ha! Primitive sonic trickery.
The device is now repaired.
(OSCILLATING DRONE)
Our presence is known.
Soldiers, we move to a war footing.
I see you faced battle open-skinned,
sir. Might I share that honour?
-You may.
-Thank you.
How do you tell each other apart?
We say the same of humans.
Tell me, boy, how many Atmos devices
have been installed?
Ah! They've gone worldwide
with only about half.
Which means 400 million cars converted.
A fine arsenal.
Is it sufficient
to trigger the conversion?
More than enough, yeah. And
the test signal proved that it works.
52 deaths in the same second, man.
That is just so cool.
Is the temperature significant?
No. That's just a phrase.
But I'll get my people ready, General.
Just tell me where and when.
-Have we infiltrated UNIT?
-The process is about to begin.
Then you'll see it completed,
Commander Skorr.
-Get to it.
-Yes, sir.
Is someone going to tell me
what the hell is going on?
Okay.
So, listen.
You're not the first aliens I've met.
Just tell me who you are.
Commander Skorr of
the 10th Sontaran Battle Fleet,
-known as Skorr, the Blood Bringer.
-What have you done to those two?
Simple hypnotic control,
as with the factory drones.
But with you,
we need something more complex.
(MACHINE BUZZING)
What is that?
Soon, that will be you.
(INDISTINCT SPEAKING ON PA SYSTEM)
Continue.
War can never come too soon.
Take your last look, boy.
It was never big enough for me.
I like your ambition.
That Doctor, he was in a UNIT jeep.
It should have Atmos installed.
You said you didn't know his name.
I don't. He just said Doctor.
Does that mean something?
There is an enemy of the Sontarans
known as the Doctor.
-A face changer.
-Do you mean he is an alien, too?
Legend says he led the battle
in the last great Time War.
The finest war in history
and we weren't allowed to be part of it.
Oh, but this is excellent.
The last of the Time Lords will die
at the hands of the Sontaran Empire
in the ruins of his precious Earth.
It is inadvisable to struggle.
The female has a weak thorax.
-But what are you doing?
-Completing mental transfer.
-The clone needs full memory access.
-Clone?
No, you can't.
-That's not...
-You'll sleep, girl.
Sleep and keep the memories alive.
Memories we can use in battle.
SKREE: We have the Doctor's vehicle.
An ordinary death
for such a remarkable enemy.
But proceed.
Greyhound 40 to Trap One.
Repeat. Can you hear me? Over.
-Why is it not working?
-Must be the Sontarans.
If they can trace that,
they can isolate the Atmos.
-SAT NAN: Turn left.
-Try going right.
-It said left.
-I know, so go right.
I've got no control.
It's driving itself.
It won't stop. The doors are locked.
Aah! It's deadlocked. I can't stop it.
-Let me...
-Turn left.
The sat nav's just a box.
It's wired into the whole car.
Is he going in the water?
I love it when they hit the water.
We're heading for the river.
Atmos, are you programmed
to contradict my orders?
-Confirmed.
-Anything I say, you'll ignore it.
Confirmed.
Then drive into the river.
I order you to drive me into the river.
Do it. Drive into the river.
Turn right. Left.
-Get down.
-Left, right, left right...
Oh, is that it?
Atmos terminated. Mission accomplished.
The Doctor is dead.
Then prepare the weapons.
Is the operative in place?
Ready and waiting to advance
the great Sontaran cause, sir.
Then go to work.
(BELL RINGING)
You would not believe
the day I'm having.
-I'll requisition us a vehicle.
-Anything without Atmos.
And don't point your gun at people.
Is it him? Is it him? Is it the Doctor?
-Oh, it's you.
-Who? Oh!
It's you.
-What, have you met before?
-Yeah. Christmas Eve.
He disappeared right in front of me.
-And you never said.
-Well, you never said.
Wilf, sir. Wilfred Mott.
You must be one of them aliens.
Yeah, but don't shout it out.
Nice to meet you properly, Wilf.
-Ah, an alien hand.
-Donna, anything?
She's not answering.
What is it, Sonterruns?
Sontarans.
But there's got to be more to it.
They can't just be remote-controlling
cars. That's not enough.
-Is anyone answering?
-Hold on.
-Don't tell me. Donna Noble.
-Martha. Hold on, he's here.
Martha, tell Colonel Mace
it's the Sontarans.
They're in the file. Code Red Sontarans.
But if they're inside the factory,
tell him not to start shooting.
UNIT will get massacred.
I'll get back as soon as I can.
You got that?
Code Red Sontaran. Gotcha.
-Dr Jones, found anything yet?
-No, sir. Nothing to report.
You tried sonicking it before
and you didn't find anything.
Yeah, but now I know it's Sontaran,
I know what I'm looking for.
The thing is, Doctor,
that Donna is my only grandchild.
You got to promise me
you're going to take care of her.
-She takes care of me.
-Oh, yeah. That's my Donna.
She was always bossing us around
even when she was tiny.
The Little General we used to call her.
-Yeah. Don't start.
-And some of the boys
she used to turn up with,
a different one every week.
Here. Who was that one
with the nail varnish?
Matthew Richards.
He lives in Kilburn now...with a man.
Whoa! It's a temporal pocket.
I knew there was
something else in there.
It's hidden just a second
out of sync with real time.
-But what's it hiding?
-I don't know. Men and their cars.
Sometimes I think if I was a car...
-Oh, it's you. Doctor, what was it?
-Yeah, that's me.
-What, have you met him as well?
-Dad, it's the man from the wedding
when you were laid up with Spanish 'flu.
I'm warning you. Last time that man
turned up, it was a disaster.
Get back.
-A converter has been activated.
-Show me where.
(DRONING)
London. That's Chiswick.
-Who can have such knowledge?
-Only the Doctor.
He survived. Excellent.
Then battle will be joined.
Glorious warfare.
Tenth Sontaran Battle Fleet.
We move to the final phase.
Prepare the subjugation of Earth
for the glory of Sontar.
VOICE ON PA:
Announcing Battle Status One.
All soldiers to positions.
Repeat, we are now at Battle Status One.
Rejoice.
That'll stop it.
I told you. He's blown up the car.
Who is he anyway?
What sort of Doctor blows up cars?
-Oh, not now, Mum.
-Oh, should I make an appointment?
That wasn't just exhaust fumes.
It's some sort of gas, artificial gas.
-And it's aliens. Is it aliens?
-Is this poisonous?
Then they've got poisonous gas
in every car on Earth.
Trigger the converters
and deadlock every single one.
It's not safe.
I'm going to get it off the street.
No, don't.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Turn it off.
-Grandad, get out of there.
-I can't. It's locked.
It's them aliens again.
(CAR HONKS)
What's he doing? What's he doing?
They've isolated it.
(CAR ALARMS SOUNDING)
Turn them off. Turn them off.
-MACE: Turn off the engines.
-SOLDIER: It's all of them, sir.
Every single car on the planet.
Now we begin. Let's get to work.
There's gas inside the car.
He's going to choke. Doctor!
It won't open.
(CARS HONKING)
It's the whole world.
400 million weapons. Sontar-ha!
-(CHANTING) Sontar-ha!
-ALL: (CHANTING) Sontar-ha!
(COUGHING AND CHOKING)
Donna!
ALL: (CHANTING) Sontar-ha!
DONNA: Doctor!
The government has declared
a state of emergency.
WOMAN: Launching in 10.
Come then.
Nine.
-Do not engage the Sontarans in battle.
-Eight.
-The planet is going nuclear.
-Seven.
It's time I reveal
what our work has been for.
-Six.
-The bravery of idiots
-is bravery, nonetheless.
-Five.
-God save us.
-Four.
They need this gas for something else.
-Three.
-All troops, Code Red.
-Two.
-At arms.
-One.
-Get them out of there!
Zero.