[chuckles] Okay.
Did we make it?
Definitely Earth. [sniffs]
Definitely London.
Yeah, got that. But definitely when?
I am working it out, Bel.
Look, look, I have found 50p.
- We are winning! [chuckles]
- Can you try and focus, please?
We need to get home.
Oh, hello.
What is your name?
Conrad.
Conrad, I am the Doctor.
And this is Belinda Chandra. [chuckles]
Um, weird question, what year is this?
Please say it's 2025.
2024?
Does the year start with a 20?
It's 2007.
[device beeps, dings]
Oh, New Year's.
Oh, I love it.
All those hopes and possibilities, huh?
Conrad, I think this is meant for you.
Why?
'Cause it is your lucky day! [chuckles]
Hey, where are your parents?
Mum's watching the fireworks.
[Belinda] Should we get you to--
Or not.
Happy New Year.
Mum! Mum! Mum! Come and see.
There's a box, a blue box
that came out of nowhere,
with a doctor and a Belinda Chandra.
How many times, Conrad?
Enough with the lies.
It's not a lie. Look.
You're spoiling my night.
[Conrad] I was eight years old
when I first saw that police box,
and I've followed stories
of that box ever since.
Interviewed eyewitnesses
right across the globe.
But this week, I've found someone
who knows its secrets.
In fact, she's even been inside it.
And I'm gonna ask her
to introduce herself.
Hello, everyone. My name is Ruby Sunday.
[♪ theme song playing]
[Conrad] 2007 was the first time
I saw that blue box.
But fast forward 17 years and
it happened again, last year.
Only this time...
[creature roaring]
...things got crazier.
[sizzling]
[creature snarling]
[breathes shakily]
[sniffs]
[snarling]
[breathes shakily]
[pants]
[creature growling]
[metal creaking]
[creature snarls]
- [pants]
- [Ruby] Where's the Shreek?
[Doctor] Zapped it back into its hive.
- Man, that was lucky.
- No, disgusting is what it was.
Please, please, tell me
I wasn't just peed on.
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Don't worry. It's, uh...
It's more like vomit.
The pheromone gets absorbed
into your blood
- and marks you as future prey.
- [gasps] Wait, what?
- Cool, right?
- Mmm.
But this neutralises the pheromone.
- [Ruby] Oh. Do I drink it? [chuckles]
- [Doctor] Tastes like candy floss.
- [gags, coughs]
- [laughs]
[Ruby] You are such a liar. [groans]
But at least you can't get tracked
by the Shreek anymore.
[Ruby] Yeah, but anyone else
can track me. This green stuff stinks.
[Doctor] You are reeking.
You are Shreeking!
[Ruby laughs]
[gasps]
[laughs, groans]
- Don't look.
- Oh, babes, take a lie down.
That antidote is gonna knock you out
for about eight hours.
Yeah, I could do with a rest
'cause life with you is mad.
Half an hour ago
we were hanging out with The Beatles.
- I know, right? [laughs]
- Oh, I miss them.
[phone camera clicks]
Hello?
Oh, and John Lennon
owes me a piano lesson.
[TARDIS warbles]
[Conrad] And I've been looking for you
ever since, for a whole year.
So, the last thing I expected was
to land you on my podcast this morning.
I have so many questions.
Well, I'm 20 years old.
I'm from Manchester.
I live in London with my mum and gran.
And I've got another mum now, Louise,
but that's a long story.
And also a new dad,
but that's an even longer one.
Christmas just gone,
that was mad. That was a lot.
[Conrad] So, how did you end up
in that shop last year,
with this doctor and his police box?
'Cause I am such a fan.
- [Ruby chuckles]
- I mean, who is he?
Look, I can't go into specifics...
Oh.
...but the Doctor's my best friend.
We used to travel together,
and that day in the shop, we were
looking for... [stammers] ...something.
- Yes, aliens... Oh.
- [Ruby] Oh.
- Sorry. [chuckles, stammers]
- [chuckles] No, it's...
[groans] Um, but, uh...
- Yes, uh, aliens, right?
- [Ruby chuckles]
Aliens are real. We all know that.
But some trolls online say UNIT,
all this talk of monsters is just
a cover story for something else.
[stammers] Well, maybe
they're afraid of the truth.
- [chuckles]
- And there's no reason to be scared.
I mean, the people at UNIT
are amazing, doing good work.
Keeping us safe.
Like the Doctor?
Like the Doctor.
Been trying to get UNIT
on the podcast for years.
No one ever returns my calls.
Oh, look, it's not you.
They're just busy. [chuckles]
So, do you live around here or...
[stammers] West. Notting Hill.
'Cause there's a great little café
around the corner
if you have time for a quick one.
- Oh. [stammers] Now?
- I mean... [stammers] ...coffee obviously,
- or-or tea or just...
- [stammers] Oh.
[chuckles] Coffee sounds great.
[chuckles]
[alien growls, snarls]
The teeth on that.
Mm-hmm.
Shreek live in a pocket dimension
and once a year
they leave the hive to hunt,
and somehow one of them made it to Earth.
That day I first saw you.
Yeah, but this is the footage
from last night.
So, it came back to the same location
one year later.
Which means, a year ago
it marked its prey.
[Shreek snarls]
And now, it's hunting you.
And if UNIT hadn't captured it,
it'd be here by now.
And then what?
[Ruby] It'd wait till night.
First thing you'd notice is the lights.
The Shreek's background radiation
messes with electricity.
Then it'd show itself,
just a glimpse,
just enough to get your heart racing.
It'd have you trapped.
It'd take its time breaking in,
enjoys the hunt.
Feeds off fear.
Wants you scared and running,
pumping with adrenaline.
Why?
Because it likes the taste.
[Shreek snarling]
[bell on door jingles]
[exhales sharply] You tell a good story.
Yeah, well, lucky for you
there's a happy ending.
This is the antidote.
Drink it tonight and it blocks
the Shreek from tracking you.
So, that day I saw you
the Doctor saved your life?
Yeah. Well, he did that a lot.
To be fair, I saved his a few times.
When I was a kid,
meeting him is what got me
into strange tech and UFOs.
[chuckles] Inspired the podcast.
Aw.
Oh, and he gave me this.
I've kept it all these years.
Oh, wow.
He said it was my lucky day.
I think he was wrong.
I think that's today.
Um... [chuckles]
...take the antidote before bed
because it'll make you sleepy. [chuckles]
On one condition.
- You let me buy you dinner. [chuckles]
- Aw.
- Or we both buy dinner.
- [stammers] I wasn't...
If that's too old-fashioned, just we...
we, you know... we eat it.
- Okay, cool. Right.
- Together.
[chuckles] Yeah. Okay.
Ta-ra then.
- Hold on, I promised Louise a photo.
- Why?
Let me be excited.
You haven't had a boyfriend for ages.
Smile.
Okay, just not the... flash.
Yeah, maybe not. Let's try again.
And he's not my boyfriend,
it's just a date.
[Carla] Smile.
Yeah, but you're getting on
with your life.
That's what's important. Moving on.
[Cherry] Conrad Clark.
How unuh spell him name?
Conrad Clark.
I wonder if him on the Instagram.
Gran, he's nice. And he's normal.
And it's no big deal. Okay?
Clark with no "E". And if you
scroll down, he's got his shirt off.
- Mum.
- Oh, don't pretend you haven't looked.
[chuckles]
[exhales sharply] Okay.
I'm gonna be late. Bye.
[Carla chuckles]
[chuckles]
Your gran sounds hilarious.
Oh, my family is mad. [chuckles]
I asked you about yours last week,
and you changed the subject.
Um, it was just me and my mum growing up.
She died. Liver cancer.
I've never really talked about it.
You could talk to me. [chuckles]
Sorry.
No.
I'm sorry I'm not as cool as the Doctor.
No, no. [stammers] You're nice.
You're lovely. [chuckles]
And that's what I need right now.
Was he your boyfriend?
No. God, no. [chuckles]
If he was here, he'd be flirting with you.
[chuckles] Don't think I'd notice.
[chuckles]
You know, I was eight
when I first saw that police box.
- The TARDIS.
- TARDIS?
Oh, it's the most incredible thing
you'll ever see in your entire life.
And I've seen incredible things, but
stuff I never really get to talk about,
so sometimes I feel like
I'm about to explode.
Well, plea-please don't.
I'm-I'm enjoying this. [chuckles]
- [passenger 1 chuckles]
- [passenger 2] Bye.
You know, I've told you things
that I haven't told anyone.
I mean, I've tried. [chuckles]
But my friends all think I'm mad.
[chuckles] Like,
properly having a breakdown.
Well, I don't think that.
I think you're amazing.
Rubes, how many dates is this now?
- [Ruby] I'm not counting.
- [chuckles]
- Five. It's five.
- Is it?
Why are you making such a fuss?
We're just pleased.
We think you need this.
Okay, right. I will see you...
[kisses] ...Monday. [chuckles]
[kisses] Have a lovely weekend, sweetheart.
Uh-huh. [kisses, chuckles]
And be very careful.
I have been to English villages.
I got looks.
[clicks tongue] I don't think
Conrad's friends are like that, Gran.
She just watched The Wicker Man.
Okay, I can't be doing this right now.
I love you.
- Bye. [chuckles]
- Love you.
Do you know, she's not mentioned
the Doctor in weeks.
Not for weeks.
[chuckles]
[groans] I tell you what,
you'd think I'd never had a relationship,
the way they're carrying on. [chuckles]
What?
You said relationship.
Am I your boyfriend?
Well, let's just see
how this weekend goes. [chuckles]
[chuckles] I'm your boyfriend.
- [chuckles]
Come on. We'll miss happy hour.
And I am happy.
[chuckles] Are you now?
[Conrad]
I met Sparky when he rewired my kitchen.
[Jack]
Before he moved to the middle of nowhere.
[Ruby] Aw, but it's gorgeous. [chuckles]
[friends laughing]
The best thing about this village,
Alfie's home brew.
- Your round, Rubes.
- Oh, no. I'll, um--
- No, no, no. It's fine. I'll get it.
- I'll give you a hand.
Aw, thanks. [chuckles, sighs]
Conrad's been keeping us apart.
Didn't want us to embarrass him?
- [chuckles]
- That means he really likes ya.
- Talks about you all the time. [chuckles]
- Really?
- Tell me everything.
- [chuckles]
Uh, what you having, girls?
Uh, hiya.
Yeah, just the same again, please.
[electricity crackles]
[groans] Not again.
This happened at the bus stop.
The generator's supposed
to kick in. That's weird.
[chuckles] Uh, I'm just gonna
make a quick call. Okay?
Well, there's no quantum echo
at that location.
Hang on, I'll check the national grid.
Sorry, Kate. I didn't even mean
to bother you. I was after Mel.
Oh, no bother. Always got time for you.
Mel's on her way to Sydney.
There's something strange
happening in the harbour.
Oh, you're on your own?
Yeah.
I like working late.
Have you... [sighs]
...heard from him recently?
The Doctor? No, not for ages.
Okay, there's no faults showing.
Must be a localised issue.
If you're still worried, I can
have a team there in 30 minutes.
No, no. It's okay.
Ruby, we've got the Shreek locked away,
and if your friend took the antidote,
he's fine.
Do you think, maybe with
everything you've been through...
That I'm paranoid?
That you're on alert all the time.
Trust me, I know what that's like.
[sighs] Yeah.
[chuckles] Maybe you're right.
Try and relax. Enjoy your night.
[Ruby, distorted] Okay. Thanks, Kate.
And sorry again.
Bye.
Just checking you're still with us.
Hello?
[shrieking, growling]
[sighs]
[exhales sharply]
- Hi.
- Everything okay?
Yeah, yeah. All good.
Hey.
Boyfriend, remember?
[sighs]
I think I'm in shock.
Like... [sighs] ...PTSD. [chuckles]
Because what happened last year
was just not normal.
I mean, I fought gods.
- Like, actual gods. [chuckles]
- [chuckles]
And I was eaten by a double bass,
and kidnapped by Goblins.
I dangled on a rope ladder above London,
and I watched the world turn to dust.
[sighs] And it's just, like,
every day is like fight or flight,
and I'm just w... waiting
for something to go wrong.
Nothing's going wrong
while I'm here. All right?
Mm-hmm.
- Thanks.
- Okay. [sniffles]
So, tell us about UNIT. All the stuff
you couldn't say on the podcast.
Just leave it, Elsa.
[sighs] Alfie.
[Alfie groans] Sorry.
Don't know what's going on.
[patron] Free drinks till they're back on.
- [patron 2] Yay!
- [Alfie sighs] Not my fault.
- Where Sparky?
- I think he's in the loo.
I'll, um... I'll check.
Uh... [breathes shakily]
[sighs]
[Audrey screams]
- [pub patrons clamouring]
- What the hell was that?
Lock the door. Lock the door!
There's something out there.
Like the devil himself.
Oh, the teeth.
Biscuit got the fright of his life.
[creature roars]
[gasps]
- [snarling]
- [pub patrons clamour]
Oh, my God.
- There's another one.
- [roaring]
- [pub patrons screaming]
- I'll call the police.
- Sparky's not there.
- So, where is he?
I don't know.
Ruby, I didn't take the antidote.
I'm so sorry.
I wanted to be brave like the Doctor.
[chuckles] You have no idea
what you've done.
Look, everything he was, I can be.
I'm not afraid.
You should be.
- [sighs]
- [pub patrons chattering]
- But the Shreek's here.
- [Ruby] Well, then there's more of them.
- They're in the village right now.
- We're on our way.
Divert the nearest ground crew to
Colson Village. We'll take the helicopter.
I need an analyst. Jordan, with me.
Everyone, just stay inside.
Call your friends, your family and just
tell them to stay indoors, all right?
Sorry, love, who put you in charge?
Or go and get some fresh air, big man.
See what happens.
Sparky's not answering.
What if he was out there?
What if that thing's got him?
Lock the door behind me.
- I'm coming. This is my fault.
- No, they're after you.
Once they're done tearing you to pieces,
the Shreek will wipe out
this entire village.
Just stay here.
[roaring, growling]
[groans, gasps]
Okay. Just me this time.
Talking to myself.
That's very Doctor.
[creature growls]
[panting]
Oh, and right about now,
I'd be telling him to shut up.
[exhales heavily] Okay.
[panting]
- Ruby. [gasps]
- [gasps] Sh... [groans]
Get back inside. [breathes heavily]
No. It's gone wrong, and it's my fault.
I don't want you dealing with this
on your own.
No, no, no. This isn't a game, Conrad.
We're in serious danger.
You are in danger.
Look, we're a team,
like you and the Doctor.
We can fix this.
[sighs]
How do we find Sparky?
- [creature growls]
- [gasps]
- [creature snarls]
[groans]
[Conrad] We're too late.
This is all because of me.
[hissing, growling]
Run! Come on, come on.
Run, run, run, run, run, run!
[soldiers shouting]
Where are they?
I don't know. Their readings are cloaked.
Get those civilians inside.
Kate, there's two of them, at least.
They've got my friend.
I want the Shreek alive.
We need to understand how they got here.
Quantum ghosting's at zero.
None of this makes sense.
Oh, just give me that.
Eyes on.
Set weapons to stun.
Get behind us. Now!
Prepare to fire.
Wait a minute.
They're not Shreek.
[chuckles]
Got ya.
[roaring, on recording]
You idiots.
How'd we do, boss?
Nailed it.
- Conrad, what's he talking about?
- [chuckles]
Conrad, what are they talking about?
What the hell is going on?
We are Think Tank,
exposing the lies perpetuated by UNIT.
By you.
And we're live-streaming.
So, don't get trigger happy.
This isn't funny.
[chuckles]
I've had to listen to your stories
for weeks now.
Put up with your insecurity, and vanity,
listen to your tedious piano solos,
and get smothered in lip gloss.
It has been a chore getting to know you.
But now it's all worth it.
Put that phone down.
Or what? Gonna arrest me, yeah?
This is censorship.
Touch us, and we'll sue.
We will bankrupt you.
- [yelps]
- [gasps]
[Elsa giggles]
You made a very big, very dangerous
mistake tonight, Conrad.
You don't even remember me, do you?
The only monsters out here are UNIT.
Lying to the public, spending our money,
hiding in your tower, and doing what, huh?
- Doing what?
- Protecting people like you.
Oh, they can't stop lying!
There are no Shreek, no Cybermen,
no Sycorax, no Yetis in the underground.
- Hey, look. Look!
- [scoffs]
They're stooges, and actors,
and special effects
paid for using taxpayers' money
to keep us scared,
to hide their real agenda.
The threat to this planet is real.
If you want evidence,
I've got plenty of it, so you could--
This one's collecting benefits,
stealing our taxes while she lies to us.
But the lies stop today.
There are people all over the world
watching this.
Sharing, reposting, demanding the truth.
They're using you. All of you.
For her dirty work.
Do you think UNIT can't handle
a few reject cosplays?
Because that's what you are, Conrad.
You've gifted me this moment, Ruby Sunday.
Is that even your name, by the way?
'Cause it's ridiculous.
- Arrest them.
- All right, let's go. Move them out.
- [protester] Don't touch me!
- [radio chatter]
[protester] They're spying on us
and lying about it.
- [protesters laughing]
- [Elsa] Yeah, go on. Arrest us, cowards.
[protester]
Are you getting this on camera?
See you around, Ruby.
Fascism on the streets of Britain tonight.
An innocent podcaster is in custody
after a harmless stunt
in the British village of Colson.
...held for twenty-four hours
on charges of civil unrest
but released after public protests
and a social media backlash.
Everyone is taking their masks off.
Uh, I mean, who's next? Jonathan Ross?
- [crowd laughs]
- Apparently, that is not a mask.
You took a big risk.
We can see on the video
there are soldiers literally
pointing their guns at you.
That's how they suppress us. With fear.
Meanwhile, they're working against us.
- [whimpers]
- So, today, I am naming and shaming
every person employed by UNIT.
Their names and addresses
are on the screen right now.
Every one of them is spying on you,
and lying about it.
So let's turn the tables.
It's time to act.
- [crowd shouting]
- [protester 2] Liar!
You people should be ashamed.
[protesters continue shouting]
His family are en route to the safe house.
HQ want you at the tower.
[Trinity Wells]
Conrad Clark has hit a nerve.
He's appealing to the disaffected youth,
and they are listening.
- Guys, they are wasting our taxes...
- Have you seen this?
Conrad Clark takes down the establishment
using a plot twist from Scooby-Doo.
- And machine guns?
- This guy is a legend.
- He's my hero.
- Taking on the army? That's a choice.
[protester] There she is!
UNIT lies! UNIT spies!
[Wells] People are now questioning
the UK government's contributions
to UNIT's overheads.
I mean,
they are debating it in Parliament.
Eight years ago,
Conrad applied to work here.
Kate even interviewed him.
This is a grudge
dressed up as a youth movement.
No, it's more than that.
It's about power. [sighs]
And this has given him a voice, right?
I mean, he's been craving attention
his whole life,
and his mum practically ignored him
until the day she died.
His mother's not dead.
Moira Clark lives in the south of France.
Nice villa. Paid for by Conrad.
Meanwhile, he's raking it in.
80,000 paid subscribers.
He owns three properties,
and of course, he's a tax dodger.
[helipad doors open]
Why is that containment cube outside?
Orders to have the payload
transferred to Geneva.
- Our security status has been downgraded.
- Oh, this is getting way out of hand.
I'm glad you're okay.
- How was Whitehall?
- Cabinet only care about their jobs.
If there's enough pressure, they'll fold.
Support a full inventory of UNIT premises.
What if your tech goes public?
[scoffs] Imagine what happens
when a dictator get access
to a time window or a transduction drive.
Our technology would tear the world apart.
[muffled shouting, clamouring]
- Are local agents all safe?
- Everyone accounted for.
How did Conrad get a staff list?
We're working on the assumption
he has someone on the inside.
Our money has been--
[grunts]
I've cleared a path to the lift,
but we need to move quick.
The Vlinx is doing a live intercept
on all personnel.
Phone, emails, the works,
looking for any links to Conrad Clark.
Deep scan at 90%.
Encode the results. This screen only.
We've got a problem.
What are you doing? [stammers]
Stop, we don't need weapons.
[grunting]
That's confirmation.
I need those results.
Results collated. Two subjects identified.
Subject one, Ruby Sunday.
- Yeah, we'll skip that.
- [Vlinx] Subject two, Jordan Lang.
[Shirley] Jordan?
There's layers of bounced VPN,
shadow accounts, false identities.
[Kate] Follows dozens of radical blogs,
subscription to Albion TV,
revisionist podcasts...
It's an echo chamber of disinformation.
[Ruby] Well, where is he now?
Attention, all units,
does anyone have eyes on Jordan Lang?
All units, locate Jordan Lang.
[Ibrahim] All units. All units.
Ground staff report shots fired.
And someone's in the lift.
I need you to authorise a deadlock seal
of this level immediately.
Kate!
How many? Are they armed?
Comms are down,
but scans indicate one male.
- Aged 20-25.
- Yeah, it's Conrad.
- Stop the lift.
- No, wait. Let him come.
- What?
- He might be armed.
That man has single-handedly
undermined everything we work for.
We need to finish this.
- Defensive positions.
- [Shirley] Yes, ma'am.
Hold your fire. Do not shoot.
Wise words.
'Cause the world is watching you
right now.
Drop the gun, Conrad.
That's a lot of weapons
pointing at one man.
I'm just defending myself.
Drop it. Now.
I don't take orders from traitors.
And that's what you are. All of you.
Conrad, this has to stop.
Go play with your imaginary goblins.
I'm exposing the truth.
You're not, though.
This isn't about a cause,
it's grandstanding and ego.
You're a lying little boy
that can't bear to be called out.
- [gasps]
- Don't you dare point a gun at her.
You were right, Conrad.
I didn't remember you,
so I checked my notes from
that interview eight years ago,
- and do you know what I wrote?
- I'd throw in a compliment.
The three words that summed you up.
"Don't trust him".
Mmm.
God, you think you're so superior...
up in your tower, looking down on us.
Keeping you safe.
I want a confession. On camera.
Admit to the lies.
Show us the monster costumes.
Show us the tech that you're hiding,
that we paid for.
- You're deluded.
- The grown-ups are talking!
[breathes deeply]
Come on, commander-in-chief. Admit.
Or are you a coward like your father was?
You should be very careful
what you say about my father.
His only legacy was a pack of lies.
He was a hundred times the man you are.
And that gun is UNIT issue,
so where's Jordan Lang?
Who?
He's been shot. Ground team
are rushing him to the infirmary.
You shot someone to get in here?
It's nothing to do with me.
A man's life is hanging in the balance,
and you're not even sorry.
Maybe you shot him.
Or he was an actor. Or he never existed.
So, come on. Confess.
All right.
Let's start with your best friend.
Where is the Doctor and his box of tricks?
Oh, you're so lucky he's not here.
She's telling the truth.
And actually, I'm glad he's not here
because he would've stopped me.
Oh. From what?
From showing you and your followers
what we're protecting them from.
The truth, Conrad. As requested.
What's that?
Conrad, get out. It's hunting you.
What's in there?
Everyone, stay well back.
It's coming, Conrad. And it's after you.
You're bluffing!
It can feel your heartbeat,
smell the blood in your veins.
[Shreek roaring]
So I'm wondering,
how committed are you
to the lies you've told?
What do you truly believe?
[Vlinx] Alert! Alert! Power instability.
- [snarling]
- Emergency mode activated.
Leave him. Stay back!
[Conrad pants] Let me out. Let me out!
[gasps, pants]
[gasping]
Ops room compromised.
It's in the vent space.
Evacuate. Evacuate.
- [Ruby] Where has it gone?
- [panting] How do I get out?
- Tell me how to get out!
- You don't.
All cameras, live transmission
to Conrad's social media.
We're locked down, Conrad.
[Ibrahim] Those vents lead outside.
[Kate] It won't leave.
Not while he's here.
[Ruby] We've got to get him out.
[sighs]
[Shreek growls, roars]
[Ibrahim] Everyone, get back!
- [pants]
- Kate, we have to help him.
[panting]
- [glass breaks]
- [gasps]
[shrieks]
[grunts]
[pants]
[roars]
Shoot it! Help me!
- [Shreek roars]
- Help me!
[roaring]
[grunts]
[panting]
Please. Please, stop it!
You told us it's not real.
Kate, do something.
[Kate] What's behind your mask, Conrad?
An angry little man who put
the safety of this country at risk.
Everything my father ever worked for,
for personal gain. For a lie.
All right, okay, I lied!
I lied about everything.
Just make it stop, please! Please!
- Help me!
- [roars]
[pants]
[breathing heavily]
Thank you.
Go to hell.
[sighs]
[chuckling] At least
your special effects are improving.
[shrieks]
[sighs]
[Vlinx] Shreek transfer now in progress.
Latest from the hospital.
Conrad will live.
And Jordan Lang's out of ICU.
Good.
Last night went way too far.
- Geneva will--
- Like you said, he'll live.
Hmm. Things are looking up.
"I stand with UNIT" is a hashtag.
So is "hot Taser lady".
- Did they mean you or me? [chuckles]
- [chuckles]
You okay?
[breathes shakily]
No, I don't think I am.
'Cause I see it now.
I've just been stuck in limbo...
[chuckles]
...waiting for the Doctor,
the end of the world.
[chuckles]
And I just don't know
how to get any better.
It's like everything I've seen,
the good and the bad...
[sighs] I just need some time
to get my head around it.
Away from everyone.
Somewhere new. On my own.
Of course you do.
And when you're ready,
if you're ready to talk,
you call me.
Yeah. [inhales sharply]
[chuckles]
You've already got two mums.
What, do you collect them?
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[breathes deeply]
[warbling]
[warbling intensifies]
[Doctor] The Shreek is back in its hive.
No need to thank me. [chuckles]
You have to be invited into my TARDIS,
Conrad.
To be special.
But you...
you're special for all the wrong reasons.
You see, I am fighting a battle
on behalf of everyday people
who just wanna get through their day,
and feel safe, and warm, and fed.
And then along comes this noise.
All day long, this relentless noise.
Cowards like you, weaponising lies,
taking people's insecurity and fear,
and making it currency.
You are exhausting.
You stamp on the truth,
choke our bandwidth,
and shred our patience
because the only strategy you have
is to wear us down.
But the thing is, Conrad,
I have energy to burn and
all the time in the universe.
[chuckling]
[sighs] What is this?
An intervention?
Are you here to save my soul?
You betrayed my friend.
You've had plenty of friends.
Have you met Belinda Chandra yet?
Who?
You want spoilers?
I'll tell you your future.
You die in a prison cell,
boiling in anger and poison
until your heart packs in at age 49.
Alone and unloved. Forgotten.
The world carries on.
The world gets better.
You aren't even a footnote.
Just ashes on the wind.
I don't accept your reality, Doctor.
I reject it.
So put me back in my prison
and get off my world.
[footsteps approaching]
Did I imagine that?
No, sweetheart.
It's ever so big, innit?
Who are you?
Oh, I'm the Governor...
and it's your lucky day.
[♪ theme song playing]
[Doctor] Lagos, Nigeria.
[leader] I've been expecting you.
Wait. You're all missing.
[leader] It is always hungry.
We must feed it.
- [Doctor] Who are you?
- [leader] This is my domain.
- [Belinda] Doctor!
- What the hell is this?
[♪ theme song continues]