What in the name of saints?
- The Flux.
- What's the Flux?
This is Serving Commander
Inston-Vee-Vinder leaving his post.
We're coming, Vinder.
Me and your beautiful
as yet unborn child.
- I'm Claire.
- Have we met?
Not yet, but we will.
In the past.
We're in the heart
of the Timestorm.
Time is playing games
with you all.
How did you get in here?
Doctor!
The Angel has the TARDIS.
Can you tell me today's date, please?
November 21st.
And the year?
1967.
There it goes again.
Can you state your name, please?
Claire Brown.
Peggy?
Peggy!
Ridiculous child.
And your date of birth?
- You know this already.
- Ah!
Control questions only.
Date of birth.
13th of May, 1985.
Beg pardon?
- Peggy!
- Peggy?
Peggy!
I said, 13th of May, 1935.
Oh, apologies.
Word of advice, Miss Brown.
Never get old.
Not even slightly.
Thank goodness for
mechanical recordings.
There it goes again.
Twice! For no reason.
It is empirically factually,
November the 21st, 1967.
And you clearly know your own birthday!
And yet, the machine would suggest you
believe neither statement.
Problematic when you need
a control reference.
- A baseline.
- Precisely.
Yes.
I forgot you're very with it.
It's happening.
The percipient exhibits immediate
and extreme physical distress.
Almost if she's physically experiencing
the event she describes.
Theta waves suggest a sleep state,
yet, she remains extraordinarily alert.
Mydriasis of the pupils
and yet no discernible trigger.
Help me.
Yes, of course, my dear,
all in good time.
There is no time, not any more.
The end begins again now.
And there will be no escape.
Not this time.
Not for her, not for them, not for you.
The Angel has the TARDIS.
The Angel has the controls.
We have to get out of here.
Both of you, keep your eyes
on the Angel, don't blink.
if you blink it could attack,
and displace us all in Time,
incredibly dangerous in a moving TARDIS.
- How long for?
- Until I say.
I've got really dry eyes.
What are they?
Two things that should never
be put together.
Or three things, if you include me.
You're gonna put them
together, aren't you?
Yep, reboot the TARDIS
dimensional compression
should eject quantum lifeforms.
But the TARDIS is broken
and Time's out of sync,
so how can you be sure it's gonna work?
It does have an element of risk.
How big an element?
Yeah, pretty big.
The only element really.
See, it's cottoned on,
not a happy bunny.
Now, when I say blink, blink.
You said, don't blink!
I'm updating the advice!
We need it to come close as possible.
Blink!
It worked.
Of course it worked.
The only problem is it will take
a very long time for the TARDIS
to reboot to operational status again.
And the other only problem is,
we don't know where we are
or even if we are.
And the third only problem is,
even if we are somewhere,
what if it's where the Angel wanted
us to be in the first place
when it hijacked the TARDIS.
At least we're alive. Thanks for that.
You're welcome.
Shall we have a nosey outside?
Hello?
Yes?
Jiminy Christmas!
Gerald, language!
Were you in there all the time?
Rapid response unit. How can we help?
Uh-huh... Coastal.
Devon, say 19...
...49.
Madam, what you're doing?
It's 1967, as you must well know.
You've had that coat a while, then.
Wait, why were you calling the police?
Hot, hot, hot...
hot, hot.
What is coming from over there?
Uh, my colleagues will assist you.
Assist them, while I...
Don't wander off.
Says she, wandering off.
Are you in charge?
It's a very flat team structure.
Tell us everything.
We're missing a little girl.
Ten years old, very responsible.
Most unlike her to go off.
Name of Peggy.
Mrs. Hayward,
I know this was you.
I know every house has
received one today.
You're deliberately scaring people.
And you're deliberately ignoring me.
Have you counted the stones?
I don't subscribe
to superstitious folklore.
I know there are exactly
92 gravestones here.
Count them.
And if there are more,
maybe you'll do what I told you.
- Peggy?
Peggy?
It's happening again.
Here you are.
Tea, with honey from my own bees.
Nature's own shock remedy.
Thank you.
What did I say?
Uh, I got it all recorded.
It was a little alarming.
Not as alarming as the readings
that have set my sonic off.
Who are you?
You can call me the Doctor.
The Institute of Psychic Investigation?
Looks like it. Interesting.
How did you get in here?
- Your door was open.
- It most certainly was not.
Well, it was once I opened it.
But let's not get bogged down
in the order of things.
Not when we could get onto
whatever experiments
- you're doing down here, Mr...
- Professor Jericho.
Eustacius Jericho.
- Eustacius?
- Yes.
Oh! Wish I had that
that in Scrabble,
33 on a triple-word score!
Ah. Wouldn't be allowed, though,
proper noun.
Not unless you play
George Eliot's rules, she allows him.
Nice to meet you,
Professor Eustatius Jericho.
Nice house, too.
With apologies to your subjects...
Oh!
Hello. Again.
Oh.
Ah!
I thought it was the experiments
the sonic was reacting to.
But it's actually you.
Claire. Right?
How are you here?
I'm feeling sick again, Professor.
Please!
You are disrupting my percipient.
Madam, explain yourself.
You break into my house.
You disrupt my experiment.
Where did you get this?
Miss Brown sketches,
what she calls her premonitions.
What are you doing?
Trying to keep you safe.
Stay here.
87, 88, 89, 90...
91, 92...
93.
Have you assigned specific areas
to specific groups?
And have you got
an agreed time to report back?
People are just out looking.
What about favourite places she goes to,
or plays in?
Are you prioritising those?
We don't need lecturing.
But if you're so set on it,
yes, I suppose...
That field and the adjacent one.
You're very welcome to them.
You can use that to alert me,
should you find her.
This is your daughter?
My great niece.
She's been in our care since
her parents died.
Anything else we might need
to know about her?
Why would you need to know anything?
If we find her, we might want
to talk to her.
So, any information on what she's like,
or that might make her feel safe,
that would be helpful.
She's a ten year old girl.
How much is there to know?
Gerald!
- Gerald, come on.
- All right, Jean.
Maybe she's not missing.
Maybe she just ran to get away
from him.
Yup.
It's no coincidence, is it?
We got put here by a mad statue.
Doctor's on the trail
of something glowing,
kid goes missing.
I doubt it.
What's the matter?
Was that scarecrow there a minute ago?
Keep your eyes on it.
Don't blink.
Walk backwards.
Keep your eyes on it.
Yeah, easy.
Don't panic.
Who's panicking?
We've got our torches.
Did it just kill our torches?
Keep your eyes on it.
We've still got the moonlight.
What are you doing?
Checking the batteries.
Oh, my universe.
Look what you've been through.
Space is empty now.
I mean, duh!
Obviously, it was empty before.
But since the flux,
there's so much more.
Space.
And so much less... everything else.
Which, when you're trying to find
someone, makes things tricky.
Remember our honeymoon plans?
20 rotations in the floating
canals of Puzano?
Then we got deployed, separately.
So, instead, we had that one night,
in a cubicle hotel opposite the Academy.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
that was more than a good night.
But I regret to inform you,
we may have missed
our moment with Puzano.
Just got here? Oh!
Uh, I was more hoping for hello.
I didn't hear you approach.
It's all right. It's not the worst
reaction I've had.
Everyone's jumpy here.
Uh, I saw you come in.
That's a Lupari Craft, right?
Because you're pretty non-Lupari.
- Borrowed.
- Yeah. Uh, no judgement.
Everyone's borrowed
everything to get here.
Welcome to Puzano.
What's left of it.
Oh, the canals are gone, I'm afraid.
I'm Namaca Ost Parvess Po.
Bel.
Nice. Yeah, short. Better. Easier.
No need to ask why you're here.
The only planetary remains
left in the quadrant.
Quarter of a sun,
third of a moon, half a planet.
Everyone comes here now.
Everyone who's left.
That's what I'm hoping.
You seen this guy?
No... Um, brother?
Life partner.
Okay. Uh, no. Sorry.
Um, he might be
at the next coalescence.
Unless he went already.
The next what?
Oh, there's this person who's made it
their mission to help us.
Get us to safety.
Oh, there'll be one later.
You, you wanna come?
Broken glass everywhere!
What is that device you're using?
Did I not tell you to stay downstairs...
This is my house!
Vandalism!
If I get my hands on the person
that threw this...
Jericho, wait...
How did they get here?
Back away slowly, into the house,
keep your eyes on them.
Don't look away and don't blink.
What're you talking about...
While you're here,
lock everything!
They're at the windows.
How are they moving?
They're just statues!
They're called Weeping Angels.
They move when unobserved.
Quantum beings.
If they touch you, they will send you
back to the distant past,
and feast on the quantum energy
of your unlived life.
Oh, don't be ridiculous...
Professor, I am many things
but I am not ridiculous.
If there's a back entrance
to this house, go and lock it now.
Oh, don't let them near you,
and don't take your eyes off them. Go!
It's them, isn't it? The Angels.
Before that night
I first saw you, I had a premonition.
A succession of disconnected images.
A stone Angel.
You. A blue box called the TARDIS
and a Liverpool street.
Um, numbers. A year.
A voice telling me not to blink.
And the name of this village.
It didn't make any sense.
But then I saw you.
And, afterwards, there was
an Angel on my street.
It followed me to my front door.
And then I was in 1965.
I've been in the 60s for two years.
An Angel attacked you. But why?
What did it want with you?
Back door is locked.
Good! Have you got a television?
- Um, yes.
- Bring it out here!
Are they really ringing the doorbell?
It's a very nice sounding doorbell.
Television!
I don't think the back door is as secure
as the Professor would have hoped.
Do you not think evacuation
might not be the order of the day?
How can we evacuate
when we're surrounded?
Exactly. The building's surrounded
and there are more of them,
than there are of us.
At least inside, we have
a defendable position.
The basement is securable,
right, Professor?
- Oh yes.
- Take the television down there,
quick smart. Follow him, Claire.
I said go!
There's something else, Doctor.
I Googled the name of this village
after I had my first premonition.
Everyone in the village disappears
on the 21st of November, 1967.
Tonight.
Whatever happens leaves no trace.
The Army move in
and turn it into a locked encampment.
Yeah, well, time isn't always fixed...
No, listen to me.
It wasn't the first time.
It also happened in 1901.
Everyone in the village vanished.
Get down to the basement now.
I'll be right behind you.
When d'you think it is?
Dunno. I mean at least there's houses.
Could've been the dinosaurs.
Yeah but there's no people.
First things first,
we're still looking for a missing girl.
And it's a strong possibility
that the Angel sent her
back in time too, so she'll be worried.
Shall we have a nose?
Cold.
Early part of the 20th century?
What, so, 100 years
before you and I are alive?
Yeah.
Like you say. No dinosaurs.
Yaz, how do we get back?
Are we stuck here?
Let's just focus on seeing
if there's anyone else around.
They're all gone.
Your name's not Peggy, is it?
How did you get here, Peggy?
What happened to all the people?
The Angels.
The Angels are here too?
Are you scared
they might come and get you again?
Mmm-mmm.
Well, that's good.
Any reason why?
They promised
they'd leave me alone now.
They talk to you?
They put thoughts in my head.
We're going to get you back, Peggy.
You have to be careful.
You have to stay within the village.
You mustn't go beyond the sign
Why's that?
It used to be further down the road.
It's got closer.
They put two words in my head.
Quantum Extraction.
She always goes missing.
Why is it my responsibility?
Is it my fault her parents died?
Is it my fault she won't talk to me?
Or ever do as I tell her?
Well, the last one, Gerald,
yes, I think it is.
- I beg your pardon?
- Would it kill you
to say one pleasant thing to her?
What do you think gives you the right
to speak to me like that, Jean?
Forty-seven years of pain, Gerald.
Right. That's it.
I'm going home.
- Be quiet, Gerald...
- Jean, what has got into you?
Look.
What's going on?
I don't know, Jean.
But I don't like it.
Let's find those police.
How did that get there?
Must be some sort of prank.
Come along, let's return it
to the churchyard.
We can't pick it up! Look at it!
Somebody must have carried it here!
It can't be that heavy.
Gerald...
Gerald?
What is happening here?
Ah! Bit rudimentary, but it'll do.
That's my hallway.
I'm going to need you
to keep an eye on this picture.
It's risky... but we've got
limited time and choices
and we're going to need
to know where they are.
Why risky?
That which holds the image
of an Angel can also be an Angel.
It'd take a lot of effort,
but if they really wanted to,
they can escape that screen.
What?
See what I mean?
You have to keep your eyes on them.
Doctor, my drawing...
Ah! Do not take your eyes
off that screen, Jericho!
Claire, keep your eyes
on the sketch Angel!
Brilliant, made it worse.
Oh, dear.
- Where were we?
- I may have to write all this down.
Once this is over, be my guest.
Well, why are they attacking my house?
What do they want?
I think: me.
Why would they want you, Claire?
Because I'm one of them.
Look.
Miss Brown...
This isn't possible.
How long have you been like this?
Um, physically, just tonight.
But I hallucinated I had Angel wings
and there was dust coming out of my eye.
There's an Angel within me, Doctor.
I'm certain of it.
You're a percipient.
A seer.
You had a premonition of an Angel
in your mind. And now it's living there.
That which contains the image
of an Angel is an Angel.
It's taken hold.
Oh my...
But it keeps coming and going.
You're saying that because she had
a premonition, a vision,
it's taken psychic root within her?
A real, genuine psychic manifestation?
Eustacius Jericho, proper scientist.
Under siege from the impossible,
doesn't even stop to be scared.
Just wants to understand
what's beyond his comprehension.
Oh, I've seen many things
beyond my comprehension, Doctor.
I was one of the first British soldiers
into Belsen at the end of the war.
If you think a few stone statues
will destroy my equilibrium,
you are mistaken.
What do you need me to do?
We need a lot of eyes
on a lot of Weeping Angels.
Claire, I need to look inside your mind.
If there's an Angel in there,
I need to get it out.
Will you give me permission
to enter your mind?
Will it hurt?
I'll be as gentle as I can.
Okay.
You're going to place yourself
inside Miss Brown's mind?
Yes.
Let me take the readings.
Please permit me to record it.
You're supposed to be
observing the Angels.
Well, I can still do that.
The machines will record any activity.
Please. This is unprecedented.
An experiment that goes
beyond anything before researched.
There!
Contact.
So, you are in here
skulking inside a human mind.
That's new.
Right. You're the one
who hijacked my TARDIS.
Yes, I brought you here.
How?
If you're here, inside Claire's mind,
the psycho-temporal effort
that would have taken is incalculable.
I need your help, Doctor.
A Weeping Angel needs my help.
I don't think so.
You won't get anything from me
until you stop terrorising this human.
I have no choice.
You hunted her down
and now you're living inside her,
corrupting what she sees,
corrupting who she thinks she is.
This is me serving you notice.
I want you out of here now.
I did not hunt her down, Doctor.
That was not me. That was another.
What do you mean?
I was already here.
This human is my sanctuary.
I Identified her as my hiding place
from others of my kind.
So you're saying those Angels
in the village in Jericho's house
they weren't coming to rescue you?
- They're coming to capture you.
- Correct.
A rogue Weeping Angel,
on the run from other Angels,
hiding in the mind of a human.
Which would mean
the Angel that pursued Claire,
that sent her back to the '60s.
It wasn't coming for her,
it was tracking you down.
- Yes.
- But why?
They are an Extraction Squad.
For the Division.
See? Everyone's here.
Oh, this is where she usually comes.
Leave a gap between you and next person
or it won't take.
Where who comes?
Oh, we don't get to ask names.
It's what she does that matters.
Here we go.
Thank you all for being here.
How are we hearing her?
How does she do that?
I know, right?
Space is disintegrating.
Time is corrupting.
I know that you've had to fight
to get here.
I promise you
that fight has been worth it.
There is a safe galaxy,
unaffected by the flux.
We've already provided transport
for many who have come here.
We can do that again, today.
Oh, praise the stars!
The non-existent stars.
Here is your transport.
What is that?
It's been here before,
but I haven't been able
to get close enough
into the transportation field.
Fourth time lucky!
Passenger will activate
the transportation field
and all those within it
will be taken to a place of safety
within the unaffected galaxy.
Did she say Passenger?
- So what?
- Come on.
What are you doing? No.
I've heard of Passenger forms.
My last deployment...
This isn't freedom she's offering.
That thing is not your way out.
Get out of the transportation field...
No, no, I've been waiting for this one!
Everybody get out
of the transportation field.
There's no other way off!
Run! Trust me! Just run!
I don't want to run!
There's nothing to fear.
You can come next time.
Tell everyone who arrives here,
they're safe with us.
What did you do?
Why did you stop me?
That was my chance.
Passenger forms are not transportation.
They're prisons, endless prisons.
- You're wrong.
- No, I'm not.
Whatever she is, she is not salvation.
I don't believe you.
Puzano is not a sanctuary.
It's a hunting ground.
Come with me.
There's room on my ship.
I can get you to another safe haven.
Stay away from me!
A village on the edge of space.
Have you seen anything like that before?
Nope.
Do you think we're on Earth or in space?
And how do statues do any of this?
And why would they want to?
Enough questions, Dan, I get it.
Sorry.
Look.
It's closing in,
like they're herding us.
Maybe not that way, then. Other way.
Maybe not that way either.
Not got many options left, have we?
Back up.
Keep your eyes on it.
Peggy! Peggy!
There she is.
I want a word with you, missy.
Don't come any closer!
Look Jean.
That's another one
of those blessed statues.
Gerald, don't touch it.
I still don't understand
how it became light.
Both of you stay back!
I'll thank you not to tell me
what to do.
Mate, listen to her!
Don't go past the statue!
Do not put your back to it!
Nobody survives it twice.
Don't go in front of the statue!
If you walk in front it,
and we can't see it...
Please don't tell us what to do.
It's just a perfectly normal...
How did that...
I'm so sorry, Peggy.
He was never nice to me.
We have to keep moving.
I've got a friend and she'll sort this.
She'll save us, she always does.
Peggy, is there anything else that
you've seen here,
anything else that you've discovered?
Because we have to find a way
back to 1967.
Don't look at it! Don't look at it!
Oh, what's happening now?
Where have they gone?
Do you
really think you can protect them?
Who's there?
You are, Jericho.
Listen to yourself, Jericho.
Look away, Jericho.
Look away.
No, thank you.
I see you, Jericho.
You see yourself.
Please stop using my voice.
It's a very clever trick,
but most impolite without permission.
So interested
in the workings of other minds
because you can't bear
to examine your own.
Loveless.
Childless.
Hiding in academia
for fear of the real world.
Always losing to a better man,
a life of failure.
You don't know me.
We have your house.
We have your attention.
We are on our way.
There is nothing
you can do to stop us.
Surrender to the
Angels, Jericho.
You know you want to.
I have never surrendered
and I've no intention of starting now.
You stop right there!
You are observed!
And that is my power over you.
For now, Jericho.
But we are patient.
We have time.
We are all around you.
We are everywhere.
What do you know about the Division?
I was Division.
As they are. As you were.
No.
But, like you, I ran.
No, no, no, no.
Don't play games with me.
Don't tell me what I did,
what I don't remember.
You really think I'm gonna trust
a creature like you to tell the truth?
We're both trapped, Doctor.
We have to trust each other.
So, you're telling me the Division
used Weeping Angels
as operatives to do its work?
Division uses everything and everyone.
Every species,
every world, every moment.
They are everywhere.
Present and unseen.
Division is unstoppable.
Yeah, well, I'm pretty good
at stopping the unstoppable.
That's why I brought you here, Doctor.
But I think this may prove too much,
even for you.
Then you need to get out
of this human's body, right now.
- No, not yet.
- They're here.
They know where you are.
Claire can't protect you any more.
But you can.
You stop them.
And I leave her.
I let her live.
Leave her first.
No.
What makes you so dangerous
that they would need so many?
What do you have
that they're so scared of?
Knowledge.
What sort of knowledge?
Of everything.
All Division, all of its history.
Including you.
I hold everything
including the memories
that were taken from you.
That's why I brought you here, Doctor.
You protect me
and I can give you
what you're looking for.
- What happened?
- Sorry.
Threw a cup at you.
I needed to shake you out of it.
We're running out of options.
I see what you mean.
How do we get out?
I'm beginning to question the wisdom
of barricading ourselves
somewhere with so few exits.
Oh, Professor, don't you read
your own floorplans?
What?
Assignation Tunnel.
Looks like the first owner of this house
was somewhat of a scoundrel.
A tunnel from the basement
out to lovers' meeting point.
Don't look away!
Never been more grateful
for another man's deceit.
Put the headsets on these front
two Angels.
I'll keep an eye on them.
Lickety split, Jericho.
To the tunnel, both of you, now.
Now, reverse polarity
of the neutron flow
might give you
a little quantum headache.
Doctor, are you all right?
Go! I'll keep my eye on the door.
Don't look back... I'll do the looking!
- Okay.
- You look forward. Keep going.
Curious patterning on the wall.
I wonder how long it's been there.
Everything all right, Doctor?
Yeah. Nothing to worry about.
Oh, Doctor.
Yeah?
I think there are Angels
in the walls here.
Of course there are.
Why wouldn't there be?
Doctor?
Angel up ahead, Doctor!
And behind.
All right. Keep your eyes on it,
Miss Brown.
Yes, thank you, Professor,
I'm very much not blinking.
If we can get past them,
we might just stand a...
...chance.
My history teacher
lied about this place.
She said it was a burial site
from the Stone Age.
What do you mean?
She said it was excavated in 1901.
But it wasn't.
We're in 1901.
And it wasn't there yesterday.
But it was there today.
And then all the people disappeared.
Why is it night over there?
Dunno. Maybe we stay this side
of it for now, eh?
Yeah.
- Mrs Hayward.
- Stop, Peggy.
Don't come any closer.
I remember this.
I remember the strange old woman.
And I remember all that followed.
I don't understand.
You're in 1901.
I'm sorry,
but you don't get back
to 1967 for a long time.
Because I'm you, Peggy.
In 66 years' time.
I remember the next bit very vaguely.
We came to show them the burial site
and we were right.
It's not a burial site.
But it is made of stone.
Just like they are.
I think it's how they got here.
They told me later why they left me,
why they left all of you.
When they could have killed us all.
It's because they're cruel.
They like to leave
a few rare witnesses.
To tell the story.
Witnesses to what?
Quantum extraction.
Great, because what I really
need now is a flickering torch.
Oh!
Oh no you don't.
Keep back, now.
The exit's
the other side of the Angel.
It's narrow but we can get through.
If one of us keeps eyes
on the Angel at all times, Professor.
Good, yes.
Are they doing that deliberately?
Yes. Trying to get you to blink.
Or sneeze.
You can't sneeze with your eyes open.
All right, Miss Brown,
if you would care to go first.
I will stay here
and keep my eyes on this Angel.
Always the gentleman, Professor.
I'm not blinking!
I'm through.
- Jericho.
- Yes.
When I say run, run.
You go left. I'll go right.
These Angels will be left
staring at each other.
If you say so.
Run.
Professor!
Peggy! Oh.
You're all right!
Mrs Hayward.
You appear to be...
...at night.
Sorry. Who are you?
Mate, it's a long story.
Unfortunately, you've got
enough time to hear it.
Something's happening with the stones.
Yes, it is.
I need to get back.
I've left someone
in the most terrible trouble.
That's going to be
a bit harder than you think.
Everyone, get away from the stones.
So here I am.
Ready to go out.
But I can't without turning my back.
But I'm quick.
Okay.
Race you.
You're not attacking.
I turned my back.
I wasn't observing you.
Why am I still here?
What are you waiting for?
Claire, good news is we made it through.
More worrying news is,
that I think it let me go.
And I don't know why...
Doctor.
My Angel says go to your friends.
It'll wait.
They'll all wait.
It says...
...they're enjoying
watching you work it out.
What's going on?
Doctor, it's been communicating
with them. I can sense it.
I don't know what it's said to them,
but...
Claire, don't worry. Stay there.
Don't come any closer.
We're stuck in 1901.
We... We're what?
Maybe we should have broke that to you
a little bit more gently.
We can't cross the line.
At the edge of the village,
it's just stars.
It's like we're marooned in space
and it's creeping in on us.
All right. Anything else?
Yeah.
What does quantum extraction mean?
Of course.
They've taken the village out of time.
Out of space.
To isolate.
To extract the target.
What target?
All right.
You've got what you came for.
I want you to take your rogue Angel
out of Claire, without harming her.
And put this village, these people,
safely back into their lives.
Come on, Rogue Angel.
Tell them to do that,
and I'll negotiate a deal
between them and you.
Well?
No.
What?
My Angel is saying no.
It says,
it's made a better trade.
That they've agreed not to take it.
Because they'll take you instead.
This was its plan all along.
It hid in you,
a human,
to attract me.
Because the only thing Division wants
more than my Angel...
...is you.
You are recalled.
To Division.
No!
Hey.
You seen this person?
Yeah.
You're kidding. Where is she?
- She left.
- When? Where did she go?
I don't know.
It was a while ago.
Time's...
...cronky, you know.
Listen, uh,
I saw her do something
before she left.
It's a bit of a walk from here, but...
...if you've got time.
It's just, er, up there.
No way.
Thank you.
I think maybe she saved my life.
If you see her, tell her...
...thank you.
What time do you call this, huh?
There's not much duration in these,
so I'll be quick.
Only one chance at recording, too.
High stakes.
Okay, so I was here.
That's obvious.
But I've had to go and help some people.
There's a creature
with a Passenger form.
They're abducting people.
And, you know me, I've never been a fan
of the old abductions.
I don't know where it'll lead me.
I've got a Lupari ship,
and I'll keep the transponder blaring.
Hurry up, Inston-Vee Vinder.
Oh, and, um, I love you.
I really love you.
I love you too.
Ooh, uh, coordinates.
So, I'm heading to,
oh, no, no, no, don't run out...
No.
I'm on my way.
That's very odd.
Pattern optimisation in progress.
We've been in this decade
for three years now.
Do you think we'll ever get back?
Karvanista to Lupari fleet.
Earth shield is now breachable.
How you expect to protect
this pitiful race, I do not know.
Can you feel
the timeforce growing?
It's working.
Just as we planned.