Niagara Falls.
Is there a better demonstration
of the sheer power of Nature?
When I first saw this view,
I was inspired to build
my Niagara Generator,
and now these waters
power a city.
But there's so much more
in Nature
that cannot be seen
by the naked eye,
forces invisible to us
which animate the universe.
And they were hidden from
our understanding...until now.
Gentlemen, I, Nikola Tesla,
have invited you here
to pull back the curtain.
Shall we begin?
Observe,
- ladies and gentlemen.
- (CROWD GASPS)
I plan to harness
these forces of Nature
on a scale never seen before.
A world wireless system.
A way for each of us to reach
beyond our immediate sphere
into every corner of the Earth.
(APPLAUSE)
I only require the small
investment of $50,000.
$50,0007?
A small price to pay
to transmit energy through
the ether with no wires.
You mean flying around
in the air?
Poppycock! They're even more
far-fetched than those
Mars stories that we've all
been hearing about.
I'm sure you gentlemen
know better than to believe
everything you read
- in the 7imes.
- Thank you, Miss Skerritt,
but I did in fact receive
a feeble electrical signal,
and I calculate
it comes from Mars.
(CROWD MURMURS)
But that's not the focus
of this project.
Mr Tesla, I'm not in the habit
of investing in fairy tales.
Good day to you.
Mr Brady, sir, please!
My work is not a fairy...tale.
I promise you,
within about a year,
my Wardenclyffe project will be
as real and functioning
as this very generator!
- (CLANG)
- (ELECTRICAL SPARKING)
Mr Tesla?
We have an emergency.
Oh, dear. How did this happen?
I think an electric shock,
miss.
What?
One of these machines must have
killed him.
That's impossible.
All the apparatus here
is perfectly safe.
Nonetheless, Mr Tesla will be
happy to take a look.
After all, we can't have people
thinking
there's some deadly flaw
in your designs.
Can we, sir?
Very well.
I work alone!
(CLANG)
Ah, Miss Skerritt!
I have solved the riddle!
Of course there is no flaw
with my machinery.
(LAUGHS) Parts are missing.
We have a thief at work!
Miss Skerritt?
Hello?
Anybody there?
(HIGH-PITCHED BURBLING)
Incredible.
- What is it?
- (GASPS)
I...I have no idea.
(CLANG)
(GASPS) I thought the foreman
went home.
Miss Skerritt, we need to leave
now.
(MISS SKERRITT GASPS)
It's locked!
- (FOOTSTEPS CLANG)
- There!
Oh. Hi!
I don't suppose you've seen
anything weird around here?
Agh! I'll take that as a yes.
Mind if I join you?
(GASPS)
It's Mr Brady.
Why would a potential investor
be shooting at us?
More urgently - who shot him?
Run!
TESLA: Who are you?
Someone with a fast way
out of here!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(GASPS) Here we go -
perfect getaway vehicle!
Full speed,
straight to New York.
What did I say?
Night train, right on schedule.
Did you find out
what was causing
this energy thing, then?
No, but I found these two.
Welcome aboard the Orient
Express! We travel in style.
This is Graham, Yaz and Ryan.
We were doing the sights
when I picked up
a funny energy reading.
Thought I'd check it out.
Ran into a tiny bit of trouble
at the plant.
Nothing to worry about.
We've lost them.
So, here we are.
I'm the Doctor, by the way.
Why don't you tell me who you
are and who's shooting at you?
Dorothy. Dorothy Skerritt.
I am Nikola Tesla, and
I assure you I have no idea.
Tesla!
I knew you looked familiar!
It's only Nikola Tesla!
- Who?
- Nicholas something.
Total genius!
I always wanted to meet you!
Shame you're a big, fat liar.
- Pardon?
- (ALL GASP)
YAZ: Doctor!
And we're off again!
Look out! Go, go, go!
- RYAN: Who's that?
- I don't know! (GASPS)
- (SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
- Locked it! Keep going!
Go!
- No way!
- Go on, Ryan!
- You've got this!
- Agh!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
It's quiet.
Why has it gone quiet?
(CREAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
I'll take that!
(GASPS)
Keep it moving, then.
Missing something?
Come on! Argh!
It's rusted together.
Got you!
(LOW GROWL)
Silurian blaster.
Nasty. Deadly thing.
But here's the funny part -
whatever was firing it wasn't
Silurian. So, Nikola Tesla,
why is someone chasing you
with an alien gun?
You believe this is alien?
Not so fast, you big, fat liar.
Why do you keep saying that?
Is she always this impertinent?
- OTHERS: Yes.
- First thing I asked you,
I said, "Have you seen
anything weird?"
And there's one important thing
you've failed to mention.
See, I started this evening
chasing an unusual
energy reading.
I followed that signal,
loud and clear,
to the Niagara Generator.
So why am I still detecting it
on board this train with you?
Whatever it is, hand it over.
This is one of the most
miraculous things
I've seen in my life.
It's a mystery
I intend to solve.
And I have no intention of
handing it to total strangers.
Strangers who just
saved your life.
Whatever you found
is putting you in danger.
Yeah. Both of you.
You all right with that?
I agree with Mr Tesla.
If anyone can make sense
of this, it's him.
Well, then,
if you won't hand it over,
you leave us no choice.
We're not letting you
out of our sights
until we've worked this out.
So, where's this lab, then?
DOCTOR: Now, this is
a bit of all right.
Gilded Age, New York!
This is when the modern world
begins!
New ideas, new technologies,
new skyscrapers.
More people getting rich quick,
and more poor people
than ever before.
I always wanted to visit
New York, see Times Square.
Yeah, bit early for that.
- Empire State Building?
- Not yet.
- Central Park?
- Yeah!
Now, that has been around
for ages.
- (CHANTING)
- RYAN: Can you hear yelling?
CROWD: No to the death current,
no AC!
No to the death current, no AC!
Who are they?
Protesters.
What are they protesting about?
- Me.
- There he is!
Do you have any idea
what you're doing?
- Shame on you!
- He's dangerous!
- Go back to Mars!
- How many more people
have to die before you admit
your machines aren't safe?
My inventions never hurt
anyone!
Isn't it true your last
invention caused an earthquake?
Those were only mild tremors.
Why are you building weapons
on Long Island?
Mr Tesla isn't building
any kind of weapon,
or going to answer
any questions!
- Excuse me!
- Foreign lunatic!
You don't belong in America.
Yeah!
I am an American citizen!
And you are trespassing
in front of my lab.
Me? A lunatic?
They wouldn't recognise genius
if it hit them in the face.
YAZ: Are you all right?
Oh. Absolutely - yeah.
Their opinions
do not affect me.
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
He'll just be a moment.
(CLATTERING)
Why don't you go on through?
Tesla's lab.
This is gonna be
something special!
I won't lie.
I was expecting more.
Well, let's have a look about.
Mm.
So, Tesla - is he something
to do with the cars, then?
Yeah, well,
they're named after him.
He's a famous inventor,
ain't he, Doc?
Yeah?
And what did he invent?
Well, he invented the, erm...
The whatchamacallit.
Tell 'em, Doc.
(YAZ LAUGHS)
Nikola Tesla dreams up the
20th century before it happens.
Before you have X-rays,
Tesla has shadowgraphs.
Before you have drones,
Tesla has automatons.
Before Marconi gets
the patent for radio,
they have to take it from Tesla
because he invents it first!
His work
on alternating currents
helps electrify the world.
He should have been
the first billionaire by now
if he hadn't have
torn up his contract.
Business isn't
his strong point.
Doctor.
I believe you wanted
to see this.
(FIZZING)
Is this what you found
in the generator?
Giving off all that energy -
but why?
- (SPHERE BUZZES)
- Whoa!
You see how it moves
independently?
I believe this is something I
like to call "remote control”.
Remote control?
You came up with that?
I believe this is operating
on a similar principle.
If we could just
work out its purpose...
I know what it is.
It's an Orb of Thassor.
But I've no idea
what it's doing here.
The Thassor were
one of the ancient races.
Amazing storytellers.
Inventors, explorers.
They built these orbs as a way
to spread information,
to send out among the stars
as a way to share their legacy
long after they were gone.
Why would someone try to kill
us to get their hands on that?
I've no idea.
- (BUZZING STOPS)
- But maybe I can find out.
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
I think it's been repurposed.
But I can't work out
what it's doing instead.
This is all wrong!
Something this elegant
shouldn't be giving off
this kind of noise.
Its energy readings
are off the charts!
That instrument detects energy?
Is-Is it your own design?
I made it!
Mainly out of spoons.
You're an inventor!
I have my moments.
I knew it!
So... So you can understand
how it feels -
you know, when you have an idea
and-and to make it real.
I don't think
there's any greater thrill!
I couldn't agree more.
You... You spoke of aliens.
People - you know -
laugh at the very idea!
- But not you.
- Well, apparently,
I'm not like other people.
It can be difficult, you know,
to feel no-one else
sees the world the way you do.
It's like you're, er...
Out of place.
Yeah.
I... I thought... I thought
things would be different.
You know, when I first arrived
in America,
I had four cents to my name -
I was robbed on the journey -
but still I thought,
"This is the beginning!”
Here I would prosper,
my ideas would live!
Changing the world takes time.
You have to be patient.
I try.
But you saw them outside.
They... They talk as if I was
dangerous or mad, or...
So prove them wrong!
(DOOR OPENS)
Sir, this was just delivered -
it's from Mr Morgan.
Excellent.
Mr Morgan is the investor
behind my Wardenclyffe project.
With his help, we...
- He's pulling the funding.
- DOROTHY: What?
I, er...can't complete
Wardenclyffe without it.
I'm never gonna be able
to prove it works.
- (FLASH BULB POPS)
- Who's that?
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
That was Harold Green -
one of Edison's men.
YAZ: As in Thomas Edison?
- Light-bulb guy?
- All right.
We all know Edison. It's Tesla
you've never heard of.
He's literally
standing right there.
Yeah - sorry, son.
Edison, Edison.
Of course it's Edison.
He's plagued me
every step of my career!
Edison champions a rival form
of electric current
to Mr Tesla's AC.
Direct current - of course,
he would champion
something so slow
and inefficient.
TESLA: That man
is a liar and a thief.
Are we saying Thomas Edison
is after the Orb of Thassor?
Don't be daft - how's Edison's
men gonna get their hands on
a Slymurian laser blaster?
Silurian.
Let's go and find out.
You three stay here
and guard the Orb.
You two - with me.
Time we paid a visit
to Mr Thomas Edison.
Ladies and gentlemen,
AC is the most deadly force
known to science.
For the public's safety,
the Niagara Generator
should be shut down.
DOCTOR: And let me guess.
An Edison Generator
built in its place.
Couldn't have
put it better myself.
Thomas Edison, we need to talk.
- As I was saying...
- We could talk here
but I think you'd prefer to go
somewhere more private.
You want to make
an appointment,
speak to my secretary.
Alien weapons.
How are you getting
your hands on them?
(CHUCKLES) Alien weapons.
You have the wrong inventor,
ma'am.
It's Nikola Tesla's
been talking to Mars.
I keep my feet on the ground.
So...you don't recognise this?
Let's take this inside.
GRAHAM: Whoa! This is
some set-up he's got.
See, this guy
I've definitely heard of -
he's got to be America's
most famous inventor.
Yeah. But not exactly
a shrinking violet, is he?
I mean, he's plastered his name
all over the shop!
Talk about
tooting your own horn!
I have never seen
anything like this in my life.
Is it your design?
Who has the patent?
This isn't
a business opportunity -
someone tried to
shoot us with it
just before we caught
an employee of yours
spying on Nikola Tesla.
Someone's trying
to steal from him,
and he seems
pretty sure it's you.
Does he, now?
Ma'am,
I may keep an eye on my rivals,
but I do not steal.
I have no need to.
There are a thousand patents
in the Edison name.
You might have seen it
on the building.
- That's not how Tesla sees it.
- He's sore about the past.
You know, I gave him a job
when he first arrived
in this country
on the factory floor.
He ended up digging ditches
for two bucks a day.
Tesla?!
Dapper dude
who dresses for the opera?
How did he end up
digging a ditch?
He heard me say I'd pay $50,000
to the man who could
fix my generator.
He worked on that thing
day and night for a year.
And he did it.
And you, being
the upstanding businessman,
paid every last cent,
I presume.
I offered him a ten-buck raise.
He quit and chose to dig.
Man just didn't understand
the American sense of humour.
I thought you'd have
more stuff.
Sketches, blueprints, you know.
For all your inventions.
All in here. (SIGHS)
Before anything else, I...
...I build things here.
Tell me about
this Wardenclyffe project.
Er...
Imagine if, er...
...wherever you were,
you were able to hear music
or, er, the speech
of a great leader, or, er...
...conjure a map
of what lay beyond.
That's what I propose
with Wardenclyffe -
all of human knowledge
shared freely.
Now that sounds
like the future.
Yeah. Yeah...
It will change the world.
Why can't anyone else see that?
There must be someone
who'll invest in it.
Well, if there is,
I can't find them,
and, er, without the money,
I have no power source,
and without power...
(ORB BUZZES)
SCIENTIST: Sir,
if you'll just permit me...
No! No, the grounding coil
goes in separately.
- I said don't touch!
- SCIENTIST: Sorry.
Really? Go over there!
(CRACKLING)
(GASPING)
(LOUD CRACKLING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(METAL CLATTERS)
Something's wrong.
Oh, I should say.
We've done this dance
for long enough.
Now, what have you done
with my man, huh?
Oh, don't play dumb.
He was keeping tabs
on that dog-and-pony show
of Tesla's at Niagara.
Now he's gone quiet -
the very day you show up
pointing the finger.
Huh?
Trust me, Mr Edison -
we're not the people
you should be worried about.
He is.
DOCTOR: behind me!
Harold? What's the matter
with him?
That's not Harold Green.
No human readings.
What is that? Not possession.
Psionic image cloaking?
Hologram?
EDISON:
What are you talking about?
- (GROWLING)
- No guns, Ryan!
Whatever you are,
whatever you've come for,
nobody else needs to get hurt.
- (GROWLS)
- DOCTOR: Desk!
Run!
EDISON: Oh, my God.
No time.
This way.
DOCTOR: In here.
GRAHAM: Doc, look!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
Oh, he's dead.
He's the real Harold Green.
Whatever's chasing us
is projecting his image
and using it to keep
his true self hidden.
You better not be
hiding anything.
People have died.
My workers!
All those men work for me.
They had families.
I had dinner with this guy
and his wife last week.
I have to tell her,
tell the families.
- Now give me the gun.
- Definitely not.
We're not shooting it!
We need to contain it,
work out what it wants.
This is your chemical lab.
Perfect!
Ammonium nitrate,
bit of green stuff.
- Where's your zinc?
- Zinc?
Have you lost your damn mi...?
Oh!
Finally thinking
like a scientist.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZES)
YAZ: What is that?
Power!
Waiting to be harnessed.
Your-Your Doctor was right.
The Orb is emitting
huge amounts of energy.
It's pulsing - like a siren.
Or radar.
Radar?
Using energy waves to work out
what's around you.
It's just a theory.
I've been working on
a similar theory myself.
I call it my exploring ray.
But, anyway -
the Orb is emitting
distinct waves of energy.
It's... It's like it's, ah,
sensing its surroundings.
YAZ: Or scanning.
Which makes me wonder...
What is it looking for?
(GROWLING HISS)
There'll be more
where that came from.
How about we try this again?
Who are you?
Show your true form.
(GROWLING HISS)
What in God's name?
Yaz! It's not Edison!
I mean, it was, but
it turns out it's aliens, too.
They can look like anyone,
so don't let anyone in!
Tell Tesla! Tell Dorothy!
Lock every door!
I'm sorry.
DOCTOR: Yaz?
Yaz, are you all right?
- You are dead.
- We know you want the Orb.
Let her go.
Exactly - you don't
have to hurt her.
With your levels of technology,
you must understand
there is no need for violence.
(DISTORTED)
We did not come for the Orb.
We came for you.
No!
Welcome, Nikola Tesla.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
(GASPS)
You're all right. You've
probably got questions.
They took them.
Where did they take them?
We know they've got
cloaking tech,
but if I rig a bypass...
Luckily, high-speed inventing
is one of my specialisms.
First time here can be a lot.
It certainly is a lot.
But you take it in your stride.
Where do you even come from?
Yorkshire, England.
I was at home - you know,
normal life, work -
then, boom... The Doctor.
Changed my whole life.
I was the same
before I met Mr Tesla.
I wanted my own career -
something steady -
then he showed me all these
discoveries that could be made.
But it seemed like
impossible things.
And now,
something normal, steady...
Doesn't seem so important.
We'll get 'em back.
She's good at impossible, too.
Right, then.
(ORB BUZZES)
On you pop.
This is the most
extraordinary thing.
Is it a single machine
or some kind of, er...
...mechanical factory?
GRAHAM: Oi!
You're in here
strictly on the QT, right?
So get those dollar signs
out of your eyes
cos this little lot ain't
for sale. Copyright - her!
That's a British accent,
isn't it?
Yes.
Now there's a country who's
never understood business.
DOCTOR: Please work.
GRAHAM: Have you
got something, Doc?
Of course!
That's why they left it behind.
It's been hacked. It's not
broadcasting any more -
it's receiving.
GRAHAM: You mean
it's a bugging device.
Thought so.
Moment I saw it.
DOCTOR: Exactly. Repurposed
from its original intent.
It's been scanning the Earth
since it got here.
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
And it must have finally found
what it's been looking for.
What is this place?
You stand on the Throne Ship
of the Skithra.
High above your meagre city.
You can see your city.
But your city cannot see us.
We have been watching,
hidden from human eyes
while we searched.
This is an electrical
condenser - from my generator.
We have gathered supplies.
Now you will work.
Work on what?
Our ship. Our weapons.
Everything.
They're hiding their real faces
behind projections -
they could look like anything,
be anywhere. There's no trail!
If we're looking for
a trail to follow,
what if Tesla already found it?
DOROTHY: But he did.
The Mars signal.
I didn't believe him -
not really.
But he records
all his observations.
We have to go to Wardenclyffe.
Wow. Now, this is a lab.
Mr Tesla started transferring
all of his work
to Wardenclyffe months ago.
He intercepted
the Mars signal with this.
He calls it his Teslascope.
Here are
all the readings he took.
They must have increased
the cloaking
when they realised
he'd spotted them.
Hey! Don't take
your eyes off him,
and don't let him
touch anything!/
We're on Long Island.
This box transported us
halfway across New York.
Unbelievable.
Yeah, well, keep it
to yourself,
or people'll say
you're as crazy as Tesla.
That, my friend,
will never happen.
Yeah, still -
bet you'd jump at the chance
to have him back working
- for you, wouldn't you?
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
- How'd you figure that?
Cos I had a supervisor
like you at my old depot.
And men like you don't pay
a bloke that much attention
unless you think
there's a pay-out coming.
DOCTOR:
It must be here somewhere.
Ah, I've found it!
The signal readout.
Now we're in business.
One of these must be good
for getting out of here.
Got to find a way off the ship.
We're hundreds of feet
above New York.
What do you suggest
we do - open a door?
I'd suggest we don't surrender
to the giant alien scorpion.
You're right. I'm sorry.
This is all my fault.
You shouldn't even be here.
Just cos you're a genius
doesn't mean
you have to figure everything
out on your own.
We're in this together.
You have examined
the equipment?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Yes, I have.
There are more secrets
on this ship
than I could discover
in a lifetime. Er...
It...
It is a scientist's dream.
Then your work shall begin.
You will prepare us for battle.
No, I won't.
(LOUD HISSING)
Your work would burn a path
across the galaxies.
On Earth, you are nothing.
Perhaps I will achieve nothing,
but if I achieve anything,
it will be in the name
of progress,
and you are not my idea
of progress.
(ROARS)
Kill the stowaway.
I knew I had one
in my tool box.
Braxium bouncer, mark III.
Found it at a bazaar.
Bit wonky, but I can't take
the TARDIS.
This should give us
enough power to transport me,
Yaz and Tesla back here.
But once I'm there,
I can't jump back
until it recharges itself.
Which, you know,
I'm not worried about.
Definitely. And you shouldn't
be worried about it either.
Not in the least.
QUEEN SKITHRA:
This is the price of refusal.
First, she dies,
then everyone down there.
Stop.
She's my assistant, I need her.
(HISSES)
She's not important.
DOCTOR: I'm going to
have to disagree with that.
Ah.
Nice place you've got here.
Probably.
If you cleaned up a bit.
I mean, I'm messy, but this?
(GROWLS)
Are you guys all right?
Better now you're here.
I'm the Doctor.
I don't believe we've met.
You address
the queen of the Skithra?
You trespass on my ship?
Oh, is this your ship?
Because it looks Venusian to me
and I'm pretty sure
that's a Klendov warp drive.
Is there a single thing
on this ship
that you've built yourselves?
This one is clever.
She will assist Tesla.
I've had worse jobs.
Or she will die.
Stolen tech...
...stolen faces,
and now all your stolen gear
is breaking down.
And what do you do?
Steal someone else to fix it.
All this killing and looting!
Did it never occur to you
to try thinking or building
something instead?
(RASPING LAUGH)
Why would we build when
all there is is ours to take?
Tesla...
Why Tesla?
Why send the sphere
to track him,
an inventor from 19007
We required an engineer.
I was talking!
Tesla showed superior signs
of intelligence.
He discovered our signal.
But how did you know that?
He signal led back.
You didn't think
to mention that?
I didn't know it worked.
YAZ: Seriously?
The Skithra have always taken
what we need.
And, Doctor...
...] do not see a need for you.
Oh, is that
a Dullirian resonator?
Oh, and this can power
a starship for months.
You think Tesla's clever?
We make him look like
the village idiot.
A smart,
forward-thinking
scorpion queen like yourself,
I wouldn't go killing
me and Yaz.
Cos Yaz...
(BEEPING)
...can tell you what this is.
- It's a camera.
- Bingo.
(SKITHRA SCREECH)
- GRAHAM: Doctor!
- RYAN: Ah, Yaz.
- Mr Tesla!
- Miss Skerritt.
- (TESLA DRAWS BREATH)
- EDISON: Well, I'll be darned.
She actually got you back.
What is he doing here?
Tesla,
quite a day we're all having.
It's not over yet.
Come on.
This is my private laboratory.
Yes.
You have no right to be he...
What is this?
- Wh... Wh...
- (DOOR CREAKS AND SHUTS)
Where are you all going?
Fantastical!
I couldn't figure it out
either.
The internal dimensions
transcends the external.
Spot-on.
(BUZZING)
Listen up, Skithra queen,
it's me, on behalf of Tesla.
Consider this your official
eviction notice.
Get your ship away from Earth
right now.
QUEEN SKITHRA:
We will take the engineer
or this planet shall burn!
Surrender him
and your lives may be spared.
You can't have him.
He's with us.
And we're not going anywhere.
Then we will kill
all the teeming millions
that infect this world.
And you and your friends
will die first.
This is the choice
you must make.
Give us Tesla, or the planet -
and all who live on it -
shall die.
It cannot be me or the Earth.
You can't place
this burden on me.
Mr Tesla!
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(GUTTURAL HISS)
Find them.
I've spent my life wondering
what might be out there.
But creatures who would destroy
the whole planet
just to get their hands on me?
Recognition at last.
(CHUCKLES)
You do realise
it's killing Edison that
they want you and not him.
(EXHALES)
This place, Wardenclyffe...
...] was so close.
People would finally see
what it can do.
What 7 can do.
Now no-one will ever know.
You must all go.
Let them take me.
That's not going to happen.
I have to surrender myself.
There is nothing else
to be done.
This is beyond me.
No.
No?
Nikola Tesla, you're going
to change the world.
But first, you're going
to save it.
Now, tell me all about
Wardenclyffe.
The tower works by harnessing
the electric field
of the Earth itself.
Here - my magnifying
transformer
pumps millions of volts
into this tunnel.
The current races down through
the Earth until it reaches
the other side of the planet,
and then bounces back.
Then it's channel led
into the tower -
wave after wave after wave -
and up into the air!
My intention was to build
a series of these towers...
...transmitting energy
throughout the ether -
a world wireless system.
That's Wi-Fi.
Did Tesla have the idea
for Wi-Fi?
But with enough power,
it could be used to send
a single bolt of lightning
high up into the sky.
Ah, well, if we generate one
large enough,
it could strike the ship,
like so!
Yes! High-five!
Too early!
In a pig's eye.
You want to bet our lives on
a contraption like this, huh?
Some fantastical idea no sane
man would ever invest in?
At least I have ideas.
You have filled a factory
full of men
to do your thinking for you.
Half of your inventions were
thought up by other people.
Anyone can have ideas.
I make them happen.
All those men,
all those inventions,
I turn them from a sketch into
real things people can buy.
That's how you change
the world.
You're too blind to see that
my factory is the best idea
either one of us ever had.
And you are too narrow-minded
to grasp the genius of my work,
and that is why you will never
achieve real greatness.
You are not a man of vision.
You're a man of...parts.
Oi! AC/DC! You two might be
the greatest minds of the age,
but is there any chance
you can stop squabbling
while we try and save
the planet?
We need to move quickly.
We have to prepare the tower.
Here's what
we're going to do...
You and me will finish
the tower.
I can extend the TARDIS shields
within the boundaries
of Wardenclyffe.
That should keep us safe...
for now.
Edison, Yaz - I need you to get
people off the streets.
- The Skithra are on their way.
- (GROWLS AND HISSES)
Dorothy, Graham, Ryan -
find anything we can use
to defend Wardenclyffe.
And be fast. For all we know,
they've already found us.
YAZ: Please! Please!
Everybody inside!
Please! Please move inside.
Everybody inside.
Why is nobody listening to me?
Is it the accent?
Please, it's an emergency!
- Please can you go inside?
- That fool Tesla
is still experimenting
with his deadly tower!
We're as good as fried
if we stay outside.
He's firing it up right now!
- Spread the word!
- (PANICKED SHOUTING)
- No-one is safe!
- (SCREAMING)
(HISSES)
(SIGHS)
"Mechanism for
photographing thoughts"?
- No.
"Apparatus for producing
ozone."
"Prototype death ray"?
- Yes!
- Yeah?
No, no.
Where is Tesla?
Hey! You stay away from him!
Get down, kid!
Where the hell did he go?
Quick, inside!
- When did you get that?
- Just be glad I did.
- (ZAPPING)
- (GROWLING)
EDISON: Oh, my dear Lord,
what is that?
(SNARLS)
(ROARS)
YAZ: Come on, run!
Run!
(GUNSHOT)
Are you sure this is right?
Tesla said it should be just...
Here!
This tunnel leads us
back to Wardenclyffe.
OK!
Doctor?
We have company.
(SKITHRA SCREECH)
Shield's working, then.
Come on. Come on!
Just in time. We need
to barricade the door now.
- Good God...
- There's too many of them.
Well, they may have
superior numbers,
but we have superior minds.
We just have to hold them off.
They're a hive species.
So if we take out the queen...
We take out all of 'em.
Yes! She's still on the ship,
and, hopefully, we're about
to zap her
with a lot of
Wardenclyffe electricity!
- There's a but.
- Small detail.
Once we power up the tower,
the TARDIS shields will drop,
but it will be about 30 seconds
before we can blast the ship.
There's not enough juice
for both.
What?
What's going to keep them out,
then?
We are.
Don't worry.
This ain't our first rodeo.
We've never been to a rodeo.
You're not helping, Ryan.
Ready?
(DOCTOR GASPS)
It's working.
DOCTOR: The tower's charging.
Nearly there.
Get ready out there.
Shields are about to drop.
Shields down.
A few more seconds.
GRAHAM: We ain't got
a few seconds, Doc!
(RATTLING)
What? Signal coming
from the Skithra ship.
(SKITHRA SCREECH)
(SCREECHING FADES)
What are they doing?
Why aren't they attacking?
Oh, no.
What is it?
Let's see what this thing
can do.
Stay out of our lab!
We can't blast the ship -
because the queen's
no longer on it.
(GASPS)
This was not the plan.
Was this meant to be
your fortress?
And you its defenders?
What was the plan?
To shiver in the dark
until we went away?
(SNARLS)
(GASPS)
Oh, you really are fragile
creatures, aren't you?
It's a miracle
your world has spun on
so long undisturbed.
Now, tell me.
Where is he?
No?
Then which of you would like
- the privilege of dying first?
- DOCTOR: Stop!
If you want Tesla,
you have to go through me.
Doctor, did you really think
I'd let you hide away
down here,
hatching your little plans?
If I'd known we were going
to have a royal visit,
I'd have put the kettle on.
As queen, I grant myself
the pleasure of killing you...
(INHALES SHARPLY)
...in person.
And what are you
queen of, exactly?
A stolen ship
and second-hand guns?
A queen of shreds and patches.
You're not a ruler,
you're a parasite.
And what are you?
So clever,
stealing onto my ship,
taking what I claimed as mine.
But where has it got you?
No weapons.
No arm our.
No escape.
Just the desperate hope
you might change my mind.
No. We're way past that.
I gave you your chance.
- A chance to be like you?
- A chance to evolve.
But you were too stupid
to take it.
When you die, there'll be
nothing left behind.
Just a trail of blood
and other people's brilliance.
No-one will even know
you existed.
(HISSES)
It's important you understand,
Doctor,
that we would have only taken
the engineer.
Now, because of you,
I will take everything.
We will overrun this world
and pick the bones clean.
Have you ever seen
a dead planet?
I've seen more
than you can possibly imagine.
And yet you still think
I can be fooled
by the same trick twice.
(GASPS)
- Doctor!
- Stay back!
(SNARLS)
A final weapon
for our collection.
And what were you planning
to do with this?
Nothing. I just wanted you
to take it.
(SCREWDRIVER BUZZES)
(ROARS)
Tesla, now!
Press the switch!
(SKITHRA ROAR)
There you go, kid.
Thank you.
I gotta hand it to you.
You did it.
Come work for me again.
You keep working on this thing,
you'll be bankrupt
within the year.
Perhaps.
But how could I stop now?
(CHUCKLES)
You take good care
of yourself.
You too.
Was that more or less
impossible than your usual day?
Yeah, about average. You?
Slightly stranger.
Normal would be boring,
wouldn't it?
Bye.
Now, this all changes, right?
The protests, the funding.
Tesla's tower's just saved
the world!
That's gotta mean
rich and famous.
No.
Nothing's changed.
A few years from now
Wardenclyffe is torn down.
Tesla keeps on inventing,
but no money, no fame.
He dies penniless.
History leaves him behind.
But his vision of wireless
energy, that does happen,
a connected world,
and that idea starts here,
with him.
That's not right.
People should know.
Either way, it doesn't change
what he's done.
Doctor...
You have to let me study
that machine of yours.
It is by far the most
magnificent invention
I've ever seen in my life.
Never mind the TARDIS,
you've got enough magnificent
inventions of your own.
Yes. Yes, you're right.
You're right, of course.
There's so much to be done.
Thank you.
Thank you, all.
Don't give up.
Whatever anyone says.
Well, let them talk.
The present is theirs.
I work for the future.
And the future is mine.
Shall we?
A Judoon warning transmission.
Who are you?
The city's under siege.
- Do you trust me, Ruth?
- Sometimes.