-(ALARMS BEEPING)
-Data breach.
There's been a data breach
in the core drives. We are compromised.
I repeat, we are compromised.
-Hello. Nice to see you again.
-Who the hell are you?
(TUTS) How quickly they forget.
I'm the Doctor.
And this is the Inforarium,
the greatest source of
illicit information in recorded history.
Which is fine, your business,
but you've been selling it
to the Daleks, to the Cybermen
and the Sontarans. That's just naughty.
-(CONSOLE BLEEPS)
-If you're trying to raise the alarm,
I wouldn't bother. I'm not really here.
I'm a recorded message.
-You're a what?
-A recorded message.
-Then how can you be replying to me?
-You're very predictable. Thing is
I'm on a bit of a mission
at the moment.
I've been deleting every piece
of information about myself
-from every database in the universe.
-Why?
-I want to be alone.
-Well, you can't delete it from here.
All our data is quantum-stored.
It exists at 12 levels of reality...
And now you're probably boasting
about "12 levels of reality”. Boring!
You're right.
I can't delete any of your data.
-But I can memory-proof it.
-Memory-what?
Any information from this facility
concerning me
will be forgotten
seconds after it is learned.
Clever trick.
Learned it from the Silence.
-(LAUGHS) That's impossible.
-Anything about me, the Doctor,
the last of the Time Lords,
will just disappear from your mind
-like it was never there.
-It can't be done.
You know what?
Better check your drives.
(ALARMS BEEPING)
Data breach. There's been a data breach
in the core drives.
We are compromised.
I repeat, we are compromised.
(HOLOGRAM PROJECTOR TURNS ON)
-Hello. Nice to see you again.
-Who the hell are you?
(TUTS) How quickly they forget.
I'm the Doctor.
And this is the Inforarium...