(CLOCK CHIMES)
Whoever those aliens are,
they haven't just arrived,
they've been here for a while.
Harriet Jones,
MP for Flydale North.
I thought
I was Prime Minister now.
(SCREAMING)
Thank you all for wearing
your ID cards.
They'll help to identify
the bodies.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Deadly to humans, maybe.
(ALIEN SHRIEKING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
Ah!
Jackie!
(ALIEN ROARS)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(ALIEN SCREECHES)
Oi, you want aliens,
you've got them.
They're inside Downing Street.
Come on.
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
Reinstate my disguise!
Hurry up, hurry! Hurry!
No, wait!
They're still in there,
the Emergency Protocols, we need them.
(SCREAMING)
(ALIEN ROARING)
Where've you been?
I called for help,
I sounded the alarm.
There was this lightning, a kind of
electricity, and they all collapsed.
I think they're all dead.
That's what I'm saying.
He did it! That man there!
I think you'll find
the Prime Minister is an alien in disguise.
That's never gonna work,
is it?
No.
Fair enough.
OFFICER: Down there!
Under the jurisdiction
of the Emergency Protocols,
I authorise you
to execute this man!
Well, now, yes, you see, uh,
the thing is,
if I was you, if I was gonna
execute someone
by backing him up
against the wall, between you and me,
-little word of advice,
-(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
don't stand him
against the Lift.
(ALIEN GROWLS)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(SNARLS)
Hello!
(SNARLING)
Hide!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
I repeat, the upper floors
are under quarantine.
You will stay where you are,
you will disregard all previous instructions,
and you will take your orders
directly from me.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Mr Green, sir, sorry,
but you've got to come with me.
We should evacuate
the entire building.
Sergeant, have you, um,
read the Emergency Protocols?
-No, sir.
-Then don't question me.
Seal off Number Ten,
secure the ground floor,
and if the Doctor
makes it downstairs, shoot on sight!
Well, you heard him! Move out!
Let the sport begin.
(JOSEPH FARTS)
I'm getting poisoned
by the gas exchange.
I need to be naked.
Rejoice in it.
Your body is magnificent.
ALIEN: (TRILLING)
Ooh, such fun.
Little human children,
where are you?
Sweet little human kins,
come to me.
Let me kiss you better.
Kiss you with
my big green lips.
(ALIEN HISSING)
(OFFICER SHOUTING)
Go and check it out!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
ASQUITH: It does
us good to hunt, it purifies the blood.
JOSEPH: We'll keep
this floor quarantined
as our last hiding ground
before the final phase.
ALIEN: My brothers.
Happy hunting?
It's wonderful.
The more you prolong it,
the more they stink.
ASQUITH: Sweat and fear!
JOSEPH: I can smell
an old girl.
Stale perfume
and brittle bones.
And a ripe youngster,
all hormones and adrenalin.
Fresh enough to bend
before she snaps.
-(SCREAMS)
-No!
Take me first, take me!
(ALIENS HISSING)
Out! With me!
(ALIEN ROARING)
Who the hell are you?
Harriet Jones,
MP for Flydale North.
-Nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
(ALIENS SCREECHING)
DOCTOR: We need to get to
the Cabinet Rooms.
The Emergency Protocols
are in there.
They give instructions
for aliens.
Harriet Jones, I like you.
I think I like you, too.
(ROARING)
One more move
and my sonic device will triplicate
the flammability
of this alcohol.
Woof, we all go up.
So back off.
Right, then, question time.
Who exactly are the Slitheen?
-They're aliens.
-Yes, I got that, thanks.
Who are you, if not human?
-Who's not human?
-He's not human.
-He's not human?
-Could I have a bit of hush?
-Sorry.
-So, what's the plan?
But he's got
a Northern accent.
Lots of planets have a north.
I said hush!
Come on!
You've got a spaceship
hidden in the North Sea.
It's transmitting a signal.
You've murdered your way
to the top of government. What for? Invasion?
Why would we invade
this godforsaken rock?
Then something's brought
the Slitheen race here. What is it?
The Slitheen race?
Slitheen is not our species.
(HISSING)
Slitheen is our surname.
Jocrassa Fel Fotch
Pasameer-Day Slitheen at your service.
So you're family?
A family business.
Then you're out
to make a profit.
How can you do that
on a godforsaken rock?
Uh, excuse me.
Your device will do what?
Triplicate the flammability?
-Is that what I said?
-You're making it up.
Oh, well. Nice try.
Harriet, have a drink.
I think you're gonna need it.
You pass it to the left first.
-Sorry.
-Thanks.
Now we can end this hunt
with a slaughter.
Don't you think we should run?
DOCTOR: Fascinating history,
Downing Street.
2,000 years ago,
this was marshland.
1730, it was occupied
by a Mr Chicken. He was a nice man.
1796, this was
the Cabinet Room.
If the Cabinet's in session
and in danger,
these are about the four most safest
walls in the whole of Great Britain.
End of lesson.
(METAL SCREECHING)
Installed in 1991.
Three inches of steel lining every single wall.
They'll never get in.
And how do we get out?
Ah.
He's safely contained.
Now cut off communications
inside that room, then summon up the family!
It's time we finished with
this insane planet for good!
(SIRENS WAILING)
And there's still no word from
inside Downing Street,
though we are getting
even more new arrivals.
That's Group Captain
Tennant James of the RAF,
though why he's been
summoned we've no idea.
And that's Ewan McAllister,
Deputy Secretary for
the Scottish Parliament.
And this is most unusual.
I'm told that is
Sylvia Dillane,
chairman of the
North Sea Boating Club.
Quite what connects
all these people, we have no idea.
Group Captain.
Delighted you could make it.
We're meeting upstairs.
-(FARTS)
-That's the spirit, off you go.
Good to see you.
Come on through.
Ah, Sergeant, now that
the Doctor's been neutralised,
the upper levels
are out of bounds to everyone.
Then who are they?
Need to know, Sergeant,
need to know.
I want you to liaise
with Communications.
The Acting Prime Minister
will be making a public address.
He will speak to
the nations of the world!
There you are. If you'd just like
to go through and get changed.
Now, if you'd like
to head down to the end of the corridor,
it's first on the left.
Thank you.
-Got anything stronger?
-No chance.
I've seen you
when you've had a few.
This ain't time for a conga!
We've got to tell someone!
Who do we trust?
For all we know,
they've all got big bog monsters inside of 'em.
I mean,
this is what he does, Jacks, that Doctor bloke.
Everywhere he goes,
death and destruction.
And he's got Rose
in the middle of it.
Has he got a great big
green thing inside him, then?
I wouldn't put it past him.
But like it or not,
he's the only person
who knows
how to fight these things.
I thought I was gonna die.
(SOBBING)
Come on, yeah?
If anyone's gonna cry, it's gonna be me.
Now, you're safe
in my flat, Jacks.
No one's gonna
look for you here,
especially since
you hate me so much.
You saved my life!
God, that's embarrassing!
Telling me!
(LIGHTLY CHUCKLES)
He wanted me dead.
And he's still out there,
Mickey.
That policeman, that thing!
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
(SNIFFS)
Right, you head off.
Inform Control I've one or two
things that still need doing.
I haven't quite finished
with Mrs Tyler yet.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Is that all of us?
All the family
except Sip Fel Fotch.
He's found a hunt of his own.
Ah. (CHUCKLES)
What was his name?
-Who?
-This one.
The, uh, secretary,
or whatever he was called.
I don't know. I talked to him.
I brought him a cup of coffee.
I never asked his name.
Sorry.
Right, what have we got?
Any terminals, anything?
Nope, this place is antique.
What I don't get is,
when they killed the Prime Minister,
why didn't they use him
as a disguise?
He's too slim.
They're big old beasts.
They need to fit
inside big humans.
But the Slitheen
are about eight feet.
How do they squeeze inside?
That's the device
around their necks, compression field,
literally shrinks them
down a bit.
That's why
there's all that gas. It's a big exchange.
Wish I had
a compression field, I could fit a size smaller.
Excuse me, people are dead!
This is not the time for making jokes.
Sorry. You get used to this
stuff when you're friends with him.
Well, that's
a strange friendship.
Harriet Jones.
I've heard that name before. Harriet Jones.
You're not famous
for anything, are you?
Oh! Hardly!
Rings a bell. Harriet Jones...
HARRIET: Lifelong backbencher,
I'm afraid,
and a fat lot of use
I'm being now.
The Protocols are redundant.
They list the people who could help
and they're all dead downstairs.
Hasn't it got, like,
defence codes and things?
Couldn't we just
launch a nuclear bomb at them?
You're a very
violent young woman.
I'm serious, we could!
Well, there's nothing
like that in here.
Nuclear strikes do need
a release code, yes,
but it's kept secret
by the United Nations.
Say that again.
-What, about the codes?
-Anything, all of it.
Um, well, the British Isles
can't gain access to atomic weapons
without a special resolution
from the UN.
Like that's ever stopped them!
Exactly,
given our past record.
And I voted against that,
thank you very much.
The codes have been taken out of the
government's hands and given to the UN.
-Is it important?
-Everything's important.
If we only knew
what the Slitheen wanted.
Listen to me,
I'm saying Slitheen as if it's normal.
What do they want, though?
Well, they're just one family,
so it's not an invasion.
They don't want
Slitheen World.
They're out to make money.
That means they want to use something,
something here on Earth,
some kind of asset.
Like what? Gold? Oil? Water?
You're very good at this.
Thank you.
Harriet Jones,
why do I know that name?
-(CELLPHONE BEEPS)
-Oh, that's me.
But we're sealed off.
How did you get a signal?
He zapped it. Super phone.
Then we can phone for help.
You must have contacts!
Dead downstairs, yeah.
It's Mickey.
Oh, tell your stupid boyfriend
we're busy.
Yeah, he's not so stupid
after all.
No, no, not just alien,
but like, proper alien,
all stinking and wet
and disgusting,
and more to the point,
it wanted to kill us!
I could have died!
Is she all right though?
Don't put her on, just tell me.
Is that Ricky? Don't talk.
Just shut up and go to your computer.
It's Mickey, and why should I?
Mickey the idiot, I might just choke before I
finish this sentence, but I need you.
It says "password".
-Say again.
-It's asking for the password.
Buffalo. Two Fs, one I.
So what's that website?
All the secret information
known to mankind.
See, they've known
about aliens for years.
They just kept us in the dark.
Mickey, you were born
in the dark.
-ROSE: Oh, leave him alone.
-Thank you.
-Password again.
-Just repeat it, every time.
Big Ben. Why did the Slitheen
go and hit Big Ben?
You said to gather
the experts, to kill them.
That lot would have gathered
for a weather balloon.
You don't need
to crash-land it in the middle of London.
The Slitheen are hiding, but then they put the
entire planet on red alert.
What did they do that for?
Oh, listen to her!
Oi! At least I'm trying.
Well, I've got a question,
if you don't mind.
Since that man
walked into our lives,
I've been attacked
in the streets,
I've had creatures
from the pits of hell in my own living room,
and my daughter disappear
off the face of the Earth.
I told you what happened.
I'm talking to him!
'Cause I've seen
this life of yours, Doctor,
and maybe you get off on it,
and maybe you think
it's all clever and smart,
but you tell me,
just answer me this,
is my daughter safe?
I'm fine.
Is she safe?
Will she always be safe,
can you promise me that?
Well what's the answer?
We're in.
Now, then.
On the left, at the top,
there's a tab, an icon,
little concentric circles, click on that.
MICKEY: What is it?
The Slitheen have got
a spaceship in the North Sea
and it's transmitting
that signal.
Now, hush, let me work out
what it's saying.
He'll have to answer me
one day.
-Hush!
-It's some sort of message.
-What's it say?
-Don't know,
it's on a loop,
keeps repeating.
-(BUZZING)
-Hush!
That's not me.
Go and see who that is.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Well, go and tell them that.
(DOORBELL CONTINUES BUZZING)
It's beaming out into space.
who's it for?
-(DOORBELL BUZZES)
-All right!
Mrs Tyler.
Ooh!
It's him, it's the thing!
It's the Slickeen!
They've found us!
Mickey, I need that signal.
Never mind the signal.
Get out! Mum, just get out! Get out!
We can't,
it's by the front door.
(ALIEN SCREECHES)
Oh, my God.
It's unmasking. It's gonna kill us.
There's got to be some way
of stopping them!
You're supposed
to be the expert. Think of something!
I'm trying!
(ALIEN GROWLING)
I'll take it on, Jackie.
You just run.
Don't look back. Just run.
(CLATTERS AND THUDS)
That's my mother.
Right. If we're gonna
find their weakness,
we need to find out
where they're from, which planet.
So, judging by
their basic shape,
that narrows it down
to 5,000 planets within travelling distance.
What else do we know
about them? Information!
-They're green.
-Yep, narrows it down.
-Good sense of smell.
-Narrows it down.
-They can smell adrenalin.
-The pig technology.
-Narrows it down.
Spaceship in the Thames.
You said "slipstream engine."
Narrows it down.
(ALIEN SCREECHES)
It's getting in!
-They hunt like it's a ritual.
-Narrows it down.
Wait a minute. Did you notice,
when they fart,
if you'll pardon the word,
it doesn't just
smell like a fart,
if you'll pardon the word.
It's something else.
What is it?
It's more like, um...
-Bad breath.
-That's it!
Calcium decay!
Now, that narrows it down.
We're getting there, Mum!
-Too late!
-(ALIEN ROARING)
Calcium phosphate.
Organic calcium. Living calcium.
Creatures made out
of living calcium. What else? What else?
Hyphenated surname! Yes!
That narrows it down
to one planet!
Raxacoricofallapatorius!
Oh, yeah, great,
we can write 'em a letter!
Get into the kitchen!
Oh, my God,
it's going to rip us apart!
Calcium weakened by the compression
field. Acetic acid! Vinegar!
-Just like Hannibal!
-Just like Hannibal.
Mickey, have you
got any vinegar?
-How should I know?
-It's your kitchen!
Cupboard by the sink,
middle shelf!
Oh, come on, give it here.
What do you need?
DOCTOR: Anything with vinegar.
Gherkins!
(ALIEN ROARS)
Yeah, pickled onions!
Pickled eggs!
You kiss this man?
(SCREECHING)
(HISSING)
(FARTING)
(ALL SIGH)
Hannibal?
Hannibal crossed the Alps
by dissolving boulders with vinegar.
Oh.
Well, there you go, then.
Whew!
He's dead. Sip Fel Fotch
Pasameer-Day Slitheen is dead.
I felt it.
How could that happen?
Somebody must've got lucky.
That's the last piece of luck
anyone on this rock will ever have.
(REPORTERS CLAMOURING)
Ladies and gentlemen...
Nations of the world.
Humankind.
The greatest experts
in extraterrestrial events came here tonight.
They gathered
in the common cause.
But the news
I bring you now is grave indeed.
The experts are dead.
Murdered,
right in front of me, by alien hands.
Peoples of the Earth,
heed my words.
These "visitors”
do not come in peace.
Listen to this!
Our inspectors have searched
the sky above our heads.
And they have found
massive weapons of destruction
capable of being deployed
within 45 seconds.
What?
Our technicians can baffle
the alien probes,
but not for long.
We are facing extinction
unless we strike first!
The United Kingdom stands directly
beneath the belly of the mothers hip.
I beg of the United Nations.
Pass an emergency resolution.
Give us the access codes.
A nuclear strike at the heart of the beast
is our only chance of survival,
because, from this moment on,
it is my solemn duty
to inform you
planet Earth is at war.
He's just making it up.
There's no weapons up there.
There's no threat.
He just invented it.
-Do you think they'll believe him?
-Well, he did last time.
That's why the Slitheen
went for spectacle.
They want
the whole world panicking
'cause you lot,
you get scared, you lash out.
They release
the defence codes...
And the Slitheen go nuclear.
But why?
You get the codes,
release the missiles.
But not into space,
'cause there's nothing there.
You attack every other country on
Earth, they retaliate, fight back.
World War Three.
Whole planet gets nuked.
And we sit through it,
safe in our spaceship waiting in the Thames.
Not crashed, just parked.
Barely two minutes away.
But you'll destroy the planet.
This beautiful place. What for?
Profit.
That's what the signal is,
beaming into space. An advert.
Sale of the century. We reduce the
Earth to molten slag, then sell it.
Piece by piece.
Radioactive chunks
capable of powering every cut-price
star liner and budget cargo ship.
There's a recession
out there, Doctor. People are buying cheap.
This rock becomes raw fuel.
At the cost
of five billion lives.
Hmm! Bargain.
I give you a choice.
Leave this planet, or I'll stop you.
(GIGGLING)
What? You?
Trapped in your box?
Yes. Me.
(LAUGHING)
Yesterday saw the start
of a brave new world.
Today might see it end.
The streets are deserted.
Everyone's home, just waiting,
as the future is decided
in New York.
AMERICAN REPORTER:
It's midnight here in New York.
The United Nations
has gathered.
England has provided them
with absolute proof
that the massive weapons
of destruction do exist.
The Security Council will be making a
resolution in a matter of minutes.
And once the codes
are released,
humanity's first
interplanetary war begins.
(SNIFFLES)
Sergeant!
We'll take the call in
the Prime Minister's office.
Maintain your positions.
And good luck.
(EXCITED BUSTLE)
Look at that!
The telephone is actually red!
(FARTING)
Oh.
How long till they phone?
Counting down...
All right, Doctor.
I'm not saying I trust you,
but there must be something you can do.
If we could ferment the port,
we could make acetic acid.
Mickey, any luck?
MICKEY: There's loads
of emergency numbers.
-They're all on voicemail.
-(ROSE SIGHS)
Voicemail dooms us all.
-ROSE: If we could just get out of here.
-There's a way out.
What?
There's always been a way out.
Then why don't we use it?
Because I can't guarantee
your daughter will be safe.
Don't you dare!
Whatever it is, don't you dare!
That's the thing.
If I don't dare, everyone dies.
Do it.
You don't even know
what it is. You'd just let me?
Yeah.
Please, Doctor, please!
She's my daughter, she's just a kid.
Do you think
I don't know that?
'Cause this is my life,
Jackie. It's not fun, it's not smart.
It's standing up and making a
decision because nobody else will.
Then what are you waiting for?
I could save the world,
but lose you.
Except it's not
your decision, Doctor.
It's mine.
And who the hell are you?
Harriet Jones,
MP for Flydale North.
The only elected
representative in this room,
chosen by the people
for the people.
And on behalf of the people,
I command you.
Do it.
Victory should be naked!
How do we get out?
We don't. We stay here.
The Council is voting.
The result should be known any second now.
(GROWLING)
Use the "buffalo” password,
it overrides everything.
What are you doing?
Hacking into the Royal Navy.
We're in!
Here it is, uh, HMS Taurean,
Trafalgar Class submarine,
10 miles off the coast
of Plymouth.
DOCTOR: Right,
we need to select a missile.
We can't go nuclear.
We don't have the defence codes.
We don't need it.
All we need is an ordinary missile.
What's the first category?
Sub harpoon, UGM-84A.
That's the one! Select!
I could stop you.
Do it, then.
DOCTOR: You ready for this?
Yeah.
Mickey the idiot,
the world is in your hands.
Fire.
(WHOOSHING)
Oh, my God.
(STEADY BEEPING)
How solid are these?
Not solid enough.
Built for short-range attack.
Nothing this big.
All right.
Now I'm making the decision.
I'm not gonna die.
We're gonna ride this one out.
It's like what
they say about earthquakes.
You can survive them
by standing under a door frame.
Now, this cupboard's small,
so it's strong.
Come and help me.
Come on!
The vote is in.
The Council says...
Yes.
They are releasing the codes.
Ring, damn you!
-(RAPID BEEPING)
-It's on radar!
MICKEY:
Counter defence 556.
Stop them intercepting it!
-I'm doing it now!
-Good boy.
556 neutralised.
What do you mean, "incoming"?
-(ALARM SHRIEKS)
-Everybody out! Now! Now!
What the hell is that for?
Sir, there's a missile...
Sorry!
That's mine. You've got mine!
Disguise me, disguise me!
No, you're the blonde.
No, I've got the other one. Take it off!
-(GUNSHOT)
-Everybody, run!
MAN: Run!
Let's get out of here!
(MISSILE SCREECHES)
Here we go.
Well, nice knowing you both.
Hannibal!
Oh, bol...
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTING)
Made in Britain!
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
Harriet Jones,
MP, Flydale North.
I want you to contact
the UN immediately.
Tell the ambassadors
the crisis is over. They can step down.
-Go on. Tell the news.
-Yes, ma'am.
Someone's got a hell
of a job sorting this lot out.
Oh, Lord! We haven't even got
a Prime Minister!
-Maybe you should have a go.
-Me! I'm only a backbencher.
I'd vote for ya.
Now, don't be silly.
Look, I'd better go
and see if I can help.
-(EMERGENCY SIRENS APPROACH)
-Hang on!
We're safe.
The Earth is safe!
Sergeant!
I thought I knew the name.
Harriet Jones.
-(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
-Future Prime Minister.
Elected for three
successive terms.
The architect
of Britain's Golden Age.
The crisis has passed!
Ladies and gentlemen, I have something to
say to you all here today...
Mankind stands tall,
proud and undefeated!
God bless the human race.
(TARDIS CLANKS AND WHEEZES)
HARRIET ON TV:
Mankind stands tall...
Harriet Jones.
Who does she think she is?
Look at her,
taking all the credit. It should be you on there.
My daughter saved the world!
I think the Doctor
helped a bit.
All right, then.
Him, too.
You should
be given knighthoods.
It's not the way
he does things.
No fuss, he just moves on.
He's not that bad,
if you gave him a chance.
He's good in a crisis,
I'll give him that.
Oh! Now, the world has changed. You're
saying nice things about him.
I reckon I've got no choice.
There's no getting rid of him
since you're infatuated.
I'm not infatuated!
What does he eat?
How do you mean?
I was gonna do shepherd's pie.
All of us, proper sit-down.
'Cause... (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm ready to listen.
I want to learn
about you and him and that life you lead.
I mean, I didn't know
he was an alien.
For all I know, he eats grass
and safety pins, and things.
He'll have shepherd's pie.
You're gonna cook for him?
What's wrong with that?
He's finally met his match.
-You're not too old for a slap, you know!
-(GIGGLES)
You can go and visit
your gran tomorrow...
-(MOBILE RINGING)
-...and learn some French.
I told her you were in France.
I said you were au-pairing.
Hello?
Right, I'll be
a couple of hours, then we can go.
You've got a phone!
You think I can travel through space and
time and I haven't got a phone?
Huh! Like I said,
couple of hours.
I've just got
to send out this dispersal.
There you go.
That's cancelling out
the Slitheen's advert
in case any bargain hunters
turn up.
Um, my mother's cooking.
Good. Put her on a slow heat
and let her simmer.
She's cooking tea. For us.
I don't do that.
She wants to get to know you.
Tough.
I've got better things to do.
It's just tea.
Not to me, it isn't.
She's my mother.
-Well, she's not mine.
-That's not fair!
Well, you can stay there
if you want.
But right now, there's this plasma storm
brewing in the Horsehead Nebula.
Fires are burning,
10 million miles wide.
I could fly the Tardis
right into the heart of it
then ride the shock wave
all the way out.
Hurtle right across the sky
and end up anywhere.
Your choice.
(DISCONNECTS)
Rose, I was thinking...
I've got that
bottle of Amaretto from New Year's Eve.
Does he drink?
I was wondering
whether he drinks or not.
Yeah, he does.
Don't go, sweetheart.
Please don't go.
Good lad.
Graffiti that again
and I'll have ya. Now, beat it.
I just went down the shop.
And I was thinking,
you know, like, the whole world's changed.
Aliens and spaceships
all in public.
And here it is.
How can they do that?
They saw it!
You're just not ready. You're happy to
believe in something that's invisible,
but if it's staring you
in the face, "Nope, can't see it!"
There's a scientific
explanation for that. You're thick.
(CHUCKLES)
-We're just idiots.
-Well, not all of you.
Yeah?
Present for you, Mickey.
That's a virus. Put it online,
and it'll destroy
every mention of me.
I'll cease to exist.
-What do you want to do that for?
-'Cause you're right.
I am dangerous.
I don't want anybody following me.
How can you say that,
and then take her with you?
You could look after her.
Come with us.
I can't.
This life of yours...
It's just too much.
I couldn't do it.
Don't tell her I said that.
I'll get a proper job.
I'll work weekends, I'll pass my test.
And if Jim comes round again,
I'll say no.
-I really will.
-I'm not leaving 'cause of you.
I'm travelling, that's all,
and then I'll come back.
But it's not safe.
Mum. If you saw it out there,
you'd never stay home.
Got enough stuff?
The first time
I stepped in there, it was spur-of-the-moment.
Now I'm signing up.
You're stuck with me. (LAUGHS)
Come with us.
There's plenty of room.
No chance. He's a liability,
I'm not having him on board.
We'd be dead without him.
My decision is final.
Sorry.
Good luck, yeah?
You still can't promise me.
What if she gets lost?
What if something
happens to you, Doctor, and she's left
all alone, standing on some
moon a million light years away?
How long do I wait, then?
Mum, you're forgetting.
It's a time machine.
I could go travelling
around suns and planets
and all the way
out to the edge of the universe,
and by the time
we get back, yeah,
10 seconds would have passed.
Just 10 seconds.
So stop worrying.
I'll see you
in 10 seconds' time, yeah?
(WHIRRING)
Ten seconds.
ROSE: It's a great, big museum.
DOCTOR: An alien museum.
Someone's got a hobby.
The cage contains
my one living specimen.
It must've fallen
through time. The only survivor.
It's killing him.
Do something!
I swear, no one
on this base is safe.
You've got to keep it
in that cell.
It can't get out.
That lock's got a billion combinations...
Civilians! Let 'em through!
That thing downstairs
is gonna kill every last one of us!
-Where's the nearest town?
-Salt Lake City.
-Population?
-One million.
All dead.
If you want orders,
follow this one.
Why don't you just die?
We're nearly there!
Give us two seconds.
I've come to help.
I'm The Doctor.
Exterminate!
-Impossible.
-Exterminate!