(MACHINERY CLICKING)
Listen!
Question.
Why do we talk out loud when we know
we're alone?
Conjecture.
Because we know we're not.
Evolution perfects survival skills.
There are perfect hunters.
(ROARING)
There is perfect defence.
Question.
Why is there no such thing
as perfect hiding?
Answer. How would you know?
Logically, if evolution
were to perfect a creature
whose primary skill
were to hide from view,
how could you know it existed?
It could be with us every second
and we would never know.
How would you detect it,
even sense it...
...except in those moments
when, for no clear reason,
you choose to speak aloud?
What would such a creature want?
What would it do?
Well?
(LOUDLY) What would you do? (ECHOES)
(LAUGHS)
(CHALK ROLLS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(EXHALES)
(INDISTINCT TALKING AND LAUGHTER)
-Hey.
Sorry.
So the famous drink at last.
Yeah. Took a bit of time,
family stuff, but here we are.
Dinner, in fact.
Yeah, straight to dinner.
I like a man who moves fast.
Yeah? I might go straight for extras.
Afters. Dessert.
-Yes, I know, I know, dessert. Gotcha.
-Straight to dessert.
So, um... How was your day?
Good. You know...
Teaching.
-Yep, teaching.
-Teaching, teaching.
Totally teaching.
-We probably shouldn't talk about work.
-God, yeah!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Though, do you take Courtney
for anything?
Are you serious?
She said she couldn't
concentrate on her work
because my face was too wide.
-Wide?
-I could kill that girl some days.
-Me, too.
-And from you, that means something.
Sorry?
I dug 23 wells.
-I'm sorry?
-Twenty-three wells.
When I was a soldier. Twenty-three!
-Okay. Good. Good wells.
-Yeah, they were good, actually.
I'm not doubting
the quality of your wells.
Whole villages saved.
Actual towns full of people.
People I didn't shoot.
People I kept safe!
-Okay. Point taken. Seriously.
-So why doesn't that ever get mentioned?
I'm sorry I didn't mention
your 23 wells!
-WAITER: Excuse me.
-Sorry.
WAITER: Uh, water for the table?
Don't you worry,
he'll probably dig for it!
(LAUGHS)
Sorry.
It's okay.
-Sensitive subject.
-Yes. Can slightly see that.
Sometimes people like you
get the wrong end of the stick.
People like me?
I wasn't making assumptions about you.
That really is exactly
what you were doing.
You were making assumptions about me!
-I made a joke.
-A not-funny joke.
Yeah, well, do you know
what I'm making now?
-A fuss?
-An exit.
(SIGHS)
-You'll just have to squeeze through.
-Doctor?
Why do you have three mirrors?
Why don't you just turn your head?
-What are you doing in here?
-You said you had a date.
I thought I'd better hide in the bedroom
in case you brought him home.
Bit early, aren't you?
Did it all go wrong?
Or is this good by your standards?
It was a disaster and I'm extremely
upset about it, since you didn't ask.
Fine! I need you, for a thing.
I can't.
Oh, of course you can.
Come on, you're free.
More than usually free, in fact.
No, it's just possible
that I might get a phone call.
From the date guy?
It's too late.
You've taken your make-up off.
No, I haven't.
I'm still wearing my make-up.
Oh, well, okay,
well, you probably just missed a bit.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
I haven't actually said yes.
Yes, you know,
sometimes when you talk to yourself,
-what if you're not?
-Not what?
What if it's not you you're talking to?
Proposition. What if no one
is ever really alone?
What if every single living being
has a companion,
a silent passenger, a shadow?
What if the prickle
on the back of your neck
is the breath of something
close behind you?
How long have you been travelling alone?
Perhaps I never have.
It looks like your handwriting.
Well, I couldn't have written it
and forgotten, could I?
(CHUCKLES) Have you met you?
What's all this?
Dreams. Accounts of dreams by
different people, all through history.
-You see, I have a theory.
-I'll bet you have. What theory?
I think everybody,
at some point in their lives,
has the exact same nightmare.
You wake up, or you think you do,
and there's someone in the dark,
someone close,
or you think there might be.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
So you sit up and turn on the light.
And the room looks different at night.
It ticks and creaks and breathes.
And you tell yourself
there's nobody there,
nobody watching, nobody listening,
nobody there at all.
And you very nearly believe it.
You really, really try.
And then...
(HISSING)
(GASPING)
There are accounts of that dream
throughout human history,
time and time again, the same dream.
Now, there is a very obvious
question I'm about to ask you.
-Do you know what it is?
-Have you had that dream?
Exactly.
No, that was me asking you,
have you had that dream?
-I asked first.
-No, I did.
You really didn't.
Okay, yeah, probably. Yes.
But everybody dreams about
something under the bed.
Why?
Just hold on tight.
If anything bites, let it.
-What is it?
-Tardis telepathic interface.
You're now in mental contact
with the Tardis.
-So don't think anything rude.
-Why not?
It might end up on all of the screens.
The Tardis is extrapolating
your entire timeline,
from the moment of your birth
to the moment of your death.
Which I do not need a preview of.
I'm turning off the safeguards
and navigation,
slaving the Tardis to you.
Focus on the dream,
focus on the details,
picture them, feel them.
The Tardis will track on
your subconscious
and extract the relevant information.
It should be able to home in
on the moment in your timeline
when you first had that dream.
And then, we'll see.
What will we see?
What's under your bed.
Ooh!
(METALLIC HUMMING)
Okay, now, don't get distracted.
Remember, you are flying a time machine.
(METALLIC HUMMING CONTINUES)
-(MOBILE RINGING)
-(GASPS)
No, no. Don't you get...
No, don't. Don't, don't.
Just ignore it.
(MOBILE CLATTERS, STOPS RINGING)
Okay, that's good.
That worked, we're here.
Sorry, I think I got distracted.
No, no, no, no, no. The date's fine.
-Come on!
-Come on where?
Your childhood.
(GRUNTS)
The West Country Children's Home.
Gloucester. By the ozone level
and the drains, mid-'90s.
You must have been here
when you had the dream.
Never been to Gloucester in my life
and I've never lived
in a children's home.
You've probably just forgotten.
Have you seen the size of human
brains? They're hilarious.
Little you must be in here somewhere,
with your little brain.
Isn't it bad if I meet myself?
It is potentially catastrophic.
So why did you bring me out here?
I was still talking,
I needed someone to nod,
probably best for you to wait
in the Tardis.
Doctor...
See you in a minute. Tardis.
Doctor!
If I had have been distracted,
what would have happened?
We would probably have ended up
in the wrong place.
But don't think we have,
because the time zone's right.
I won't be long.
BOY: What are you doing down there?
Nothing.
Uh... I'm just...
What's your name?
-Rupert.
-Oh. Okay.
Hello, Rupert.
Rupert Pink. It's a stupid name.
No, it isn't.
I know somebody called Pink.
I meant Rupert. I'm going to change it.
Why are you awake?
Are you scared?
(HUMMING)
(TV PLAYING, MUFFLED)
(DOOR OPENS)
MAN: How did you get in?
Your door must be faulty.
An inspection?
-It's 2:00 in the morning.
-When better?
Do you always work here nights?
Most nights, yes.
Ever end up talking to yourself?
All the time. It's this place.
You can't help it.
What about your coffee?
My coffee?
Sometimes do you put it down
and look round
and it's not there?
-Everybody does that.
-Yes.
Everybody.
(TV TURNS OFF)
Who turned your telly off?
It does that. It...
just goes off.
Hmm.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Hello.
Nice room.
You know, you should have
more than one chair.
What do you do when people come round?
RUPERT: Sit on the bed.
CLARA: Why aren't you
sitting on it, then?
Do you think that there's
something underneath it?
Hey.
Everyone thinks that sometimes.
-That's just how people think at night.
-Why?
Did you have a dream,
a hand grabbing your foot?
You have, haven't you?
You've had that exact dream.
How did you know?
Do you know why dreams
are called dreams?
-Why?
-Because they're not real.
If they were, they wouldn't need a name.
What are you doing?
-Do you know what's under there?
-What?
Me!
Come on! It's perfectly safe.
See?
Nobody here. Except us.
Sometimes I hear noises.
It's a house full of people,
of course you hear noises.
-They're all asleep.
-They're all dreaming.
Can you hear dreams?
If you're clever enough,
but they can't harm you.
You know, sometimes we think
there's something behind us
and the space under your bed is
what's behind you at night.
Simple as that.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
(BED CREAKS)
(RUPERT BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(WHISPERS) Who else is in this room?
-Nobody.
-Someone must have come in.
-Nobody came in.
CLARA: Hello?
Who's this?
This is a friend of yours
playing a game.
Playing a trick, are you, hey,
a little trick on Rupert here?
(BED CREAKING)
Okay. It's not funny this, you know.
Where is he?
Doctor?
DOCTOR: I can't find him.
Can you find him?
CLARA: Find who?
DOCTOR: Wally.
-Wally?
-He's nowhere in this book.
RUPERT: It's not a Where's Wally? one.
Well, how would you know? Maybe you
just haven't found him yet.
-He's not in every book.
-Really?
Well, that's a few years of my life
I'll be needing back.
Are you scared?
The thing on the bed, whatever it is,
look at it. Does it scare you?
-Yes.
-Well, that's good.
Want to know why that's good?
-Why?
-Let me tell you about scared.
(HEART BEATING)
Your heart is beating so hard
I can feel it through your hands.
There's so much blood and oxygen
pumping through your brain,
it's like rocket fuel.
Right now, you could run faster
and you could fight harder,
you could jump higher
than ever in your life,
and you are so alert
it's like you can slow down time.
What's wrong with scared?
Scared is a superpower.
It's your superpower.
There is danger in this room
and guess what? It's you.
Do you feel it?
Do you think he feels it?
Do you think he's scared?
Nah!
Loser! Turn your back on him.
-What?
-Yeah, turn your back on him, come on.
You too, Clara.
Clara, your back, now.
Do it, just do it now, turn your back.
Do it now, turn your back.
Lovely view out this window.
CLARA: Yeah. Come and see all the dark.
DOCTOR: The deep and lovely dark.
We'd never see the stars without it.
Now, there are two possibilities.
Possibility one, it's just
one of your friends standing there
and he's playing a joke on you.
Possibility two, it isn't.
So, plan? Plans are good.
DOCTOR: You on the bed,
I'm talking to you now.
Go in peace.
We won't look.
Just go.
If all you want to do is stay
hidden, it's okay. Just leave.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Is it gone?
Don't look round, not yet.
-I can't hear anything.
-DOCTOR: Don't look round.
Look away! Look away now!
Don't look at it! Don't look round.
Don't look round.
Don't look at the reflection.
What is it?
DOCTOR: Imagine a thing
that must never be seen.
-What would it do if you saw it?
-I don't know.
-Neither do I. Close your eyes.
-RUPERT: What?
Close your eyes. You, too, Clara.
Give it what it wants.
Prove to it
that you're not going to look at it.
Make a promise. Promise
you're never going to look at it.
I promise never to look.
DOCTOR: The breath on the back
of your neck,
like your hairs standing on end,
that means don't look round.
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
Gone.
He took my bedspread.
Oh, the human race.
You're never happy, are you?
-Am I safe now?
-DOCTOR: Nobody's safe,
especially not at night,
in the dark. Anything can get you,
you're all the way up here,
you're all alone.
-What was that for?
-Shut up, leave this to me.
-These yours?
-RUPERT: They're the home's.
-They're yours now.
-People don't need to be lied to.
People don't need to be scared
by a big grey-haired stick insect
but here you are. Stay still, shut up.
See what I'm doing?
This is your army.
-Plastic army.
-Sit!
And they're going to guard
under your bed.
See this one? This one's the boss one,
the colonel. He's going to
keep a special eye out.
It's broken, that one.
It doesn't have a gun.
CLARA: That's why he's the boss.
A soldier so brave
he doesn't need a gun.
He can keep the whole world safe.
-What shall we call him?
-Dan.
Sorry?
Dan, the soldier man.
That's what I call him.
Good. Good name.
Yeah.
Would you read me a story?
It'll help me get to sleep.
Sure.
DOCTOR: Once upon a time,
the end.
Dad skills.
So...is it possible
that we just saved that kid
from another kid in a bedspread?
DOCTOR: Entirely possible, yes.
The bigger question is why did
we end up with him and not you?
I got distracted.
But why that particular boy?
You don't have any...
You don't have any kind of connection
with him, do you?
No. No, no, no, of course not.
Why do you ask?
The Tardis was slaved to your timeline.
Theoretically, there should have
been some connection.
Will, um...
Will he remember any of that?
Scrambled his memory,
gave him a big old dream
about being Dan the soldier man.
(SIGHS)
(CLARA WHIMPERS)
Are you okay?
Doctor...
I am sorry to ask and, you know,
I realise this is probably
against the laws of time
or summat, um...
Could you do me a favour?
Is that what I look like from the back?
DOCTOR: It's fine.
CLARA: I was thinking it was good.
Really?
CLARA: Sorry.
Hey.
Hello. I'm Clara Oswald.
I'm a bit tricky sometimes, a bit up
myself and I do not like my surname
but I think that is basically
everything you need to worry about.
Hello, I'm... I'm sorry...
Also, I mouth off when I'm nervous
and I've got a mouth on me.
Seriously, it's got a mind of its
own. I'm worried it wants to go solo.
-I don't know what to say.
-Don't say anything.
Or say something nice.
I like your name.
It's a start.
Oswald. It suits you.
-Drifting now.
-It's better than Pink.
No, Pink... Pink is nice. I like pink.
-You can have it.
-Oh, a bold offer, Mr Pink.
I meant... No... (STAMMERS)
I know, I know.
Why can't I speak today?
It's that foot you're keeping
in your mouth.
Is that where I put it?
Anyway. Clara Pink, too much.
Yeah, it is a bit much.
Mind you, Rupert Pink!
Sorry?
Uh...
(CHUCKLES)
Rupert...Pink. It's not good.
Rupert?
Yeah. That was your name, yeah?
-Who told you that?
-Um, someone in the school.
No, I haven't used that name for years.
I cannot remember who it was...
-Are you making fun of me?
-No! No, no, no. No way!
Is this a joke?
Danny, nothing about this
is any kind of joke!
(DOOR CREAKS)
Where's your coat?
-(EXHALES) My what?
-You put your coat on when you left.
Uh, I'm really sorry. Danny, um,
there is something that I should
probably be honest about.
-How about everything?
-Everything in my case
is actually quite a lot.
-Well, that's weird.
-No, no, it's not weird, not really...
Where are you going?
-I don't do weird.
-Don't go.
Then do something for me.
Tell me the truth, because I know
when people are lying to me.
However weird this thing may be,
just tell me the truth!
It's not weird...
exactly.
I've had enough.
(EXHALES)
I am trying to have a date,
a real-life, inter-human actual date!
It's a normal, nice, everyday,
meeting-up sort of thing.
And I would just like to know,
is there any other way
you can make this any more surreal
than it already is?
Hello.
DOCTOR: Ah, Clara!
Well done, you found her.
Now, this is really a bit strange.
Danny?
What's gone wrong with your face?
It's all eyes!
Why are you all eyes?
Get them under control.
-Uh, who's Danny?
-This is Colonel Orson Pink,
from about a hundred years
into your future.
(CHUCKLES) Orson Pink?
Yeah, I laughed, too. Sorry.
-Do you have any connection with him?
-Connection?
Yes, maybe you're like a distant
relative or something?
(STAMMERS) How would I know?
Right, okay.
Um, well, do you have any
old family photographs of her?
You know, probably quite old
and really fat-looking?
I don't.
How did you find him?
Well, you left a trace in the Tardis
telepathic circuits.
I fired them up again and the Tardis
brought me straight to him.
So he is something to do
with your timeline.
Okay...
And you will never guess
where I found him.
Where are we?
DOCTOR: The end of the road.
This is it, the end of everything.
The last planet.
The end of the universe?
The Tardis isn't supposed
to come this far
but some idiot
turned the safeguards off.
Listen!
To what?
Nothing.
There's nothing to hear.
There's nothing anywhere,
not a breath,
not a slither, not a click or a tick.
All the clocks have stopped.
This is the silence at the end of time.
(CLATTERING)
Then how did he get here?
If he's 100 years in my future...
Pioneer time traveller.
(HUMMING)
Rode the first of the great time shots.
They were supposed to fire him
into the middle of next week.
-What happened?
-He went a bit far.
-A bit?
-A big bit.
Look at him now. Robinson Crusoe
at the end of time itself,
the last man standing in the universe.
I always thought that would be me.
It's not a competition.
I know it's not a competition,
course it isn't.
Still time, though.
CLARA: He looks like he's packing.
He's been stranded for six months,
just met a time traveller.
Of course he's packing.
You can do it, then?
You can get me home?
I just showed you, didn't I?
A test flight to a restaurant.
Yes, but to my family, to my own time?
-Easy! I can do that, can't I, Clara?
-He can, yes.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, fine. I'm fine.
-Do I know you?
-No, nope.
Is she doing the all-eyes thing?
It's because her face is so wide.
She needs three mirrors!
Doctor!
We can't leave immediately, though.
The Tardis needs to recharge.
Sorry...
what?
Overnight, that should do it,
shouldn't it, Clara?
Overnight?
One more night, that's...
That's not a problem, is it?
No.
No, no problem.
That's a shame, isn't it?
What's a shame?
DOCTOR: There's only three people left
in the universe
and you're lying to the other two.
It was the first thing I noticed
when I stepped in here.
You must have seen it, too, Clara,
-you've got eyes out to here!
-Seen what?
The universe is dead.
Everything that ever was
is dead and gone.
There's nothing beyond this door
but nothingness forever.
So why is it locked?
Please...
don't make me spend another night here.
Afraid of the dark?
But the dark is empty now.
No.
No, it isn't.
You'll be safe in here. Nothing gets
through those doors, I promise.
And you two are going to wait out there?
That would seem to be the plan.
Wait for what, exactly?
Why can't we just leave?
Like he said, it's recharging.
You didn't look like you believed him.
That's just how my face looks
when he talks.
It's just a silly toy thing,
a family heirloom.
Supposed to bring good luck.
Right. Yes.
Well, it didn't do
a very good job, did it?
It did. You're here, aren't you?
What were the chances
of you two finding me?
Orson...
do me a favour, take my advice,
when you get home,
stay away from time travel.
It runs in the family.
What?
Sorry. What do you mean,
"runs in the family"?
Nothing. It's just silly stories.
One of my grandparents...
-Well, great-grandparents...
-What is it? Tell me.
You asked if you knew me.
-It's a family heirloom.
-Yeah.
CLARA: What are we doing?
-Waiting.
-For what? For who?
If everybody in the universe is dead,
then there's nobody out there.
That's one way of looking at it.
What's the other?
That's a hell of a lot of ghosts.
Do you have your own mood lighting now?
Because frankly, the accent is enough.
(CREAKING)
-Where did that come from?
-It's always been there.
It's only visible in the night light.
But who wrote it?
Colonel Pink. Apparently, at night,
he needs a reminder.
Six months stranded alone,
I suppose it must be tempting.
-What is?
-Company.
(CREAKING)
What's that?
What kind of explanation
would you like?
A reassuring one.
Well, the systems are switching
to low power.
There are temperature differentials
all over this ship.
It's like pipes banging
when the heating goes off.
Always thought there was
something in the pipes.
Me, too.
Who were you having dinner with?
Are you making conversation?
I thought that I would give it a try.
(SIGHS) I told you. A date.
-Serious?
-It's a date.
A serious date?
(LAUGHS) Do I have to bring him
to you for approval?
Well, I would like to know about
his prospects.
If you like,
I can pop ahead and check them out.
Frankly, you've already done enough.
(SCREECHING)
Atmospheric pressure equalising...
or?
Company.
Why are we doing this?
Why don't we just go?
-Because I need to know.
-Why? About what?
Suppose that there are creatures
that live to hide,
that only show themselves
to the very young or the very old
or the mad or anyone
who wouldn't be believed?
-Okay...
-What would those creatures do
when everyone was gone,
when there was only one man
left standing in the universe?
(METALLIC KNOCKING)
-What's that?
-Potentially the hull cooling.
-"Potentially"?
-Believably.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
-Someone knocking.
-(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Yes.
Doctor, you don't actually believe
all this, do you?
Hiding creatures,
things from under the bed.
What's that in the mirror
or the corner of your eye?
What's that footstep following
but never passing by?
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Did we come to the end of the
universe because of a nursery rhyme?
ETHEREAL VOICE: Listen.
(KNOCKING INTENSIFIES)
(BUZZING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
-CLARA: That's you turning it, right?
-No.
-Get in the Tardis.
-Why?
I have to know.
Doctor. Doctor...
Tardis, now!
Okay, okay. Somebody is out there.
Now we know we can leave!
-Oh, Doctor!
-It's a pressure lock.
Releasing it could've triggered
the opening mechanism.
-Is there even an atmosphere out there?
-There's an air shell around the ship.
Why are you still here?
Because I am not
going to leave you in danger!
Then you will never travel with me again
because that is the deal!
Tardis, now! Do as you are told!
You're an idiot.
I know.
-What's happening?
-He's opening the door.
Perhaps they're all just waiting,
perhaps when we're all dead,
out they'll come a-slithering
from underneath the bed.
Oh, no, no, no, not now, come on!
(STATIC)
Oh! Always when it's important!
(THUDDING)
What's happening?
(ALARM BLARING)
What's that?
The alarm. The air shell's breached.
Stay here.
CLARA: Is he okay?
He's out cold. He'll be fine, though.
Something hit him.
Everything was flying out of that door.
Could've been that.
Yeah.
What was out there?
What were you so afraid of?
I've been here a long time.
My own shadow, probably.
-Yeah.
-(RUMBLING)
That's probably just
the rest of the air escaping.
You say "probably” a lot.
(BANGING)
We are safe?
Nothing can get in here, right?
Probably.
(HISSING)
Have you got a plan?
Telepathic circuits.
I left a trace in them before.
-So?
-So apparently, that can do a thing.
-That's your plan?
-It's not a plan. It's a thing.
(WHISPERING) Okay. Come on, come on,
you can do it.
-(GASPS)
-CLARA: Come on!
Sorry.
-(RUMBLING)
-Here we go!
(MACHINERY HUMMING)
Come on!
(WHOOSHING)
(THUDDING)
Is that it?
I don't know.
I think so.
Where are we?
Somewhere else, I hope! No, no, no,
you stay, look after the Doctor.
You can't go out there by yourself.
Thing is, my timeline, it keeps on...
Orson, you don't want to meet yourself.
It's really embarrassing.
(BOY SOBBING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
Rupert?
Orson?
MAN: Why does he have to sleep out here?
WOMAN: He doesn't want the others
to hear him crying.
MAN: Why does he have
to cry all the time?
WOMAN: You know why.
MAN: There'll be no crying in the army.
WOMAN: Hush!
MAN: Don't pretend you're not awake.
We're not idiots.
WOMAN: Come and sleep in the house.
You don't have to be alone.
If you can hear me,
you're very welcome in the house
with the other boys.
I'LL leave the door on the latch.
Come in any time.
MAN: He can't just run away
crying all the time
if he wants to join the army.
WOMAN: He doesn't want to join the army.
I keep telling you.
MAN: Well, he's not going to
the Academy, is he, that boy?
He'll never make a Time Lord.
Sontarans! Perverting
the course of human history!
You're confusing me.
What? Shut up, shut up!
Where's Clara?
Clara! Clara!
BOY: Hello, who's there?
Hello?
It's okay.
This is just a dream.
Just lie back again,
just lie back on the bed.
It will all be okay
if you just lie down and go to sleep.
Just do that for me.
Just sleep.
(SOBBING)
Listen...
What happened? What did you see?
What's out there?
CLARA: What if there was nothing?
What if there was never anything?
Nothing under the bed,
nothing at the door.
What if the big, bad Time Lord
doesn't want to admit
he's just afraid of the dark?
Where are we? Have we moved?
Where have we landed?
CLARA: Don't look where we are.
Take off and promise me
you will never look where we've been.
-Why?
-Just take off, don't ask questions.
I don't take orders, Clara.
Do as you're told.
(WHOOSHING)
-(GASPS)
-CLARA: Listen...
This is just a dream.
But very clever people can hear dreams.
So, please, just listen.
I know you're afraid
but being afraid is all right.
Because didn't anybody ever tell you
fear is a superpower?
Fear can make you faster
and cleverer and stronger.
And one day, you're going to
come back to this barn
and on that day you are going
to be very afraid indeed.
But that's okay.
Because if you're very wise
and very strong,
fear doesn't have to make you
cruel or cowardly.
Fear can make you kind.
No, no! Not the hugging! No, no, no.
I'm against the hugging, please...
(DOORBELL RINGS)
-I am so...
-I know.
It doesn't matter if there's nothing
under the bed or in the dark,
so long as you know it's okay
to be afraid of it.
I just get nervous.
-Me, too.
-I don't even know what I'm nervous of.
I'll show you.
So listen. If you listen to
nothing else, listen to this.
You're always going to be afraid,
even if you learn to hide it.
Fear is like...
a companion,
a constant companion, always there.
But that's okay,
because fear can bring us together.
Fear can bring you home.
I'm going to leave you something,
just so you'll always remember.
Fear makes companions of us all.
ARCHITECT:
This is the bank of Karabraxos...
Picture the thing
you want most in the universe.
-(SCREAMS)
-(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
And decide how badly you want it.
We're actually going to do it?
Rob the bank?
DOCTOR: If we don't we die.
We must locate them.
PSI: (WHISPERS) What is that?
DOCTOR: I don't know. Hate not knowing.
Are you hungry, boy?
DOCTOR: The bank is now open.