(BIRDS TWEETING)
(CROWS CAW)
It's a beautiful day.
Hallucinogenic lipstick.
She's here.
(GUN POWERS UP)
(CRACKLING)
Wrong. Wrong.
Bit right, mostly wrong.
I love museums!
Yeah, great(!) Can we go to a planet now?
A big spaceship, Churchill's bunker...?
You promised me a planet next.
Amy, this isn't any old asteroid.
It's the Delerium Archive,
the final resting place of the headless
monks, the biggest museum ever.
You've got a time machine.
What do you need museums for?
Wrong! Very wrong!
Oooh, one of mine. Also one of mine.
Oh, I see. It's how you keep score.
Oh, great, an old box(!)
It's from one of the old starliners.
A Home Box.
What's a Home Box?
Like a black box on a plane,
except it homes.
Anything happens to the ship,
the Home Box flies home
with all the flight data.
So?
The writing, the graffiti -
Old High Gallifreyan.
The lost language of the Time Lords.
There were days, there were many days,
these words could burn stars
and raise up empires, and topple gods.
What does it say?
"Hello, sweetie!"
(ALARM BELL RINGING)
Party's over, Doctor Song.
Why are we doing this?
Cos someone on a spaceship 12,000 years
ago is trying to attract my attention.
Let's see if we can get
the security playback working.
The party's over, Doctor Song,
yet still you're on board.
(SHE LAUGHS) Sorry, Alistair.
I needed to see what was in your vault.
Do you all know what's down there?
Any of you?
Because I'll tell you something.
This ship won't reach its destination.
Wait till she runs.
Don't make it look like an execution.
Triple-seven, five, slash,
three, four, nine by ten.
Zero, twelve, slash, acorn.
Oh, and I could do with an air corridor.
- What was that, what did she say?
- Co-ordinates!
Like I said on the dance floor,
you might want to find something
to hang on to!
(BEEPING)
WWhoo!
Doctor?
River?
Follow that ship!
They've gone into warp drive.
We're losing them!
- Stay close!
- I'm trying!
Use the stabilisers.
There aren't stabilisers!
The blue switches!
The blue ones don't do anything,
they're just...blue.
Yes, they're blue.
They're the blue stabilisers!
See?
Yeah, well, it's just boring now,
isn't it? They're boring-ers.
They're blue boring-ers.
Doctor, how come she can fly the TARDIS?
You call that flying the TARDIS? Ha!
OK. I've mapped the probability vectors,
done a fold-back on the temporal isometry,
charted the ship to its destination,
and...parked us right alongside.
Parked us? We haven't landed.
Of course we've landed. I just landed her.
But it didn't make the noise.
- What noise?
- You know, the...
(HE IMPERSONATES TARDIS)
It's not supposed to make that noise.
You leave the brakes on.
Yeah, well, it's a brilliant noise.
I love that noise.
Come along, Pond, let's have a look.
- No, wait! Environment checks.
- Oh, yes, sorry! Quite right.
Environment checks.
Nice out.
We're somewhere in the Garn Belt.
There's an atmosphere.
Early indications suggest...
We're on Alfava Metraxis,
the seventh planet of the Dundra System.
Oxygen-rich atmosphere, toxins
in the soft band, 11-hour day, and...
...chances of rain later.
He thinks he's so hot when he does that.
How come you can fly the TARDIS?
- Oh, I had lessons from the very best.
- Well, yeah.
It's a shame you were busy that day.
Right, then, why did they land here?
They didn't land.
Sorry?
You should've checked the Home Box -
it crashed.
Explain! Who is that
and how did she do that museum thing?
It's a long story and I don't know
most of it. Off we go.
- What are you doing?
- Leaving.
She's got where she wants to go,
- let's go where we want to go.
- Are you basically running away?
- Yep.
- Why?
- Cos she's my future.
- Can you run away from that?
I can run away from anything I like.
Time is not the boss of me.
- Hang on, is that a planet out there?
- Yes, of course it's a planet.
You promised me a planet. Five minutes?
- OK, five minutes!
- Yes!
But that's all, cos I'm telling you now,
that woman is not dragging me
into anything!
What caused it to crash? Not me.
Nah, the airlock would've sealed
seconds after you blew it.
According to the Home Box,
the warp engines had a phase-shift.
No survivors.
A phase-shift would have to be sabotage.
I did warn them.
About what?
Well, at least the building was empty.
Aplan temple.
Unoccupied for centuries.
Aren't you going to introduce us?
Amy Pond, Professor River Song.
(GASPS) I'm going to be a professor
some day, am I?
How exciting!
(LAUGHS) Spoilers!
Yeah, but who is she
and how did she do that?
She just left you a note in a museum.
Two things always guaranteed
to turn up in a museum.
The Home Box of category-four star liner
and, sooner or later, him.
- It's how he keeps score.
- I know!
It's hilarious, isn't it?
I'm nobody's taxi service!
I'm not going to be there to catch you
every time you feel like
jumping out of a spaceship.
And you are so wrong.
There's one survivor.
There's a thing in the belly
of that ship that can't ever die.
Now he's listening. You lot in orbit yet?
Yeah, I saw it land.
I'm at the crash site.
Try and home in on my signal.
Doctor, can you sonic me?
I need to boost the signal
so we can use it as a beacon.
Ooh, Doctor! You soniced her(!)
We have a minute. Shall we?
Where are we up to?
- Have we done the Bone Meadows?
- What's the book?
Stay away from it.
- What is it, though?
- Her diary.
- Ourdiary.
- Her past, my.. future.
Time travel.
We keep meeting in the wrong order.
You promised me an army, Dr Song.
No. I promised you the equivalent
of an army. This is the Doctor.
Father Octavian, sir. Bishop, second
class. 20 clerics at my command.
The troops are already in the drop ship
and landing shortly.
Dr Song was helping us
with a covert investigation.
Has Dr Song explained
what we're dealing with?
Doctor, what do you know
of the Weeping Angels?
The Angel, as far as we know,
is still trapped in the ship.
Our mission is to get inside
and neutralise it.
We can't get through up top,
we'd be too close to the drives.
According to this, behind the cliff face,
there's a network of catacombs
leading right up to the temple.
We can blow through
the base of the cliffs,
get into the entrance chamber,
then work our way up.
- Oh, good.
- Good, sir?
Catacombs, probably dark ones.
Dark catacombs, great(!)
Technically, I think it's called
a maze of the dead.
You can stop any time you like.
- Father Octavian?
- Excuse me, sir.
You're letting people call you "sir".
You never do that.
So whatever a Weeping Angel is,
it's really bad, yeah?
Now, that's interesting.
You're still here. Which part of "Wait
in the TARDIS till I tell you it's safe”
- was so confusing?
- Ooh, are you all Mr Grumpy Face today?
A Weeping Angel, Amy, is the deadliest,
most powerful, most malevolent
life form evolution has ever produced,
and one is trapped inside that wreckage
and I'm supposed to climb in
with a screwdriver and a torch,
and assuming I survive the radiation,
and the whole ship
doesn't blow up in my face,
do something clever
which I haven't thought of yet.
That's my day, that's what I'm up to.
Any questions?
Is River Song your wife?
Cos she's someone from your future,
and the way she talks to you,
I've never seen anyone do that.
She's kinda like, you know, "Heel, boy!"
She's Mrs Doctor from the future,
isn't she?
- Is she going to be your wife one day?
- Yes.
You're right.
I am definitely Mr Grumpy Face today.
RIVER SONG: Doctor! Doctor!
Oops! Her indoors!
Father Octavian?
Why do they call him "Father"?
He's their bishop, they're his clerics.
It's the 51st century,
the Church has moved on.
What do you think? It's from the
security cameras in the Byzantium vault.
I ripped it when I was on board.
Sorry about the quality.
- It's four seconds. I've put it on loop.
- Yep. It's an Angel.
- Hands covering its face.
- You've encountered the Angels before?
Once, on Earth, a long time ago. But
those were scavengers, barely surviving.
But it's just a statue.
- It's a statue when you see it.
- Where did it come from?
Oh, pulled from the ruins
of Razbahan, end of last century.
It's been in private hands ever since,
dormant all that time.
There's a difference
between dormant and patient.
What does that mean,
it's a statue when you see it?
The Weeping Angels can only move
if they're unseen. So legend has it.
No, it's not legend. It's a quantum lock.
In the sight of any living creature,
the Angels literally cease to exist.
They're just stone.
The ultimate defence mechanism.
What, being a stone?
Being a stone...until you turn your back.
The hyperdrive would've split open
on impact.
The whole ship will be flooded
with radiation, cracked electrons,
gravity storms,
deadly to almost any living thing.
Deadly to an Angel?
Dinner to an Angel. The longer
we leave it, the stronger it will grow.
Who built that temple?
Are they still around?
The Aplans. Indigenous life form.
Died out 400 years ago.
200 years later,
the planet was terraformed.
Currently there are
six billion human colonists.
You lot, you're everywhere! Like rabbits!
I'll never get done saving you.
Sir, if there is a clear and present
danger to the local population...
Oh, there is. Bad as it gets.
Bishop, lock and load!
Verger, how are we doing
with those explosives? Dr Song, with me.
- Two minutes. Sweetie, I need you.
- (HE MOUTHS)
Anybody need me? Nobody?
I found this.
Definitive work on the Angels.
Well, the only one.
Written by a madman, it's barely readable,
- but I've marked a few passages.
- Not bad, bit slow in the middle,
didn't you hate his girlfriend?
No, hang on, wait, wait!
Dr Song? Did you have
more than one clip of the Angel?
No, just the four seconds.
This book is wrong. What's wrong
with this book? It's wrong.
It's so strange when you go
all baby-face. How early is this for you?
Very early.
So you don't know who I am yet?
How do you know who I am?
I don't always look the same.
I've got pictures of all your faces.
You never show up in the right order,
though. I need the spotter's guide.
Pictures? Why aren't there pictures?
You're just a recording. You can't move.
(SHE GASPS)
Doctor!
This whole book - it's a warning
about the Weeping Angels.
So why no pictures?
Why not show us what to look out for?
There was a bit about images.
What was that?
Yes! Hang on...
"That which holds the image
of an angel becomes itself an angel.”
Doctor!
What does that mean? "An image
of a Angel becomes itself an Angel.”
Doctor! It's in the room!
- Amy!
- Doctor!
Are you all right? What's happening?
Doctor! Doctor, it's coming
out of the television. The Angel is here.
Don't take your eyes off it! Keep
looking. It can't move if you're looking.
- What's wrong?
- Deadlocked.
- There is no deadlock.
- Don't even blink, Amy!
Doctor!
- What are you doing?
- Cutting the power.
It's using the screen,
I'm turning the screen off.
- It's deadlocked the whole system.
- There's no deadlock.
- There is now.
- Help me!
- Can you turn it off?
- Doctor!
- The screen, can you turn it off?
- I tried.
Try again, but don't take your eyes
off the Angel.
I'm not!
If something moves,
it'll move faster. Don't even blink.
I'm not blinking!
Have you ever tried not blinking?
- It just keeps switching it back on!
- Yeah, it's the Angel.
But it's just a recording.
No, anything that takes
the image of an Angel ls an Angel.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to cut through.
It's not even warm.
There is no way in,
it's not physically possible.
Doctor, what's it going to do to me?
Just keep looking at it.
Don't stop looking!
Just tell me.
Just tell me. Tell me!
Amy, not the eyes. Look at the Angel,
but don't look at the eyes.
- Why?
- What is it?
"The eyes are not the windows
of the soul, they are the doors.
- "Beware what may enter there."”
- Doctor, what did you say?
Don't look at the eyes!
No, about images,
what did you say about images?
Whatever holds the image
of an angel ls an angel.
OK... Hold this.
One, two, three, four...
(DOOR OPENS)
I froze it!
There was a sort of blip on the tape
and I froze it on the blip.
It wasn't the image of an angel
any more. That was good, yeah?
It was, wasn't it? That was pretty good.
- RIVER: That was amazing!
- River, hug Amy.
- Why?
- Cos I'm busy.
I'm fine.
- You're brilliant!
- Thanks. Yeah.
I kind of creamed it, didn't I?
- So it was here? That was the Angel?
- That was the projection of the Angel.
It's reaching out, getting
a good look at us. It's no longer dormant.
Plus one positive!
Doctor! We're through!
OK. Now it starts.
- Coming?
- Yeah, coming.
There's just...something in my eye.
Do we have a gravity globe?
Grav globe.
Where are we? What is this?
It's an Aplan mortarium -
sometimes called a maze of the dead.
What's that?
Well, if you happen to be
a creature of living stone...
Ha, ha.
...the perfect hiding place.
I guess this makes it a bit trickier.
A bit, yeah.
A stone angel on the loose
amongst stone statues.
A lot harder than I prayed for.
A needle in a haystack.
A needle that looks like hay.
A hay-like needle. Of death.
A hay-like needle of death
in a haystack of, er, statues.
No, yours was fine.
Right. Check every single statue
in this chamber.
You know what you're looking for.
Complete visual inspection.
One question - how do we fight it?
We find it, and hope.
He doesn't know yet, does he?
Who and what you are.
It's too early in his time stream.
Well, make sure he doesn't work it out,
or he's not going to help us.
I won't let you down.
Believe you me, I have no intention
of going back to prison.
Sir? Side chamber. One visible exit.
Check it out. Angelo, go with him.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
So what's a maze of the dead?
Oh, it's not as bad as it sounds.
It's just a labyrinth
with dead people buried in the walls.
OK, that was fairly bad.
Right, give me your arm...
This won't hurt a bit.
- Ow!
- There, you see. I lied.
It's a viro-stabiliser.
Stabilises your metabolism
against radiation, drive burn, anything.
You'll need it
when we get up to that ship.
AMY: So what's he like?
In the future, I mean. Cos you know him
in the future, don't you?
The Doctor?
Well, the Doctor's the Doctor.
Oh, well, that's, um, very helpful.
Mind if I write that down?
- Yes, we are.
- Sorry, what?
- Talking about you.
- I wasn't listening, I'm busy.
Ah. The other way up.
- Yeah.
- You're so his wife.
Oh, Amy, Amy, Amy!
This is the Doctor we're talking about.
Do you really think it could be
anything that simple?
Yep.
You're good. I'm not saying you're right,
but you are very good.
CLERIC: Can you believe this?
We're hunting statues.
Better than chasing lava snakes.
Actually, lava snakes weren't that bad.
(STONE SCRAPES)
Who's there? Is someone there?
Angelo?
Angelo!
Christian, is that you?
OVER RADIO: Angelo, come and see this.
- What is it?
- Just come and see it.
It's not a school trip. Just tell me.
No, really, come and see.
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
Sorry. Sorry, I thought...
I thought it looked at me.
We know what the Angel looks like.
Is that the Angel?
- No, sir.
- No, sir, it is not!
According to the Doctor,
we are facing an enemy
of unknowable power and infinite evil.
So it would be good,
it would be very good,
if we could all remain calm
in the presence of décor.
- What's your name?
- Bob, sir.
- Ah, that's a great name. I love Bob.
- It's a Sacred Name.
We all have Sacred Names. They're given
to us in the service of the Church.
Sacred Bob. More like Scared Bob now, eh?
Yes, sir.
Ah, good.
Scared keeps you fast.
Anyone in this room who isn't scared
is a moron.
Carry on.
We'll be moving into the maze
in two minutes.
You stay with Christian and Angelo.
Guard the approach.
Isn't there a chance
this lot's just going to collapse?
- There's a whole ship up there.
- RIVER: Incredible builders, the Aplans.
Had dinner with their chief architect
once. Two heads are better than one.
- What, you mean you helped him?
- No, I mean he had two heads.
That book. The very end, what did it say?
- Hang on.
- Read it to me.
"What if we had ideas
that could think for themselves?
"What if one day our dreams
no longer needed us?
"When these things occur and are held
to be true, the time will be upon us.
"The time of Angels."
OVER RADIO: Hey, Angelo. Christian?
Where are you?
(GUNSHOT)
AMY: Are we there yet?
It's a hell of a climb.
RIVER: The maze is on six levels
representing the ascent of the soul.
Only two levels to go.
THE DOCTOR: Lovely species, the Aplans.
We should visit them sometime.
AMY: I thought they were all dead.
So's Virginia Woolf.
I'm on her bowling team.
Very relaxed, sort of cheerful.
That's having two heads. You're never
short of a snog with an extra head.
Doctor, there's something.
I don't know what it is...
Yeah, there's something wrong.
Don't know what it is yet, either.
Working on it.
Then they had laws against self-marrying
and what was that about?
But that's the Church for you.
Er, no offence, Bishop.
Quite a lot taken,
if that's all right, Doctor.
Lowest point in the wreckage is only
about 50 feet up from here. That way.
AMY: Church had a point,
if you think about it.
The divorces must have been messy.
Oh!
What's wrong?
Oh.
Exactly.
How could we not notice that?
Low-level perception filter,
or maybe we're thick.
What's wrong, sir? Nobody move.
Everyone stay exactly where they are.
Bishop, I am truly sorry.
I've made a mistake
and we are all in terrible danger.
What danger?
RIVER: The Aplans.
The Aplans?
- They've got two heads.
- Yes, I get that. So?
THE DOCTOR: So why don't the statues?
Everyone, over there. Just move,
don't ask questions, don't speak.
OK. I want you all to switch off
your torches.
- Sir?
- Just do it.
OK. I'm going to turn off this one, too,
just for a moment.
RIVER: Are you sure about this?
No.
Oh, my God! They've moved.
They're Angels.
- All of them!
- But they can't be.
Clerics, keep watching them.
Every statue in this maze,
every single one, is a Weeping Angel.
They're coming after us.
OVER RADIO: Bob, come and see this.
Angelo?
Come and see what we've found.
Are you with Christian?
The Bishop said you'd be five minutes.
I'm here, Bob. Come and see this.
Where are you?
Through the arch, Bob.
Honestly, you've got to come and see this.
What have you found?
Come and see.
No. What is it?
There was only one Angel on the ship.
Just the one, I swear.
Could they have been here already?
- The Aplans, how did they die out?
- Nobody knows.
We know. They don't look like Angels.
And they're not fast.
You said they were fast.
They should have had us by now.
They're dying. Losing their form.
They've been here for centuries,
- starving.
- Losing their image.
And their image is their power. Power...
- Power!
- Doctor?
Don't you see? All that radiation
spilling out, the drive burn.
The crash of the Byzantium wasn't
an accident - it was a rescue mission
for the Angels. We're in the middle
of an army and it's waking up.
We need to get out of here fast.
Bob, Angelo, Christian, come in,
please. Any of you, come in!
OVER RADIO:
It's Bob, sir. Sorry, sir.
Bob, are Angelo and Christian with you?
All the statues are active.
- I repeat, all the statues are active!
- I know, sir.
Angelo and Christian are dead, sir.
The statues killed them, sir.
Bob, Sacred Bob, it's me, the Doctor.
Where are you now?
- I'm talking to my...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, shut up!
I'm on my way up to you, sir.
I'm homing in on your signal.
Well done, Bob.
Scared keeps you fast. Told you.
Your friends, Bob,
what did the Angel do to them?
- Snapped their necks, sir.
- That's odd.
That's not how the Angels kill you,
they displace you in time.
Unless they needed bodies for something.
Bob, did you check
their data packs for vital signs?
We may be able to initiate a rescue plan.
Don't be an idiot!
The Angels don't leave you alive!
Bob, keep running, but tell me,
how did you escape?
I didn't escape, sir.
The Angel killed me, too.
What do you mean,
the Angel killed you, too?
Snapped my neck, sir.
Wasn't as painless as I expected,
but it was pretty quick,
so that was something.
If you're dead,
how can I be talking to you?
You're not talking to me, sir.
The Angel has no voice.
It stripped my cerebral cortex
and re-animated a version
of my consciousness to communicate
with you. Sorry about the confusion.
So when you say
you're on your way up to us...
- It's the Angel that's coming, sir, yes.
- No way out.
- Then we get out through the wreckage.
- Go, go. All of you, run!
- Doctor?
- Yes, I'm coming, just go, go, go!
Called you an idiot. Sorry, but there's
no way we could have rescued your men.
I know that, sir. And when you've
flown away in your little blue box,
I'll explain that to their families.
Angel Bob, which Angel
am I talking to? The one from the ship?
Yes, sir.
And the other Angels are still restoring.
Ah, so the Angel is not
in the wreckage. Thank you.
Don't wait for me. Go, run.
I can't!
No, really, I can't.
- Why not?
- Look at it. Look at my hand. It's stone!
Well. There it is - the Byzantium.
It's got to be 30 feet.
How do we get up there?
Check all these exits.
I want them all secure.
You looked into the eyes
of an Angel, didn't you?
I couldn't stop myself. I tried.
Listen. It's messing with your head.
Your hand is not made of stone.
It is. Look at it!
It's in your mind. I promise you.
You can move that hand.
- You can let go.
- I can't, OK?
I've tried and I can't. It's stone.
The Angel is going to come
and it's going to turn this light off,
and then there's nothing
I can do to stop it.
- So do it, concentrate, move your hand.
- I can't.
- Then we're both going to die.
- You're not going to die.
They'll kill the lights.
You've got to go, you know you have.
You've got all that stuff with River
and that's all got to happen.
You know you can't die here!
Time can be re-written,
it doesn't work like that.
- Keep your eyes on it. Don't blink.
- Run!
You see, I'm not going,
I'm not leaving you here.
I don't need you to die for me,
Doctor, do I look that clingy?
You can move your hand.
- It's stone.
- It's not stone!
Those people up there
will die without you.
If you stay here with me,
you'll have as good as killed them.
Amy Pond, you are magnificent.
And I'm sorry.
It's OK. I understand.
You've got to leave me.
Oh, no, I'm not leaving you, never.
I'm sorry about this.
- See, not stone! Now run!
- You bit me!
Yeah, and you're alive.
I've got a mark! Look at my hand!
- Yeah, and you're alive, did I mention?
- Blimey, your teeth!
Have you got space teeth?
Alive. All I'm saying.
The statues are advancing
along all corridors.
And, sir, my torch keeps flickering.
- They all do.
- So does the gravity globe.
Clerics, we're down to four men.
Expect incoming.
Yeah, it's the Angels.
They're coming. And they're draining
the power for themselves.
Which means we won't be able to see them.
- Which means we can't stay here.
- There are two more incoming!
Any suggestions?
The statues are advancing on all sides
and we don't have the climbing equipment
to reach the Byzantium.
There's no way up, no way back,
no way out.
No pressure, but this is usually
when you have a really good idea.
There's always a way out.
RADIO: Doctor?
- Can I speak to the Doctor, please?
- Hello, Angels. What's your problem?
Your power will not last much longer,
and the Angels will be with you shortly.
Sorry, sir.
Why are you telling me this?
There's something the Angels are very
keen you should know before the end.
- Which is?
- I died in fear.
I'm sorry?
You told me my fear would keep me alive,
but I died afraid, in pain and alone.
You made me trust you,
and when it mattered, you let me down.
What are they doing?
They're trying to make him angry.
I'm sorry, sir. The Angels were very keen
for you to know that.
Well, then, the Angels have made
their second mistake,
because I'm not going to let that pass.
I'm sorry you're dead, Bob,
but I swear to whatever is left of you,
they will be sorrier.
But you're trapped, sir, and about to die.
Yeah. I'm trapped.
Speaking of traps, this trap has got
a great, big mistake in it.
A great, big, whopping mistake!
- What mistake, sir?
- Trust me.
- Yeah.
- Trust me?
- Always.
- You lot - trust me?
- Sir, two more incoming!
- We have faith, sir.
Then give me your gun.
I'm about to do something
incredibly stupid and dangerous.
- When I do...jump!
- Jump where?
Just jump, high as you can.
Come on, leap of faith, Bishop.
- On my signal.
- What signal?
You won't miss it.
RADIO: Sorry, can I ask again?
You mentioned a mistake?
Oh, big mistake. Really huge.
There's one thing you never put in a trap
if you're smart.
If you value your continued existence, if
you have any plans about seeing tomorrow,
there is one thing
you never, ever put in a trap.
And what would that be, sir?
Me.