MORAN: Private journal
of Captain Jonathan Moran.
21st November, 211789.
We have located a craft
of unknown origin on the lake floor.
Visual scans in situ revealed nothing.
So, we have brought the craft on-board
and myself and the crew
will now investigate.
MORAN: How did they miss this
in the initial survey?
Cass says it was buried.
And the currents of the water
must have shifted the rubble around.
Conversation needs to be had
about who owns this spaceship.
MORAN: Can we stop
calling it a spaceship?
We don't know what it is.
PRITCHARD: A case could be made
that this is an asset
and my company has bought
the rights to all assets...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's this?
Lunn, grab me a torch, will you?
It was found on MOD property,
even if that property is underwater.
MORAN: Lunn, where's the torch?
CanIgo in?
What is the, uh, radiation count?
PRITCHARD: Pretty much background level.
Anything more it would have shown up
in the initial survey 20 years ago.
If it's not safe,
how come you can go in?
How long do you think
it's been down here?
Well, there's next to no corrosion.
-I've not seen technology like this...
-Please, don't say "On Earth".
-...on Earth before.
-(SIGHS) Oh.
-(CHUCKLES)
-Maybe it's some kind
of experimental craft
that got left behind
when they abandoned the site.
Wait, you think the army
would just lose a prototype weapon?
You're new to the military
aren't you, son?
BENNETT: Cass says he might be right.
It might have been here since the 1980s,
before the valley flooded.
Cass!
(BEEPING)
(SCREAMS)
LUNN: Come on!
-Move!
-LUNN: Come on! We have to go now!
TANNOY: Fire in main hangar.
Safety protocols have been initiated.
All crew must evacuate immediately.
This safety message was
brought to you by Vector Petroleum.
We can't just leave him in there!
There's something in the spaceship.
I saw it!
O'Donnell. O'Donnell, he's dead.
Didn't you see him?
Are we... The fire,
are we safe out here?
It's fine,
the CO2 will put the fire out.
It was you!
You were messing about
with the controls on that ship!
(SCREAMS)
Moran.
We just saw you...
He's... Oh, my God.
He's a ghost.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHOOSHING)
What's wrong? You're not happy.
Why aren't you happy? Tell me.
CLARA: Come on, we're on a roll!
Monsters, things blowing up.
Oh, hey, can we go back to that place
where the people
with the long necks have been
celebrating New Year for two centuries?
I left my sunglasses there.
And most of my dignity.
DOCTOR: Why have you brought us here?
(EXHALES) Here, being?
Underwater.
Some sort of a base.
Technology's 22nd century.
Maybe military. Maybe scientific.
Is there a crew?
Must be. Somewhere. There's oxygen.
(SIGHING) I want another adventure.
Come on, you feel the same.
You're itching to save
a planet, I know it.
Doctor, look at this.
Well, looks like you got your wish.
CLARA: Food fight?
DOCTOR: I think there was
more to it than that.
Whatever it was,
it happened pretty recently.
Seven or eight hours ago.
No bodies, though.
And they took provisions.
OK, so, something or someone
forced the crew to abandon the base.
Maybe they went for a swim
in the creepy,
flooded village outside.
Oh, yeah, you see, this is more like it.
Well, come on. Don't leave me hanging.
Look, told you.
Crew.
Hello, sailors.
Right, did not expect that.
Hands up, who expected that.
Wait, wait, wait.
I don't think they're going to hurt us.
I think that they're just curious.
You sure?
Well, I mean, define "sure".
Look at you, lovely chaps.
What's happened to you, then?
Come on.
CLARA: What are they?
DOCTOR: I haven't a clue.
Isn't that exciting?
Where did they go?
What is it, some kind of submarine?
No, it's alien.
DOCTOR: That's weird.
The Tardis hasn't translated it.
(WHOOSHING)
(WHISPERING) Hey, look! They're back.
Hello, did you want to show us this?
It's very nice.
(INAUDIBLE)
Wait, are they saying something?
OK, they now appear
to be arming themselves.
Yes, I spotted that too.
Was it something she said?
She does that.
She once had an argument with Gandhi!
I'm starting to see
why the crew did a runner.
(CLANKING)
(GASPS)
(INAUDIBLE)
CLARA: Run!
In here! Quick!
(GASPING)
(INAUDIBLE)
DOCTOR: What are you?
Who the hell are you
and what are you doing here?
This is Clara.
And I'm the Doctor.
-You're from UNIT.
-Well, if that's what it says.
I'm Pritchard. This is Bennett.
O'Donnell!
(CHUCKLES) You're really the Doctor?
I'm a huge fan.
(LAUGHS)
Uh, I mean, um, you know, nice work.
Tim Lunn, I sign for Cass.
Tell me, what about
those things out there, what are they?
Why are they trying to kill us?
Well, they're, uh, they're ghosts.
They're not ghosts.
-Cass is saying a...
-Thank you,
but I actually don't need your help.
I can speak sign. Go ahead.
Wait, no, no, actually, I can't.
It's been deleted for semaphore.
Someone get me a selection of flags.
"One of the ghosts is our previous
commanding officer.
"The other, moley-guy,
we don't know what he is."”
He's from the planet Tivoli.
See? I told you he was an alien.
Didn't I say that?
Weird thing is, they're not violent.
They're too cowardly.
They wouldn't say boo to a goose.
More like to give the goose
their car keys and bank details.
When did they first appear?
Oh, did you see
that spaceship in the hangar?
Yeah, we found that on the lake bed.
We just got it on board
and one of the engines started up
and then Moran got...
Moran was killed.
"Then, they appeared
"and pretty much straightaway
started trying to kill us.
"So, we grabbed what we could
and were looking for somewhere to hide,
"and that's when we realised
the ghosts couldn't come in here."
-What is this place?
-It's a Faraday cage.
Completely impenetrable
to radio waves and, apparently,
whatever those things are out there.
So, who's in charge now?
-I need to know who to ignore.
-That'd be me.
Her.
Actually, that would be me.
I represent Vector Petroleum.
-We own the mining rights to the oil.
-The oil?
Where are we?
Uh, this used to be
a military training site.
Uh, there was a, a dam overlooking it,
but the dam burst
and the valley was submerged.
Then 20 years ago, we discovered
a massive oil reservoir underneath it.
COMPUTER VOICE: Good morning.
Entering day mode.
OK, it's morning.
We can go outside now.
LUNN: Thank God for that.
PRITCHARD: At last,
we can get out of here.
Morning?
Yeah, uh, we're too far below
the surface for daylight,
so we have to demarcate
artificial days and nights.
Um, I'd like to have
a look at that spaceship,
but what about those things
that aren't ghosts?
Oh, it's all right,
they only come out at night.
Weird how that is not comforting.
If whatever they are...
-They're ghosts.
-They're not ghosts!
...have been trying to kill you,
why haven't you abandoned the base?
That was my call.
We've got about a trillion dollars'
worth of mining equipment here.
We're not just going to abandon it.
What? If it all goes pear-shaped,
it's not them that lose their bonus.
It's OK, I understand.
You're an idiot.
Come to mention it,
why is there a Faraday cage on the base?
It's the, uh, mining equipment.
It runs on nuclear fission.
The Faraday cage
has been lined with lead
to act as a shelter
in the event of a radiation leak.
So, we are fighting
an unknown homicidal force
that has taken the form of your
commanding officer and a cowardly alien,
underwater, in a nuclear reactor?
Anything else I should know? Has someone
got a peanut allergy or something?
(CHUCKLES)
It all started with this ship.
This is where the answer will be.
What's happened
to the stuff you've removed?
This is for long-haul flights.
There should be
a suspended animation chamber
for the pilot, right here.
-Plus, a power cell is missing.
-Power cell?
Yeah, you can see the casing is empty.
It's not safe out here!
CLARA: What's the matter?
She won't let me look
inside the spaceship.
-She says it's not safe.
-I'm saying it's not safe out here.
I imagine they're pretty valuable.
-What?
-PRITCHARD: I mean powerful.
I imagine those power cells
are pretty powerful.
They can zap a vessel from
one side of the galaxy to the other,
so, you take
a wild stab in the dark.
And the missing one
must still be out there.
Yes, well, otherwise... Sorry.
Why is this man still talking to me?
We haven't removed anything.
There hasn't been time.
DOCTOR: So what have we got?
Moran dies and then those things appear.
They can walk through walls.
They only come out at night.
And they're sort of see-through.
CLARA: Doctor, wait,
you're not saying...
They're ghosts.
Yeah, ghosts!
CLARA: You said there was no such thing.
You actually pooh-poohed
the ghost theory.
Yes, well... Well,
there was no such thing
as socks or smart phones
and badgers until there suddenly were.
Besides, what else could they be?
They're not holograms.
They're not Flesh Avatars.
They're not Autons.
They're not digital copies
bouncing around the Nethersphere.
No, these people are literally,
actually dead!
Wow!
This is... It's amazing!
I've never actually met a proper ghost!
(MOUTHING)
"Moran was our friend."
(WHISPERING) The cards.
Oh! Oh, right you are. Uh...
(SIGHS) Come here.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm very sorry for your loss.
I'll do all I can
to solve the death of your
friend, slash family member, slash pet.
But don't you see what this means?
Death, it was the one thing that unified
every single living creature
in the universe,
and now it's gone!
How can you just sit there?
Don't you want
to go out there right now,
wrestle them to the ground
and ask them questions
until your throat falls out?
What's death like? Does it hurt?
Do you still get hungry?
Do you miss being alive?
Why can you only handle metal objects?
Oh, I didn't know I'd noticed that.
OK, so they'll try
to kill you, blah, blah, blah.
What does that matter? You come back!
A bit murdery, sure, but even so!
Calm, Doctor, calm.
You were like this
when you met Shirley Bassey.
OK.
Question one. What is a ghost?
Question two. What do they want?
Whoa, whoa, what's happening?
COMPUTER VOICE: Good evening.
Entering night mode.
That's not right. We're switching back
into night mode again.
This can't happen.
No. No. No.
-(BELL TOLLING)
-BENNETT: Um, what's doing that?
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
CLARA: Doctor?
DOCTOR: The Tardis Cloister Bell!
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
CLARA: Doctor, what's wrong?
DOCTOR: It must be the ghosts.
That's why she was upset
when we got here.
Why? I don't understand.
It was just what I was saying.
You live and you die, that's it.
The ghosts are aberrations.
A splinter of time in the skin.
They're unnatural.
She wants to get away from them.
So what do we do?
Put the hand brake on.
Whoa, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho!
Where do you think you're going?
Out there, where the action is.
Look, um...
-What?
-Oh. This is my own fault.
I like adventures
as much as the next man.
If the next man is a man
who likes adventures.
Even so, don't... Don't go native.
(CHUCKLES) What do you mean? I'm not.
Look, there's a whole dimension in here.
But there's only room for one me.
Wait. Wait a second.
You just raved about ghosts like a kid
who had too much sherbet.
Do you know what you need?
You need a hobby!
(LAUGHS) I really don't.
DOCTOR: Or even better,
another relationship!
Come on, you lot,
you're bananas about relationships.
You're always writing songs about them
or going to war or getting tattooed.
Doctor. I'm fine.
I just felt that I had to say something.
I know, and I appreciated it.
-'Cause I've got a duty of care.
-Which you take very seriously, I know.
-So can stop now?
-Please.
Please do. (CHUCKLES)
O'DONNELL: (ON PA) Attention all crew.
The Drum switched to night mode early,
so grab provisions
and make your way to the Faraday cage.
PRITCHARD: That you, Bennett?
I went out
looking for that missing power cell.
OK, contractually it's a grey area,
but I reckon we can argue
everything non-indigenous is an asset
and therefore...
(WATER DRIPPING)
Bennett?
(GASPS)
-We're meant to be in day mode!
-(INAUDIBLE)
You shouldn't be here.
What?
What are you saying?
-No, Moran! Don't!
-(BEEPING)
(GASPS)
O'DONNELL: (ON PA)
Pritchard, you are unaccounted for.
Contact the bridge or get to
the Faraday cage immediately.
Pritchard! Contact the bridge,
or get to the Faraday cage!
BENNETT: I'd love to work for UNIT.
Earth's first line of defence and all.
Yeah. I'm probably not suited though.
Not much of a fighter.
Uh, more of a bleeder.
CLARA: Pritchard! Where have you been?
Everyone's been looking for you.
-What's with the wet suit?
-Yeah, where've you been?
BENNETT: O'Donnell it's OK
Pritchard's in here!
Pritchard, you moron, grab your stuff,
we're locking down early.
In case I can't get this back
into day mode.
CLARA: Is he all right?
-(THUD)
-(BOTH GASP)
BENNETT: Man overboard.
Man overboard! We need a rescue team!
Bennett, wait! It's Pritchard!
He's a ghost.
He's another ghost.
O'DONNELL: Come on. Come on.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
-COMPUTER VOICE: Good morning.
-(EXHALES)
Entering day mode.
No, no, Moran! Don't!
(BEEP)
They're working out
how to use the base against us.
Altering the time settings
so they can go about uninhibited,
opening the airlocks.
They're learning.
And now there's three of them?
Cass, what do we do?
"We abandon the base.
"Topside can send down
a whole team of marines
"or Ghostbusters or whatever."
Wait, wait!
"I can't force you to leave,
"so you can stay and do the whole
"The Cabin in the Woods thing
"and get killed or drowned if you want.
"But my first priority
is to protect my crew.”
(WHISPERING) Yeah,
but we're coming back, aren't we?
(WHISPERS) Yes, we're coming back.
"O'Donnell, tell them
we're abandoning base on my orders."
Topside, Topside,
this is Lance Corporal Alice O'Donnell
from Drum Control. Over.
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Drum Control, this is Topside.
We have received your message,
submarine on its way. Over.
O'DONNELL: Repeat, Topside. Over.
We've received your request
for a rescue sub,
it's two minutes away. Over.
Topside, who did you speak to,
and when was this request made? Over.
Drum Control, it was in Morse code.
Arrived maybe half an hour ago.
Said it was urgent, comms were down,
two crew members critically il
full paramedic team requested. Over.
Topside, this is the Doctor,
UNIT security visa 7-1-0 Apple 0-0.
You may be familiar with my work.
Call back the sub.
-Doctor, why...
-DOCTOR: Call it back!
We have a hazardous
and undefined contagion on board.
This base is now under quarantine.
What did you do that for?
Well, none of us sent
the message, did we?
So that means that the ghosts sent it.
Which means they want
that crew down here.
"Why would they do that?"
Well, I don't know,
but I'm pretty certain it's not
so they can all form a boy band.
OK, we solve this on our own.
The ghosts can only come out at night
so they change the base's
time settings, why?
-What's different at night?
-It's mainly atmospheric.
The lights are dim,
the noise from the engines is muffled.
No, something... Something else.
"The diagnostic sweep,
when the systems are checked.
"That stops at night to save power."”
What systems, specifically?
Life support, the locks.
They're electromagnetic.
They have to be
secured in case of flooding,
so throughout the day they're checked
one by one, every few seconds.
(SIGHS) The answer's
in there somewhere, I can smell it.
Doctor, what do we do?
O'Donnell. Excellent work.
Returning the base to day mode.
(SHEEPISHLY) Shut up. It was nothing.
-You really think so?
-Now put it back into night mode.
-What?
-We know nothing!
We don't know what they want.
That's what's getting us killed.
Well, I won't run. Not any more.
So, O'Donnell, kindly put the base
back into night mode.
We want to know what
these ghosts are after,
we ask them.
We are going to do the impossible.
Capture a ghost.
(BEEPING)
(CLUNKING)
COMPUTER VOICE: Good evening,
entering night mode.
(SHUDDERING)
Hey, how's it going?
(WHIMPERING)
Bennett's got them moving
and Clara's in position.
Clara, Bennett is gonna run
across the top of the T-junction
to your right in about ten seconds.
Draw the ghosts towards you.
Turn right, and then take second left.
Hey! Hey, ghosts.
Down here!
DOCTOR: Lunn, they're coming your way.
Clara's going to duck down to her left.
You're gonna keep the ghosts
going on the same route they are on now.
Then, after about 50 yards,
on your left there's a flood door.
O'Donnell will close the door
once you're through.
I...I can hear them.
Lunn. Don't let them see where you go.
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Hey. Yeah, this way.
We've got a problem!
They've separated.
What?
O'DONNELL: Moran and the mole guy
are going after Clara.
O'DONNELL: Clara, look out.
Two ghosts are still on your case.
Right behind you.
I'm beginning to think we should have
let the ghosts in on the plan.
Clara, there's a flood door
at the end of the corridor
around the corner to your right.
We'll close it from here.
Listen to me.
You've got to get through that door
before Moran
and the other ghost sees you.
CLARA: Doctor!
DOCTOR: Now, O'Donnell! Fast as you can.
(BEEPING)
(CLANGING)
Guys, I'm nearly at my door.
Now, Lunn. Quickly.
It saw me.
Oh, God. It saw me.
It's coming through.
It's coming through the door!
-We don't have a camera in there.
-Lunn, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Lunn, what's happening?
(GROANS)
(SHUDDERING)
(CLATTERING)
DOCTOR: Lunn! Can you hear me?
Lunn! Lunn!
Can you hear me? Lunn! Lunn!
Lunn!
What's happening? Lunn!
-Lunn, can you hear me?
-I'm OK.
Cass. He's alive.
LUNN: 7t didn't hurt me. I'm OK.
What? What's wrong with you?
Why didn't it hurt you?
Bennett, you're on again.
-Bennett, where are you?
-(BEEPING)
O'DONNELL: There.
Oh, God, look.
Bennett, can you hear me?
There are two ghosts
Just around the corner from you.
(WHISPERS) Yes, thanks, I'd noticed.
The Faraday cage
is across the intersection
and down the corridor to your right.
This last bit is down to you.
(GRUNTS)
OK, so, the good news is
they aren't split up any more.
Cue Clara!
(STATIC CRACKLING)
We need to talk.
Sorry, chaps. Just a hologram.
You play a little bit too rough.
I'm fine, by the way.
In case any of you were worried.
Cass, are you seeing this?
O'DONNELL: Sonic glasses Wi-Fi
locked in. On screen B2.
She says she can't see them properly.
"The glass is too thick
and they're too far away."
-Open the door.
-What?
Doctor, you can't go in there.
They will kill you!
They don't have any weapons
or access to any of the controls.
They can't hurt me. So open the door.
(BEEPING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(WHISPERS) Cold...
(NORMAL VOICE) ..isn't it?
Take your weapons away
and you're not so scary, are you?
That better, Cass?
She says they're saying the same thing,
the same phrase, over and over.
They're saying,
"The dark... The score...
"No, the sword...
"The for sale?
"No, the forsaken. The temple."
-What?
-LUNN: Yes, she's sure.
"'The Dark. The Sword.
The Forsaken. The Temple.'
"lust that. Over and over.”
Dark. Sword. Forsaken. Temple.
What does that mean?
What are you telling me, big man?
Bennett. I need maps!
I think I just worked out
what our friend here is telling us.
DOCTOR: They're coordinates.
BENNETT: How can they be coordinates?
The Dark... Space.
So, whoever's following the coordinates
knows they're going to another planet.
The Sword...
Orion's sword.
The sword, the three stars,
although one isn't actually a star
but the Orion nebula
hanging down from Orion's Belt. But...
If viewed from back here,
the Earth becomes
the fourth bit of the sword.
So, narrowed it down to a planet now.
Getting closer!
The Forsaken...
The forsaken or abandoned or empty town.
See, it's a location,
beaming out to someone
or something across the universe,
over and over.
-Every time they kill one of us...
-It strengthens the signal.
Another ghost, another transmitter.
Which is why they sent
for that rescue sub.
Get more people down here. Kill them.
Make even more ghosts
to beam out the coordinates.
"But why are they beaming out
the coordinates?
"Is it a distress call?"
It could be.
Or a warning.
Might even be a call to arms.
It could mean "Come here,
they're vulnerable, help yourself."
Wait a minute, though.
Wait a minuet. You know what this means?
It means that they're not
a natural phenomenon.
It means that someone
is deliberately getting people killed,
high jacking their souls
and turning them into transmitters.
But what do the coordinates
lead to, though?
To us? To the ghosts, what?
Ah! What the coordinates are for.
That is part of the answer to the other
question you're all thinking.
Really? Come on, none of you?
Surely, just being around me
makes you cleverer by osmosis!
What is the other question?
"The Temple.
The fourth part of the directions.
"What's the Temple?"
Finally. It's like pulling teeth.
This is the flooded military town.
Shops, houses, a town square,
and this...
A church!
Whatever the coordinates
are for, it's in that church.
Find that and you're a hop, skip
and a jump to stopping them.
Wait, you're not suggesting that...
But we're safe now.
The ghosts are in the cage,
we can get out of here.
No one has to stay.
In fact, I would prefer it if you went.
You'll get in the way and ask
ridiculous questions. But...
You know, you have chosen
to protect and serve.
You have given yourself
to science and the pursuit of knowledge.
None of you have chosen
anonymous or selfish lives.
Go, and a part of you
will always wonder,
"What would have happened if I'd stayed?
"How could I have helped?
What would I have learned?”
I want you to go.
But you should know
what it is that you're leaving.
Cass says we should go,
but everything that happens here
is her responsibility now...
So she's going to stay.
So I, uh, guess I should, too.
Oh, count me in.
Who wants to live forever, anyway?
Sorry, um, have you gone insane?
We can go home.
They're ghosts though.
How can they be ghosts?
Well, at least if I die,
you know I really will
come back and haunt you, all.
BENNETT: OK,
the sub is approaching the town square.
Which way is the church?
O'DONNELL: North-northwest, 150 yards.
That's it. Starboard, 2 degrees.
CLARA: What are we looking for, exactly?
DOCTOR: Something that has
the power to raise the dead
and turn them into transmitters.
I expect we'll know it when we see it.
BENNETT: Wait, I've found the church.
DOCTOR: That's it, keep going.
Wait...
What's that?
Move closer.
It's the suspended animation chamber
from the spaceship.
So the pilot could be in there.
There's something inside there.
But it's dead-lock sealed,
I can't open it.
It should be the pilot, it should be.
So why do I think it isn't?
More questions.
Everything I solve, just more questions.
I have to go back to the beginning.
We arrive, we see the ghosts.
They don't kill us.
They lead us here,
they show us the spaceship.
Then they try to kill us.
Not translated by the Tardis. Why?
Lunn, translate for me.
Whenever I step outside,
you are the smartest person in the room.
So, tell me. What's weird about this?
I know that it's all bonkers,
but, you know, when you think about it,
one thing keeps snagging
in your mind. What is it?
"The markings on the inside
of the spaceship.”
The markings on the inside
of the spaceship. Yes!
Why?
-"I don't think they're just words."
-They're not.
They're magnets.
Magnets, how?
Well, a localised and manufactured
electromagnetic field to be precise.
The dark. The sword.
The forsaken. The temple.
When we heard the coordinates
for the first time,
did anyone expect them not to be that?
No, exactly. Me neither.
It's like we already knew somehow.
Like the words were already in us.
So that writing is the coordinates?
Everything we see
or experience shapes us in some way.
But these words actually rewrite
the synaptic connections in your brain.
They literally change the way
you are wired.
Clara, why don't I have
a radio in the Tardis?
You took it apart and used the pieces
to make a clockwork squirrel.
And because whatever song
I heard first thing in the morning,
I was stuck with.
Two weeks of
Mysterious Girl by Peter Andre.
I was begging for the brush
of death's merciful hand.
Don't you see?
These words are an ear-worm.
A song you can't stop humming
even after you die.
CLARA: OK,
so the spaceship lands here.
The pilot leaves the writing on the wall
so whoever sees it, when they die,
they become a beacon of the coordinates,
while he, slash she, slash it
snoozes in the suspended
animation chamber.
Waiting for his, slash her,
slash its mates to pick the message up.
My God.
Every time I think it couldn't
get more extraordinary, it surprises me.
It's impossible! I hate it!
It's evil! It's astonishing!
I want to kiss it to death.
COMPUTER VOICE: Attention, all crew.
Evacuate base immediately.
Emergency protocols have been initiated.
This safety message
was brought to you by Vector Petroleum.
-Fuel for our futures.
-Oh, no!
The ghosts tampering
with the day/night settings has caused
a computer malfunction.
Its first priority
is to keep the reactor cool,
so it's opening the hull doors
and is flooding the base.
LUNN: Cass says,
"Close the internal flood doors.
"That'll contain the water
in the central corridor."”
-Where's the Tardis?
-O'DONNELL: On the other side.
DOCTOR: We need to get there.
It's our only way out.
OK, we've got 30 seconds
before the flood doors close.
(PANTING)
Come on!
Doctor!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
DOCTOR: I'll get you and the others out.
Sit tight, I'll come back for you.
CLARA: Just come over here
in the Tardis now.
The Tardis won't go there.
It won't go near the ghosts.
You can't just leave us!
Listen to me. I'm going back in time
to when the spaceship landed.
If I can understand
why this is happening,
I can stop them killing anyone else.
I can save you.
You trust me, don't you, Clara?
Wait, you're gonna go back in time?
How do you do that?
Extremely well.
"You're sure
they're not going to hurt us?"
They can't get out of the Faraday cage.
(CLANKING)
(WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: Back to before the flood.
"And you're sure the Doctor
won't just leave us here?”
Guys, look. This is how we roll.
He's gonna go away, come back,
and we'll have to listen
to how he did it.
LUNN: Is it Moran? Or Pritchard?
Or the mole guy?
How... How'd they get out?
No, I don't think
it's any of them, I think it's...
A new ghost.
-What does that mean?
-Well, it means that
something happened in the past,
it means that somebody else must have...
Oh, no!
Oh, no, no, no, no.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Another ghost has appeared.
What does it mean?
I have to die.
DOCTOR: 7his is the town
before it flooded.
I need to know how you
create these creatures.
Nothing but words.
He's opened the Faraday cage.
He's let the other ghosts out.
DOCTOR: This isn't about saving me.
I am a dead man walking.
So, who's next?