Martha, have you met my friend?
MARTHA: Always wanted to go to New York.
November 1st 71930.
You only come to Hooverville
when there's nowhere else to go.
Men going missing, is this true?
Laszlo?
DALEX: The Empire State Building
must be completed in time.
-Are you trying to kill us?
-Don't argue with me!
This human is our best option.
No!
The Final Experiment will begin.
The children of Skaro must walk again.
What is it?
I am a human Dalek.
These humans will become like me.
Prepare them for hybridisation.
(PIG SLAVES SNORTING)
MARTHA: Leave me alone. Don't you dare!
(HAPPY DAYS ARE HERE AGAIN PLAYING)
What is that sound?
Ah, well now, that would be me.
Hello. Surprise! Boo! Etcetera.
-Doctor?
-The enemy of the Daleks!
-Exterminate!
-Wait!
Well, then, a new form of Dalek.
Fascinating and very clever.
The Cult of Skaro
escaped your slaughter.
How did you end up in 19307
Emergency temporal shift.
Oh, that must've roasted up
your power cells, eh?
Time was, four Daleks
could've conquered the world!
But instead, you're skulking away,
hidden in the dark, experimenting.
-All of which results in you.
-I am Dalek in human form.
But what does it feel like?
You can talk to me, Dalek Sec.
It is Dalek Sec, isn't it,
that's your name?
You've got a name
and a mind of your own.
Tell me what you're thinking right now.
I feel humanity.
Good, that's good.
I feel everything
we wanted from mankind,
which is ambition,
hatred, aggression and war.
Such a genius for war...
-No, that's not what humanity means.
-I think it does!
At heart, this species is so very Dalek.
All right,
so what have you achieved, then,
with this Final Experiment, eh? Nothing!
'Cause I can show you
what you're missing with this thing.
A simple, little radio.
What is the purpose of that device?
Well, exactly.
It plays music.
What's the point of that?
Oh, with music, you can dance to it,
sing with it,
fall in love to it.
Unless you're a Dalek, of course.
Then it's all just noise.
(SHRILL BUZZING)
-Run!
-Protect the hybrid!
Protect! Protect! Protect!
Report status.
Pain. Pain of the flesh
like no Dalek has felt
for thousands of years.
-The Doctor has escaped!
-DALEK SEC: Then find him! Find him!
Find the Doctor.
The prisoners must be recaptured.
Come on! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
-And you, Tallulah, run!
-What's happened to Laszlo?
Come on, everyone up! Come on! Come on!
They have ascended.
Return to base!
Request information.
What is your opinion of Dalek Sec?
We were created to follow him.
But you have doubts?
Affirmative.
SOLOMON: These Daleks,
they sound like the stuff of nightmares.
And they want to breed?
They're splicing themselves
on to human bodies.
And, if I'm right, they've got
a farm of breeding stock,
right here in Hooverville.
You've got to get everyone out.
Hooverville's the lowest place
a man can fall.
There's nowhere else to go.
I'm sorry, Solomon,
you've got to scatter, go anywhere,
get on to the railroads,
travel across state,
just get out of New York.
There's got to be a way
to reason with these things.
-There's not a chance.
-You ain't seen 'em, boss.
Daleks are bad enough at any time,
but right now, they're vulnerable.
That makes them
more dangerous than ever.
(SNORTING)
-They're coming! They're coming!
-A sentry must have seen something.
They're here, I've seen them!
Monsters! They're monsters!
It's started.
We're under attack! Everyone to arms!
I'm ready, boss.
But all of you, find a weapon!
Use anything!
Come back! We've got to stick together.
It's not safe out there, come back!
(SNORTING)
WOMAN: Hurry, hurry! Come on!
-We need to get out of the park.
-We can't.
They're on all sides. They're driving
everyone back towards us.
-TALLULAH: We're trapped.
-Then we stand together!
Gather round! Everybody come to me!
You there, Jethro, Harry,
Seamus, stay together.
They can't take all of us!
If we can just hold them off
till daylight...
Oh, Martha,
they're just the foot soldiers.
Oh, my God!
-What in this world...
-It's the devil. A devil in the sky.
-God save us all, it's damnation.
-Oh, yeah? We'll see about that!
That's not gonna work.
Establish visual contact.
Commence the attack.
There's more than one of them.
(ALL SCREAMING)
The humans will surrender!
Leave them alone,
they've done nothing to you!
We have located the Doctor.
No, Solomon, stay back!
I'm told that I'm addressing
the Daleks. Is that right?
DALEK SEC: Observe humanity.
For all their faults,
they have such courage.
From what I hear, you're outcasts, too.
-Solomon, don't.
-Doctor, this is my township.
SOLOMON: You will respect my authority.
Just let me try.
Daleks, ain't we the same?
Underneath, ain't we all kin?
"Cause you see,
I've just discovered, this past day,
that God's universe is a thousand times
the size I thought it was.
And that scares me. Oh, yeah,
terrifies me right down to the bone.
But surely, it's got to give me hope,
hope that, maybe together,
we can make a better tomorrow.
So I beg you now,
if you have any compassion
in your hearts,
then you'll meet with us
and stop this fight.
Well?
What do you say?
Exterminate.
(SCREAMING)
Solomon!
No! Solomon!
They killed him.
They just shot him on the spot.
Daleks!
All right. So it's my turn.
Then kill me.
Kill me, if it'll stop you
attacking these people.
I will be the destroyer
of our greatest enemy!
Then do it! Do it! Just do it!
Do it!
-Exterminate.
-Stop! I command you, stop!
I do not understand. It is the Doctor!
-But I want him alive.
-The urge to kill is too strong.
I have decided. The Doctor must live.
And you will obey me!
I obey.
-What's going on?
-DALEK SEC: Bring him to me.
-You will follow.
-No. You can't go.
I've got to go.
The Daleks just changed their minds,
Daleks never change their minds.
But what about us?
One condition.
If I come with you,
you spare the lives of everyone here.
Do you hear me?
Obey the Doctor.
Humans will be spared. Doctor, follow.
-Then I'm coming with you.
-Martha, stay here.
Do what you do best.
People are hurt, you can help them.
Let me go.
Oh, and can I just say
thank you very much.
You saved the Doctor. Why?
He's a genius
and we can use him.
The future of the Daleks
might well depend upon the Doctor.
MAN: Somebody help me!
Here you go,
I got some more on the boil.
Thanks.
You'll be all right, it's just a cut.
Try and keep it clean.
Thanks.
So what about us? What do we do now?
The Doctor gave me this.
-He must've had a reason.
-What's that for?
It gets you into places.
Buildings and things.
-But where?
-He must want me to go somewhere,
but what am I supposed to do?
Those people were defenceless!
You only wanted me, but no,
that wasn't enough for you,
you had to start killing,
'cause that's the only thing
a Dalek's good for.
The deaths were wrong.
I'm sorry?
That man, their leader, Solomon,
-he showed courage.
-And that's good?
That's excellent.
Is it me, or are you just becoming
a little bit more human?
You are the last of your kind.
And now I am the first of mine.
What do you want me for?
We tried everything to survive.
When we found ourselves
stranded in this ignorant age,
first we tried
growing new Dalek embryos,
but their flesh was too weak.
Yeah, I found one of your experiments
just left to die out there in the dark.
It forced us to conclude
what is the greatest resource
of this planet?
Its people.
We stole them.
We stole human beings for our purpose.
Look inside.
This is the true extent
of the Final Experiment.
-Is he dead?
-Near death.
With his mind wiped,
ready to be filled with new ideas.
-Dalek ideas.
-The human Dalek race.
All of these people... How many?
We have caverns beyond this
storing more than 1,000.
Is there any way to restore them,
to make them human again?
Everything that they were has been lost.
So they're like shells.
You got empty human beings
ready to be converted.
That's gonna take
a hell of a lot of power.
This planet
hasn't even split the atom yet.
How are you going to do it?
DALEK SEC: Open the conductor plan.
Wait a minute.
Down in the sewers, the Daleks
mentioned this energy conductor.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
Maybe like a lightning conductor, or...
-Dalekanium!
-Oh!
They said the Dalekanium was in place.
In place where?
-Frank might know.
-Right.
-Frank?
-Hmm?
That Mr Diagoras,
he was like some sort of fixer, yeah?
-Get you jobs all over town?
-Yeah, he could find a profit anywhere.
-But where, though? What sort of things?
-You name it.
We're all so desperate for work,
you'd just hope Diagoras
would pick you something good.
Building work, that pays the best.
But what sort of building work?
Mainly building that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
the Empire State Building.
We're right underneath that.
I worked that out already, thanks.
But what,
you've hijacked the whole building?
-We needed an energy conductor.
-What for?
I am the genetic template.
My altered DNA was to be administered
to each human body.
A strong enough blast of gamma radiation
can splice the Dalek
and human genetic codes
and waken each body from its sleep.
Gamma radiation? What...
Oh, the sun. You're using the sun.
Soon, the greatest solar flare
for 1,000 years will hit the Earth.
Gamma radiation
will be drawn to the energy conductor.
-And when it strikes...
-The army wakes.
I still don't know what you need me for.
Your genius.
Consider a pure Dalek.
Intelligent but emotionless.
Removing the emotions
makes you stronger.
That's what your creator thought
all those years ago.
-He was wrong.
-He was what?
It makes us lesser than our enemies.
We must return to the flesh
and also the heart.
You wouldn't be
the supreme beings any more.
-And that is good.
-That is incorrect!
-Daleks are supreme!
-No!
-Not any more.
-But that is our purpose!
Then our purpose is wrong!
Where has our quest for supremacy
led us?
To this. Hiding in the sewers
on a primitive world.
Just four of us left.
If we do not change now,
then we deserve extinction.
So you want to change everything
that makes a Dalek a Dalek?
If you can help me.
I've always wanted to go
to the Empire State!
I never imagined it
quite like this, though.
Where are we headed, anyway?
The top, where they're still building.
Hey, how come those guys
just let us through?
How does that thing work?
Psychic paper, shows them
whatever I want them to think.
According to this, we're two engineers
and an architect.
Your knowledge of genetic engineering
is even greater than ours.
The new race must be ready
by the time the solar flare erupts.
But you're the template. I thought
they were getting a dose of you.
-I want to change the gene sequence.
-To make them even more human.
Humans are the great survivors.
We need that ability.
Hold on a minute, though.
There's no way this lot
are gonna let you do it.
I am their leader.
-Oh, and that's enough for you, is it?
-Daleks must follow orders.
Dalek Sec commands. We obey.
If you don't help me,
nothing will change.
There's no room on Earth
for another race of people.
You have your Tardis.
Take us across the stars.
Find us a new home
and allow the new Daleks to start again.
-When's that solar flare?
-Eleven minutes.
Right, then!
Better get to work!
Look at this place!
Top of the world!
Okay, now this looks good.
Hey, look at the date.
These designs were issued today.
They must have changed something
last minute.
MARTHA: You mean
the Daleks changed something?
Yeah, could be.
The ones underneath,
they're from before.
That means whatever they changed must be
on this top sheet but not on this one.
-We need to check one against the other.
-All right.
The height of this place.
This is amazing!
Careful! We're 100 floors up,
don't go wandering off.
I just wanna see.
New York City.
If aliens had to come to Earth,
oh, no wonder they came here.
There's no point in
chromosomal grafting, it's too erratic.
We need to split the genome
and force the new Dalek human sequence
right into the cortex.
We need more chromatin solution.
The Pig Slaves have it.
These Pig Slaves,
what happens to them in the grand plan?
Nothing. They're just simple beasts.
Their life span is limited.
None survive beyond a few weeks.
Power up the line feeds.
Laszlo, I can't undo
what they've done to you.
But they won't do it to anyone else.
Do you trust him?
I know that one man
can change the course of history.
The right idea, in the right place,
at the right time, that's all it takes.
I've got to believe it's possible.
I'll go and keep an eye out,
make sure we're safe up here.
-Don't want nobody butting in.
-There's a hell of a storm moving in.
I wish the Doctor was here.
He'd know what we're looking for.
So tell me.
Where did you and him first hook up?
It was in hospital. Sort of.
"Course, him being a doctor.
Actually, I'm the doctor.
-Well, kind of.
-You're a physician?
Really?
I was training.
Still am, if I ever get back home.
You could be doctors together.
What a partnership!
Ah, such a shame.
If only he wasn't so different,
you know what I mean?
Oh, you have no idea
how different he really is.
Yeah, he's a man, sweetheart.
That's different enough.
He had this companion a while back,
this friend.
And ever since then,
he's been on his own.
But you know, sometimes,
I say something, or do something,
and he looks at me
and I just sort of think
that he's not seeing me.
He's just remembering.
Oh, listen, sweetheart,
you want to get all sad,
you want to have a contest
with me and Laszlo?
No.
But listen,
if the Doctor's with Laszlo now,
there's every chance
that he could get him out.
And then what?
Don't talk crazy.
There's no future for me and him.
Those Dalek things took that away.
The one good thing I had in my life
and they destroyed it.
The line feeds are ready.
-Then it's all systems go!
-The solar flare is imminent.
The radiation will reach Earth
in a matter of minutes.
And we'll be ready for it.
That compound will allow the gene bonds
to reconfigure in a brand new pattern.
Power up!
Start the line feeds.
-There goes the gene solution.
-The life blood.
Gotcha! Look!
There, on the mast, those little lines,
they're new.
They've added something, see?
Added what?
-Dalekanium!
(ALARM BLARING)
What's that?
What's happening?
Is there a malfunction?
Answer me!
No, no, no. The gene feed!
-They're overriding the gene feed.
-Impossible!
They cannot disobey orders.
The Doctor will step away
from the controls.
Stop! You will not fire!
He is an enemy of the Daleks.
And so are you.
I am your commander. I am Dalek Sec!
-You have lost your authority.
-You are no longer a Dalek.
What have you done?
What's going into the gene feed?
The new bodies will be 100% Dalek.
No! You can't do this!
Pig Slaves, restrain Dalek Sec
and the Doctor.
DALEK SEC: Release me!
I created you! I am your master!
DALEK: Solar flare approaching!
Prepare to intercept!
-There's the lift.
-After you.
DALEX: The Doctor is escaping.
Stop him! Stop him!
We've only got minutes
before the gamma radiation
reaches the earth.
We need to get
to the top of the building.
Laszlo, what's wrong?
Out of breath. It's nothing.
We escaped them, Doctor,
that's all that matters.
You have betrayed me.
You told us to imagine.
And we imagined your irrelevance.
I was your leader! I am Dalek Sec!
Obey me!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
-Doctor!
-First floor, perfumery.
I never thought I'd see you again!
No stopping me.
We've worked it out.
We know what they've done.
There's Dalekanium on the mast and
it's good to see you, too, by the way.
Oh, come here!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
See, never waste time with a hug!
-Deadlock seal, I can't stop it.
-Where's it going?
Back down to the Daleks and they aren't
gonna leave us alone up here.
-What's the time?
-11:15.
Six minutes to go!
I've got to remove the Dalekanium
before the gamma radiation hits.
Gammon radiation? What the heck is that?
Oh, that's high.
That's very... Blimey, that's high.
And we've got to go even higher.
That's the mast, up there, look.
There's three pieces of Dalekanium
on the base. We've got to get "em off.
That's not we, that's just me.
I'm not gonna just stand here
and watch you.
No, you're gonna have
your hands full anyway.
I'm sorry, Martha,
but you've got to fight.
Confirm time until solar intercept.
Gamma strike, four minutes and counting!
(BUZZING)
Pig Slaves will take the lift!
Find the Doctor! Kill him!
(PIG SLAVES SNORTING)
-The lift's coming up.
-I should have brought that gun.
Tallulah, stay back. You, too, Martha.
If they send Pig Slaves,
they're trained to kill.
The Doctor needs me to fight,
I'm not going anywhere.
But they're savages. I should know.
They're trained to slit your throat
with their bare teeth.
Laszlo, what is it?
No, it's nothing, I'm fine.
Just leave me.
Oh, honey, you're burning up.
What's wrong with you? Tell me!
One man down, we ain't even started yet.
-It's not looking good, Frank.
-No.
We're gonna get slaughtered.
Wait a minute.
Lightning!
You'll be all right, sweetheart.
Don't you worry.
What the hell are you two clowns doing?
Even if the Doctor stops the Dalekanium,
this place is still gonna get hit.
Great big bolt of lightning!
Electricity all down the building!
Connect this to the lift,
and they get zapped!
-Oh, my God, that could work!
-Then give us a hand!
Gamma strike imminent. In 40 rels,
39, 38,
37...
-TALLULAH: Is that gonna work?
-It's got to!
I got it all piped up
to the scaffolding outside.
Come here, Frank,
just sit in the middle.
-Don't touch anything metal!
-FRANK: Okay.
(SCREAMING)
I can't!
12, 71, 10...
...zero! Gamma strike!
(SCREAMING)
The army awakes.
You did it, Martha.
They used to be like Laszlo.
They were people.
And I killed them.
No. The Daleks killed them.
Long ago.
What about the Doctor?
You will identify.
-I am a Dalek.
-Excellent!
Begin the invasion of Manhattan.
The population
will be converted into Daleks.
And from this island,
we will conquer the world!
Assume battle positions! Take arms!
Doctor!
Doctor?
Look what we found.
Halfway down.
You're getting careless.
Oh, my head!
Hiya.
Hi.
-You survived, then.
-So did you.
Just about.
I can't help noticing
there's Dalekanium still attached.
War demands strategy.
I am designated Controller!
That was to be my position.
You are unfit!
Connect me to the military computer.
I will coordinate all units.
DOCTOR: The Daleks will have gone
straight to a war footing.
They'll be using the sewer system.
Spreading the soldiers out
underneath Manhattan.
-How do we stop them?
-There's only one chance.
I got in the way.
That gamma strike
went zapping through me first.
Yeah, but what does that mean?
We need to draw fire.
Before they can attack New York,
I need to face them.
Where can I draw them out?
Think, think, think, think, think.
I need some sort of space, somewhere
safe, somewhere out of the way.
-Tallulah!
-That's me, three L's and an H!
The theatre! It's right above them!
And what, it's gone midnight.
Can you get us inside?
-Don't see why not.
-Is there another Lift?
We came up in the service elevator.
That'll do! Allons-y!
DALEK: Report status!
Maximum efficiency!
I am now ready for full-scale war!
-Control over Dalek humans?
-Connection confirmed!
All soldiers will take heed!
Weapons will be primed!
This should do it. Here we go.
There ain't nothing more creepy
than a theatre in the dark.
Listen, Doctor, I know you've got
a thing for show tunes,
but there's a time and a place, huh?
Laszlo? What's wrong?
Nothing. It's just so hot.
But it's freezing in here.
Doctor, what's happening to him?
Not now, Tallulah, sorry.
What are you doing?
If the Daleks are going to war,
they'll want to find
their number one enemy.
I'm just telling them where I am.
Sonic device detected!
-The Doctor survived!
-Find him and exterminate!
I'm telling you to go.
Frank can take you back to Hooverville.
And I'm telling you, I'm not going.
Martha! That's an order!
Who are you then, some sort of Dalek?
(CRASHING)
Doctor! Oh, my God!
-Well, I guess that's them, then, huh?
-Humans with Dalek DNA?
It's all right.
All right, just stay calm.
-Don't antagonise them.
-But what of the Dalek masters?
Where are they?
Doctor located! Advance! Advance!
(SCREAMING)
DALEX:. The Doctor
will stand before the Daleks.
You will die, Doctor.
It's the beginning of a new age.
Planet Earth will become new Skaro!
Oh, and what a world.
With anything just the slightest bit
different ground into the dirt.
That's Dalek Sec! Don't you remember?
The cleverest Dalek ever
and look what you've done to him.
Is that your new empire? Hmm?
Is that the foundation
for a whole new civilisation?
My Daleks,
just understand this.
If you choose death and destruction,
then death and destruction
will choose you.
Incorrect! We always survive.
Now we will destroy our greatest enemy,
the Doctor.
DALEK SEC: But he can help you.
The Doctor must die!
-No, I beg you, don't...
-Exterminate!
(SCREAMING)
Your own leader.
The only creature who might have
led you out of the darkness,
and you destroyed him.
Did you see what they did? Huh?
Do you see what a Dalek really is?
Warning! Dalek humans
show increased levels of serotonin!
If I'm gonna die, let's give the new
boys a shot, what do you think, eh?
The Dalek humans. Their first blood.
Go on! Baptise them!
Dalek humans, take aim.
What are you waiting for?
Give the command!
Exterminate!
Obey! Dalek humans will obey!
They're not firing.
What have you done?
You will obey!
-Exterminate!
-Why?
-Daleks do not question orders!
-But why?
-You will stop this!
You must not question!
But you are not our master.
And we... We are not Daleks.
DOCTOR: No, you're not.
And you never will be.
Sorry.
I got in the way
of the lightning strike.
Time Lord DNA got all mixed up.
Just that little bit of freedom.
If they will not obey,
then they must die.
(SCREAMING)
Get down!
Exterminate!
Destroy the hybrids!
Destroy and exterminate!
It's all right, it's all right,
it's all right. You did it.
You're free.
The Dalek humans are failures/
Destruct! Destruct! Destruct!
(BUZZING)
No!
-They can't, they can't, they can't!
-What happened? What was that?
They killed them,
rather than let them live.
An entire species.
Genocide.
Only two of the Daleks
have been destroyed.
One of the Dalek masters
must still be alive.
Oh, yes.
In the whole universe,
just one.
-Now what?
-You will be exterminated!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Just think
about it, Dalek what-was-your-name?
Dalek Caan.
Your entire species has been wiped out
and now the Cult of Skaro
has been eradicated,
leaving only you.
Right now, you're facing
the only man in the universe
who might show you some compassion.
'Cause I've just seen one genocide.
I won't cause another.
Caan,
let me help you.
-What do you say?
-Emergency temporal shift!
(EXCLAIMS)
Doctor! Doctor!
He's sick.
(WHEEZING)
It's okay. You're all right.
(LASZLO GRUNTING)
It's his heart. It's racing like mad.
I've never seen anything like it.
TALLULAH: What is it, Doctor?
What's the matter with him?
He says he can't breathe. What is it?
It's time, sweetheart.
What do you mean, "time"?
What are you talking about?
None of the slaves survive for long.
Most of them only live for a few weeks.
I was lucky.
I held on 'cause I had you.
But now...
I'm dying, Tallulah.
No, you're not. Not now, after all this.
Doctor, can't you do something?
Oh, Tallulah, with three L's and an H,
just you watch me. What do I need?
Oh, I don't know, how about
a great, big genetic laboratory?
Oh, look! I've got one!
Laszlo, just you hold on!
There's been too many deaths today.
Way too many people have died.
Brand-new creatures and wise old men
and age-old enemies.
And I'm telling you,
I'm telling you right now,
I am not having one more death!
You got that? Not one!
Tallulah, out of the way.
The Doctor is in!
Well, I talked to them and I told them
what Solomon would've said,
and I reckon
I shamed one or two of them.
What did they say?
They said yes.
They'll give you a home, Laszlo.
I mean, don't imagine
people ain't gonna stare.
I can't promise you'll be at peace.
But, in the end,
that is what Hooverville is for.
People who ain't got nowhere else.
Thank you.
I...I can't thank you enough.
MARTHA: Do you reckon it's gonna work?
-Those two?
-I don't know.
Anywhere else in the universe,
I might worry about them.
But New York?
That's what this city's good at.
Give me your tired, your poor,
your huddled masses
and maybe the odd Pig Slave-Dalek
mutant hybrid, too.
-The pig and the showgirl!
-The pig and the showgirl.
Just proves it, I suppose.
There's someone for everyone.
Maybe.
I meant to say, I'm sorry.
What for?
Just 'cause that Dalek got away.
I know what that means to you.
Mmm.
Do you think you'll ever see it again?
Oh, yes.
One day.
Tonight, I'm going to perform a miracle.
Something's wrong.
I'm 76 years old and I am reborn.
-This is a friend of mine.
-Lovely to meet you, Mrs Jones.
Tish!
DOCTOR: You people
are in serious danger!
You need to get out of here right now!
No, get away from her!
There's one more.