Space, 1969.
No!
The Doctor we saw on the beach
is a future version,
200 years older than the one up there.
DOCTOR: Canton Everett Delaware III.
Who's he?
What the hell is that?
Mr President...
You didn't have to kill her,
she couldn't even remember you!
How does that work?
We can only remember you
while we're seeing you, is that it?
(GASPS)
Canton! Are you okay?
Doctor, I'm pregnant.
No!
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
Suspect directly ahead.
Coming to you now. Over.
(PANTING)
(CRIES OUT)
-Canton.
-Miss Pond.
-Is that a body bag?
-Yes, it is.
-It's empty.
-How about that?
Do you even know
why you're doing this, hey?
Can you even remember?
The warehouse?
It's that monster. Amy! Amy!
(INAUDIBLE SHOUTING)
-What the hell's going on?
-Look behind you.
There's nothing behind me!
-(SCREAMING)
-Look! Canton, look!
ALIEN: Canton.
(GUNSHOT)
MAN ON PA: All visitors
to remain behind the yellow line.
All visitors to remain behind
the yellow line.
We found Amy Pond.
She had strange markings on her arm.
Do you know what they are?
Why don't you ask her?
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(METALLIC CLATTER)
(CHITTERING)
I see you.
I see you!
-Dr Song.
-(GASPS)
Dr Song!
Go, go, go!
Don't move!
-It's over.
-They're here, Canton.
-They're everywhere.
-I know.
-America's being invaded.
-You were invaded a long time ago.
America is occupied.
You're coming with us, Dr Song.
There's no way out this time.
There's always a way out.
We found Dr Song.
These bricks, what are they made of?
-Where is she?
-She ran.
Off the 50th floor.
I'd say zero-balanced dwarf star alloy.
The densest material in the universe.
Nothing gets through that.
You're building me the perfect prison.
And it still won't be enough.
-What are you waiting for?
-I'm waiting for you to run.
It'd look better if I shot you
while you were running.
Then again, looks aren't everything.
(GUNSHOT)
Is there a reason you're doing this?
I want you to know where you stand.
In a cell.
In a perfect cell.
Nothing can penetrate these walls.
Not a sound, not a radio wave.
Not the tiniest particle of anything.
In here, you are literally cut off
from the rest of the universe.
(CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
So I guess they can't hear us, right?
-Good work, Canton. Door sealed?
-You bet.
(BOTH GASPING)
-You okay?
-Finally.
These things
could really do with air holes.
Never had a complaint before.
Isn't it going to look odd that
you're staying in here with us?
Odd, but not alarming.
They know
there's no way out of this place.
Exactly. Whatever they might think
we're doing in here,
they know we're not going anywhere.
Shall we?
What about Dr Song?
-She dove off a rooftop!
-Don't worry. She does that.
Amy, Rory,
open all the doors to the swimming pool.
So, we know they're everywhere.
Not just a landing party,
an occupying force.
And they've been here
a very, very long time.
But nobody knows that,
"cause no one can remember them.
-So what are they up to?
-No idea.
But the good news is...
we've got a secret weapon.
Apollo 71'syour secret weapon?
No, no, it's not Apollo 71,
that would be silly.
It's Neil Armstrong's foot.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
RADIO NEWSREADER: In just a few days
mankind will set foot on the moon
for the first time.
Today the President reaffirmed
America's commitment...
(RADIO OFF)
Ready. Check.
-Clear.
-Ow!
-Ha! So, three months.
-What have we found out?
-Well, they are everywhere.
-Every state in America. Ow!
-Not just America, the entire world.
There's a greater concentration
here, though.
Ow!
You okay?
-All better.
-Better?
Turns out I was wrong.
I'm... I'm not pregnant.
-What's up?
-Nothing.
(CHUCKLES) Really, nothing, seriously.
So you've seen them,
but you don't remember them.
You've seen them, too.
That night at the warehouse, remember?
While you were pretending
to hunt us down,
we saw hundreds of those things.
We still don't know what they look like.
It's like they edit themselves
out of your memory
as soon as you look away.
The exact second you're not looking
at them, you can't remember anything.
Sometimes you feel a bit sick, though,
but not always.
So that's why you marked your skin?
Only way we'd know
if we'd had an encounter.
How long have they been here?
That's what we've spent the last
three months trying to find out.
Not easy, if you can't remember
anything you discover.
But how long do you think?
As long as there's been something
in the corner of your eye
or creaking in your house
or breathing under your bed
or voices through a wall.
They've been running your lives
for a very long time now,
so keep this straight in your head.
We are not fighting an alien invasion.
We're leading a revolution.
And today the battle begins.
-How?
-Like this.
-Ow!
-(LAUGHS)
Nano recorder.
Fuses with the cartilage in your hand.
Ow! Then it tunes itself directly
to the speech centres in your brain.
It'll pick up your voice,
no matter what. Telepathic connection.
So, the moment you see
one of the creatures, you activate it
and describe aloud
exactly what you're seeing.
DOCTOR: And describe aloud
Because the moment you break contact,
you're going to forget it happened.
The light will flash if
you've left yourself a message.
You keep checking your hand.
If you've had an encounter,
that's the first you'll know about it.
Why didn't you tell me this
before we started?
I did. But even information about
these creatures erases itself over time.
I couldn't refresh it
'cause I couldn't talk to you.
(THUDDING)
What?
-What are you staring at?
-Look at your hand.
Why's it doing that?
What does it mean if the light's
flashing? What did I just tell you?
-I haven't...
-Play it.
CANTON: My God, how did it get in here?
DOCTOR: Keep eye contact with
the creature and when I say,
turn back, and when you do,
straighten my bow tie.
CANTON: What? What are you staring at?
RIVER: Look at your hand.
It's a hologram, extrapolated
from the photo on Amy's phone.
Take a good long look.
You just saw an image
of one of the creatures we're fighting.
Describe it to me.
-I can't.
-No.
Neither can I.
You straightened my bow tie
because I planted the idea in your head
-while you were looking at the creature.
-So they could do that to people.
You could be doing stuff and
not really knowing why you're doing it.
Like post-hypnotic suggestion.
Ruling the world
with post-hypnotic suggestion?
Now then, a little girl in a space suit.
They got the suit from NASA,
but where did they get the girl?
-Could be anywhere.
-Except they probably stayed
close to that warehouse,
"cause why bother doing anything else?
And they take her from somewhere
that will cause
the least amount of attention.
But you'll have to find her.
I'm off to NASA.
CANTON: Find her? Where do we look?
Children's homes.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
-Hello?
-FBI.
You must be Dr Renfrew. Can we come in?
-The children are asleep.
-We'll be very quiet.
Is there a problem?
-It's about a missing child.
-Well, what are you...
Yes, yes, come in, please.
This way.
Please excuse the writing. It...
(CHUCKLES) ...keeps happening.
I try to clean it up.
-It's the kids, yeah? They do that?
-Yes. The children.
It must be, yes.
Anyway, my office is this way.
We nearly didn't come to this place.
I understood Graystark Hall
was closed in '67.
-That's the plan, yes.
-The plan?
-Not long now.
-It's 1969.
Uh, no, no. We close in '67.
That's the plan, yes.
You misunderstood me, sir.
It's 1969 now.
Why are you saying that?
Of course it isn't.
July.
(MUMBLING) My office is this way,
this way.
-I'll check upstairs.
-Be careful.
-(MOBILE BLEEPS)
-Amy?
I think we've found the place
she was taken from.
-How do you know?
-'Cause those things have been here.
But the whole place is deserted.
There's just one guy here
and I think he's lost it.
Repeated memory wipes
fry your head eventually.
Find out what you can
but don't hang around.
Where are you?
Gotta go. Got company.
Don't worry. I put everything
back the way I found out.
Oh, except this. There's always a bit
left over, isn't there?
(STEADY BEEPING)
(GASPS)
AMY: I can see them, but I think
they're asleep. Get out! Just get out!
(GASPS)
(CHITTERING QUIETLY)
(BIN CLATTERS, ALIEN CHITTERING)
(SIGHS)
Now, one more time, sir.
How the hell did you get
into the command module?
I told you!
I'm on a top-secret mission
for the President.
Well, maybe if you'd just get President
Nixon to assure us of that, sir,
that would be swell.
I sent him a message.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Hello. I believe it's Mr Gardner,
is that correct? Head of security?
Ah, yes, sir. Yes, Mr President.
-Mr Grant, is it?
-Yes, Mr President.
The hopes and dreams of millions
of Americans stand here today,
at Cape Kennedy, and you're
the men who guard those dreams.
On behalf of the American people,
I thank you.
You're welcome, Mr President.
I understand you have a baby on the way,
Mr Grant?
Yes, Mr President.
What are you hoping for,
a boy or a girl?
-Just a healthy American, sir.
-(CHUCKLES)
A healthy American will do just nicely.
(CHUCKLING)
Now, fellas, listen. This man here,
code name The Doctor, is doing
some work for me personally.
Could you, uh, cut him a little slack?
Er, Mr President,
he did break into Apollo 71.
Well, I'm sure he had
a very good reason for that. (CHUCKLES)
Uh, but I need you to release him now,
so he can get on
with some very important work
for the American people.
-Could you do that for me?
-Well...
Son, I am your Commander in Chief.
Uh, then I guess that would be fine,
Mr President.
Glad to hear it.
Thank you! Bye-bye.
Carry on, gentlemen.
(CLEARS THROAT) America salutes you.
This place, it's been closed for years.
What have you been doing?
Oh, the child,
she must be cared for.
It's important.
That's what they said.
That's what who said?
(DOOR OPENS, AMY GASPS)
Hello. Who are you?
No, I think she's just dreaming.
Hello?
I saw you looking through the hatch...
(GASPS)
How... How can that be me?
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Who are you? I don't understand,
so just tell me who you are!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to shoot you.
I'm glad I missed.
But you killed the Doctor.
Or you're...you're going to kill him.
But who are you?
Just please tell me,
because I don't understand!
Please help me.
Help me, please.
(SCREAMS)
(THUMPING)
Oh. It's just some questions.
Yes, I see.
Who was that? Dr Renfrew?
Who was that?
Who was who?
What are you? You can tell me.
'Cause I won't remember.
You invaded us. You're everywhere.
AMY: Help me! Please.
Canton, please, will you help me!
-Are you armed?
-This world is ours.
We have ruled it
since the wheel and the fire.
-We have no need of weapons.
-Yeah?
Welcome to America.
Amy!
You have to tape everything
that happens in this office, every word.
Or we won't know
if you're under the influence.
Doctor, you have to give me
more than this.
-What were you doing to Apollo 777
-A thing. A clever thing.
Now, no more questions.
You have to trust me and nobody else.
Doctor! It's Canton!
Quick, he needs us!
AMY: Help me! Please, I can't...
I can't see! Somebody help me!
Amy!
Amy, can you hear me?
Amy, I'm going to try to blow the lock.
I need you to stand back.
-Okay, gun down, I've got it!
-Amy, we're here. Are you okay?
AMY: I can't see! (SOBBING)
Where is she, Doctor?
-It's empty.
-AMY: It's dark, so dark.
I don't know where I am.
(SOBBING) Please, can anybody hear me?
They took this out of her.
How did they do that, Doctor?
(AMY SOBBING)
And, and... Why can I still hear her?
Is it a recording?
Um, it defaults to live.
This is current.
Wherever she is right now,
this is what she's saying.
Amy, can you hear me?
We're coming for you.
Wherever you are, we're coming, I swear.
She can't hear you.
I'm so sorry. It's one-way.
She can always hear me, Doctor.
Always, wherever she is.
And she always knows that I am coming
for her, do you understand me?
Always.
AMY: Doctor, are you out there?
Can you hear me? Doctor?
Oh, God. Please, please, Doctor,
Just get me out of this.
He's coming. I'll bring him, I swear.
Hello, is somebody there? Who...
I, I think someone has been shot.
I think we should help. We...
I can't... I can't remember.
Okay.
Who and what are you?
Silence, Doctor.
We are the Silence.
-Rory, listen to that.
-Silence?
-We ran from the Silence?
-Silence.
And Silence will fall.
-Hello, again.
-Sir, you've been in there for days.
-What the hell have you been doing?
-Doesn't matter.
I need Dr Shepherd here right now.
Sir, I need to talk to Colonel Jefferson
right now.
No, you really don't.
Uh...
Hi, fellas.
I'm President Nixon.
I want to tell you,
on behalf of the American people,
how much we appreciate
all of your hard work.
MISSION CONTROL: 7he target
for the Apollo 11 astronauts,
the moon, at liftoff. will be
at a distance of 218,096 miles away.
We're just past
the two-minute mark on the countdown.
T minus one minute 54 seconds
and counting.
Our status board indicates...
It's an exo-skeleton.
Basically, life support.
There's about 20 different kinds
of alien tech in here.
Who was she? Why put her in here?
Put this on,
you don't even need to eat.
The suit processes sunlight directly.
It's got built-in weaponry
and a communications system
that can hack into anything.
Including the telephone network?
-Easily.
-But why phone the President?
It defaults to the highest authority
it can find.
The little girl gets frightened,
the most powerful man on Earth
gets a phone call.
The night terrors
with a hotline to the White House.
You won't learn anything
from that envelope, you know.
Purchased on Earth, perfectly
ordinary stationery, Tardis blue.
Summoned by a stranger
who won't even show his face.
That's a first for me. How about you?
Our lives are back to front.
Your future's my past,
your firsts are my lasts.
-Not really what I asked.
-Ask something else, then.
What are the Silence doing?
Raising a child?
Keeping her safe.
Even giving her independence.
The only way to save Amy is to work out
what the Silence are doing.
-I know.
-Every single thing we learn about them
-brings us a step closer.
-Yeah, Doctor, I get it, I know.
Of course, it's possible
she's not just any little girl.
Well, I'd say she's human,
going by the life support software.
-But?
-She climbed out of this suit.
Like, she forced her way out.
She must be incredibly strong.
Incredibly strong and running away.
I like her.
-We should be trying to find her.
-Yes, I know, but how?
Anyway, I have the strangest feeling
she's going to find us.
MISSION CONTROL: Apollo 11,
this is Houston, do you read? Over.
(WHITE NOISE)
Why does it look like a NASA space suit?
Because that's what the Silence do.
Think about it.
They don't make anything themselves.
They don't have to. They get
other life forms to do it for them.
-So they're parasites, then?
-Super parasites.
Standing in the shadows of human history
since the very beginning.
We know they can influence
human behaviour any way they want.
If they've been doing that on
a global scale for thousands of years...
Then what?
Then why did the human race
suddenly decide to go to the moon?
Ten, nine,
ignition sequence start,
six, five four...
Because the Silence needed a space suit.
MISSION CONTROL: ...one, zero,
all engines firing.
Liftoff. We have a liftoff.
Thirty-two minutes past the hour,
liftoff on Apollo 11.
My God!
-What is it?
-It's just an alien, Dr Shepherd.
-Someone's already been treating it.
-Yeah. You've been treating it.
Does Colonel Jefferson know
this thing is here?
-No.
-Then I'm going to tell him right now!
-Again?
-Sorry, what?
Exactly.
Sergeant, why was I called in here
for no reason?
You tend to my wounds.
You are foolish.
Why? What would you do in my place?
We have ruled your lives
since your lives began.
You should kill us all on sight,
but you will never remember
we were even here.
Your will is ours.
Yeah, well, sorry to disappoint you,
but thanks.
It's exactly what I needed to hear.
This is a video phone.
Whatever a video phone is.
You should kill us all on sight.
(AMY SOBBING)
This suit, it seems to be
repairing itself. How is it doing that?
Doctor, a unit like this,
would it ever be able to move
without an occupant?
-Why?
-Well, the little girl said
the spaceman was coming to eat her.
Maybe that's exactly what happened.
AMY: I love you.
I know you think it's him.
I know you think it ought to be him.
But it's not, it's you.
And when I see you again
I'm going to tell you properly,
Just to see your stupid face.
My life was so boring before you
Just dropped out of the sky.
So just get your stupid
face where I can see it. Okay?
Okay? (SOBBING)
She'll be safe for now.
No point in a dead hostage.
Can't you save her?
I can track that signal back.
Take us right to her.
-Then why haven't you?
-Because then what?
I find her and then what do I do?
This isn't an alien invasion,
they live here.
This is their empire.
This is kicking the Romans out of Rome.
Rome fell.
I know. I was there.
So was I.
Personal question.
Seriously, you?
Do you ever remember it?
2,000 years, waiting for Amy?
The Last Centurion?
-No.
-Are you lying?
-Course I'm lying.
-Course you are.
Not the sort of thing anyone forgets.
But I don't remember it all the time.
It's like there's a door in my head.
-(AMY SOBBING)
-I can keep it shut.
Please, please, please come and get me.
Come and get me. (SOBBING)
Okay, all flight controllers,
GO/NO-GO for landing?
NEWSCASTER: Just five days since
Apollo 11 blasted off from Cape Kennedy,
this unprecedented journey
is reaching its crucial moment.
Armstrong and Aldrin
are making their descent
to the surface of the moon.
MISSION CONTROL: ...on the ground.
You got a bunch of guys
about to turn blue.
Where am I? Where is this?
(CHITTERING)
You are Amelia Pond.
You're ugly,
has anyone mentioned that to you?
We do you honour.
You will bring the Silence.
But your part will soon be over.
Whatever that means, you've made
a big mistake bringing me here,
"cause wait till you see
what's coming for you now.
You have been here many days.
No. I just got here.
You just put me in here.
Your memory is weak.
You have been here many days.
No. No, I can't have been.
You will sleep now.
Sleep.
-No! No! Get off me!
-Sleep.
-No! No! No!
(WHOOSHING)
Oh! Interesting.
Very Aickman Road,
I've seen one of these before.
Abandoned. Wonder how that happened?
Oh, well!
I suppose I'm about to find out.
Rory, River,
keep one Silent in eye shot at all times.
Oh, hello, sorry.
You're in the middle of something.
Just had to say, though,
have you seen what's on the telly?
Oh, hello, Amy, you all right?
Want to watch some television?
Ah, now, stay where you are.
'Cause look at me, I'm confident.
You want to watch that, me,
when I'm confident.
Oh, and this is my friend River.
Nice hair, clever, has her own gun,
and unlike me, she really doesn't mind
shooting people. I shouldn't like that
-but I kind of do a bit.
-Thank you, sweetie.
I know you're team players
and everything,
but she'll definitely kill
at least the first three of you.
-Well, the first seven, easily.
-Seven, really?
-Oh, eight for you, honey.
-Stop it.
-Make me!
-Yeah, well, maybe I will.
Is this really important, flirting?
'Cause I feel like I should be
higher on the list right now.
Yes, right. Sorry.
As I was saying, my naughty friend here
is going to kill the first three of you
to attack, plus him behind.
So maybe you want to draw lots
or have a quiz.
-What's he got?
-Something, I hope.
Or maybe
you could just listen a minute,
because all I really want to do
is accept your total surrender
and then I'll let you go in peace. Yes.
You've been interfering in human
history for thousands of years. Yes.
People have suffered and died.
But what's the point in two hearts
if you can't be a bit forgiving
now and then?
Ooh! The Silence.
You guys take that seriously, don't you?
Okay, you got me, I'm lying.
I'm not really going to let you go
that easily.
Nice thought, but it's not Christmas.
First, you tell me about the girl.
Who is she? Why is she important?
What's she for?
Yeah, we're getting
a picture of it here.
Guys, sorry,
but you're way out of time.
Now, come on, a bit of history for you.
Aren't you proud? Because you helped.
Now, do you know how many people
are watching this live on the telly?
Half a billion, and that's nothing,
"cause the human race
will spread out among the stars,
you just watch them fly.
Billions and billions of them,
for billions and billions of years.
And every single one of them
at some point in their lives
will look back at this man,
taking that very first step,
and they will never, ever forget it.
ALDRIN: Okay. Engine stopped.
ACA out of detent.
Descent Engine Command Override, off.
Oh. But they'll forget this bit.
-Ready?
-Ready.
(SIGNAL WARBLING)
(BEEPING)
ARMSTRONG: It's one small step
for man...
SILENCE: You should kill us all
on sight.
You should kill us all on sight.
You've given the order
for your own execution,
and the whole planet just heard you.
You should kill us all on sight.
ARMSTRONG: ...one giant leap
for mankind.
And one whacking great
kick up the backside for the Silence!
You just raised an army
against yourself.
And now, for a thousand generations,
you're going to be ordering
them to destroy you every day.
How fast can you run?
'Cause today's the day the human race
throw you off their planet.
They won't even know they're doing it.
I think quite possibly the word
you're looking for right now is,
"Oops!" Run! Guys, I mean us. Run!
(GUNS FIRING)
-I can't get her out!
-Go, just go!
We are not leaving without you!
Will you just get your stupid face
out of here!
Run! Into the Tardis, quickly!
Don't let them build to full power!
I know! There's a reason why
I'm shooting, honey!
-What are you doing?
-Helping.
You've got a screwdriver.
Go build a cabinet!
-That's really rude!
-Shut up and drive!
(GUN POWERS DOWN)
My old fella didn't see that, did he?
He gets ever so cross.
-So, what kind of doctor are you?
-Archaeology.
Love a tomb.
You can let me fly it!
Yeah, or we could go
where we're supposed to.
-What's the matter with you?
-You called me stupid.
-I always call you stupid.
-No, but...
My face.
I wasn't sure who you
were talking about.
-You know, me or...
-Him?
Well, you did say
"dropped out of the sky".
It's a figure of speech, moron!
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
(CHUCKLES) So we're safe again.
Safe? No, of course you're not safe.
There's about a billion other things
out there
just waiting to burn your whole world.
But if you want to pretend you're safe
just so you can sleep at night,
okay, you're safe.
But you're not really.
-Canton. Till the next one, eh?
-Looking forward to it.
Canton just wants to get married.
Helluva reason
to kick him out of the FBI.
I'm sure something can be arranged.
-I'm counting on you.
-Er, Doctor...
Canton here tells me you're...
You're from the future.
Hardly seems possible,
but I was wondering...
Should warn you.
I don't answer a lot of questions.
But I'm a president
at the beginning of his time.
Dare I ask?
Will I be remembered?
Oh, Dicky. Tricky Dicky.
They're never going to forget you.
-Say hi to David Frost for me.
-David Frost?
This person you want to marry.
-Black?
-Yes...
I know what people think of me,
but perhaps I'm a little more liberal...
...he is.
I think the moon is far enough
for now, don't you, Mr Delaware?
I figured it might be.
(EXHALES)
-You could come with us.
-I escape often enough, thank you.
And I have a promise to live up to.
You'll understand soon enough.
Okay, up to you.
-See you next time. Call me.
-What, that's it?
-(CHUCKLES) What's the matter with you?
-Have I forgotten something?
Oh, shut up.
Right. Okay. Interesting.
What's wrong?
You're acting like
we've never done that before.
We haven't.
-We haven't?
-Oh, look at the time, must be off.
Um, but it was very nice.
It was... It was good.
It was unexpected.
You know what they say,
there's a first time for everything.
And a last time.
Rory, I'm going to need
thermo couplings.
-The green ones and the blue ones.
-Okay, hold on.
-So.
-You're okay?
-Fine. Head's a bit weird.
There's lots of stuff
I can't quite remember.
After-effect of the Silence.
Natural enough.
That's not what I was asking.
You told me you were pregnant.
-Yes.
-Why?
Because I was. I mean, I...
I thought I was. Turns out I wasn't.
-No. Why did you tell me?
-Because you're my friend.
You're my best friend.
Hmm. Did you tell Rory?
AMY: No.
DOCTOR: Amy,
why tell me and not Rory?
-Why do you think?
-I don't know.
I travelled with you in this Tardis
for so long.
All that time.
If I was pregnant for some of it,
wouldn't it have had an effect?
Because I don't want to tell Rory
his baby might have three heads
or like a time head or something.
-What's a time head?
-I don't know, but what if it had one?
-A time head?
-Shut up, all right?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
AMY: Oi, stupid face!
Uh, yeah?
Hello.
I'm taking that away from you if
you're going to listen in all the time.
Okay, that's... That's a fair point.
But you should've told me
that you thought you were pregnant.
I'm a nurse, I'm good with pregnancy.
Not, as it turns out, that good.
-So can you stop being stupid?
-Er, no.
Never. I'm never,
ever going to stop being stupid!
So, this little girl,
it's all about her. Who was she?
Or we could just go off
and have some adventures.
Anyone in the mood for adventures?
"Cause I am. You only live once.
(SCANNER BEEPS)
(SIREN WAILING, HORNS HONKING)
(GIRL COUGHS)
Are you okay?
-Little girl...
-(GIRL COUGHING)
-Are you okay?
-It's all right.
It's quite all right.
I'm dying, but I can fix that.
It's easy, really. See?
Yo ho ho!
Our sensors picked you up.
Ship in distress.
It's dangerous here.
There is a monster aboard.
She leaves a mark on men's skin.
Hello, Doctor, what's happening to me?
You're stowaways!
-(LAUGHING)
-Amy, what are you doing?
Saving your life.
Okay with that, are you?
There's a stroppy, homicidal mermaid
trying to kill all.
(SCREECHING)
(AMY SCREAMING)
She's here.