Oh, yes! We are in Wales!
- Spectacular!
- What? How can you tell?
Oh!
That smell, that green,
that coastline, Ruby.
- Oh!
The rocks and the water, it never ends.
The war between the land and the sea.
Oh, you know what?
I've been to Wales twice.
- I went to see Shygirl in Cardiff.
- Oh.
And then I went to Mumbles
when I was about 16 because of a boy.
- I broke his heart, but there you go.
- Oh, bless him.
Mind you, Roger ap Gwilliam,
that's a bad example of the Welsh.
- Terrifying.
- Oh, yeah?
The most dangerous
prime minister in history.
He led the world to the brink of nuclear--
Wait, what year are you from?
2024.
Oh, yikes. Sorry. He was 2046.
Sorry, spoilers.
- Forget I said anything.
- No, no, no. Tell me what happened.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What is this?
Oh, it's a circle. Someone made this.
I'm sorry, man. I am sorry.
Aw. It looks like something
made by children, doesn't it?
Lucky charms and bird skulls.
Hey, there's little messages. Look.
"I miss you." That's all it says.
"Rest in peace, Mad Jack."
Aw, poor old Mad Jack.
Bless him, eh?
Looks like some sort of memorial.
All right,
don't be doing that to me.
Hey, it's locked!
You've locked it from the inside.
Doctor.
I hope you're not having a pee
'round the back.
Hmm...
Hiya. Um, have you seen my friend?
He was here. H-He's just, um--
Can you just w-wait there? J--
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Very clever.
Are you a part of this?
What-- What-- What have you done?
Did-- Did you do this?
Where is the Doctor?
Where is he? What have you done to him?
- Hello there.
- Ah.
Ooh, you must be mad.
Is that all you're wearing?
Yeah, I got kind of caught.
Um, the-the car broke down.
Oh, no.
Oh, you poor thing.
I know. What a day.
Um, wh-where is that?
Down there. What is it?
Oh, that's Glyngatwg,
if you'll forgive my pronunciation.
Which they don't.
I-- I haven't met you before, have I?
Well, I don't think so. Have you?
Uh, no, that was a different--
Uh, sorry, could you help me?
That, um, woman over there,
do you see her?
Of course I can. Who is she?
Um, this is gonna sound a bit mad.
But she's following me.
I think I may have trespassed
or something,
I dunno,
but could you just tell her I'm sorry?
Sorry for what?
Uh, I don't know.
Have I walked into something?
No, no, no, no. Sorry.
You're just going that way,
so could you just tell her that I'm fine?
She can go home.
Well, I'm intrigued now,
and it's no skin off my nose.
But once that's done,
get in the warm, both of you.
Whatever little game this is.
Oh, could you
ask her if she knows the Doctor?
Oh, do you need a doctor?
No, but can you just ask?
I'll try.
State on you.
Who goes out in this without a coat?
No, I've lost my things.
Sorry, it's kind of a long story.
Is it?
Um, I-I-- I don't suppose--
I'm a bit stuck.
- Have you got a room for the night?
- I have.
65 quid.
I haven't got anything in for breakfast,
but I can do yoghurt and toast.
Don't let her cook, for God's sake.
- Shut it.
- Don't let her cook.
Uh, no, that's fine.
I haven't got any cash on me.
C-C-Can I pay on my phone?
Can you what?
Can I pay with my phone?
Pay with your phone?
Yeah.
How do you pay with your phone?
Oh, well,
it's sort of like online banking,
but the phone can transfer money
from my account into--
Yes, you can pay with your phone.
Oh. Sorry. Thank you.
We're not quite the Dark Ages, young lady.
Despite what they say.
Well, apparently,
next week we're getting Christianity.
- Throw 'em to the lions.
Throw them to the lions
and watch them getting eaten alive.
With-With great big teeth
and the blood and things.
Drink?
Yeah, I-- I'll-- I'll have, um--
No, I'll just have a Coke.
Last of the big spenders.
'Ey, do-- do you mind if I ask,
that woman out there, can you see her?
Oh, she must be bloody freezing, mun.
Do you know who she is?
I've never seen her. Why? Who is she?
I don't know.
I rather think, in this sort of weather,
you should try asking her in.
Oh, no, no. She's-- She's not with me.
She's just following me.
What for?
I don't know.
But she's definitely following you?
Well, yeah, I think so. Yeah.
Five quid.
How much?
- Five quid.
Pardon me for stating the obvious,
but if there's a woman following you,
have you tried asking her why?
- No.
- Oh, my God!
I'll ask her now. I'm off home for my tea.
I'll send her in for a pie and a pint.
- Hey, you can pay on your magic phone.
- All right. Night, girls.
- Night then, Josh.
Safely home.
Um, could you ask her--
There was a friend of mine
in a yellow duffel coat.
Could you just ask her if she's seen him?
Black guy, 5'10''.
Yeah, I'll give it a go.
Cheerio, then.
See you tomorrow, Josh.
Following's the wrong word
because she doesn't approach.
She comes so far,
and it's like she stays away,
never comes any closer.
I can't think of a synonym
for keeping your distance.
I suppose to coin a new word,
in Latin, it would be semperdistans,
always distant.
She's semperdistans to you.
Oh, my God. Josh is running.
It's his wife shouting at him.
No, really though. He's running.
He saw that woman, and he ran away.
He ran away like the devil was on his bum.
What'd she say to him?
- I-I don't know.
- Who is she?
- I don't know!
It seems that Josh is semperdistans.
I wonder-- [sighs] I thought--
See, I was with my friend,
and we walked into this thing
up on the clifftops.
Like, a circle of cotton,
little toy things,
like charms and skulls of birds.
I-- Just, like,
a witchcraft sort of thing.
What you mean cotton?
Like strands with these things.
Witchcraft is a very strong word.
No, no, no, no. I did not mean witchcraft.
I just meant it's like--
Where was it?
Up on the cliffs, a couple miles that way.
It's what they call a fairy circle.
You can ask him about that.
Shut your face.
When you say you walked into it,
did you break it?
Well, it-- [sighs] Yeah.
Uh, no. But it was by mistake.
I mean, it's not magic, is it?
Is it not?
The clifftops are a boundary
between the land and the sea.
A liminal space, neither here nor there,
where rules are suspended.
And then there's the blood.
What-- What blood?
Do you know why Wales
has so many picturesque little castles?
No.
They were torture centres set up
by the English to rule with fear.
Steeped in blood, we are.
Tons of blood.
This land is a powerful place.
It's said that he walks through the gaps.
The spiteful one.
No, but it was by accident.
My friend--
He would never disrespect a circle
or do anything like that.
And I walked away as soon as
it said "rest in peace".
What did?
The messages. The little scrolls.
- You read them?
- J-Just a couple.
You opened them and read them?
Why did you do that?
Well, they were there!
I think whatever spell was cast
in this circle is now broken.
What else did they say?
- It was just, um--
- What else did they say?
O-One said, "Rest in peace."
-"Rest in peace, Mad Jack."
- Oh, my God.
I think, perhaps, that wasn't wise.
No, I-I just thought it was someone's dog
or something.
Say that to Mad Jack's face.
Why? Who was he?
- He was insane.
And he's dead!
But now she's broken the circle.
Yeah, but what does that mean?
The charm was very clear.
Binding his soul to rest in peace.
Semperdistans to keep him away.
But now you've broken it.
And if that woman outside is his herald,
that means Mad Jack is unbound.
- Oh, don't.
He'd kill me. He would kill me!
I'm the one he'd kill first,
and you know why, don't you?
What the hell have you done?
- No, that's just someone at the door.
No, no, no. But he'd go home!
He wouldn't have come here. He'd go home!
There's no home to go to, you idiot.
Not anymore.
He drank in this pub.
He called this place home.
That is not Mad Jack out there!
Then answer the door.
It's him. It's him.
Oh, my God. It's him.
Hurry up. I've got my hands full.
You've got enough pasties here
to last two weeks!
Get 'em in the freezer fast.
- What's so funny?
Her face! Oh, my God, her face.
Best one yet, that was.
His herald, I loved that bit.
It's racist, my dear, to be blunt.
People come from outside,
they think we're all witches and druids.
For God's sake, child,
you walked into a piece of string.
Can I stand you a pint, Eddie?
Don't mind if I do.
Got those spare.
I'll have them back, mind.
I said to Josh--
I said, "We haven't seen you."
He said, "I'm never coming back."
I said, "Why?" And he said, "Ask her."
So, I'm asking you, why?
I think he meant ask her.
Well, I made it very clear to Josh
you will be packing and going.
And we won't see you again as of today.
Is that understood?
Look, maybe I should just go home.
I haven't even known you
for that long anyway, but--
You know, maybe t-this--
this is what you do.
But if you come back...
...I would love to see you again.
God, I-I-I'd just absolutely love it.
Okay.
Bye-bye.
I'm going now!
Okay?
You win!
This is the Great Western Railway service
to London Paddington.
- Here she is, here she is, here she is.
- All safe and sound.
- Love you.
She's back!
I told her that man was no good
with his box of magic tricks!
Some kind of guzum.
Maybe the Doctor went inside his box and--
That's what men do.
They go into their sheds and they potter.
They have train sets and hobbies,
and things women should never know about.
I mean, I don't know.
I've never had a garden. Never had a shed.
I've never had a man.
But that's what they say.
And your intergalactic nutcase is doing it
on a cosmic scale.
But he's still, essentially,
inside his shed pottering.
He must be!
Look, I-I didn't tell you everything.
There's this woman.
This is what we'll do!
If I can approach her,
then I'll phone you.
I'll walk up to her like this.
- Hello?
- Hi.
- Then I can talk to her.
- Then you can hear what she's got to say.
- No, I've told you.
Everyone she talks to, they just run away.
Yes, but Welsh people.
Trust me, darling. It's a plan.
All right. Well, just be careful! Okay.
Having a nice time?
Yeah, I'm just speaking to...
You're standing in the street
on the phone to your own mother?
Yeah.
Nothing to do with me.
Mum, what does she look like?
She looks like what she looks like.
What does that mean?
She looks like what she is.
Mum, what's she saying?
I can't-- [sighs] I can't quite hear.
- What's she saying?
Mum?
Mum, whatever she's saying
just don't-- No, Mum!
Mum, don't listen to her!
- Please, don't do this to me. Mum!
- Mum, don't do this to me. Mum!
Mum!
Mum, please! Just stop!
Mum?
Mum! Mum, please!
She run away? What did you say to her?
What? It wasn't me. It was the woman.
Mum, phone me back.
Just-- [huffs] Just tell me what she said.
Just talk to me, okay?
Just please phone me back.
Look, I don't care
if you're on answerphone.
I will keep calling
a hundred times a day.
And you've got to come home.
Come on, Mum.
Gran is calling you everything.
...and if you do come home,
I'll make that shepherd's pie, yeah?
The one we saw on Saturday Kitchen
with the cheese,
and we can sit down
and just pretend that--
Hang on.
Oh, no, you did not.
Mum! Mum, can you hear me?
Gran? Gran, are you in there?
Come on. You can't change the locks on me!
Come on!
Mum!
I won't ask you again, Ruby.
Please stop calling and go away.
But I'm your daughter.
Well, except you're not.
Are you?
Even your real mother didn't want you.
I take it that's the woman behind me,
is that right?
- Yes.
- Good.
Well, just look at me instead.
I'm Kate Lethbridge-Stewart,
and I think I can help.
Yeah, and that was over a year ago.
She's put an injunction out against me,
my own mother.
I thought about going back to Manchester,
but I don't want to leave, you know,
just in case.
And I've got this rubbish job
at Kleinermann's to make ends meet.
- Well, I think we can help with that.
We have a tradition of helping
the Doctor's former companions
once they return to a normal life.
No, I-I was hardly with him really.
- But it felt like a lifetime?
- Yeah.
Well, we're
the Unified Intelligence Taskforce
created to investigate
the extraterrestrial.
And, more and more, the supernatural.
Things seem to be turning that way
these days.
And you work with the Doctor?
With him, despite him,
against him sometimes.
And I adore him.
I can only say that now he's not here.
Oh, no, I-- I won't say a word.
I wish you'd got in touch with us sooner.
We thought the Doctor was-- was silent.
Oh, I know. I keep wondering
how the world survives without him.
Well, that's classified.
I think I can say, skin of our teeth.
Although, I think this timeline
might be suspended along your event.
- I'm glad we found you.
- Oh, my-- [sighs] So am I.
And you can take us to the TARDIS?
Yeah, it's just sitting there.
I'm actually surprised
no one's reported it, really.
It has a perception filter.
People notice it,
but sort of-- sort of don't.
Mmm.
I wonder if it's connected.
If-- If landing a perception filter
on top of that circle has affected things.
Huh.
Well, maybe.
'Cause she-- she has a perception thing.
- Huh.
- Like, no one at work has complained
about the old woman stood outside
every day.
It's like they see her,
but they don't notice her.
'Ey, I once positioned her
right in front of a police car,
and they drove right around her.
And if you sit in a room with no windows?
No, I can't see her.
But I know she's there.
Seventy-three yards.
I have measured it a hundred times.
I have measured it a thousand times.
It's 73 yards.
- But if you went on a plane?
- Or a boat.
Yeah, I know, I know.
But I don't.
'Cause I keep thinking if I cut her off,
I might die
or she might die.
I-- I don't know. Does that sound mad?
- Sounds wise.
- Mm-hmm.
It's what we do, all of us.
We see something inexplicable
and invent the rules to make it work.
Mankind saw the sunrise and created God.
Or we saw the arrival of a Sontaran,
one or the other.
And I can confirm.
Our scan says 73 yards exactly.
I hope you don't mind.
I didn't come alone.
Don't worry. You're quite safe.
No, no.
That's great. That's fine.
We photographed her.
But this is the only image we can get.
Oh, I know.
I bought the most expensive camera,
and I still couldn't zoom in on her face.
Well, our equipment is
a bit more sophisticated, and yet
she only registers from the point of view
of an average person's 20/20 eyesight
from 73 yards, 219 feet,
- 66.7 metres.
66.7 metres.
- But it proves you're not going mad.
Thank you.
Well, there's only one more option.
Let's bring her in.
Oh, but she won't--
If you talk to her, she--
I don't know, she does something.
My staff have full psychic training.
We have telepathic dampeners,
mesmeric shielding,
and necklaces of silver and salt
in case of witchcraft.
- Don't worry. You're with experts now.
Phew.
Go, go, go!
Initiate target approach.
Do not talk to her.
Do not look her in the eyes.
Do not engage with her in any way.
Just bring her in.
I said, "Do not engage!"
No, Kate.
No, Kate, what's she saying?
Disengage.
Kate. No, Kate, you can't leave.
Kate! Kate, please don't go. Kate!
Kate, wait! Kate!
All right.
All right, all right, all right!
- Oi! Do you mind?
Yeah, I said, "All right!"
You know what? I'm not complaining.
But I say let's go away.
Let's go to New York, and you say no.
So, I keep thinking--
I don't want you to take this
the wrong way, but I've got to ask.
Is there someone else?
It's just, sometimes,
I get the impression
you're not really listening,
like you're drifting off
thinking of something else.
♪ Watch me when you call my name ♪
Well, like now, to be honest.
♪ See me sparkle ♪
♪ See me flame ♪
Mmm.
The thing is,
I know you've had a tough time.
That whole thing
with your mother is weird...
...okay, but it's hard for me
sometimes, you know?
Thank you. And what's your
take on this, Roger ap Gwilliam?
Well, no public school for me.
I've done hard work.
I started off as a pizza delivery boy.
I worked on a fruit stall
in Swansea Market.
Hospital porter, the steel mills,
security guard.
I was a jack of all trades.
"Mad Jack" they used to call me.
Mad Jack.
Roger ap Gwilliam, that's
a bad example of the Welsh. Terrifying.
The most dangerous
prime minister in history.
Even in bed,
it's like you're always a distance away.
Semperdistans is the word.
Look, you were sweet, and this was--
Oh, this was nice, yeah?
But you were right. It was never
gonna work, and that is my fault.
E-Except for the bed thing.
'Cause that--
That really was you.
But it has taken me all this time
to realise what I'm here to do.
Which is what?
I'm gonna save the world.
See ya!
Come on. We've got work to do.
Hi there.
I would like to offer my services.
- I thought I'd volunteer.
- Okay, good news.
What for exactly?
Oh, anything. Anything at all.
I just think Roger ap Gwilliam is amazing,
and I want to help the cause.
I have a thousand pounds in my savings
which I can donate right now.
I'll do leaflets, answering the phones.
Just tell me what to do,
and I'll do anything.
'Ey, I'll even carry the coats.
Yes, but the government says--
What government?
The government has collapsed in shame.
In absolute shame, Amol.
Now's the time to vote,
you know, uh,
for Britain to find its voice,
to find its pride, its future.
Yes, but the point is that
if people are worried about anything,
it's the cost of living, it's inflation,
it's a price cap at £15,000.
And you want to spend billions.
Indeed, you're committed to spending
£65 billion on nuclear weapons.
Amol, I'm a Welshman.
I-I was born in Wales.
That's what the "ap" in my name means.
It's not one of those apps that you used
to have on your phones in the old days.
It means "son of".
I am a son of Wales.
And the Welsh know
what it's like to be oppressed.
And that has taught me to say, "No more."
And that's what I am saying. No more.
I want Great Britain to say, "No more."
So, yes,
I have pledged to defend our borders
and set us up on high as
one of the greatest nations in the world.
But we are members of NATO.
When did NATO ever, you know,
fire a nuclear missile? Ever?
2031, the Great Russian War,
not a single rocket.
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Are you saying that you actually
want to fire a nuclear missile?
We'll cut that bit out, right?
Uh, okay, everyone,
let's take ten.
Danny, uh, speak to comms about next week.
Yeah. Yeah.
- Immediately.
Yes, sir.
- Craig, get the car.
Are you with us?
Yes.
My name's Ruby.
Tell me, um, what about her?
The girl over there. Is she one of ours?
She's on Danny's team. She's a volunteer.
What's her name?
Marti Bridges.
Marti.
Boy's name.
Huh.
Marti?
Yeah? Yes, hi.
I declare that Roger ap Gwilliam
is duly elected as member of parliament
for the constituency.
- Yeah! Come on!
I will go to His Majesty
and prepare for government.
Roger! Roger! Roger!
Good news?
Between you and me, I know he's brilliant.
But sometimes, I don't know,
I think he gives me the shivers.
Oh, he is a monster.
Come on! Yes!
Yes, thank you.
We're here to help, okay?
You see anything suspect,
talk to security.
And back at the hotel, eyes and ears open.
We have a busy three days, so stay alert.
If you could all
be checked for clearance again.
You know Roger.
He arouses strong opinions.
Uh, and let me tell you. Rule number one,
do not step on the grass.
Well, I don't see why.
Come Saturday,
there's gonna be 10,000 people on there.
And until then, keep off the grass.
This place has a capacity of 30,000,
plus 10,000 on the pitch.
It's gonna be amazing.
Cardiff City, he's brought it home.
This place will broadcast
Roger ap Gwilliam all over the world.
Here he is.
Look at him. He still says hello
to every single person.
I'd love to meet him face to face.
Well, he's Prime Minister now.
We don't get access anymore.
Our job's on the sidelines.
Except for you, Marti.
Roger said there's room for you
at the party Saturday night.
He asked for you by name.
They're saying it's gonna be wild.
Now, we need to help branding
on the grandstand, rows 11 to 61.
They won't be watching, though.
The whole world.
Who cares about the British Prime Minister
making a speech in Cardiff?
That's the point.
They'll listen
if he's got something to say.
What do you mean?
Mmm. There are rumours.
They say Saturday
is when control transfers.
What? F-For what?
We're purchasing
the nuclear arsenal from Pakistan.
And on Saturday, Roger will declare us
independent from NATO.
Saturday, Roger ap Gwilliam
gets the codes.
Saturday?
He'll launch.
Don't be stupid, Marti.
It's symbolic.
The moment is completely symbolic.
I'm sorry I took so long.
Because I think I'll only get one chance,
and I had to make sure I was right.
But I wish I could have helped you.
I'm so sorry.
Uh, get us a coffee while you're there.
Ruby, I said keep off the grass.
Hey, get off the pitch, love.
Ruby, what are you doing?
What is she doing?
Hey, there are no unofficial photos.
Thank you.
Fifty-five yards.
Put that down!
Get off the pitch!
Fifty-six yards.
- Ruby!
Just stop that, and get back here.
- Fifty-eight yards, 59 yards.
- Ruby!
Excuse me. Hey, can you get off the grass?
I said get off the pitch.
- Are you listening?
- 62 yards.
Get off the pitch!
Ruby! What are you doing?
I'll have to ask you
to put that device down immediately.
Ruby! Stop it! Ruby!
Stay where you are. That's an order.
I said stay where you are!
- 70 yards.
- I said stay where you are.
- 72 yards, 73 yards.
- Final warning, stay where you are!
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
Sir! Sir!
And fifty minutes later,
Roger ap Gwilliam resigned
from the office of prime minister,
refusing to give any reasons
for his actions.
What happened?
Why did you resign?
Ask her.
- Ask her.
Ask her!
The deputy prime minister, Iris Cabriola,
has stepped forward to take control
and has already promised what she calls
a more lenient and listening government.
Is that it?
'Ey, is that what you were for?
Can you leave me alone now?
I'm sorry, Ruby. I can't drive any closer.
I can't get a signal for the engine
this far out.
No, it's fine.
I haven't been here in such a long time.
What a beautiful view.
Why do people put flowers here?
I don't think they know.
I presume she must be gone, my mother.
No one ever told me.
And I didn't find my birth mother.
It never snowed again.
But I keep thinking I know why.
The woman.
And I've been thinking about it
my whole life.
Why is she here?
And I think, at the end, I have hope.
Because that's very you,
isn't it, my old friend?
I dare to hope.
I've set the light, Ruby.
If you wake up in the night, you say
"light" out loud, and it comes on.
Yes, I know. That's not new.
We had that when I was young.
Anything else you need?
I could make it snow once upon a time.
That's nice.
If you need me, I'm just down the hall.
So, you won't be on your own.
Don't worry.
Everyone has abandoned me my whole life...
but I haven't been alone for 65 years.
Night then, Ruby.
- Light off.
Light.
I'm sorry I took so long,
and I tried so hard.
What else could I do?
It took all these years.
All these long years.
And look at me, I was so young.
Spectacular! We are in Wales!
What? How can you tell?
- Oh!
That smell, that green,
that coastline, Ruby.
- The rock and the water, it never ends.
The war between the land and the sea.
'Ey, you know what?
I have been to Wales three times now.
- I went to see Shygirl in Cardiff.
- Oh, yeah?
And then went to Mumbles because of a boy.
- I broke his heart, but there you go.
- Oh, bless him.
Mind you, Roger ap Gwilliam,
that's a bad example of the Welsh.
- Terrifying.
Don't step...
The most dangerous
prime minister in history.
- Who's she?
Don't step...
Who?
- Well, over there.
Don't step...
- Where?
There was a woman...
Well, she's not there anymore.
But there was. There was a woman.
She was just standing there.
Maybe she was looking for someone.
All right, Ruby. All right.
Oh, no, no, no. Don't step.
Oh.
I almost broke that.
Careful.
Oh, honey, what a beautiful thing.
- What is it?
- It's a-- It's a fairy circle.
Man, they are so delicate.
Just charms and spells
and hopes and dreams.
It's here at the end of the land.
- Well, yeah. What do they say?
- No, no, no, no. Better not.
Give them their respect, Ruby.
Let them rest in peace.
- Like your mysterious woman.
Oh, she was there.
Uh-huh.
And we are here!
So, what was the third time
that you've been to Wales?
You said you've been three times.
What was the other one?
Oh, um, oh, I don't know. When was it?
I can't think.
I suppose it must've been...
...now.
It's a glorious day
in Finetime.
There are creatures out there
in the real world.
There are monsters...
- ...and they're coming to get you.
Just look at my Close Friends.
Look how many are missing.
- God, it's me! They're coming for me!
Forward. Forward.