(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
RYAN: We're never gonna find one.
DOCTOR: Course we are!
I've programmed
the detector specifically.
I found seven last time I was here.
GRAHAM: And how long did that take you?
DOCTOR: It couldn't have been
more than a month.
Unless that was Seffilun 59.
Which one is this?
Seffilun 27.
Maybe 59's the one
with the big pile of these.
That's the problem with junk galaxies,
all the planets look the same,
it's hard to keep track.
If we've wasted the last four hours
on the wrong planet...
Oi, who took you rain bathing
in the upward tropics of Kinstarno?
Oh, no, no. Listen, that was amazing.
I was just saying,
like needle, haystack.
Yeah, you might be right.
(BUZZING)
No, hold on. I've found something.
(WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
I'm sorry.
YASMIN: What's he found?
Nobody move.
If I can keep it in temporal lock.
No, there's too many sensors,
it won't work.
It was camouflaged.
This is someone's idea of a nasty joke.
-What is it?
-Sonic mine.
It's counting down.
(BEEPING FASTER)
-How long have we got?
-Three, two...
WOMAN: I can't find their med tags.
This is how rubbish I am at this.
You'd think it'd be simple enough.
MAN: Mabli, stop beating yourself up.
I'm sure there's a simple explanation.
(GASPS)
It's all right. You're safe.
Just don't make any sudden moves.
Your body will take
a moment to catch up.
Can you point out your med tag for me,
I can't find it anywhere.
Where are we?
We're in hospital. They've just brought
us all round. You're the last one up.
YASMIN: We don't have med tags.
Oh, it wasn't my mistake.
Told you.
Except you must have.
We need your full bio. History,
allergies, fluid levels, life-span data.
Basically, to help us avoid killing you.
Take it slow.
There was...
A sonic mine.
Yeah, the robot dredgers notified us
as they were pulling you
from the debris.
We've stabilised your vital organs.
You're lucky they got to you first.
Stabilised my organs?
What happened to them?
I've seen quite a few
sonic mine injuries here.
They disrupt
your internal organic stability
whilst churning up
the exterior environment.
Tsuranga is actually agitating
for the territories
to be swept more fully, but...
(BEEPING)
That doesn't make sense.
-Tsuranga.
-GRAHAM: What have they done?
I know that name.
(GASPING)
Where have I heard the name "Tsuranga"?
Whatever. I'm very grateful.
Need to get back to our ship.
(GROANING) Come on, you lot.
-MAN: Hey, come back.
-Which way is out?
Can you return
to the assessment zone, please?
We're not discharging you.
You need to rest.
Well, I appreciate
how much you've looked after us,
but my ship is very valuable.
It's also my home. Our home.
And I'm worried about leaving it here,
on a junk planet
where people come and scavenge.
I might never see it again.
And I've only just got it back.
Wait here.
This way out.
Whether you agree or not,
it is my responsibility
to protect the general.
I understand
your responsibilities, Ronan.
Okay, I hear about them endlessly.
Says the man who never wants
any of his own.
Sorry.
Looking for the exit. There's no signs.
General Cicero's privacy indicators
are clearly on.
Sorry, we're not really up
on privacy indicators.
General Cicero? Not Eve Cicero?
Keeba galaxy? Neuro Pilot?
You're mentioned
in the Book of Celebrants.
You helped defeat the Army of the Aeons
at the Battle of the Underkind.
I was one of many.
You're a bit of a legend though.
This is my brother, Durkas,
and my consort, Ronan.
When she says consort,
she really means clone drone. Android.
You can tell by the hair.
Durkas.
-And who are you?
-I'm the Doctor.
Wait, I've heard that name.
Aren't you in the Book of Celebrants?
Isn't there a whole chapter about you?
Me? No.
Very common name.
Anyway, lovely chatting, must be off.
Hope you all get better soon.
I'd say it was more of a volume
than a chapter.
Just so you know.
Oh, that bit hurts.
Oh, that bit really hurts.
Where is the exit?
Why are there no signs for the exit?
-Hi. Very sorry. Looking for the exit.
-Hello.
Somebody needs to have a big rethink
on the signage in this building.
I'd do it myself, but I need...
(GROANING)
My ectospleen hurts.
I can feel it resettling.
Oh, you're the sonic mine lot.
It sounded pretty serious.
-How're you feeling?
-Rough.
What are you in for?
Pregnant.
Blimey, yes you are.
Almost ready to pop.
How did you get like that?
On holiday, got involved with someone,
didn't take precautions. Like an idiot.
So, what's that? Nine months?
No, last week.
-Last week?
-Oh, you're a Gifftan?
Male pregnancies last a week.
Very intense.
Yeah, feels like forever.
I'm a day overdue.
They're thinking they might induce me
at Resus One, otherwise...
Well, it wouldn't be good
for either of us.
You're here. Look, you can't
keep disturbing all the other patients.
Astos, found them.
They're here in Pod Two.
We need to go now.
I'm sure you'll be fine.
We'll be thinking of you.
What do you mean "go"?
How're you gonna do that?
-What do you mean?
-We have been trying to tell you.
Yes.
You have.
Vibrations.
Too wrapped up in myself.
Missed the vibrations.
I was trying to break it to you gently.
Tsuranga.
This isn't a hospital,
it's a ship.
And we're already in flight.
ASTOS: Tsuranga operates
emergency medical transport.
This is a quad zone rescue craft.
Like the Red Cross.
You'll be fine.
We'll be at Resus One soon enough.
-How long were we out for?
-ASTOS: Four days.
Four days flight from the TARDIS.
I'm walking.
(GROANING)
No need to walk with me.
I need to walk on my own.
Four days. Walking.
Come on, limbs.
Have you got onboard teleport?
No, but there's post-recuperation
onward teleport at Resus One.
I don't wanna go to Resus One.
Let me talk to the pilot.
Hey, it's not just you onboard.
What are you doing? Don't touch that.
Patients aren't allowed access
to any onboard systems
or non-medical facilities.
What were you worried about?
Just as I was waking up you...
You saw something and you were worried.
No.
Ooh. Bad liar.
Must be difficult in your job.
Hey, I'm an excellent liar.
-So, you were lying then?
-I didn't say that.
See? Bad liar.
Nav chamber. This way.
(GROANING) Still hurts!
Running can disrupt
the ongoing internal healing process.
Enough now. You can't be in here.
I don't know what that device is,
but if you don't leave
I have to restrain you.
Where is the crew?
Rescue crafts are automated.
It's a two-medic crew,
just me and Mabli.
Our course is remotely programmed
from the Tsuranga hub at Resus One.
How do we turn it around?
We can't.
The course is remotely set and locked.
The onboard crew don't have privileges
to unlock it.
We'll see about privileges.
Don't! If you interfere
with the navi system
they'll take it
as an active hostility or hijack.
They can detonate the craft.
I'm not being hostile!
Yes, you are!
You are being hostile and selfish.
There are patients onboard
who need to get to Resus One
as a matter of urgency.
My job is to keep all of you safe.
You are stopping me from doing that.
You're right.
Of course, you're right.
Sorry.
That mine hit me harder than I thought.
I've done 37 tours.
We will get you back safe.
Where are we?
There's a lot of stuff out there.
Space junk, asteroids...
We're on the edges
of the Constant Division,
that's what threw me back there.
The routine usually
keeps us out of here.
-Why?
-It's disputed territory.
We're only just over the boundary
so nothing to worry about.
So, what's that?
What's what?
Not sure.
(CRASHING)
Probably an asteroid shower.
(RAPID BEEPING)
Shield breach.
No, wait. Reconfiguring.
Resealed and solid.
But something breached it for a second.
(THUDDING)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
I'll check the system monitors.
(THUDDING)
Something is inside the shields.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Bad liar, Astos.
Go back to your patient pod.
I don't know your name.
I'm the Doctor.
-Are you kidding?
-Sometimes.
But not right now.
Tell me the ship's structure, Astos,
as quick as you can.
Central walkway goes all the way around.
We have an assessment area in the heart,
three patient pods,
one emergency suite on the sides.
We can perform
limited medical procedures,
but our job is basically,
keep people alive
till we can get them to a facility.
Evacuation equipment?
Two LifePods, port side and starboard.
Maximum five per pod.
We're just within our occupancy limit.
Oh, that's good.
This ship was designed
for 100,000 tours.
It can withstand a hell of a lot.
Are you trying to reassure me
or yourself?
(THUDDING AND BEEPING)
-That's a breach alert.
-It's in the port side LifePod.
-It can't be.
-Are there comms in the LifePod?
(STATIC)
(THUDDING)
It's using the LifePod
as a way into the ship.
You know these territories.
What can it be? Whoa!
That thing can really move.
It's heading from the port side
to the starboard.
Area around the starboard pod's
offline, I can't get a reading.
We have to take a look.
Okay. You take port,
I'll check starboard.
No, no, no. Too dangerous.
You take port, I'll take starboard.
You're not in charge here.
This is my craft, you are my patient
and my responsibility.
As is everyone else here.
You're still recovering.
You're still in pain.
I'll check starboard,
you check port side.
I don't like being told what to do.
Yeah.
I'm getting that impression.
Take a comm dock.
Mabli already has one.
Stay off her channel
while we work out what this is.
She doesn't need to know about this yet.
It's only her second tour.
Neither do any of the other patients.
-Obviously.
Why am I trusting you, Doctor?
You might be a bad liar, Astos,
but you've got excellent instincts.
Did you just buzz me?
I'm requesting
further adrenaline blockers.
-What, already?
-Yes.
Let me check with Astos.
No, you must supply them without delay.
But we only carry a limited stock.
I'm not sure I'm allowed to.
The panels are down this way.
You know our status
and how Keeba Central regard us.
We would not
ideally register a complaint
against someone
so early in their career.
Let's get them, then.
I think that's staff only.
Yeah.
(SIGHING) I'm trying to figure out
what to do next.
Deny everything or...
Ask you to turn a blind eye?
I see your problem. Yeah.
Generally, truth is always
your best option.
I was trying to hack
into my sister's medical records.
Well, we've all hacked
into our loved ones confidential records
at one stage or another, haven't we?
(SCOFFING)
Can I ask why?
Well, she's lying to me.
About...
About what's wrong with her.
She might have good reason for that.
I know the reason.
She's a control freak.
Even to her own little brother.
The most decorated General
in Keeba history,
907 days in continual flight,
on residual energy.
Fighting the Ayonians,
saving our species.
So, what do you do then?
Me, I'm...
-Engineer.
-Oh.
Yeah.
I have to fix the things
pilots like my sister tend to wreck.
And she looks down on me for it.
And she always will.
(DOCTOR PANTING)
(CREAKING)
DOCTOR: See anything, Astos?
Nothing so far.
DOCTOR: Me neither.
ASYOS: The LifePod
is just around the corner.
Me too.
DOCTOR: Go carefully. Whatever
this thing is, it can move very fast.
The power has been shorted
around the LifePod.
The power has gone out in this section.
ASTOS: You need to check
if the pod is still secure.
DOCTOR: The system is all drained.
ASTOS: No sign of anything here, so far.
How about you?
(GASPING)
Astos,
the port side LifePod, it's gone.
-Jettisoned.
-Understood.
(RATTLING)
Doctor, it's here.
It's inside this pod.
Don't engage with it.
Stay where you are. We need you safe.
Astos, what's happening there?
Astos? Are you listening to me?
Do not engage.
No, no, don't!
COMPUTER: LifePod active,
disengaging.
Use life-restraint straps, now.
Astos, what's happening?
Rookie mistake.
It's jettisoning the pod.
The internal controls are broken.
And I'm inside.
COMPUTER: Systems malfunction.
Currently unavailable.
Hold on. I'm coming.
COMPUTER: Evacuation, critical
Mabli. Mabli!
Astos, I'm just with a patient.
Do you need something?
ASTOS: I'm sorry, Mabli.
It tricked me. I can't get back.
What are you talking about?
Get back from where?
You can do this, Mabli.
You're good enough.
You have to believe in yourself.
I believe in you.
I always have.
Astos?
Astos!
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(CLANKING)
-Where's Astos? Oh my saints!
-Doc, that bloke's lab our...
What is that?
(ROARS)
I don't know.
But it's incredibly dangerous.
It jettisoned the LifePods.
And it killed Astos.
What?
I'm sorry, Mabli.
But it's down to us to get us
safely back to Resus One now.
And you, off this ship!
Back into space, right now.
Else you'll have me to deal with.
(GROWLS)
It just, sort of,
ignored you there, Doc.
Got that, thanks, Graham.
How is it eating all that stuff?
What even is it?
No idea.
Hit the ship from the depths of space,
so it can survive a vacuum.
It doesn't need oxygen.
And can digest pretty much whatever
it wants, by the looks of things.
(CHOMPING)
(GASPING)
And it's got nerve.
It's just ate my sonic!
(CLICKS)
-(SIGHS)
-(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
Get them?
I think there may have been an incident.
The ship's data banks,
I shouldn't let you in here,
but I am and that's fine.
I've already been in here with Astos.
Has he really gone?
I'm sorry, Mabli.
He was one of the only people
who ever believed in me, including me.
He was so kind.
There aren't enough kind people.
What would he want you to do now?
Make sure everyone stays safe.
You can do this.
Right. Yeah.
-I can.
-What did you want to show us?
Well, if I sync my ocular recorders
with the data banks...
Oh, yeah, sync
the old ocular recorders, it's obvious.
All Tsuranga medics
are implanted with lenses,
so we can record
all treatments for training purposes,
lawsuits, data records.
Like a posh version
of my uniform camera.
Hang on. So, if this is the control deck
where is the rest of the crew?
No crew. All automated.
-So, it's just us.
-Yeah.
-Alone.
-In space.
-Yeah.
With that creature.
-Right.
-I don't fancy its chances.
-Yeah.
I back us every time.
COMPUTER: Thank you for choosing
perils of the Constant Division.
We know you have a choice of
vid-briefings concerning
the most threatening of...
Sorry. Here we go.
COMPUTER:
Item Seven Alpha Cubed. Pting.
ALL: Pting?
COMPUTER: Pting.
Threat Level: Chalice.
Is that bad?
Worst one.
One up from Beetroot.
COMPUTER: ...the species,
if it is a species, birth or creation,
many studies having failed, due to
the fatally violent nature of the Pting.
No Pting has ever been kept
in captivity,
due to their ability to eat through any
material that would incarcerate them.
While strictly non-carnivorous,
they devour all non-organic material.
Well, at least that's something.
Is it really? I mean, it won't eat us,
but it will eat the ship we're on.
...and while they may be momentarily
stunned are impossible to wound or kill.
Pting's skin is understood to be toxic
to most lifeforms.
Never touch a Pting directly.
Ptings should never be restricted
to a confined space.
Condensed advice,
never engage with Pting.
Risk to life, ultimate.
On the plus side,
I now feel very well informed.
Seven minutes.
Get everyone into the assessment area.
Why seven minutes?
I need a moment to think.
(PTING CHITTERS)
What are you doing?
Adrenaline blocker.
You can't take adrenaline blockers
with corton fever.
It's fine.
You know, I knew
you were up to something.
I knew you were lying.
-Durkas, I would respectfully...
-No, I would respectfully ask
don't talk to me.
-Hi. We're gonna need you to...
-Oh.
Oh.
Put your hand there.
No, you're all right.
Oh, go on, please.
Both of you, quick. It's kicking.
Come on, it'll be nice to share it.
Oh, wait for it.
Wait for it.
Oh!
-Whoa.
See? He likes you guys.
Oh, and again.
You know it's a boy?
Of course, it is.
Boys give birth to boys,
and girls give birth to girls.
-That's how it is.
-Not where we come from.
Ugh, how does that work?
Do you wanna see my baby pics?
We all need to be in the assessment area
in six minutes.
Ha!
One hour.
Three hours.
End of the first day.
Mid second day.
And, oh...
Three hours ago.
Mate...
You're growing a person.
Yeah.
I couldn't do that.
No, he really couldn't do that.
Yeah.
Almost seems a shame to give him away.
That's what you're gonna do?
Oh, I'm not fit to raise a kid.
Besides, dark times right now.
Turbulent world.
I'm not sure I'm his best option.
I can't even operate my oven.
But...
Won't you miss him?
Six minutes you said? I'll be there.
Yeah.
RYAN: He's the same age as my dad
must have been when he had me.
Same age as I am now.
Never really thought about it like that.
I wouldn't be able to cope
having a kid now.
When was the last time you saw your dad?
A year ago.
Didn't go well.
Got angry with him.
Why?
He ducked out when I needed him.
He's like a gap in my life.
Even at Nan's funeral.
Do you mind me asking?
How did your mum die?
(SIGHING)
Washing up in the kitchen,
massive heart attack, just...
Just out on the floor.
God.
Who found her?
Me.
How old were you?
Thirteen.
Ryan,
I'm so sorry.
I never knew.
I never knew life
threw that sort of stuff at you.
I never knew that when it does,
sometimes adults don't cope either.
Your dad.
I get it.
He loved her too.
People always said
that I looked like her.
He must have found that hard.
Why am I even talking
about this? (SCOFFS)
Come on.
Four minutes to the briefing.
DOCTOR: Too fast to chase and capture.
Too toxic to touch directly.
It's a bit of a puzzle.
It's gonna kill us all, isn't it?
Oh, Mabli,
you went there way too quick.
I said a puzzle, not a death sentence.
I mean,
it's a bit of a challenge,
and I can't quite see the solution yet,
but that's life. Or medicine.
Patients present problems,
you figure them out
and come up with solutions.
That's what this is,
a problem to be diagnosed.
Medicine to be administered.
You're a medic, I'm the Doctor.
A doctor of medicine?
Well, medicine, science,
engineering, candy floss,
Lego, philosophy, music,
problems, people, hope.
Mostly hope.
I'm struggling to see much hope here.
It doesn't just offer itself up,
you have to use your imagination.
Imagine the solution,
and work to make it a reality.
Whole worlds pivot
on acts of imagination.
So, what are you imagining now?
Broadly, I'm imagining
that thing off this ship.
Specifically, I'm trying to imagine
the answer to the question.
What does it want?
Does it have to want anything?
Every living thing,
from the tiniest to the largest,
wants something. Food, survival, peace.
But, the first thing it did
was kill Astos.
That must be what it wants to do
to all of us.
You know there's a much faster way
back to Resus One.
Why is it routing us this way?
Asteroid field. Fast moving asteroids
all around, really unpredictable.
(ALARM BUZZING)
What are these?
They are bad.
This craft has over 5,000
different scan sensors,
constantly feeding back to Resus One.
They monitor everything,
both internally and externally.
Check the routing is stable,
and there are no hostile forms,
however microbial, on board.
The systems have detected the Pting.
They are asking us to confirm or deny
anything is wrong.
We can't take a creature like that
back to Resus One.
There's thousands
of vulnerable patients.
And if we confirm it's onboard?
They will recommend evacuation.
But we can't evacuate.
It goes straight to RST,
remote structural termination.
They destroy the ship.
Right.
Nothing wrong. We're fine.
We can't keep doing that.
Three dismissals
and they don't believe you.
Precautionary detonation.
Oh, great. Who designed that?
So, this ship either gets destroyed
by that creature,
or by control from Resus One.
Yeah.
Sorry.
(GRUNTS)
You're probably wondering
why I called you all here.
Sorry.
Bit Poirot!
I need to bring you all up to speed,
very directly, very succinctly.
I can't sugarcoat this.
-Where's the chief medic?
-Gone.
Killed by an alien organism
called Piing that's come onboard.
Very fast moving, very deadly,
and it's eating its way
through the structure of the ship.
Also, and this is the bit
you need to work on not panicking.
It has jettisoned the LifePods.
Oh.
I'm the Doctor, these are my friends,
Ryan, Graham and Yaz.
You know Mabli, our very capable medic.
We will pool all our brilliance
and get us all safely to Resus One.
I thought there'd be more questions.
I've encountered a Pting before,
it massacred my fleet.
Okay.
What did you learn about them?
What do they want?
They kill, relentlessly.
(RYAN GASPS)
MABLI: It must have got
to the central systems.
That means we'll soon lose
oxygen and heat.
EVE: It'll go for whatever
is powering the craft next.
We're on an anti-matter drive.
We could use
stazers to defend ourselves.
They can stun it briefly.
Got any onboard?
A couple, I think, in here.
If we're gonna live through this
-protect the anti-matter drive.
-Protect the anti-matter drive. Snap!
Can we get to Resus One
any faster than currently routed?
Not without breaking
the ship's auto routing,
which would send a signal back
to Resus One.
And they go straight
to Hostility Protocols.
I could create a false
positive route signal to send back.
But there's no manual controls
in the nav chamber.
-Show us.
-General...
Shush now, Ronan. I know.
We could go past the drive chamber
on the way.
Durkas with me. Please?
Um, is this a bad moment
to mention my internal fluids
have broken?
I think the baby is coming.
Really sorry.
The BirthBud is set up
in your PatientPod.
-Let's get you back there.
-But it won't have any power.
It's got a backup generator,
no need to panic.
Would you two be my Dhulas?
I haven't got any Dhulas.
-Do what?
-Dhulas, birth partners.
She's brilliant,
but I need some men with me.
-Yeah, we're blokes, aren't we?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, yeah. All over it. Yeah.
-Come on.
Right, now I'm imagining
you're sorting all this out?
Me too. Be cautious,
it could be anywhere.
Come on.
-MABLI: You're fine.
-I need another adrenaline blocker.
You used the last one, General.
Everything okay?
-Yeah.
-With me, please.
Where do you think it is right now?
I don't know.
Can't trace it,
since the diagnostic systems drained.
Doctor, quick word. Private.
Catch you up, go on.
Eve Cicero, her condition.
-What about it?
-Patient confidentiality,
I can't discuss with you,
but if you're a doctor,
maybe you should examine her.
I've got to go.
Sorry, where are we?
Oh, anti-matter drive.
What century is this?
-You're joking?
-No, we travel in time.
-Are you joking now?
-No.
-Sixty-seventh.
-Oh, nice century.
Bit tricky in the middle.
Turns out all right in the end.
See this, Yaz? Anti-matter drive.
Oh, I did a bit
on anti-matter at school.
Never quite understood it.
The thing with anti-matter is you
either have to find it or generate it.
That's what this bit does.
Particle accelerator.
Like at CERN. We did that in physics.
No, but the thing at CERN is massive.
In your time, generating anti-matter
cost a massive amount of money.
This is progress.
Things get smaller, faster and cheaper.
This is like the iPhone version
of CERN.
Accelerating enough particles
to power this entire craft.
So, how does it work?
The particle accelerator
smashes the atoms together,
like a little anti-matter factory
to produce positrons.
Which are then stored very carefully
inside electric and magnetic fields.
The positrons interact
with the fuel materials
to produce heat, which produces thrust.
It's pretty old school, this one.
It's beautiful.
Anti-matter powering
the movement of matter,
bringing positrons into existence
to move other forms of life
across space.
I love it.
Conceptually,
and actually.
Yaz, you have to keep this safe
from the Piing.
If this drive gets destroyed,
This ship will lose propulsion,
will drift endlessly while the Piing...
I get it. It won't be good.
Ronan can stay with you.
No. General, my responsibility is to...
Ronan, you're able to touch it
without it toxifying you.
That's useful to all of us,
including me.
Of course, General.
You might need this, med blanket.
Sterilised barrier.
67th century technology.
In case you need to pick anything up.
(THUDS)
(ALARM BUZZES)
(DOCTOR GASPING)
Piing presence denied.
Strike two, one left.
Now, you two, see? A more direct route.
Obviously, fast moving asteroids
and debris to avoid on the way,
which is presumably
why the systems wanted to avoid it.
Now, if I can rig up a cover signal
back to Resus One...
Doctor, I'm a Neuro Pilot,
my expertise is
in symbiotic neuro-piloting
pulse systems at a push, but not this.
Oh, I can make a rig
out of this chamber.
No, you can't.
You would't be able to make your way
through those asteroids even if I did.
Yeah? Says you.
-How long have I got?
-Literally, no time at all.
Give me some space to work.
Siblings... Bless.
Why are you on this ship, General?
Corton fever.
Contracted on my last duty.
Can't quite shake it.
What are you doing?
Why would you be using
adrenaline blockers for Corton fever?
How'd you know about the blockers?
Your slow pulse, my really good hearing.
You asked Ronan for some.
It isn't Corton fever, is it?
Is it Pilot's Heart?
I'm sorry, Eve,
but if we're gonna survive this,
you need to be honest with me.
I started as a Pulse Pilot.
I graduated to Neuro Fleet Commander
faster than anyone in Keeban history.
I'm the most decorated general.
I'm the poster woman.
I cannot have Pilot's Heart.
I cannot be that example to others.
But you have, and you have been using
more and more blocker shots
to get through the day.
Trying to control
the surges of adrenaline
around the heart.
One big surge could kill me.
Does Durkas know?
I don't want him worrying.
He's gonna find out sooner or later.
DURKAS: He already has.
Not that he's surprised, just...
Disappointed.
-Durkas...
-We don't have time now.
I've rigged a primitive piloting bypass,
-combining pulse and neuro...
-I'll do it.
Ever flown that way?
No.
But you can talk me through it.
It takes people a dozen years to train.
I really need to spend more time
in 67th century.
I know how to do this.
I'm not stopping now.
Everyone is going to live. Including me.
(GROANING)
-Breathe deep, cockle.
-I am breathing.
Oh, this really hurts!
Yoss. Yoss.
I'm giving you some stronger
pain management, it should help.
(YOSS SCREAMING)
Yeah. Yeah, that's better.
Where's the BirthBud? Is it running?
No, backup generator isn't working.
(SCREAMING) What?
I can't do this without a BirthBud!
-Yoss, don't panic, mate.
-I am panicking.
Which is why I'm telling you not to.
Listen to your Dhulas.
We're here for you.
I don't even know you! Who are you?
You're not the one about to have a baby
you don't want, on a ship
without a BirthBud.
-(GROANS)
-The baby is ready to come out.
Oh, God.
Oh. (GRUNTING)
It's close.
Just focus on protecting
the anti-matter drive.
(SCREAMING)
(YELPS)
Stazers ready.
-(SHIP CREAKING)
-(THUDDING)
The creature is toying with us.
(RUMBLING)
(PTING GROWLING)
-(SCREAMS)
-(GROWLING)
I'll get it as far away
from the drive as I can.
Be fast, the stun power
will only last a few seconds.
Siobhan Chamberlain
with a goal kick for England.
(CHITTERING)
Okay, it's rigged.
I've leeched some system power
off the anti-matter drive.
Now if they can keep that
up and running,
we'll have enough power
to keep basic systems going
and still get to Resus One.
That's if that thing
doesn't get in there
and drain the energy.
This isn't gonna work.
Keep quiet, General.
Trust your engineer
and tell me you're well enough.
I'm well enough.
Now promise me that's true.
You're gonna need every scrap
of energy you have.
Cover signal transmitting to Resus One.
Hopefully, bit of luck, they're still
gonna think they're in control.
Durkas.
You're a genius.
The energy.
It doesn't wanna kill us,
it doesn't care about us.
It wants the systems,
it wants the power.
It didn't go for Astos,
it went for the life-support systems
in the LifePod.
It drained the lights and the power
and my sonic,
it drains everything it eats.
That little creature seeks out
and feasts on energy.
That's why it homed-in on us here,
pulsing with it in the wilds of space.
Locked in, General.
Try it out.
I can see the course.
I need to increase speed.
Turning over control...
It's all yours.
-(RUMBLING)
-(GRUNTING)
Eve.
Still got it, boy.
I've missed this so much.
(EXHALES)
How is it?
Rough.
But it'll work.
Take us in safely, General.
Nice and calm.
(ALARM BLARING)
Pting denial, strike three.
After which, tricky.
DURKAS: What will we do with the Piing
when we gel to Resus One?
(ALARM BLARING)
Nothing to worry about,
I'll deal with the Pting.
Well, how are you gonna do that?
Piing, bomb... No, can't get it.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS) Still hurting.
Yes.
Maybe, maybe...
It's me, I'm not a Pting.
It was here.
I got rid of it.
-But it'll be coming back.
-What is the situation elsewhere?
Eve's piloting the ship.
Durkas is maintaining
controls and signals.
You're guarding
the particle accelerator.
-(EXPLOSION)
-(RUMBLING)
Mabli, Graham and Ryan
are presumably delivering Yoss's baby.
And the bomb's going to detonate.
I'm just going to move it away
from this room.
-Mind helping?
-Yes! |
(GASPS) Clever sonic.
Self-rebooting.
There's a bomb in this room?
Right in here.
Mabli said that Resus One
would terminate the ship
if they found the Pting on board.
How would they do that?
We're too far for missiles.
Has to be the same
for every Tsurangan rescue craft.
It's built in.
Self detonation.
Bingo.
Ten points for Yasmin Khan, and yes,
I am keeping score for all of you.
Ronan, up your game.
Jokes.
So...
You're interfering with the bomb?
-Yes.
-Is it going to detonate?
Yes.
What will you do?
Speed it up.
To save our lives.
Are you also experiencing
comprehension deficiency?
Oh, every day right now, mate.
Need to be so careful,
tiny little device.
Could blow us all to pieces.
And I'm going to set it off.
Ronan.
Keep guard.
Yaz, come on.
Resus One in sight.
We join the route
back in at this point,
they won't know we've deviated.
You okay?
All those times
I thought I was going to die in battle,
that you'd get a dispatch
and hear about it.
I always felt so bad.
But now...
I'm glad you're here.
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
Funny.
I'm normally the one defusing the bomb.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
Pick a number
between one and a hundred.
Fifty one.
Pentagonal number! Interesting.
Get in that corner.
What was the number for?
Number of seconds before
the bomb goes off.
I moved it forward a bit.
What?
I would've gone higher.
Good number 51,
atomic number of antimony.
The number of federalist papers
written by Alexander Hamilton.
I love that show,
I've seen all 900 casts.
(BEEPING)
I'm giving you more gas, Yoss,
this will relax you.
I've never been less relaxed
in all my life.
I do not want to do this.
Hey, hey, we're all here for you,
aren't we?
Too right.
Oh, yeah, I've seen every episode
of Call the Midwife.
And he's descended from
an old Earth nurse, it's in his blood.
-Every episode?
-Yeah, it's bang on,
see whilst you've been mucking around
on YouTube,
I've been learning useful life skills.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
I'm really trusting you on this bomb,
but I don't know what you're doing.
Think of the Piing as a mouse
and the bomb as a piece of cheese.
A very large piece of cheese
about to explode
and take us all with it.
It's not the perfect analogy,
I'll admit.
You could've picked a bigger number.
Where is it? Come on.
So how do we do this then?
Really straightforward,
cut open his stomach sac,
reach in, remove the baby.
Done.
Cut him open?
Won't that, like, hurt him?
Oh, no, male Gifftan pregnancy sacs
don't have any pain sensors
for precisely this reason.
Yeah, but all the same, I mean,
cut open a bloke's stomach,
do we have to?
What, they didn't have that
on Gall The Midwife?
I dunno, I always looked away
at the squeamish bits.
As the bomb gets closer,
the energy is building
getting ready to blow.
The Piing must be attracted to that.
Surely! That's what I've been working
on this whole time.
Oh, please don't be wrong,
I'll be so embarrassed.
And dead.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Doctor.
I'm not bad, admit it,
I'm not bad, it's all in the timing.
(SNARLING)
When you're ready, mate.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Making the incision.
(GRUNTING)
Oh, I am never getting pregnant.
All right now, opening up.
Oh, I do not want this baby.
I can't be a dad.
Hey, none of that now.
Listen to me, Yoss, you can do this.
You're a good man, your baby,
your son will be lucky
to have a good man like you as his dad.
Starting now,
you're going to give him life.
You're going to bring a person
into being, mate,
that is epic.
I'm not ready.
Really? Get a shift on.
It ate it.
Wait for it.
(GROWLING)
(CHITTERING)
Absorbed, every bit of energy.
One massive, massive hit.
Bye-bye, Piing.
Intruder ejected.
First problem gone.
That should keep it fed
for a very long time.
We're still not home and dry though.
(BOTH GASPING)
I'm sorry.
For what?
I didn't tell you I was ill.
There's... Plenty of things
I've never told you.
Yeah, like what?
Like I love you.
I'm proud of you, sis.
I love you too, bro.
I'm sorry.
General.
Sac open.
Oh, shouldn't have looked,
can't unsee that.
-There's the baby.
-What does he look like?
Is he okay?
He's fine.
(PANTING)
Yoss, you don't have to be perfect.
You just have to be there.
(BABY CRYING)
It's okay, my darling.
-(CRYING)
-(SHUSHING)
You have to cut the cord simultaneously.
It's okay.
Come on, Professor Squeamish.
We're doing this.
-(RUMBLING)
-(GRUNTING)
-Three...
-Hang on.
Two, one...
Now.
YASMIN: (PANTING) Eve.
What happened?
Her heart couldn't take it.
She gave me control.
Do you know how to do this?
I'm a Cicero.
I've studied for this.
Coming into Resus One.
Resus One,
request emergency assistance landing.
Bringing her in safe.
Thank you.
Both.
Careful, dad.
Oh, my saints.
I did it.
It's a baby.
(BABY COOING)
Hello, mate.
I'm your dad.
I'm his dad.
-Yeah.
-(RUMBLING)
Nice one, Yoss.
You all right?
If your nan could see us now, eh?
-She'd be laughing herself crazy.
-Yeah!
No.
(SIGHS)
Um...
They say, quarantine scanning
and craft detox
should take no more
than three hours, then...
they'll admit us to the facility.
They're booking
your teleport to Seffilun,
soon as you've spoken
to the investigators.
Thank you, Mabli.
I'll be sure to tell them
how brilliant you were.
You all were.
Light in dark times.
People prevail.
Hope prevails.
(BABY CRYING)
-Have you got a name for the baby?
-Yeah.
In honour of you both,
I wanted to call him Avocado.
(SNORTS)
You what?
Avocado?
Yeah, after the ancient Earth hero.
Avocado Pear.
No, mate, that is a fruit.
No, it's a vegetable.
No, well, either way it's not a hero.
But we did it in school, you mean,
the Gifftan history logs are wrong?
Well, just a bit, I thought
he was gonna say,
you'd call him after us.
Graham-Ryan.
Or Ryan-Graham.
(LAUGHING) No.
He'd be a laughingstock.
Well, cheers.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
If you're naming him,
does that mean you're gonna keep him?
I thought I'd give being a dad a try.
I'm gonna make mistakes, aren't I?
But I'll just keep going.
What happens to you now?
Without her?
I've come to the end of my service,
there is only shutdown.
I'm sorry, Ronan.
I wasn't always kind to you.
No.
(SIGHS)
You gave her great service.
As did you.
Yeah.
Will you in cant for her?
It would be my honour.
DOCTOR: Could we join you?
Please.
May the saints of all the stars
and constellations...
ALL: Bring you hope.
ALL: As they guide you out
of the dark and into the light.
ALL: On this voyage and in the next.
And all the journeys still to come.
DOCTOR: For now and ever more.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
I want you to have this.
YASMIN: What's the point
in having a mate with a time machine
if you can't nip back
and can see your gran
when she were younger?
GRAHAM: 7947.
DOCTOR: We're in the middle of
the Partition of India.