Bye, then. Lovely meeting you.
Sorry about the mess!
Whoa!
You think I'd just let you leave
without me, huh?
After what we've just been through?
Yeah, but you've got the Egyptian people
to rule, Queen Nefertiti,
they'll need reassuring after that
weapon-bearing giant alien locust attack
we just stopped rather brilliantly...
-(CLOWN HORN SOUNDS)
-Oh, dear!
Sorry, I've got it set to Temporal
News... Ooh, that's interesting.
-Oh, what is?
-Nothing, not interesting, not at...
Ooh-whoo! Never been there, excited!
DOCTOR: You're not coming!
Craft size, approximately 10 million
square kilometres.
A ship the size of Canada
coming at Earth very fast.
Any signs of life?
We sent up a drone craft.
It took these readings.
Crikey Charlie! Look at that!
Oh, I know somebody who'd love
a look at that.
And the Ponds, we mustn't forget
the Ponds, Nefi.
Haven't seen them in ages. I'm riffing.
People usually stop me when I'm riffing.
Or carry on without me.
That's also an option.
-Can you communicate with this craft?
-She's with me.
Good question, Nefi.
No. No response on any channel,
in any recognised language.
If it comes within 10,000 kilometres
of Earth,
we send up missiles.
Oh, Indira. I liked you
before you said missiles.
How long till the ship gets that close?
Six hours, 19 minutes.
Right. Better get a shift on, then.
Leave it with us. Come on then, Nefi.
We're going to need help.
-More stew.
-Where have you been, man?
Seven months. You said
you were popping out for some liquorice.
I had two very disappointed dancers
on my hands.
Not that I couldn't manage.
Riddell, listen. I found...well...
something.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I shan't fall for that again.
-What is it?
-I have no idea.
Do you want to find out?
(JANGLING)
-I think it's the fitting.
-Dad, it's not the fitting,
it just need a new bulb.
-You're wobbling the ladder.
-I'm not.
I don't want another loft incident.
-How is my side, Brian?
-Perfect, as ever, Amy.
Thank you, Brian.
I don't know what he said to you
to make you marry him.
But he's a lucky man.
(WHOOSHING)
Not here, not now.
You leave the back door open?
-What is he doing?
-I'm going to kill him.
Hello, you weren't busy, were you?
Well, even if you were,
it wasn't as interesting as this...
probably is.
Didn't want you to miss it.
Now, just a quick hop.
(RUMBLING)
Everybody grab a torch.
Spiders.
We don't normally get spiders in space.
What the...
Don't move!
Do you really think I'm that stupid,
I wouldn't notice?
How did you get aboard, hey? Transmat?
-Who sent you?
-Doctor... (CLEARS THROAT)
That's my dad.
-Well, frankly, that's outrageous.
-What?
You think you can just bring
your dad along without asking?
-I'm not a taxi service, you know.
-You materialised around us!
Oh. Well, that's fine then.
My mistake. Hello, Brian.
How are you? Nice to meet you. Welcome.
Welcome. This is the gang.
I've got a gang.
Yes. Come on, then, everyone.
-Tell him something, quick.
-Yes. Thank you.
I'm not entirely sure what's going on.
You know when Amy and I first got
married and we went travelling...
-To Thailand.
-More the entirety of space and time.
In that police box.
(LOUD THUDDING)
All right, where are we?
What is that noise?
And hello, 10 months!
Orbiting Earth. Well, I say orbiting.
More like pre-crashing.
On a spaceship. Don't know.
And hello, Pond.
Ten months.
Time flies. Never really understood
that phrase.
This is Nefi. This is Riddell.
They're with me.
With you? What, they're "with" you?
Are they the new us?
Is that why we haven't seen you?
No, they're just people.
They're not Ponds.
I thought we might need a gang.
Not really had a gang before.
It's new.
(WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
-It's coming down.
-What is it?
No idea.
(ALARM BLARING)
(GROWLING)
Not possible.
Run!
(ROARING)
-Doctor!
-I know.
Dinosaurs, on a spaceship!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(ROARING)
(CRYING OUT)
In here!
Oh, dear. Ohhh!
(FOOTSTEPS CRASHING, CREATURES ROARING)
I can take one of them.
Short blow up in the throat.
Or not. We just found dinosaurs.
In space! We need to preserve them.
-And who's going to preserve us?
-Shh!
Okay, so...how? And whose ship?
DOCTOR: Well there's so much
to discover.
Think how much wiser we'll be
by the end of all this.
Sorry. Sorry.
Are you saying dinosaurs
are flying a spaceship?
Brian, please. That would be ridiculous.
They're probably just passengers.
-Did I mention missiles?
-Missiles?
Didn't want to worry you.
Anyway, six hours is a lifetime.
Not literally a lifetime.
That's what we're trying to avoid.
And we're all really clever. Ooh.
Let's see what we can find out.
Come on.
Ugh...
How many dinosaurs do you think
are on here?
(BUZZING)
Oh, well done, whoever you are.
Looking for engines.
Thank you, computer. Look at that.
Different sections
have different engines,
but these look like
the primary clusters.
Where are we now, computer?
We need to get down to these engines.
-What happened?
-Oh, great.
Find out...
What?
We're outside. We're on a beach.
Teleport... Oh, I hate teleports!
-Must have activated on my voice.
-Ah, yes.
Well, thank you, Arthur C Clarke.
Teleport, obviously. I mean,
we're on a spaceship with dinosaurs.
Why wouldn't there be a teleport?
In fact, why don't we just teleport now?
-Is he all right?
-No, he hates travelling.
It makes him really anxious.
He only goes to the paper shop and golf.
What did you bring him for?
I didn't! Why can't you just phone ahead
like any normal person?
Somebody tell me where we are. Now!
Well, it's not Earth.
Doesn't taste right. Too metallic.
-(SQUAWKING)
-Is that a kestrel?
I do hope so.
-The beach is humming.
-Is it?
Oh, yes. Well, don't just stand there,
you two. Dig!
I'm going to look at rocks.
-Love a rock.
-Dig with what?
Ah! Well.
-Did you just have that on you?
-Course.
What sort of a man doesn't carry
a trowel?
-Put it on your Christmas list.
-Dad, I'm 31.
-I don't have a Christmas list any more.
-I do!
(CLANGING)
There's a floor under this beach.
Doctor!
MAN: Did you hear that?
Did you hear what he called him?
Doctor.
After all this time.
-Doctor!
-Bring them to me.
Doctor!
There are clearly more than
just two of these creatures.
Hey, put that away. I need you sober.
It's medicinal.
And I don't take orders from females.
NEFERTITI: Then learn.
Any man who speaks to me that way,
I execute.
You're very welcome to try.
Sorry, what was your name again?
Lady of the Two Lands,
wife of the great King Amenhotep.
Queen Nefertiti of Egypt.
-I'll be damned.
-Oh, my God. Queen Nefertiti?
I learned all about you at school.
You're awesome. Big fan. High five.
Yeah, a bit behind on that.
-You're really famous.
-Shh! Listen.
(LOW SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
Okay.
AX a guess, 1. rex.
Not yet full size.
We're in the middle of a dinosaur nest.
I propose a retreat.
-Perhaps forwards.
-Agreed.
Just don't wake the baby.
(GROWLING)
(RIDDELL LAUGHING)
Oh, my God.
Who are you, anyway?
John Riddell. Big game hunter
in the African plains.
-I'm sure you've heard of me, too.
-No.
Well, you clearly have
some alarming gaps in your education.
Or men who hunt defenceless creatures
just don't impact on history.
Face it, she's just way cooler than you.
And you, Amy?
Are you also a queen?
Yes.
Yes, I am.
See? Metal floors. Screens in rocks.
It was just a short-range teleport.
We're still on the ship.
-No, we're outside on a beach.
-No, it's part of the ship, Dad.
-Don't be ridiculous.
-Well, it is quite ridiculous.
Also, brilliant. That's why
the system teleported us here.
I wanted the engines.
This is the engine room!
Hydro-generators! Ha!
I have literally no idea
what he's saying.
-A spaceship powered by waves.
-Fabulously impossible.
Oh, think of the things we could learn
from this ship
if we managed to stop it
being blown to pieces.
-Plus, not dying.
-Bad news is
can't shut the wave system down
in time. It takes...
It takes way too long.
Well, if these are the engines,
there must be a control room.
Exactly.
That's what we need to find, now.
What do we do about the things
that aren't kestrels?
(CREATURES SQUAWKING)
Oh, my lord.
-Are those pterodactyls?
-Yes.
On any other occasion, I'd be thrilled.
Exposed on a beach, less than thrilled.
-We should be going.
-Where?
-Definitely away from them.
-That's the plan?
-That's the plan.
-Amendments welcome.
Move away from the pterodactyls.
-RORY: I think they might be noticing.
-Amended plan - run!
RORY: Can't we
just teleport or something?
No! Local teleports
burned out on arrival.
(PTERODACTYLS SCREECHING)
Ah! There's an opening
in the cliffs over there!
-Come on!
-I'm trying!
Oh!
(SQUAWKING)
-Are you all right?
-Yeah, I'm fine. Oh!
What do we do now?
There's no way back out there.
Through the cave. Come on.
(LOUD THUD)
That suggestion was a work in progress.
-We're trapped.
-Yes, thanks for spelling it out.
Doctor, whatever's down there
is coming this way.
Spelling it out is hereditary.
Wonderful!
That sound's getting nearer.
(RHYTHMIC THUDDING)
(THUDDING SPEEDS UP)
ROBOT: We're very cross with you.
Bit of weed killer wouldn't go amiss
in here.
Whoever was running this vessel
left in a hurry.
Maybe a plague came and took them.
-No, there'd be corpses and bones.
-Unless the animals ate them.
Whoa, Chuckle Brothers.
Lighten up, would you?
(WHIRRING)
How'd you know how to do that?
Well, I've spent enough time
with the Doctor
to know whenever you enter
somewhere new, press buttons.
What else have you learned from him?
Don't stop at button-pressing.
-MAN: 777 years.
-Data records.
-Ship's owners?
-Could be.
Come on, help us out.
...remain cryogenic.
Whilst they sleep, I will continue
to work, being careful to...
How about a picture? Hmm?
Come on. For me?
...far beyond our land.
Look!
Oh, it's beautiful!
I can't tell how far we have come.
Far enough to avoid
the destructive impact
forecast for our planet.
Far enough for me to feel
a profound sense of loss.
What is that?
Silurian.
ROBOT: You're going straight
on the naughty step.
What's the escape plan?
Why do we want to escape?
They have us hostage.
They're taking us somewhere.
We might learn from it.
Ah, you see? So clever.
I've missed you, Rory.
-Don't do that.
-What if they kill us?
They wouldn't do that. You're not
going to kill us, are you, rusty?
ROBOT 1: Who are you calling rusty?
Have you seen yourself lately?
You try being on this ship
for two millennia.
See how your paintwork does.
ROBOT 2: Don't listen to him. He's just
being mean because we captured him.
Oh, my goodness!
-Whoa!
-Ooh!
Herbivore, Brian.
Don't panic. Triceratops.
Ha! Beautiful.
ROBOT 2: Shall I shoot it?
ROBOT 1: We're not supposed to shoot
the creatures, stupid.
-ROBOT 2: Stop calling me stupid.
-"Rah!" yourself.
Hello, cutie-pie.
Who's a lovely Tricey, then, eh?
Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
What do I do? What do I do?
What's it doing?
You don't have any vegetable matter
in your trousers, do you, Brian?
Only my balls.
-I'm sorry?
-Golf balls.
-Grassy residue.
-What are you carrying those around for?
(SLOBBERING)
Ugh!
Ew! Ah!
-DOCTOR: Oh, bless.
-Get it away from me!
-Throw one.
-Really?
Is this what you want? Is it?
And breathe out.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Right. Take us to your leader.
-Really?
-Too good to resist.
Of the 50 species loaded, only one
has had any difficulty surviving.
All the others are thriving
and we expect them to be able
to repopulate.
We're on an ark. A Silurian ark.
Lizard-people herding dinosaurs
onto a space ark?
Absolute tommyrot.
Only an idiot denies the evidence
of their own eyes.
Egyptian queen or not, I shall
put you across my knee and spank you.
-Oh, Lord.
-Try!
-And I'll snap your neck in a heartbeat.
-Hmm.
Well, they certainly bred firecrackers
in your time.
Oh, no, no, no.
Please don't start flirting.
I will not have flirting companions.
If the Doctor trusts Amy, so do I.
Stop doubting her.
-If this ship was built by...
-Silurians, yeah?
Yeah, where are they?
Surprisingly good question.
Display life-signs for Homo reptilia.
AMY: Where have they gone?
Perhaps they found another world,
left the ship.
Well, why are the dinosaurs
still on board?
And why is the ship coming back
to Earth? It doesn't make sense.
What's changed between then and now?
Wait, computer?
Show me the ship at launch
with all life signals.
Now show me the ship today
Thousands less.
But why? I mean...
Show me both images, then and now,
side by side.
What are you looking for?
Okay, two images, spot the difference.
What changed?
What happened to the Silurians?
-The centre.
-Computer, zoom in to the centre.
AMY: Oh, no.
RIDDELL: What is it?
Another spacecraft.
This ship's been boarded before.
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
Love what you've done with the place
down here.
MAN: Let him in. Open the gate.
It's fine. It's fine.
-He's not interested in you.
-Look.
-You need to learn some manners.
-No, you need to learn some manners.
No, you do.
No. You do, Mr Manners.
Fantasia in F Minorfor four hands.
-You know it.
-Know it?
Say hello to hands three and four.
Schubert kept tickling me
to try and put me off.
Franz the Hands.
Oh, that takes me back.
Well, this is...cosy.
It's fate you came.
Is it?
-I'm the Doctor.
-Yes, I know.
I'm Solomon.
What's that?
System malfunction. Ignore it.
What happened to you?
I was attacked.
Three raptors. They cornered me.
The robots rescued me
but it was nearly too late.
Ah, yes. The robots.
-They're...unusual.
-I got them cheap.
From a concession on Aluria 7.
The robots did as best they could
with my legs but...
you can help me so much more.
Oh, a doctor doctor, I see.
Let's have a look.
They chewed through a part of the bone
in my legs.
Yes. Very nasty.
But you can repair them?
If you tell me how you came by
so many dinosaurs.
-Injure the older one.
-What?
(CRYING OUT)
It's all right, Dad.
It's okay. It's okay.
I don't respond well
to violence, Solomon.
And I don't like questions, Doctor.
You boarded without my permission.
Now, fix me
or the next bolt will be fatal.
I will take you apart cog by cog
and melt you down when all this is over.
Oh, I'm so scared.
Actually, I might be.
A little bit of oil just came out.
Now, stay still. It's just a burn.
It's nothing serious.
-What's that?
-While you carry a trowel,
I carry a Med-Pack.
It's all about the pockets
in our family.
This is an ice patch, it cools the skin.
Never seen one of those.
Yeah, I look out for cool stuff
wherever we go.
Some people it's cars
and hardware, for me,
-it is nursing supplies.
-(GROANING)
-Mmm.
-Now, painkiller.
Now, this won't hurt.
Ow!
I lied.
It won't hurt from now on, though.
All right, you.
-You're done.
-Thanks.
That's all right.
You get to see my awesome nursing skills
in action for once.
(PHONE RINGING)
-What's that?
-Your phone's ringing.
-In space?
-You get used to it.
I have to take this. The wife.
-Hello, missus.
-Where are you?
Still on board.
Met some pterodactyls and some rusty
robots that I'm going to melt down.
Rory, this is a Silurian ship.
How did you get on board, Doctor?
Oh, I never talk about myself
with a gun pointed at me.
Let's talk about you.
Your cosy little craft,
embedded in a vast old ship.
-You're very observant.
-I'm a Sagittarius.
Probably.
I'm transporting it
to the Roxbourne Peninsula.
Commerce colony?
You're a trader.
I search out opportunities for profit
across the nine galaxies.
Ah, the purple light.
That's what it was.
(BEEPING)
An IV system, identifying value,
the database of everything across space
and time allocated a market value.
Argos for the universe.
You were trying to find out
how much I'm worth.
Would you like to know?
You don't exist.
It's never done that.
That's me. Worthless.
Unlike these creatures
you have on board.
Very valuable,
-given they're extinct.
-(WHIRRING)
(GROANS)
Done.
Sit up. Very slowly.
Doctor! Amy.
I need to take this.
-Amy.
-This is an ark,
built by the Silurians.
They were looking for another planet.
-Where are they now?
-None on board.
I mean, thousands of stasis pods,
all empty.
I'll see you soon.
(SIGHS)
Be ready.
The pain in my legs is gone.
I can move them. Thank you, Doctor.
What did you do to the Silurians?
We ejected them.
The robots woke them from cryosleep
a handful at a time
and jettisoned them from the airlocks.
We must have left a trail
of dust and bone.
Because you wanted the dinosaurs.
Their ship crossed my path.
I sent out a distress signal,
they let me board,
but when I saw the cargo,
things became more complex.
Piracy, then genocide.
-Very emotive words, Doctor.
-Oh, I'm a very emotive man.
The lizards wouldn't negotiate.
I made them a generous offer.
The creatures onboard this ship
are not objects to be sold or traded.
I feel like you're judging me.
You said Roxbourne Peninsula,
so why are you heading to Earth?
You're on the wrong course.
Oh.
You don't know how. Ha.
Brilliant.
You couldn't change the pre-programmed
course without instructions,
the ship defaulted, returned home.
Oh, dear.
The Silurians outwitted you,
even after you massacred them.
So now
you're a prisoner on the ship
you hijacked.
Not now you're here.
You're going to help me
to where I want to go, Doctor.
Little bit of news, Solomon.
You're being targeted by missiles.
Get off this ship.
While you still can.
You think I believe that?
You just want them for yourself.
You won't profit from me, Doctor.
Don't ever judge me by your standards.
Well, don't just stand there, Rory.
Hey, he wants to see you.
Dad, up.
-What are we doing?
-Just do exactly as I do!
-Doctor, no!
-Geronimo!
(ROARING)
-Did you call?
-SOLOMON: What are you doing?
Stop them!
-All right. Don't shout.
-SOLOMON: Useless machines!
Go, Tricey! Run like the wind!
(SNORTS)
Oh!
Quick, how do you start a triceratops?
-There they are.
-I know. I saw them before you.
Hang on a minute. Tricey, fetch!
Ha-ha! Good boy!
Yee-ha!
Come on, Tricey!
(WHOOPING)
-They've stolen a dinosaur!
-I can see that.
Come on, Tricey! Faster, baby!
ALL: Whoa!
ROBOT 1: They're turning off!
We're losing them!
ROBOT 2: Which way did they go?
ROBOT 1: I thought you were looking.
ROBOT 2: No, now they've got away.
ROBOT 1: We definitely
used to be faster.
I'm riding a dinosaur! On a spaceship!
-I know!
-I only came round to fix your light!
Come on, Tricey!
Where are the brakes?
(ALL SHOUTING)
Ahh! (THUDDING)
(ALL GROANING)
Good! That worked. Okay.
Uh, where are we now? Ooh!
Incoming message from Earth!
Hello, Earth! How are things?
Doctor, the ship's coming through
the atmosphere.
- I have to start the missile programme.
-No. No, no, no, don't do that.
Everything's completely
under control here.
Turning round any moment. Need a bit
of wriggle room on the timings.
-I can't do that.
-You can. Of course you can!
A tiny bit more time. Indira, please.
This ship contains the most
precious cargo.
My only responsibility
Is the Earth's safety.
I'm launching the missiles.
Goodbye, Doctor.
No, Indira!
Hey, come back! Please!
MAN: (ON PA) Target identified.
Navigation systems locking
on to target.
Missile launch procedure initiated.
Estimated impact, 30 minutes.
Now, these are what we need.
Dinosaur protection.
No weapons.
Anaesthetic?
These are stun guns.
-You're almost clever.
-Enough to make a dinosaur take a nap.
Even the Doctor couldn't object to that.
You and the Doctor, are you his queen?
No, no, I'm Rory's queen. Wife.
Wife. I'm his wife.
Please don't tell him I said
I was his queen.
I'll never hear the end of it.
And the Doctor, does he have a queen?
I thought you had a husband.
A male equivalent of a sleeping potion.
You clearly need a man of action
and excitement.
One with a very large weapon.
(WHIRRING)
So, human sleeping potion
or walking innuendo.
Take your pick.
(BEEPING)
DOCTOR: That's very bad indeed.
Completely unhelpful.
RORY: Doesn't this ship have
any defence systems installed?
Good thinking, Rory!
Computer, show us weapons
and defence systems.
Oh. That was a waste of time, wasn't it?
Getting my hopes up like that.
What ship doesn't have weapons?
The ancient species, Rory -
still full of hope.
What about the control deck?
You said we should go to
the control deck next.
It's too late.
It won't make any difference.
-We could at least try.
-It won't work, Rory.
-The missiles are locked on.
-So, what,
-we're just giving up?
-I don't know.
I don't know!
SOLOMON: You were telling
the truth, Doctor.
Earth has launched missiles.
This vessel is too clumsy
to outrun them
but I have my own ship.
You won't get your precious cargo
on board, though. Just be you
and your metal tantrum machines.
-We do not have tantrums/!
-Shut up!
You're right, Doctor.
I can't keep the dinosaurs
and live myself.
But I had the IV system scan
the entire ship.
And it found something even more
valuable.
Utterly unique.
I don't know where you found it
or how you got it here
-but I want it.
-I don't know what you're talking about.
Earth Queen Nefertiti of Egypt.
A face stamped across history.
Give her to me
and I'll let the rest of you live.
No.
You think I won't punish those
who get in my way?
Whatever they're worth?
(ROARING)
(TRICERATOPS HOWLING)
(GROANING SOFTLY)
You must be very proud.
Bring her to me or the robots will
make their way through your corpses.
-Bring her now.
-No.
-What are you doing?
-I demanded to be brought here.
No. No, no, no, no. No way.
It isn't your choice, Doctor, it's mine.
Listen to me. If you go with him,
I can't guarantee your safety.
-You saved my people. I am in your debt.
-No.
No debts. You don't owe me anything.
-Then I do it of my own will.
-Nefi! Nefi!
No!
-Take her, I shoot you.
-Put your weapon down.
Let me make my choice.
Do it, boy.
My bounty increases.
And what an extraordinary bounty
you are.
Never touch me.
I like my possessions to have spirit.
It means I can have fun breaking them.
And I will break you in
with immense pleasure.
Thank you, Doctor.
Computer, take us back to my ship.
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE:
Hostile targeting in progress.
-Bingo.
-What is it? Doctor?
Okay. Control deck.
RORY: So, what's the plan?
Come on.
The missiles are locked on to us.
We can't outrun them.
We have to save the dinosaurs
and get Nefertiti back from Solomon.
Isn't it obvious?
Uh, it's sort of the opposite
of obvious.
Seventeen minutes
before the missiles hit.
We need to turn this ship around.
RORY: You said it was too late,
that there wasn't any time.
Ah, yes, but I didn't have this plan
then, did I? Riddell?
Keep an eye out for dinosaurs.
I was rather hoping you'd say that.
No killing any.
Rory, Brian, get rid of the cobwebs.
Come on. Come on! We're not moving.
He's magnetised us.
We can't move away.
(RAPTOR TRILLING)
(GROWLING)
Keep walking, big chap.
(CROAKING)
(ALL ROARING)
Hell's teeth. That's really not fair.
MAN: (ON PA) Missile target
will be reached in 11 minutes.
No, don't be like that.
Really unhelpful.
-What's the matter?
-Parallel pilot compartment,
it's bio-configured, needs two operators
of the same gene chain.
That's why Solomon couldn't change
the ship's course and neither can we.
-What?
-We can.
Me and Rory. We must be the same
gene thingy you just said.
Brian Pond, you are delicious.
-I'm not a Pond.
-Of course you are. Sit down.
Both of you. Lickety-split.
Ship does all the engineering.
The controls are straightforward.
Even a monkey could use them.
Oh, look, they're going to.
Guys, come on. Comedy gold.
Where's a Silurian audience
when you need one?
Anyway, two eyeline screens,
velocity and trajectory.
Steer away from the Earth.
Try not to bump into the Moon, otherwise
the races who live there will be livid.
What?
Primary control's in the arms
of the chairs.
Principle's the same as any vehicle.
Eight minutes, 45 seconds.
Get us as far away as you can.
Right.
Phase two sorted, now for phase one.
(LAUGHING) No, phase two
comes after phase one.
Humans, you're so linear.
Shine a torch in here.
-What are you doing?
-Mixing my messages.
How's the job?
We're about to be hit by missiles
and you're asking me that?
I work best when I'm multitasking.
Keep talking.
How's the job?
-1...gave it up.
-You gave the last one up.
Yeah, well, I can't settle.
Every minute I'm listening out
for that stupid Tardis...
-Right, so it's my fault now, is it?
-I can't not wait for you. Even now.
And they're getting longer, you know,
the gaps between your visits.
-Are they?
-I think you're weaning us off you.
I'm not. I promise.
I really promise.
The others, they're not you,
but you're more, you have lives,
each other.
I thought that's what we agreed.
I know. I just worry there'll come
a time when you never turn up,
that something will have happened to you
and I'll still be waiting,
never knowing.
No, come on, Pond.
-You'll be there till the end of me.
-Or vice-versa.
Done.
Doctor, this is a two-man job.
What are you doing?
I'm easily worth two men.
You can help, too, if you like.
(BEEPING)
A-ha!
Doctor, what are you going to do...
(SCREEN BEEPING)
(GROWLING)
Quickens the blood, doesn't it?
The sooner this lot go back
to being extinct, the better.
You know what I want more than anything?
Lessons in gender politics?
A dinosaur tooth to take home.
Dinosaurs ahead, a lady at my side,
about to be blown up,
I'm not sure I've ever been happier.
Shut up and shoot.
Duck!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Uh, I'm flying a spaceship.
-Rory?
-Hmm?
-We're flying a spaceship!
-I know! (LAUGHS)
The ship's trajectory is changing.
This makes no difference.
The missiles have locked on.
How long till target?
Seven minutes.
No!
That's it, that's it!
That's it, that's it.
Me, me, me, me, me!
Yes, yes!
It's better than golf.
Hello! Having trouble leaving?
ROBOTS: (POWERING DOWN)
# Daisy, Daisy
# Give me your answer, do #
Ship's still magnetised.
Couldn't bear to lose you.
Release my ship, Doctor.
Or I kill this precious little object.
(SOLOMON GRUNTING)
I'm not your possession now,
nor will I ever be.
Now, stay there.
Don't mess with Egyptian queens,
Solomon.
-I hope you've learnt that now.
-(SOLOMON GRUNTING)
-What are you doing?
-Disabling this ship's signal
and replacing it with the one
from the Silurian ship.
I send this craft off emitting
the signal they're looking for,
the missiles will follow.
Hopefully, Silurian ship's safe,
dinosaurs safe, everybody's safe.
Bit tight for time, though, shouldn't
really be chatting. Nefi, let's go.
How remiss of me. Almost forgot.
The thing about missiles,
very literal.
This is what they latch on to.
Now, one press of this
and the ship's demagnetised.
Doctor, whatever you want,
I can get it for you.
Whatever object you desire.
Did the Silurians beg you to stop?
Look, Solomon, the missiles.
See them shine?
See how valuable they are?
-And they're all yours.
-You wouldn't leave me, Doctor!
Enjoy your bounty.
Doctor!
(ALARM BLARING)
(LOW GROWLING)
So, dinosaur drop-off time.
RORY: Actually, we think home for us.
Oh.
-Fine. Of course.
-Not forever. Just a couple of months.
Right, yes. I'm pretty busy, anyway.
I mean, I've got to drop everyone back.
About that.
Can I ask a favour?
There's something I want to see.
Oh.
More postcards from your dad.
Do you know what?
I think it is the fitting.
Our Father who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name, Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done.
DOCTOR: The gunslinger is a cyborg,
half man, half machine.
-You're really letting him do this?
-Save us all? Yeah, I really am.
Everyone who isn't an American,
drop your gun.