(TICKING)
(TICKING INTENSIFIES)
(SIGHS) Proper.
A-ha!
I said I'd make you
your birthday breakfast.
Yeah, well, I was hungry
and you were dead to the world.
Sorry.
Truckload of presents
should make up for that.
Yeah, about that...
I'm joking!
- No presents. Just a cake.
- Yeah.
- You have got me a cake?
- Yeah, I'm all over the cake.
(LAUGHS)
Mm. Now there's an image!
All right, Monday.
Do your worst.
- Mwah.
- Have a great day.
- I will.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(EXHALES)
Whoa! You all right, love?
Hello! Hello!
Hello, pooch.
- Have a leaflet.
- All right. Thanks.
- Morning. Have one of these.
- Thanks.
Hi. You all right?
Morning, Reggie.
(BELL CHIMES)
(EXHALES)
Hello, good morning.
First time in Gloucester?
Try my guided tour.
Is this your first time
in Gloucester?
Try my guided tour.
This is me. Try my guided tour.
I know all the exciting facts
about Gloucester - yes, I do.
Test me! (LAUGHS)
Go on, then.
Tell me something.
OK.
In 1216, the cathedral hosted
the coronation
of King Henry III,
and he was only nine
at the time! (CHUCKLES)
Th-They filmed Harry Potter
here, too.
Oh!
Yeah, well, plenty more
where that came from.
Tours start at 10.00, 12.00,
and 2.00.
I'll...think about it.
Yeah.
She won't think about it.
No, dear, she won't.
Oh, well. Never mind.
Day's still young.
It's meant to be a heart.
Er... Needs work.
I know. Man spends
his entire life behind a bar -
pivoting to the café trade
ain't easy,
but I try.
For you, I'd try anything.
Allan, we've talked about this.
Oh, I know you're with Lee,
but you deserve better!
Oh.
You know there's
something wrong there.
Is that an actual dossier?
- Yes, on Lee - my Lee dossier.
- Oh, come on!
- He hardly talk to anyone...
- (GASPS)
...cuts his own hair,
gets weird books out
from the library,
claims that his family's
from round here
but I can't find anyone
who knew them.
How can you trust that?
Thank you for
my birthday coffee.
Ruth, I'm telling you,
I hear things.
They don't call me
All Ears Allan for nothin'.
It's not a nickname if you
give it to yourself, is it?
(DOOR BELLS TINKLE)
Ko Fro Lo!
Bo Fro Sho To!
No Bo Ko!
Mo Lo So!
No Kro Do!
She's doing it again.
Spending hours at the controls
looking for something.
Thinks we haven't noticed.
I'll ask her.
Hey, Doc, what are you
looking for?
How long have you been there?
20 minutes.
You haven't.
What you looking for?
Not looking for anything.
Don't lie to us.
The Master.
Why would you do that?
- The Kasaavin took him.
- Yes.
They transported him
to their dimension
and I can't get there
in the TARDIS, but I thought...
...if he escaped,
I could track him.
There's no sign.
I thought he'd be the last
person you'd wanna see.
He left a message for me.
Saying what?
It's personal.
Is that where you go?
When you leave us
to explore and you say
you'll be back in an hour
but you never are?
Are you out looking for him?
Where do you go?
Home.
On my own.
Why? Why not with us?
Cos you ask too many questions.
Maybe because
we're worried about you?
I mean, one minute
you're all smiles,
next minute
your mind's somewhere else.
(ALARM BLARES)
Kro Kro Tro Kro
So Fro So So To!
Kro Kro Tro Kro...
What is that?
A Judoon warning transmission.
The cheek!
Judoon?
Are you just saying that
to shut us up?
Dangerous intergalactic police
for hire.
Notice...of a zonal enforcement
field on Earth -
no-one can get in or out.
What?
They're preparing
to beam down there.
A platoon of Judoon.
Near the moon.
They can't do that. They've got
no jurisdiction there.
Right in the centre
of Gloucester!
I am not having that!
If I can match
the TARDIS's rotation
to the frequency
of the enforcement field's
refresh rate,
I might - just might - be able
to slip us in before
anyone gets killed.
I thought you said
they were the police.
Trigger-happy police.
(ALARM BLARES)
Do Po Lo Sho!
No Dro Fo Ro! Zo!
To Fo Ro!
Dro Ro Fro!
Bo.
Dro!
So 70 Ro!
To Sho Fro!
So Zo To!
No Fo Lo!
(BEEPING)
- (BEEPING)
- No Fo Lo!
No Fo Bo Bo Lo!
Ro!
Bo Ro Kro To Fro Bo!
AN!
- Marcia, don't!
- How dare you!
This is a peaceful, small city.
Who even are you?
Tro Ko Sho.
That took me nine weeks.
RECORDING: That took me
nine weeks.
Language: human.
(BEEPING)
What's this?
Compensation for your weapon.
Answer her question!
Who are you?
We are...
...the Judoon.
Oh...my...God!
You will be catalogued.
I will not! Stay away from me!
- No!
- Marcia!
Enforcement field perimeter
at maximum strength.
You killed her!
Category: human.
- Fugitive match: negative.
- (GROWLS)
- What do you want with us?
- All within the perimeter
must be catalogued.
The fugitive is here.
(DOOR BELLS TINKLE)
Well, look who it isn't...!
I've come to get the cake
that I've ordered
for Ruth's birthday.
Oh, got it right here.
A special birthday message
to her.
What is the matter with you?
Why don't you let it go?
You want to take this outside?
(LAUGHS) Stop asking me that
every time I come in here
for a latte!
(TARDIS THRUMS)
Humans!
- DOCTOR: Through here.
- What are you doing
- in my kitchen?
- Stay inside.
Keep the door closed.
Do not let anyone in,
especially alien police
in helmets and black leather.
The city's under siege.
We're going to sort it.
Oh, yeah, go on,
get out. Coward!
- What is up with him?
- How long you got?
No time at all.
Stay inside. Lock the door.
Come on, gang, no time.
No, no, guys,
look at this little lot.
Lovely! (CHUCKLES)
Look at the state of that!
That's the worst cake
I've ever seen!
Ruth, I've been looking
everywhere for you.
(WHIMPERS) Have you seen?
Yeah.
- They're aliens!
- I know, I know.
Real aliens.
They killed Marcia.
- What?
- Marcia's dead.
We need to get home. Now.
Space rhinos?
I've got no money. I'm sorry,
I'm terrible at this job.
(BEEPING)
Category: human.
Fugitive match: negative.
- Oh, you're after a fugitive?
- (GRUNTS)
I can help. He just left.
On the counter,
there's a dossier.
It's really thorough.
(GRUNTS)
Hey! Watch it, you big...lunk!
Sorry.
Assaulting an officer.
Sentence: execution.
Sentence complete!
OK.
Need to grab some essentials,
a few clothes. We need to go.
What are you talking about?
Go where?
Do you trust me, Ruth?
Sometimes.
You need to just do what I say.
Just get some clothes
and put them in a suitcase.
They can't be after you.
They're aliens.
They've got the heads
of rhinos.
You're from Stroud, Lee.
If there's something
I need to know,
you tell me right now.
There's no time. Come on.
Fugitive house unit located.
Prepare isolator.
I hope you've got
a permit for that.
You're an Imperial Regulator?
Yes. And there's plenty
here to regulate.
For starters, you don't
have jurisdiction here.
So why you're using
a Class Seven Enforcement Field
around this city
bothers me a lot.
More importantly,
this temporal isolator
is an outlawed piece of kit.
Radiation leakage
and civilian casualties.
Designed to freeze time
but causes
horrific collateral damage
to anything and anyone
that gets in its path.
Horrible thing.
Hey, you're not using
that thing here, pal,
so consider your rhino backside
imperially regulated.
(SNARLS)
It sounded tougher in me head.
Fugitive is highly dangerous.
Precautions must be taken.
Not that weapon, not here.
Humans will die, and you,
Captain, will have racked up
enough violations
to ensure that your troop
never get hired again.
(GROWLS)
Look at you and your platoon
of Judoon near the...
...that lagoon.
More of a canal.
- RYAN: Yeah.
- Where's your pride?
(GROWLS)
Where's your respect
for the rules?
I'm very disappointed in you.
(GRUNTS)
So, we will take over from
here.
Negative!
Mission must be fulfilled
by the contracted troop.
Judoon Engagement Article 163B!
That article...is overridden
by local Earth law...
-12...
(GRUNTS)
...which clearly states
that any potential arrestee
is entitled to arbitration
with a third party.
Isn't that correct,
Liaison Officer Khan?
Absolutely correct. 100%.
Rule 127 Massive.
Imperial regulation.
So you will give us the time
to go in there and arbitrate.
That weapon will not
need to be used.
- Clear?
- (GRUNTS)
Come on! We can sort this,
woman to woman.
Give me ten Earth minutes
and we can have this
resolved for you.
Five minutes.
- Nine.
- Four!
Er, fine. I'll take five.
I hate it when they do that.
We'd best take the lift.
Hang on, where's Graham?
- I don't know.
- Have you lost him?
He's not my responsibility.
He's always a few steps behind.
I've stopped checking.
Four minutes thirty.
We haven't started yet!
Come on.
(GROANS)
(AMERICAN ACCENT) Don't move.
Seriously, not a muscle.
Working on
the movement sensors.
If you even flinch,
it'll set off the laser spikes.
Trust me, they get everywhere.
By the way, lookin' good.
Who is this? What's going on?
Where am I? And where are you?
Neutralised.
Comin' to join you.
You can get excited now.
Ha! You missed me, right?
Ha-ha!
Have we met?
Still cheeky.
Regeneration can't change that.
Gotta say, loving the grey
at the temple.
Kinda distinguished,
yet still sexy.
- Oh, come here!
- Whoa!
How you been, Doctor?
Ah.
Pay attention, cos every word
I'm about to say is true.
There's a nasty bunch
of alien police outside.
They're pointing a highly
dangerous cannon at this flat,
and they'll fire it
in about, er, four minutes.
I might be able to stop them,
but I need to understand
exactly why they're here, so
you need to let us in, quick.
Right, tell us everything.
Who are you? We need to leave!
Right into the arms of
intergalactic mercenaries
who seem to think you are
a fugitive from justice.
- They've got it wrong.
- Sure about that?
Yeah! It's mistaken identity.
He works at Bathrooms4U,
for God's sake!
You'd better be telling
the truth, both of you,
otherwise the Judoon
will have you
for harbouring the fugitive,
and their justice is brutal.
I'm not harbouring anyone!
If you're both so innocent,
why are your bags packed?
Yeah, like you're about to
go on the run.
Khan and Sinclair
with the key questions.
Not that you'll get very far,
given the enforcement perimeter
they've just knocked up.
Come on, quick with the truth!
We've got about three minutes,
probably less.
What are you hiding?
Check the flat,
see what's here.
If it isn't these two, it could
be something inside here.
You're not
going through my flat!
Yes, they are.
Have you seen
those things outside?
Yeah, and I've seen
what they do,
and that's why we're running.
- (SONIC WHIRS)
- What are you doing?
- What is that?!
- A device that tells me...
...you're both
completely human.
Please,
I'm trying to save a lot of
lives here, including yours.
If you have any idea why
the Judoon are pursuing you,
you have to tell me right now.
What the...?
What's happening out there?
I guess they want
their ship back.
What, this ain't your ship?
You think I'd choose this look?
Doesn't even have a bar!
A little evasive action.
Hoping these shields
are as good as they say.
A few battles
going on around us...
You're not just kidding me?
You're really not the Doctor?
Oh, no, no. My name's Graham.
I just travel with the Doc.
Ha! Which is why the scoop
read the wrong signal!
Ho-ho, using the old
Quanticum Scoop
I got from a fourple
on Ibiza 13... Whoo!
That was a night!
Actually, that was a month.
Well, look, now you know
who I am, tell me who you are,
why you've kidnapped me
and why you're after the Doc.
I mean, we're in the middle
of something right now.
Captain Jack Harkness
at your service.
Me and the Doc, we go way back.
This is important.
He needs to know the future
of the universe is at stake.
Not he, she.
(LAUGHS)
Oh!
This I gotta see.
Temporal isolator primed,
Captain.
Prepare Final Warning Missile.
Find anything?
A few cash-flow problems,
a collection of old phones
and keys.
I found this in the bedroom.
Hollow compartment
at the back of the wardrobe.
(SONIC WHIRS)
And that...
...is not from Earth.
So where's it from?
- (WHOOSHING)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- Oh, my God!
- What was that?!
This came flying
through the window.
Isolation of fugitive
housing unit
in 108 seconds.
Doesn't time fly when you don't
have all the answers?
So, anyone know what this is?
No, I've never seen it before.
Me neither.
We found it hidden
in your bedroom.
You'd better be
telling the truth,
cos there's a lot of
innocent people
that could die if we don't
sort this out quick.
92 seconds.
Give me the box.
82 seconds.
- Lee? What is that?
- It's nothing.
No, it clearly is something,
cos suddenly you're
all bothered about it,
and I've never seen it
before in my life.
You're in charge, right?
It's a very flat
team structure.
You're the smartest.
I can see it in your eyes.
Use the fire exit out the back.
Take Ruth.
Get her out
and make sure she's OK.
I can take care of this.
What? No, you can't!
What's in the box, Lee?
Who are you really?
It's none of your business.
You've got half of Gloucester
under Judoon lockdown.
I'm making it my business.
45 seconds.
I can deal with this.
Just take Ruth.
40 seconds.
Look, I've...
I've made a mistake.
You're the most important thing
in my life.
I can't let others
lose their lives.
I need to make sure
you're safe.
What do you mean, "a mistake"?
I just need
to talk to them, OK?
But they're space rhinos, Lee.
What are you going to
chat to them about?
- 23 seconds.
- They'll see us
getting out of the fire escape.
- Unless...
- (TOGETHER) Diversion!
Look, you take Ruth.
We'll go out the front
and distract the space feds.
- You think that'll work?
- Come on!
No, cos I'm not going anywhere
without Lee.
I'm a police officer.
I speak their language.
A bit of stalling,
buy time to get them away.
Then we can come inside
with them and be by your side.
I don't need you to be here.
You obviously do,
because there's a cannon
about to fire at your flat.
Time limit exceeded.
Initiating temporal isolation.
We're out of time.
It's the best plan we've got
for keeping this block safe.
Right, be careful.
The Judoon might look dumb,
but they're deadly.
Go to the cathedral.
I'll meet you there.
- OK?
- You better.
Not going to miss
your birthday, am I?
Go, go, go,
before they launch that thing.
...Full documentation
available on request.
See you at the cathedral.
Activate Temporal Blast.
(WHIRRING)
Stop!
Arbitration complete.
Arbitration result?
You can come in now.
So long as you turn that off.
Pause isolation. Remain here.
No fugitives in there,
by the way.
(GROWLS)
And as for you lot,
I don't want you using that.
Keeping my promise.
(PHONE BEEPS)
- (CRASHING)
- JUDOON: Surrender!
This property now
under Judoon jurisdiction.
I surrender. OK?
You can tell your boss.
You-You got me.
- YAZ: Graham!
- RYAN: What just happened?
What are we doing here?
Short answers - this guy,
stolen ship, being fired at.
We need to get back.
And who are you?
Young. I like you young.
But silver fox said,
"She, not he."
So you, not you, right?
I hope you kept
the receipt for the scoop.
Seriously? Three of you?
I had a dream about this once.
- (SUDDEN CRASH)
- Whoa!
- Hold on to something.
- (ALARM BLARES)
JUDOON: Incoming matter
transmission.
Commander Gat,
your presence is not required.
Could've fooled me.
I've been watching it all.
You're so noisy.
Talk about sledgehammers
to crack a nut.
Presenting occupant
of housing unit.
Hello, old friend.
I see you're back
from the dead.
We had such a moving funeral
for you.
But I suppose
that was your intention.
Did you really think
that we wouldn't find you?
Did you think that I'd ever
stop looking?
Good place to hide, mind, the
far backside of a tiny galaxy.
How did you find me?
Sentiment was always
going to be your downfall.
You kept it.
Silly.
Chronotelluric alloy,
strong entanglement.
Very trackable.
It just takes a while.
Yeah, well...
...] wanted to repair it...
...polish it.
My service medal.
Honour and courage
still mean something.
I agree.
See, this is the problem
with our identical training.
We share all the same tricks.
Kill him.
Detained fugitive must be
transferred to contracted...
No, idiot.
You didn't scan him yet,
- did you?
- Uh-uh.
Bless.
(BEEPING)
Fugitive: negative.
Explain.
I'm sorry it has to
end this way.
You got so close to escaping.
Faithful companion.
(GROWLS)
Do I have to spell it out
for you?
(BELLS PEAL)
All clear.
Now, you need to tell me
everything you know about Lee -
how long you've been together,
and what was that metallic box?
- Er...
- (PHONE CHIMES)
(UNZIPS POCKET)
(ECHOING WHISPERS)
- Is that from Lee?
- No.
It's...nothing.
JUDOON: This cathedral
is under Judoon control.
All occupants must
surrender immediately.
There will be no escape
this time.
We have you surrounded.
How can I help?
You interfered, Regulator.
You know what they say,
one person's arbitration is
another person's interference.
Very blurry line.
This is a place of worship.
Show some respect,
or I'll overload
those guns and make it
a bad day for everyone.
Now, let's go,
and nobody needs to get hurt.
What have you done with Lee?
Information request granted.
(BEEPING)
Sentence: execution.
You murdered him.
That is a violation
of your contract!
Incorrect.
Contract stated
retrieval of fugitive.
Fugitive identified.
- What?
- Biological shielding
decrypted.
Fugitive: positive.
That's it. Back up
or Daddy Rhinoform gets it.
What are you doing?!
It feels like...instinct
against the bullies.
Cos you know
the thing about bullies?
There's always a weak spot.
(ROARS)
Bo! Ko! Fo! Jo! To!
Do you know
what you've just done?
Who agre you?!
You have to get us back there.
The Doctor needs us.
Listen, kid, working with
some low-rent equipment here.
Why doesn't that surprise me?
Oh, she likes them mouthy,
then, huh?
Yeah, one up from cheesy.
OK, he's my favourite. (LAUGHS)
(SUDDEN CRASH)
Whoo!
Why didn't it scoop her?
Why can't I get her here?
(SHOUTS IN FRUSTRATION)
Are there Judoon anywhere near
where I scooped you?
Yeah! A lot.
Oh, I knew it!
Level Seven Enforcement Field.
That's why I can't get
accurate traces on her.
Interfering with everything.
Is she safe?
(BELLS CHIME)
(SONIC WHIRS)
Total Judoon evacuation.
They've even removed
the enforcement perimeter.
That's got to be good?
No! Judoon switching strategy
means things have got very bad
and very personal now.
Ruth...
...you just dishonoured
a Judoon captain,
and removing their horn
is the worst insult.
I think you know far more
than you're telling me
about Lee and about
why the Judoon are here.
It's time to share.
I don't know anything.
I don't even know how I did
what I just did to them.
(SONIC WHIRS)
I don't have the decryption
for your bio-shield.
You and Lee
must have both had them.
Very sophisticated,
like biological cloaking.
Look at me.
I know my own life.
I'm Ruth Clayton.
I am 44.
I'm married.
I'm a tour guide.
And I am scared!
Back then...
...that was not me.
My hands, they just moved.
They...
Well, if it wasn't you,
who was it?
I don't know.
I don't understand any of this.
None of this is me.
It can't be.
Help me.
Show me your phone.
You received a message
just before you turned into
Jackie Chan.
"Follow the light.
Break the glass.”
Ruth...
...I don't think you are
who you say you are
or who you think you are.
I think there's another
identity hidden within you.
Maybe this text is
an activation message...
...words to trigger
the real you,
the instincts that enabled you
to attack the Judoon.
No. I'm not that person.
I don't want to be that person.
I'm afraid you don't have
a choice!
Do you have any idea
what this means?
The light. The glass.
(BELL CHIMES)
(ECHOING WHISPERS)
Yeah, I do.
I just saw it.
But it's just a memory.
A memory of what?
The lighthouse where I grew up,
my family home.
Why am I seeing that now?
I haven't thought about that
for years.
It's something to do
with this message.
He had to send it to you
before the Judoon got to him.
What did he know?
Are you sure it's your home?
Of course I'm sure!
I know...where I was
brought up.
My parents are buried there,
on the land outside.
I haven't thought about them
for years, either.
- Do you know how to get there?
- Course I do.
Then we're going,
me and you, now.
Ship's security
is fighting back.
You gotta be kidding me!
Anti-theft attack system.
Oh! Well, now I'm offended.
Look, guys, I'm sorry,
I got get out of here.
I got about a minute
before the ship's nanogenes
attack my body.
- What's going to happen to us?
- Oh!
I'll pre-set the coordinates
to get you back.
Just tell her this.
I'm going to see her again.
Maybe not soon.
When she needs me,
I'll be there.
In the meantime...
...tell her...
...beware the lone Cyberman.
You don't know what a Cyberman
is yet, do you?
No. What are they?
An empire of evil...
...in ruins right now...
...brought down to nothing...
...finally.
But that could all change
if she doesn't listen
to this message.
To defeat them, the alliance
sent this thing back
through time, across space.
Agh! Oh!
They are coming for me!
Always the nanogenes!
(CRIES OUT)
I gotta go.
I've set the scoop for return.
It should take you back
to where you were.
Tell the Doctor...
the lone Cyberman.
Don't give it what it wants.
At all costs!
Tell her!
We've lost him!
Are we stuck here now?
I hope he's got
this thing right.
Tell me about your parents.
I wish I could tell you
I adored them.
But they chose to live
in a disused lighthouse.
That tells you how good
they were with people.
Not like you,
in the heart of the city,
talking to people
all day long.
I guess we all rebel
against our parents.
It's part of growing up, innit?
Never been a fan of growing up.
They loved it out here.
Suited them.
Loved it so much
they wanted to be buried here?
Yep.
- You'd moved away by then.
- Yeah.
But you still own
the lighthouse?
Yeah, they left it to me.
But I never wanted to
come back here to live, though.
When did you move
to Gloucester?
Ooh...1999.
Mid-December.
Are you testing me?
Yes.
I don't know
why I'm even trusting you.
I've got one of those faces.
I promise you...
...I'm your best hope
of finding out who you are
and staying alive.
(ECHOING WHISPERS)
Ruth?
What are you seeing or hearing?
Nothing.
We're nearly there.
That smell...
...home.
Forgotten what it feels
like to come back here.
Like nothing can touch me.
Mind if I take a look around?
Sure.
I'll get a fire going.
(SONIC WHIRS)
(ECHOING WHISPERS)
Why have a blank gravestone?
(SONIC WHIRS)
Because it's not a grave.
(ECHOING WHISPERS)
(WHISPERS) Break the glass
and follow the light.
Break the glass
(GRUNTS AND PANTS)
and follow the light.
Break the glass and follow
the light.
Break the glass and...
(WHOOSHING)
(BUZZING)
(PANTS HEAVILY)
(WEAPON BEEPS)
You're probably
a bit confused right now.
I broke the glass.
It's all come back to me.
This.
What is this?
That's my ship.
What?!
Let me take it from the top.
Hello, I'm The Doctor.
I'm a traveller
in space and time,
and that thing buried
down there is called a TARDIS.
Time And Relative Dimension
In Space.
You're gonna love this.
Come on, old girl.
Too sleepy.
Power up!
(TARDIS WARBLES)
Need you right now.
Hi. Struggling with this.
Can you just...?
No, I can't. Not right now.
No time.
Just stand there
and don't ask questions.
Sorry you got caught up
in all this,
but if Gat is half the
operative she used to be,
she's already figured out
where we are.
And we need to be ready,
and we're not.
Stop. Who's Gat?
And who are you, really?
Truly.
I told you, love.
I'm The Doctor.
- You can't be.
- Yeah? And why's that?
Because I'm The Doctor.
You have got to be kidding me!
Really?
Yes, really!
Since when?
Since forever.
And how did I end up like...
...that?
All rainbows
and trousers that don't reach?
What?
No, how did I end up like you?
You don't.
You're in my future,
not the other way round.
I've never been
anything like you.
Trust me, I'd remember.
Especially that shirt.
So would I, if I'd ever
been you, which I haven't.
DOCTOR: What?
Huh?
TOGETHER: That's not
possible. Unless it is.
But what would that mean?
Doesn't make sense.
Stop doing that!
Oh. Same brain.
No, this doesn't
make any sense.
Either I should know you
or you should know me.
- Agreed.
- So why don't we?
I don't know.
Why don't you try asking that
cute little gizmo of yours?
Yeah, that's the one.
I did. I used it on you,
but it couldn't decrypt
the bio-shield.
If you've been restored...
(SONIC WHIRS)
(SONIC CHIRPS)
Same person.
Oh, no.
But you don't recognise
the sonic screwdriver.
Smart enough not to need one.
Oh, yeah, nothing screams
"smart" like a laser rifle.
I stored that before hiding,
cos I knew Gat would come
one day, and now she has.
Who is this Gat?
I worked for her once.
- You've got a job?
- Oh, sort of.
Not one you apply for.
Not one you can ever leave.
Believe me, I tried.
You've been hiding on Earth.
You used the Chameleon Arch
to hide your identity,
to hide your mind,
even from yourself.
That's why the sonic
didn't pick it up!
And Lee was your protector.
(CONDESCENDING) Well done.
You're only five minutes behind
someone who just had
their memory fully restored.
(GASPS) Five points.
Don't do points, I do points.
Points are my thing.
- (CRASHING)
- Oh!
(CRACKLING)
- (RUMBLING)
- What's happening?
She's here.
RUTH: The Judoon have got us
in a tractor beam,
dragging us aboard their ship.
Now listen to me, Doctor.
Let me do the talking.
Do not get involved.
Because, if you really are me,
and Gat figures that?
She'll kill us both.
(RIFLE BEEPS)
(DOOR CREAKS)
GAT: Here we are, then.
End of the road.
I thought I'd be angry
when I saw you.
Turns out I'm just sorry.
Not as sorry
as I'm about to be.
Ruth, put it down.
Yes, "Ruth”.
Do as your little friend says.
You are surrounded, after all.
Don't point that thing at me,
Gat.
This was mine - you stole it.
Mm, confiscated it.
No, really,
don't point it at me.
Perfect for your execution.
I really wouldn't do that, Gat.
Enough now.
Let's get off this rust bucket
and finish this on my ship.
- When you say "finish this"?
- Shut up.
Take her advice, little woman.
"Little"?
Biting my tongue.
Contract states Judoon
must deliver fugitive
to contractee at Division.
I'm here on behalf
of the contractee!
Hang on, I thought you'd
hired the Judoon.
- Who are you?
-I'm...
Imperial Regulator.
Sort of. Bit of a fib. Sorry.
- Actually, I'm...
- She's nobody.
Fine.
I'm nobody.
Absolutely nobody.
See, I know why you want her -
you've got a contract,
fair enough. But you?
You want her dead
because she left her job?
Shut up!
Is that what she told you?
This goes way higher than me.
So, who would that be?
Who are you all
ultimately working for?
I'd really like to know.
Really.
Information confidential.
I told you to keep quiet!
And look where
that's gotten us -
lots of guns in lots of faces.
And have you got
a better idea?
I do, actually. My favourite -
the curve ball and the Judoon.
You wanted to find The Doctor?
Don't you dare.
Well, here I am.
Will you be quiet?!
Go on, scan me.
(SCANNER BEEPS)
Fugitive match positive.
Is there even a word
for how dumb you are?
"Doctor"?
Subsection 951 triggered.
Two fugitives, two payments.
There won't be two payments,
because two
of the same Time Lord
can't occupy the same space
at the same time.
It's an abomination!
It'll destroy the time streams
before you get
anywhere near Gallifrey!
What did you say?
(SONIC WHIRS)
(SONIC CHIRPS)
Gallifreyan.
You're from home.
I serve for the glory
of Gallifrey.
Then both of you
can only be my past.
But that's impossible,
because I know my own past -
I lived through it. All of it.
You're wrong.
DOCTOR: I'm not wrong!
I've seen Gallifrey destroyed.
Twice.
First by a war,
second by a lunatic
who I'm still trying to find.
In my time,
Gallifrey doesn't exist.
It's gone! Forever.
And if you don't know that,
you're in my past.
So you are only serving
at the glory of ash and bone.
This is a trick.
Check my mind -
one Time Lord to another.
See what I saw.
Keep an eye on her.
Contact.
(FIRES CRACKLE)
RUTH: What did you see?
What did she show you?
I don't know
what trickery this is...
(RIFLE BEEPS)
Put the gun down, Gat.
...but it ends here!
Don't do this.
(CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
You knew that would happen.
You sabotaged the gun.
I told her not to do it,
I begged her not to fire.
But you knew she would!
Don't take the moral
high ground with me.
Crime has been witnessed.
RUTH: No crime.
- (SNARLS)
- An accident.
And, besides, a Judoonese
Talwak Freighter like this,
moving at 80 million clicks
an hour,
entered interstellar space...
...12 seconds ago.
No-one has jurisdiction
in interstellar space.
So no laws, and no crime.
Isn't that right, Doctor?
Yes.
- (RIFLE BEEPS)
- Recalibrated.
Who wants some?
The Doctor never uses weapons.
I know. Shut up!
We're leaving now.
(GROWLS)
If you know what's good for
you, do /70t come for me again.
Ever.
Consider your
contract cancelled.
(SNARLS)
JUDOON: Judoon contracts will
always be fulfilled!
Homing in your TARDIS signal.
Can't get too close.
Imagine the temporal
feedback loop.
I'll drop you at the docks
near my flat.
How's that?
You can't be me.
I know what I've done,
I know my own life.
One of us has to be wrong.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
(THUD)
I'd quite like it
if you got off my ship now.
YAZ: There she is!
Doctor! Found you.
RYAN: Hey, what happened?
Where you been?
What happened to Ruth?
The Judoon things are gone.
You're never going to guess
what happened to us.
Captain Jack Harkness
said hello.
What?
GRAHAM: "Beware
the lone Cyberman.
"Do not let it have
what it wants, at all costs.”
That's all he said?
RYAN: Yeah, he got interrupted.
YAZ: Who is he, anyway?
An old friend.
I liked him.
Kinda cheesy.
But good cheesy.
That's Jack.
He didn't say any more
about the Cybermen?
Er, he said that
they were fallen empire
and they should stay that way.
What are they, these Cybermen?
They're one of the most
dangerous species
I've ever encountered,
up there with the Daleks.
Oh, I can't wait to meet then,
then.
And they're in our future?
They're always somewhere...
...waiting.
You haven't told us about Lee
and Ruth and the Judoon.
Who was the fugitive?
It was Ruth.
But Ruth was me.
What?
What are you talking about?
How's that possible?
She said she was my past,
but I know my past.
And she's never been me.
I'm sure there's
a simple explanation.
Time is swirling around me.
The Master,
Captain Jack Harkness, Ruth.
Something's coming for me.
I can feel it.
Let it come.
You've got us.
Ryan...
...I've lived for thousands of
years, so long I've lost count.
I've had so many faces.
How long have you been here?
You don't know me.
Not even a little bit.
Don't talk to him like that!
Yeah, I'm not having that.
We do know who you are.
You're the woman
that brought us together,
the woman that saved us
and loads of other people.
You're The Doctor.
Whoever you were in the past
or are in the future,
we know who you are right now.
Right?
Right!
The best person we know.
And whatever is coming
for you, we'll be here.
Cos we're your mates.
Well, not just mates. Family.
- Yeah.
So, whether you
want to go looking
for whatever trouble's coming,
or whether you want
to wait here
and let it come to you...
...we'll be right here,
by your side,
like it or not, Doctor.
(ALARM BLARES)
What's that?
I know what you're doing -
siding with them,
distracting me.
You're doing this deliberately.
Whoa!
Multiple alerts across
three continents here on Earth.
Can't be connected.
Unless they are.
Quick look?
Quick look.
Let's go.
Need some help over here!
Two identical deaths
on two different continents.
It's even more dangerous
than I thought.
This can't be happening.