There she is.
So small, I could reach out and...
Crush it! Crush it! Crush it!
Quiet, Caw!
This is my moment of destiny...
Moment of Destiny!
Moment of destiny...
Attention armoury!
Prepare plasma cannons for firing.
Commence countdown!
I'm the king of the world!
King of the world!
King of the world! Aaark!
Now, forget your Bonapartes, your
Boudiceas, your Blackbeards, even...
Wha...?
This, Martha Jones, this is Baltazar.
Scourge of the Galaxy, corsair
King of Triton on the 40th century,
the greatest despot
that ever, ever lived!
This is just...just...fantastic!
Yeah, it's kinda cool.
Now, the thing about Baltazar.
Scourge of the Galaxy! Yeah...the
most amazing thing about him is...
he forged this ship himself.
He didn't!
By hand. Go on, tell her, Baltazar!
I tended her by hand,
over countless decades.
Burnished her into the
greatest warship in history!
And not that long ago, blew all of
Earth's defence force from the sky.
He really shouldn't have done that.
Shouldn't have done that!
And now I'm going to envelop
Earth in a field of plasma fire.
Superheat the carbonites
who crawl across its surface...
Really? So all carbon-based life
will be super-compressed in a plasma
field, making... Diamonds?!
Precisely.
Yeah, well done. Yes, every
living being turned into diamonds.
And the plan starts in seconds!
Now, that IS a Plan.
That...is...indeed...a...plan.
Is that not the most incredible plan?
Oh, incredible,
but, we're gonna stop him, yeah?
Mm. By giving him...this!
Wha...? I like to stir things up.
Oooh, shouldn't have done that.
He shouldn't have broken it
because...?
It wasn't just any old spoon.
It passed through the hands of the
greatest chefs of planet Earth.
Fanny, Delia, Madame Cholet. It was
antique, forged by inhabitants of a
planet that specialised in Ribicola.
Fungus?
Oh, yes, but not just any old fungus.
No, a special hydroxiding fungus...
There's been no treatment for it
these last 2,000 years.
Which is why,
Baltazar, Scourge of the Galaxy...
Your deck is rusting away!
Wha...?
Nooo!
That's not ordinary rust!
Nah, I pepped it up a bit.
Gave it a bit of zing.
A bit of va-va-voom.
Va-va-voom! Va-va-voom!
Doctor, you can't leave him.
Not to the rust!
Ah well...
Will Baltazar ever get caught?
I imagine so. His luck
can't hold out forever.
So what'll happen, d'you think?
In this era? Most likely
prison planet for him would be...
Volag-Noc.
Yeah, that's where I'd take him
if it was up to me.
Coldest place in the galaxy.
Brrrr. Nasty. Yup. Now...give
me a number between zero and 99!
45. And another!
72. Another! Three.
What is this? Galactic lottery?
Destination setting!
And you, Martha Jones, have
randomly chosen to take us to...
Copacabana Beach! Arriba!
I'll get you for this, Doctor!
I'll make you
sorry you were ever born!
Yes!
670 million miles an hour, and a bit!
Rock on!
You're just a boy racer, aren't you?
Ha!
Whoah!
What was that - emergency stop?
Owww, search me.
There's nothing in the manual...
Go on, then. We've stopped.
I've died and gone to Bill
Oddie heaven. Bill Oddie heaven!
I know you! It's Caw, isn't it?
Welcome to Pheros, Miss Martha.
It's Caw's home.
How're you doing, Caw?
I likes you, Miss Martha.
Oh! That's for savin' Caw's
life all them years ago.
Thank you, Caw. It's really lovely.
Got some news for you, Doctor.
'Bout Baltazar.
Let him out of Volag-Noc.
Volag-Noc? I was right, Martha!
Yeah, great. Caw, why'd
they release him?
Say he's reformed.
But Caw reckons he's as bad as ever
he was. He'll be comin' for Caw.
Caw sold him out, for a bar of gold.
Or three...
What do you need gold for?
He eats it.
He won't rest, Doctor!
He seeks his heart's desire
and knows how to find it. He does?
The Infinite!
Oh, that's just a legend.
What is?
Baltazar thinks different.
Thinks he knows how to find it.
Find what? The Infinite.
Yeah, I got that.
But what exactly is the Infinite?
Well, let's just say there are
things out there in space, Martha,
things that pre-date our reality,
relics from the Dark Times.
Oh, a fairy tale?
Oh, far, far more than that.
There was a time when the universe
was so much smaller than it is now...
A darker, older time of chaos.
Creatures like the Racnoss,
the Nestenes and the Great Vampyres
rampaged through the Void.
And this Infinite is one of those
"relics from the dark time"?
It's said that if anyone
were to find the Infinite,
they'd receive their heart's desire.
And frankly, that's
quite a thing to receive.
Yeah, but how's
Baltazar gonna find it?
That's how.
What's that? It's a data chip.
Part of a black-box recorder.
Dark Time technology.
Baltazar gave it to me
for safekeeping.
Should be four of 'em.
You need to use each one
to find the next.
And find all four,
you find the Infinite?
Are we going on a quest, then?
No. The Infinite stays lost.
Nothing more than a legend.
As last custodian to the Secrets
of the Universe, it's my duty
to see it stays that way.
He mustn't! Mustn't!
He's got a copy!
I can't let someone like Baltazar,
corrupt and twisted, have access
to that kind of power.
Caw, you'd better
be right about this.
Planet Bouken.
OK. Here...we...go!
The tracker's in place?
Thank you, Caw.
It's really lovely. Aaaark!
Then the Doctor's going to
find me the Infinite, going to
find me my heart's desire...
Heart's desire! Heart's desire!
And then, I'll have my revenge!
Revenge! Revenge!
Ah, Martha, see those?
Artificial suns. Never!
Someone wanted the planet Bouken
warmed up.
What are they? Oil rigs.
Oil rigs?! Hang on.
They still need oil, in the future?
It ran out on Earth. The
corporations went drilling elsewhere.
To look at them,
you'd think they were alive.
You think?! Run? What now?
Er, well, I'm open to suggestions...
Er...
How'd you do that?
Oh, Martha, you're brilliant!
Oh, yeah, now you're just
showing off. Whoah!
Hoist the colours, Mr Mate!
Aye aye, Captain! Let OilCorp see
that the Black Gold is in business!
Aye aye, Captain! A-harr.
Pirates?! I'm Swabb,
First Mate aboard the Black.
Now then, Mr Mate, put her in
reverse! Aye aye, Captain! A-Harr!
You two might want to hold on tight.
To the rail? Aye aye, Captain!
Take the strain, me hearties!
Heave lads!
All right, Swabb, maximum power!
Aye!
Well, that I didn't expect.
Cut thrust, Mr Mate.
Then pull the rig in?
And siphon it, Swabb!
Hello there, Captain...? Captain
Kaliko. Hello. I'm the Doctor.
Martha and I...
Why are they smashing the oil rigs?
Told you, it's the 40th century.
The oil corporations are sucking
the solar system dry to feed demand.
Petrol prices are through the roof
and the colonies that can't afford
to pay are dying.
Aye. And the oil companies
call us pirates.
So you're smashing the rigs,
siphoning off the petrol...I see.
Robbing the rich to fuel the poor?
But that's brilliant! What d'you
think we should do with them, Swabb?
I don't know, Cap'n.
Can't hear you!
A skeleton crew? Literally.
Less of a drain on rations.
Now, what I reckon is, to land
up in a place like this,
you dogs're either OilCorp spies
or planning a spot
of piratin' yourselves...
Or indeed, none of the above...
Either way, I don't want you
on the Black Gold.
So ahoy there,
me heartless hearties,
throw these sandlubbers overboard!
Yeah...ahhh...
Hold hard there, lads!
Swabb, you swab! Is this mutiny?
Yesss!
Never, Cap'n Kaliko, not mutiny!
Nooo.
I just wondered if they be OilCorp
spies, mayhaps we dispose
of the bodies by putting them inside
one of the oil rigs? A-harr...
Make it look like an accident?
Yer not as empty-headed
as you seems, Mr Mate!
We'll use the one
we just keelhauled!
Aye aye, Cap'n.
Don't worry, Doctor, Martha.
You're perfectly safe with me.
What's he up to? Hmmm...
I don't think our Mr Swabb is all
he's cracked up to be. I wonder...
Said your prayers yet, Doctor?
So, um, sorry, let me see
if I've got this right?
We somehow get inside this rig
you've drained of oil, and then what?
A quick blast from me mate
Swabb's laser pistol,
the remaining oil ignites...
OilCorp find us dead inside.
Boiled in oil? That's murder!
Accidents happen.
Now, me hearties! The plank!
Careful with that!
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh...me first.
Thought Swabb would have
made his move by now.
What move? He's no pirate.
If he thinks we're with this OilCorp,
then my guess is... That he is too?
Yeah. Fingers crossed. Ready!
I like your style, Doctor.
Shame you have to die!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Now, let us go,
or I'll destroy your ship!
What, with that?
No deal!
I wish you weren't so obstinate,
Kaliko. Oh, well.
Why's it not working?
Um, patience.
Er...sand in the mechanism.
Hang on...
Success! And?
And hold on tight.
OilCorp dog!
You're damaging the Black Gold!
We're actually on your side,
Captain! We came here to save you!
It's all right, Martha.
The Captain's pirate days are over.
I'm with OilCorp.
Told you!
And OilCorp have promised me a new
body to replace this bag of bones.
Same goes for you, me hearties, if
you'll help me turn the Captain in!
They'll never turn on me!
Oh, no.
Thing is, Captain, Swabb here seems
to think Martha and I are
with OilCorp too... You're not?
No. You're not. No!
Captain, we've come here
to rescue you.
Why? Doesn't matter, Captain.
You're time is up!
Rigs! Attack!
Lucky they're not great shots!
Define "lucky"!
No! No, more precision.
Fire with more... Waaaaghhh.
Roll with it, Martha!
Doctor?
Aah! Forget it, he's gone.
But at least I can think
of a good use for you.
Oh, really! Yes.
My five year service reward
from OilCorp is that I get
to choose a new body soon.
And you know what?
I can see myself wearing yours.
Slinky, yeah!
Look, me and the Doctor aren't here
to cause you and OilCorp trouble.
We're on a dead important mission.
Gotta collect data chips.
Stop this Baltazar stealing a big
spaceship called the Infinite,
which'll give him infinite power.
And that's bad cos he's not
a nice bloke. Oh, and Swabb?
Yeah? Um...behind you?
Aye-aye!
Oooh, sorry! Doctor!
Wooah...
Will the vile dog live?
The sand seemed soft,
so it probably broke his fall.
I'll get you for this! Yup, he's OK.
You need some help?
Could you?
Ow, oooh! Doctor, you said
you'd come here for me.
What exactly did you mean by that?
Ah. Well?
Your earring, Captain.
You know what it is, really?
You're after the Infinite? You fool!
Now, I was going offer you
both a berth on my next ship,
but seeing as you had an
ulterior motive in rescuing me...
There's only room for one
in my lifeboat, anyhow.
Looks like she came down near
the TARDIS. We have to catch her.
If Baltazar gets that data chip,
and finds the Infinite...
He gets his heart's desire -
destruction of you, me and Earth.
Look! Aw, no.
Surely the fall couldn't do that?
No. She's been murdered.
Live by the cutlass, die by
the cutlass, it seems. Doctor?
I'm so sorry Kaliko...but we've
got what we came for, Martha.
Let's see where we're going next.
Hang on! There could be anything out
there. Snakes like bendy buses,
sabre-toothed gorillas. Anything!
Excellent! Right...that way is Main
Street, so that's probably downtown.
Where's the lights? Lights?!
City like this should be full
of lights, especially at night.
INSECTS BUZZ
Doctor! They're bugs!
So I see, and they're about to swarm!
Doctor! The bugs...
Swarming...all around us...
Go on! Get out of it!
What's the matter with you two?
Doctor? I know.
And what are you staring at?
Thank you. For the timely arrival.
Mr, Um? Mergrass. Ulysees Mergrass.
Good thing the bugs listen to you.
We have an understanding. I noticed.
I'm here to provide their community,
via their Queen, with protection.
SIREN WAILS
What's that?
What they need protecting from.
Hang on. Those are warplanes.
What do you expect in a war zone?
BOTH: A war zone?!
Sonic attack! Incoming!
You know what?
I think he's got the right idea.
Martha? Martha! Look out!
Pretty, isn't it?
If you like that sort of thing.
Careful!
Don't touch what isn't yours. Yet.
Breakages must still be paid for.
Besides which, they won't activate
until I give your Queen this
keycoder to switch everything on.
You all right? Turns out the
towers are built from dung, not rock.
But even so. Yeah, I'm fine.
It's beautiful.
Really beautiful.
Well said, Martha Jones.
Ah! Martha Jones, the Mantasphid
Queen; the Mantasphid Queen, Ma'am,
Martha Jones.
Your...Majesty? Spot on.
As I was saying,
these alien attackers...
I hope you're not putting
a business proposition, Doctor!
The bidding is over. I won.
Mergrass is correct, Doctor.
We have our military adviser
already, we do not need another.
Oh. "Military adviser", is it?
Interesting euphemism for
gun-running. Gun-running?
In the crates.
They've caught a pilot!
Mergrass, they've caught a pilot!
Stand well back. I want to see
what it is you're fighting against.
Oh. What are you?
Crush it! Squash it!
Get it away from me!
Wait, Doctor, it's...
Trying to kill me, I know!
No! It's panicking.
Doctor, it's just frightened!
Oh.
Oh, oh, Martha, you're a marvel.
Calm, calm, calm, calm.
Hey, I'm not going to hurt you.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Training didn't prepare me!
I didn't... It's all right,
it's all right, calm down.
You're fine now. Sorry.
Suit got damaged when I came down.
No air left. I thought I was
gonna die, I don't want to die.
Well, you didn't. Fleshy biped!
We must be protected from
fleshy bipeds! Destroy them all!
You can destroy them, Your Majesty.
With the weapons you've bought.
What's your name, pilot?
Pilot Kelvin.
Well, Pilot Kelvin,
what's wrong with you?
Picking a fight with a
bunch of defenceless bugs?!
Eh? We didn't start it!
Yes, they did.
The fleshy bipeds have been trying
to exterminate us! Wipe us out!
No! You don't understand.
This is my er... This...
This was my home.
Where I was born, brought up.
We were here first!
Is this true?
This used to be a lovely place.
My parents had a homestead here.
Then the bugs arrived and drove the
people out. I only joined up once...
Once my parents were killed.
Killed? Why?
Why did you attack?
So many lovely animals
they had here.
So much lovely dung!
You invaded this planet for dung?!
It's one of the last
fertile planets in the galaxy.
If it falls, there'll be a
famine like you wouldn't believe.
Your Majesty, if I may?
My job here is done.
I've supplied you with the
means to destroy your enemies.
Your contract stipulates
final payment on delivery.
Did it?
Guess what, Mergrass. I lied!
There will be no payment!
Mantasphids don't make deals
with fleshy bipeds.
Typical mantashpid.
I should've listened to the others.
What others? The prisoners.
There was a mantasphid there, too.
Tipped me off about this little
war, so I decided to do the deal.
You were in prison? Good grief, no.
I was a broker, a dealer.
I'd get letters and gifts to
the inmates, and in return...
You got well paid?
Of course.
But the governor always said that
you could never trust a mantasphid.
The Governor of which prison
was this? Volag-Noc perhaps?
Volag-Noc? But isn't that where
Baltazar was? You know of Baltazar?
AIR-RAID SIRENS WAIL
The fly-ships, they're coming back!
Bugs, defend us!
They'll destroy us all.
We're going to die too unless
we get away. Forget it.
You can't get far enough away.
Why not? Because Earth Command
can't afford to lose this planet!
You see, they'll even sacrifice me.
Your Majesty,
there might still be a way.
Ah, Doctor.
This is a fleshy biped thing,
is it not?
"Never say die"? Yeah, exactly!
Fleshy bipeds are very
stupid creatures.
But the fight goes on!
We'll win this war yet!
Pilot Kelvin!
What will they do to the city? Well,
the plan was spatial disintegration
of this 100-mile vector.
They're going to burn us
out of space and time?
Kills all known bugs. Dead.
So we stand here
while they vaporise us?
Mergrass, what do we do?
- You're asking me?
- You're my military adviser!
You know tactics! You know weapons!
Help us!
I'd have happily helped you
when I thought I was getting paid
but without this,
the weapons are useless.
And without my money,
you get nothing.
Mergrass! Mergrass! Come back!
We need to keep track of Mergrass. He
has the data chip we need
to continue this treasure hunt.
It is decided.
How do we surrender
to the fleshy bipeds?
At last. Pilot Kelvin, have you
got a communications system?
Inside my helmet, sir!
But it was damaged when I crashed.
Oh, we'll soon
have that sorted.
Hurry! Hurry! We want to surrender!
Doctor, there's no protocol for
negotiation with the Mantasphids.
Then make one! I can't. They invaded
our homes, killed our families.
They're also living sentient
beings that have a right to exist.
Maybe not here, but somewhere.
'Mantasphid hive destruction
commences in 60 seconds.'
Oooh, that's not good.
Please, Doctor. Hurry.
Doctor! Listen, if the bugs can't
surrender, surely we can, can't we?
You are brilliant! Pilot, tell them
to open up a visual channel. Control!
This is Pilot Kelvin, imperative you
open a visual link to this system.
Please respond. Roger.
Hurry, Doctor!
Ahoy there,
ye Earth Command nobodies!
You got Doctor Vile,
pirate o' the constellations,
givin' you a big white flag!
Fact is, me an' me
mad mucker Martha here...
Arr! Arr! Arr!
Umm, no. No, don't, don't do that.
We've been rulin' over these insect
raiders, held their Queenie hostage!
But, we has to admit,
you got us beaten.
Come on in and get us.
We surrender! That should do it.
What have you done, Doctor?
Taken the rap for you, Queenie.
Ended your war!
They'll never believe it.
You reckon?
All units,
hive destruction cancelled.
Your priority now is to apprehend
male human, codename "Doctor Vile"!
How can we thank you, Doctor?
Easy. Work with the humans, not
against them. Young Kelvin here
could make a great ambassador. Me?
Listen, Your Majesty,
the humans' farms will need power.
Light and heat are hard to come by
in an oil-starved universe, right?
And you're naturally phosphorescent.
Think you can make a deal?
And you'll get all the dung
you could ever want!
Brilliant! So what's next?
We skedaddle out of here
before Kelvin's mates arrive.
Good luck, everyone.
What now?
Catch up with Mergrass and go?
Oh, we've found him.
Oh, no! No!
Sudden dehydration.
Take the data chip, and let's go.
We can't just leave him!
It's like Captain Kaliko
all over again. Isn't it just.
But Martha, we can't stay!
We're criminals, remember?
Next data chip located!
It's... Ah. It's... Oooh.
Where? Is it bad?
You wearing thermals?
Come on, you.
Where are we going?
Where are we, full stop!
Well, we've now met two people
from the prison on Volag-Noc, right?
Right, but there's no prison here!
You were saying?
Doctor!
I thought you'd never get here!
Er, we're visitors.
Visitors, mind! Oi!
This item is confiscated.
What? Scanning for malfeasance.
No convictions. No confirmation of
criminal activity. Well, obviously.
Scanning.
3,005 outstanding convictions...
That many? ..With 6,000 more to be
taken into consideration. Doctor?
It's an unfair cop! Prison Cell 8447.
Doctor!
The governor will see you now.
Oh, good. Great. I think.
Ooh. Hello, you're clearly an
android and I'm your new cellmate!
You all right? It hurts!
I'm the Doctor. Tell me the trouble.
Interesting.
You're the governor?
There's been a mistake.
We don't make mistakes on Volag-Noc.
Safe!
But my friend's been...
Close. You were saying?
I... Ah, yes, your "friend".
We're still collating charges,
but he's been a very naughty boy.
Minor traffic violations,
1,400 counts.
Evading library fines, 250 counts.
C'mon, that's nothing serious!
Planetary demolition.
How many counts? 17. No, 18.
Ouch. And all dating back...
3,000 years?!
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons.
Maybe, but these charges have
been extracted from his own brain.
He knows what he's guilty of. And
they've earned him... Let's see...
2 billion years in prison.
2 billion?! He really should have
taken back those library books.
Hang on, there's more.
There's something here about a
"Doctor Vile", wanted for piracy.
As well as his accomplice.
You!
So anyway, Caw then said -
did I mention Caw before?
Big, metal, bird, eats gold for
breakfast - anyway, he told us that
Baltazar is after the Infinite,
the starship that has the
power to create your heart's desire.
Baltazar - nasty flea, used to live
here. Anyway, we have to chase
around, stopping him...
Ow! Oooh, sorry! Sorry.
Hang on,
you've been inhibited! I have.
You couldn't commit
a crime if you tried! I could not.
you shouldn't be here at all!
Oh, I'm not having this.
Thank you. Right, we'll have
to dig our way out.
Don't suppose you've concealed
a teaspoon? I lost mine.
There's a more direct way.
Now.
Oooh! What was that?
Warder, what's up with the lights?
Power fluctuation detected,
Governor.
A cell has been opened from within.
Opened? Where? Cell 8447.
That cell is off limits.
Didn't your tin pet there
put the Doctor in Cell 8447?
No, I gave explicit orders no-one
was to be put in with the gover...
The governor, were you gonna say?
I saw the data chip in your safe!
If you're not the governor,
who are you?
Don't you get it? He's escaped.
Your friend's let him out!
And we've only been here five
minutes! Nice one, Doctor.
No.
What's doing that?
Locke.
Hello, Martha Jones!
You'll never guess who I'm with!
The real governor?
Oh, you guessed! Thing is, if Locke
here is the governor, who are you?
Warder!
You don't know what you've done,
letting him out.
Hang on, hold this for a moment,
will you?
But there's nothing on it!
It's psychic, and it tells me you're
"Constantine Ethelred Gurney.
"Prisoner" Aha! Convicted of
blackmail, fraud...blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, released... Released?!
I did my time, I got let out,
I broke back in.
That's new. Why?
Because of him!
Living here in luxury.
He's an android.
He doesn't even need it.
But me, there are people
across the seven galaxies
who still want my head on a plate,
putting my face on Wanted posters.
"Wanted Dead or Alive"
open brackets, "preferably dead".
Close brackets. I get the picture.
There was this guy I met.
Sold me a nifty little
program on the warders.
They saw me as Locke,
and Locke as me.
This "guy", name of Mergrass?
You know him! Great guy.
Anyway, I kept Locke safely
locked up, until you come along!
Free.
At last, Gurney.
Now now, Mr Locke, we had a deal.
No deals. Creatures like Gurney
are beyond redemption.
Their rehabilitation is pointless.
Warder. All the prisoners in
Volag-Noc are beyond rehabilitation.
They must die.
Commencing cell sterilisation.
On your command.
You can't! Stop it!
Stop it now! It's not their fault.
It's the only way to cure them.
Safe!
It's the only way.
Doctor, the prisoners! I'm on it.
Gurney, how do we stop it? I need
that program Mergrass sold you
so the Warders won't take Locke's
orders any more! Not my problem.
I'm getting out of here!
The data chip! Gurney! Stop. Stop!
Order terminated.
Oh, yes! Skill.
Now, where's my sonic screwdriver?
Mind. You'll do yourself a damage.
There's nowhere to run, Gurney!
Got to get away from here.
Gurney?
Gurney? Greener than a
seasick kitten, aren't you?
Take me with you, in your ship!
I can't fly the TARDIS. Is that so?
Then you're no use to me, are...
It can't be.
What?
Revenge!
Finally!
Baltazar!
The final data chip,
at last! Gurney, no!
Caw!
Oh, no, you don't.
Caw? Sorry, Miss Martha.
Caw's been a dirty birdie.
So you were working with him
all the time, weren't you?
You sent us on this hunt
for the data chips, on his orders.
I'm sorry.
It's the gold, see.
He promised me
all the gold I could eat.
Caw!
Gurney, he got me right
in the fusion chamber.
I'm done for now.
There must be something I can do.
There's not.
Doctor! Doctor, we have to help him,
we have to do something please.
Caw runs on gold fusion.
Once his reactor's burned out,
that's it.
Va...
va...
voom.
Caw?
Caw!
Good afternoon, Doctor.
We have some unfinished business!
Get in. Turn around.
Hands in the air!
So, how'd you find us?
It's very tricky to track a TARDIS.
I had insider information.
Have you met Squawk? My brooch!
Aw, no.
This little accessory has helped
me track you every step of the way.
Fly away, birdie.
Squawk! An accessory to murder.
Surely that's you, Doctor?
You needed a little bit of help,
collecting the data chips.
I knew my poor old cellmates,
who told me all about the Infinite,
would never willingly
give you theirs.
First, there was Kaliko.
Then, there was Mergrass.
Now, he dried up very quickly.
And that was Gurney's. Pick it up.
This is why you needed me, isn't it?
You knew only my TARDIS could track
each data chip from planet to planet.
I knew only you'd have something
that could read data chips older
than recorded history itself.
Off you go.
The Hesperus Galaxy.
Next.
And that'll be the Ceres system.
It's a map! Telling us the location
of the Infinite.
Keep going.
I spy...
asteroid seven five seven four...
B? Yeah, B.
Set your controls. We're going.
This isn't a taxi! Set the controls,
or Miss Martha gets skewered.
Look, Baltazar, the Infinite -
it's a myth, a legend.
But even if it does exist, even if
it contains a fraction of the power
everyone claims, it'll consume you.
Destroy you! No, it'll give
me my heart's desire, Doctor.
So set the controls.
That's the course laid in?
Yes. And all you have to do
is push the button?
Well, more or less. Then I
don't need you any more, do I?
Er... No! Doctor!
Martha?
No!
Martha!
MARTHA!
He'll be back.
He's a thousand light years away,
alone in the cold.
We won't be seeing him again
for a while,
not before I get
my heart's desire anyway.
She's huge.
The wreck of the Infinite.
At last.
She was smashed to bits
centuries back.
Flotsam spread out
over half the galaxy.
Found out on Volag-Noc that Kaliko,
Mergrass and Gurney had all come
by bits of the flight recorder.
Aw, and they wouldn't
share them with you?!
Not even with each other.
I guess X marks the spot?
In you go.
You're looking for the hold.
The hold? Won't that be... Aah!
Down, yup.
Diagnosis: no bones broken.
Well, that's something.
Hello?
Hello.
Doctor!
I knew it! I knew you'd be back!
Wait a minute, how?
Girl?
Girly?
Martha?
Watch out below!
What? Ahoy there! Meet Squawk!
All grown up now! Squawk!
We haven't... We haven't quite
got the hang of landing yet!
Doctor?
Out for the count, Squawk!
And I thought I could
rely on you, at least.
Doctor says you're a bad influence,
like y'were on me Dad!
And now I've exactly what you need.
Gold. Lots and lots
of lovely, glittering gold.
Keep you fed for years.
Squawk!
Oi! What do I keep on telling you?
Don't listen to the villains!
That hurt.
Where is she? Where's Martha?
But what about the treasure?
The heart's desire.
Of course.
You're not the Doctor.
My heart's desire indeed.
Now you have it.
No. No! Nooo!
Excuse me, I think that's
my friend you're scaring.
Hiya! Can you make him go away?
That's up to you, I'm afraid.
You conjured him up.
But how am I supposed to...?
Heart's desire.
I don't believe I walked into this.
Gotcha! I said
"I don't believe this!"
Oh, yes!
Oh, don't even try to
find my heart's desire.
Hello, you.
Proper you.
Aren't you gonna ask how I got here?
And about my adventures on Volag-Noc?
I bottle-fed Squawk with molten gold
and reprogrammed Locke to run
a better prison?
It's been three years, you know.
Three years?
Well, two and three-quarters.
Regained a bit by flying
past light speed.
Light speed? How?
I gave Squawk's engine a bit of pep.
Bit of zing. Bit of... Va-va-voom!
Yeah. I knew you'd be back.
So, this is the Infinite.
Every pirate and freebooter
and treasure-hunter dreams
of being the one to find this.
Their heart's desire.
What did it show you, by the way?
Doesn't matter. Didn't work on me.
Anyway, whatever power this place
had is fading away daily.
Whole ship's held together
by wishes and hopes.
There's nothing living here?
Not now. One of the Great Old
Ones was once. It died out here,
alone and lost.
Screaming its rage and fury
into the solitude
until its unique power dissipated.
Just left a little fading echo,
enough to give us a glimpse
of our heart's desires.
LAUGHTER
Oh, no. Gold!
Diamonds! Treasure, Doctor, enough
treasure to buy me a new ship.
A whole fleet,
and I can destroy you, Earth,
Volag-Noc and everything in between.
Be scourge of the Galaxy again?
Is that the best you can think of?
It's not real.
It's just an echo of the power.
He's not listening, Martha.
Ship's so old and rusted, just
held together by wishful thinking.
What?
Come on, Captain Useless.
Sorry, full up. There'll be
another one along in a minute.
No! Doctor, you can't leave me here!
I know he was rotten
to the core, but still...
Oh, I left him a way out.
Whoah!
Squawk!
Course, it'd only matter if
I didn't know exactly where Squawk
was gonna drop him off.
Curse you, Doctor! Curse you!
Searching for your heart's desire,
Martha.
Never been all it's cracked up to be.
Now, then, Martha Jones.
Another job for you. Oh, yes? Yes.
Start giving me some random numbers.
Oh, not again.
Come on, it'll be fun!
When have I ever let you down?
Ha ha ha ha!