WOMAN: Did you see
that spaceship in the hangar?
WOMAN: Yeah, we found
that on the lake bed.
In here!
CLARA: Wait
are they saying something?
"The dark. The sword.
The forsaken. The temple."”
DOCTOR: These words actually rewrite the
synaptic connections in your brain.
They're coordinates.
Someone is deliberately
getting people killed.
-(YELLING)
-They're turning them into transmitters.
(YELLS)
(GASPS)
I can save you.
A new ghost.
CLARA: Oh, no, no, no, no.
So there's this man,
he has a time machine.
Up and down history he goes,
zip, zip, zip, zip, zip.
Getting into scrapes.
Another thing he has
is a passion for the works
of Ludwig van Beethoven.
And one day he thinks, "What's the point
of having a time machine
"if you don't get to meet your heroes?"
So, off he goes to
18th-century Germany.
But he can't find Beethoven anywhere.
No one's heard of him.
Not even his family have any idea
who the time traveller
is talking about.
Beethoven literally doesn't exist.
This didn't happen, by the way.
I've met Beethoven. Nice chap.
Very intense. Loved an arm wrestle.
No, this is called
the Bootstrap Paradox.
Google it.
The time traveller panics.
He can't bear the thought of a world
without the music of Beethoven.
Luckily, he brought all of his Beethoven
sheet music for Ludwig to sign.
So he copies out
all the concertos and the symphonies
and he gets them published.
He becomes Beethoven.
And history continues
with barely a feather ruffled.
(AMPLIFIER DISTORTION)
My question is this.
Who put those notes
and phrases together?
Who really composed Beethoven's Fifth?
(PLAYING BEETHOVEN'S SYMPHONY NO. 5)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: Where's Bennett?
We need to get going.
O'DONNELL: Oh, he's still throwing up.
One small step for man,
one giant... (WRETCHES)
Time travel does that sometimes.
I somehow doubt that
Rose, or Martha or Amy
lost their breakfast on the first trip.
You seem to know an awful lot about me.
I used to be military intelligence.
I was demoted for dangling
a colleague out a window.
In anger?
Is there another way to dangle
someone out the window?
What year are we in?
1980.
(SCOFFS) So, pre-Harold Saxon,
pre-the Minister of War,
pre-the moon exploding,
the big bat coming out...
The Minister of War?
-Yeah?
-No, never mind.
I expect I'll find out soon enough.
Sorry about that.
The prawn sandwich might have been off.
Uh-huh.
Uh, don't worry.
Shall we go?
Uh, just one sec.
I've just got something in my boot.
It's bigger on the inside,
it's bigger on the inside,
it's bigger on the inside!
(LAUGHS) How can it be
bigger on the inside, Bennett?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Okay, let's roll.
BENNETT:
Why have we gone to Russia?
DOCTOR: Uh, we haven't.
We're still in Scotland.
This is the town before it flooded.
The TARDIS has brought us to when
the spaceship first touched down.
But here and now
it's the height of the Cold War.
The military were being trained
for offensives on Soviet soil.
Oh, is that the pilot?
My God, look at the size of it.
DOCTOR: No, that's the body.
O'DONNELL:
What do you mean, "the body"?
This isn't just any spaceship.
It's a hearse.
The suspended animation
chamber is still here,
and the power cells for the engine.
And there are no markings on the wall.
Yet.
Greetings!
It's him. That's the ghost
from the Drum.
(SNIFFING)
Remarkable. (GASPS)
And humans, too.
Albar Prentis, Funeral Director.
You're from Tivoli, aren't you?
(PROUDLY) The most invaded
planet in the galaxy.
Our capital city has a sign saying,
"If you occupied us,
you'd be home by now."
Yes, I've had dealings with your lot
before, I can't say I'm a fan.
Oh, we do tend to antagonize. (LAUGHS)
DOCTOR:
What are you doing here?
Ah, yes. Of course.
This is the Fisher King.
He and his armies invaded Tivoli
and enslaved us for ten glorious years.
(DISGUSTED) Until we were
liberated by the Arcateenians.
But, thank the gods,
soon we'd irritated them so much,
they enslaved us, too. (LAUGHS)
My first proper alien,
and he's an idiot.
And now, in accordance with
Arcateenian custom,
I've come to bury him
on a barren, savage outpost.
You mean the town?
He means the planet.
Although, at the risk of starting
a bidding war, you could enslave me.
In the ship,
I have directions to my planet
and a selection of items
that you can appraise me with.
Listen, we've come from the future,
you're about to send
some sort of a signal.
How do you do it? Is it a special pen?
-What are you talking about?
-The technology you use.
The thing that wrenches the soul
out of the body and makes it repeat
your coordinates for eternity.
Give it to me now,
I'm going to take the batteries out.
We don't have anything
like that. (LAUGHS)
Even this belongs to
the glorious Arcateenians.
So who sends the message?
(SNIFFING)
DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS.
I need to talk to Clara.
You've been here before.
In situations like this before.
Yeah, not exactly like, but...
Yeah, once or twice.
So you've had to deal with
people who are scared.
What do you say to them?
I'm asking what I should say to you.
That it will be all right.
That the Doctor will save us.
And when you say it, do you believe it?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
And now?
Cass thinks the Doctor's saying
something different to the others.
He's saying, "Moran,
Pritchard, apprentice..."
No... "Prentis"?
“"...O'Donnell, Clara,
Doctor, Bennett, Cass.”™
It's just a list of all our names.
And when he finishes, he just goes
back to the beginning again,
over and over, that's it.
Who's Prentis?
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
-It's the Doctor.
-He's alive?
For the moment.
CLARA: Doctor?
Doctor, are you all right?
Yeah, fine. So listen,
the spaceship, it's a hearse.
Clara, what's wrong?
Another ghost has appeared.
What? Who? Has someone died?
Doctor, it's you.
You okay?
Yeah.
Well, currently.
What does it mean?
It means I die.
No, not necessarily, we can change
the sequence of events, so...
This isn't the potential future.
This is the future now.
It's already happened.
The proof is right there
in front of you.
I have to die.
No.
You can change things.
I can't.
Even the tiniest change,
the ramifications could be catastrophic,
could spread carnage
and chaos across the universe,
like ripples on a pond.
Oh, well, I've had a good innings.
This regeneration,
it's a bit of a clerical error, anyway.
Gotta go sometime.
Not with me!
Die with whoever comes after me,
you do not leave me!
Clara, I need to talk to you
just on your own.
Listen to me.
We all have to face death eventually,
be it ours or someone else's.
I'm not ready yet.
I don't want to think
about that, not yet.
I can't change what's already happened.
There are rules.
So break them.
And anyway, you owe me.
You've made yourself essential to me,
you've given me something else to be.
And you can't do that and then die,
it's not fair.
Clara...
No, Doctor, I don't care about your
rules or your bloody survivor's guilt,
if you love me in any way,
you'll come back.
Doctor, are you...
I can't save Moran or Pritchard.
I know. Like you said, if you can,
if you can find out
why this is happening,
then maybe you can stop them
killing anybody else.
You can save us.
And you can stop it happening to you.
I'll do what I can,
but the future has already happened.
We've just met the undertaker
and he's still alive.
(GASPS)
(SNIFFING)
(GROWLING)
(LASER SHOTS FIRING)
(PHONE CLICKS IN RECEIVER)
So, ghost me.
You've got a better view than me.
DOCTOR: How do I look?
Any signs of trauma, any scars?
-Any clues as to how I die?
-No.
Nothing. You're the same
as all the other ghosts,
with the weird black eyes and...
No, no, wait.
Your coat is torn on the right shoulder.
I assume that I'm just saying
the same thing as the others.
No, you're saying a list of names,
our names mainly.
Moran, Pritchard, Prentis,
O'Donnell, Clara, Doctor, Bennett, Cass.
-Who's Prentis?
-DOCTOR: Mole-faced chap.
(WHOOSHING)
-(STATIC)
-What's the matter?
Clara, what's happening?
(INAUDIBLE)
You've moved inside.
You're inside here now.
-What am I doing?
-Uh...
(INAUDIBLE)
Nothing. You're just standing there.
I'm not trying to kill you?
Why am I not trying to kill you?
No, wait. You're moving,
going toward the control panel.
(BEEPING)
Oh, no!
He's opened the Faraday cage.
He's let the other ghosts out.
Clara, I need to talk to me now.
What, didn't you hear me?
You just opened the Faraday cage.
The other ghosts are outside.
Shouldn't we be hiding?
In a minute.
I need to talk to the ghost me.
Okay.
CLARA: Doctor, you're on.
Doctor, such an honour.
I've always been a huge admirer.
This is really a delight.
Finally, someone worth talking to.
So, firstly, why are you here?
Clara, Clara, what's happening?
Um...
Uh...
You've just stopped.
CLARA: Oh, no, wait.
You've started again.
(INAUDIBLE)
His message changed.
He's saying something different.
He's saying...
-What?
What?
He's saying,
"The chamber will open tonight.”
Clara, now the ghosts are out,
go to the Faraday cage.
They won't be able to get you in there.
-Oh, there's a problem.
-CLARA: Problem!
What problem? Oh, really, 'cause
everything else is going so smoothly.
The phone signal won't be able
to get through.
What you'll have to do...
I know, put the phone outside
and you can watch it through
the little round porthole.
And when you see it ringing, if it is
safe to do so, go out and answer it.
Okay, well, how long are you gonna...
Clara, listen to me,
don't let that phone out of your sight.
I need to be able to reach you.
I need to know everything my ghost does.
Do you understand?
I'll come back for you. I swear.
(STATIC)
Come on.
Oh, wait a minute.
-Not you, O'Donnell.
-Well, why not?
Someone need to stay here
and mind the shop.
-(SCOFFS)
-What if Clara calls?
The last bloke that said something like
that to me got dangled out of a window.
Maybe the Doctor's right.
Maybe it's best if you stay here.
Never going to happen.
Seriously, have you two met me?
Prentis.
Prentis!
Guess that dead body
wasn't so dead after all.
And now we've got the writing.
DOCTOR: The Fisher King
did it himself.
The future is still coming.
He's taking the suspended-animation
chamber to the judge.
(ROARING)
What was that?
We need to get back to the TARDIS.
Now!
(ROARING)
Let's cut it off!
O'DONNELL: Let's split up!
Go on, Bennett!
(CRASHING FOOTSTEPS)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING INTENSIFIES)
(ROARING)
(LASER SHOT FIRING)
No, Bennett, wait!
(DISTANT MOANING)
-(GASPS)
-Why did you come?
You shouldn't have come.
I mean, you never listen to anyone.
-It drives me mad.
-To keep an eye on you.
Idiot.
So, don't die.
Who's next on the list?
BENNETT: That list your ghost
was saying,
that's the order in which
people are going to die. Isn't it?
I mean, I've only just figured that out,
but you knew that all along.
Didn't you?
Moran, Pritchard, Prentis, O'Donnell.
I thought, perhaps
because her ghost wasn't there
in the future, like Prentis' was...
I thought maybe...
Maybe it wouldn't happen.
Maybe she stood a chance.
Yeah, but you didn't try very hard
to stop her, though, did you?
It's almost like you
wanted to test your theory.
So, who's next?
-Clara.
-Yeah.
Except now you're gonna
do something about it, aren't you?
Yeah, 'cause it's getting closer to you.
You change history
to save yourself,
but not to save O'Donnell.
You wouldn't save her.
This isn't about saving me.
I'm a dead man walking.
I'm changing history to save Clara.
(GASPS)
O'Donnell's dead.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
Oh, now, don't you dare.
Don't you dare!
.—(TYPING)
-Big day for you.
Time travel, twice.
Whoa, uh, really?
When are we going to?
DOCTOR: Off the map,
out of the rule book.
What if I don't die?
What if I refuse?
I'm gonna go back to the base
and I'm gonna save Clara
because that's what I do.
And I don't see anyone here
who's going to stop me.
(DISTORTED WHOOSHING)
Why're we still here?
No! No, no, no, no.
-What?
-We've moved half an hour backwards.
I'm locked in my own time stream.
The TARDIS won't let me leave.
Well, what do we do?
Now we have to keep out of sight,
until time catches up.
DOCTOR: Where's Bennett?
We need to get going.
O'DONNELL: Probably still throwing up.
Prentis. He's alive.
No, he's just not dead yet
and we don't tell him.
-But he's right there. We can just...
-No.
However that sentence ends,
no, we can't.
Save him and you want to save O'Donnell.
You can't cheat time. I just tried.
You can't just go back
and cut off tragedy at the root.
Because you find yourself talking to
someone you just saw dead on a slab.
Because then you really do see ghosts.
We don't tell him. Understand?
Not a word. We don't have that right.
PRENTIS: Albar Prentis,
Funeral Director.
BENNETT: You're from Tivoli, aren't you?
The most invaded planet in the galaxy.
PRENTIS: Our capital city
has a sign saying,
"If you occupied us,
you'd be home by now."
DOCTOR: Yes, I've had dealings with
your lot before, I can't say I'm a fan.
PRENTIS: Oh, we do tend
to antagonize. (LAUGHS)
(THUD)
-DOCTOR: What are you doing here?
-Ah, yes, of course.
The Doc, the sword,
the forsaken, the temple.
When we found out
what the ghost was saying,
we weren't surprised,
because the words,
they were already inside us.
But you...
You were, weren't you?
You didn't know what
the words were going to be.
Uh, no, I didn't. How did you know?
Who was the one person who didn't
see the writing in the space ship?
Me. Cass wouldn't let me go inside.
That's why the ghosts didn't
hurt you when they had the chance,
because the message isn't inside you.
Yes, I suppose that makes sense.
So you can get the phone back?
What?
She's saying I should
go get the phone back.
-No.
-Listen. Listen, I need...
We... We need to be able
to contact the Doctor
and you are the only one
who can do this.
Okay.
No. She's right.
Neither of you can get it back.
What? What is it?
-What does she say?
-LUNN: It doesn't matter.
Please.
She said to ask you whether
travelling with the Doctor changed you
and why you always have to put
other people's lives at risk.
He taught me to do what has to be done.
(STRUGGLING) We should get going.
I need more time.
It's too soon. I haven't saved her yet.
Tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock,
tick-tock, tick-tock.
I've got no choice now.
I have to face the Fisher King.
You, back to the TARDIS.
Look, he'll be fine.
I promise.
Okay. Didn't need anyone
to translate that.
(DOOR CLICKS SHUT)
Now I'm ready.
I've come from the future.
(LOW GROWLING)
I've seen the chaos you caused,
the bloodshed.
FISHER KING:
Tell me what you have seen.
-Ghosts.
-Ghosts?
Souls wrenched from the dead,
repeating directions to here,
to this spot, over and over.
FISHER KING: How many ghosts
do I create? How many?
Four that I know of.
Maybe five, by now.
Probably more since I left.
FISHER KING: My ghosts
will make more ghosts.
FISHER KING:
Enough to bring an armada,
enough to wake me from my sleep.
(WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(RHYTHMIC BANGING)
What will happen
when your people arrive?
FISHER KING: We will drain the
oceans and put the humans in chains.
DOCTOR: This world is protected, by me.
FISHER KING: Yes,
one man, lost in time.
COMPUTER VOICE:
Door emergency security lock.
(RHYTHMIC BANGING)
FISHER KING: The seed
of their destruction is already sown.
They will die. The message will be sent.
My people will come
and you will do nothing to stop it,
Time Lord.
Hey! No, no, no, no!
Cass, wait!
What are you doing?
Look... Lunn, he is going to be fine.
I promise.
We have to stay here.
I know that look. I do that look.
Okay, fine.
But we stick together.
Time Lords,
cowardly, vain curators,
who suddenly remembered they had teeth,
and became the most
war-like race in the galaxy.
But, you...
You!
You are curious.
You have seen the words, too.
I can hear them tick inside you.
But you are still locked
in your history,
still slavishly protecting time.
Willing to die,
rather than change a word of the future.
(WHISPERING) Lunn?
Lunn?
Oh, Cass.
Cass?
Ugh. Idiot. I'm an idiot.
(METAL SCRAPING)
(SCRAPING CONTINUES)
You will be a strong beacon.
How many ghosts can I make of you?
You really have got
a lot in common with the Tivolians.
You'll both do anything to survive.
DOCTOR: They'll surrender to anyone.
You will hijack other peoples' souls
and turn them into
electromagnetic projections.
That will to endure,
that refusal
to ever cease,
it's extraordinary.
And it makes a fellow think,
because you know what,
if all I had to do to survive is tweak
The future a bit, what's stopping me?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, the ripple effect.
Maybe it will mean
that the universe will be ruled by cats
or something in the future.
But the way I see it,
even a ghastly future
is better than no future at all.
You robbed those people of their deaths.
Made them nothing more
than a message in a bottle.
You violated something
more important than time.
DOCTOR: You bent
the rules of life and death.
So I'm putting things straight.
Here. Now.
This is where your story ends.
(GROWLING)
(WHIRRING)
(METAL SCRAPING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(LOW VIBRATING)
(CASS GASPS)
Oh! There you are.
There is nothing you can do.
DOCTOR: I've already done it.
The words have gone. I got rid of them.
The future I saw,
none of that will happen now.
The message will never
contaminate my friends.
No one will die.
No one is coming to save you.
That's the thing about knowing
you're going to die,
you've got nothing left to lose.
(YELLING)
(BANGING RECEDES)
No, no, no.
You've got to get out of here.
The ghost locked me in. It's a trap.
Come on! Faraday cage, now!
(GROWLING)
The Time Lord.
Night.
(BEEPING)
(QUICK BEEPING)
(EXPLOSION)
This is Security Protocol 712.
The echelon circuit has been activated.
Please stow any hand-luggage
and prepare for departure.
(ALL PANTING)
Back. Get back.
(BEEPING)
(RUMBLING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(WHIRRING)
Don't kiss me. Morning breath.
(GASPS) Doctor?
Follow me.
(WHIRRING)
-(ROARING)
-What's that noise?
DOCTOR: It's the call of the
Fisher King. The call of their master.
(ROARING)
Where they going?
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(ELECTRICITY PULSING)
So what was it?
-Your ghost?
-A hologram,
like the one we made of you, to lure
the ghosts into the Faraday cage.
With a soupcon
of artificial intelligence
and a few pre-recorded
phrases from there. Eh!
All beamed from the sonic glasses.
As soon as you brought me
and the chamber on board
it connected with the base's Wi-Fi.
Bob's your uncle for the Ghost Doctor.
CLARA: Why do they only
come out at night?
Because they're electromagnetic
projections that were out of phase
with the base's day-mode.
Right!
That's it. I've erased
the memory of the writing.
Though, you might find you've lost
a couple of other memories, too.
You know, like,
people you went to school with,
or previous addresses,
or how to drink liquids.
Uh, that's you two done.
Where's Bennett?
What will happen to them?
UNIT will cut out the Faraday cage
with them inside and take it away.
Then the space hearse will be destroyed
so the writing doesn't
infect anyone else.
What do I do now?
I don't understand.
I do.
You keep going. You have to.
Take it from me,
there is a whole world out there.
A galaxy. A life.
What would O'Donnell have wanted?
I need to erase that message
from your mind, but it's fine.
I'll do it later.
Lunn, will you translate
something to Cass for me?
Of course.
Tell her that you're in love with her
and that you always have been.
What?
Tell her there's no point
in wasting time,
'cause things happen
and then it's too late.
Tell her I wish someone
had given me that advice.
Oh, God, no.
I was just passing on what he said.
Please, don't...
What will UNIT do with the ghosts?
Drag the cage into space,
away from the Earth's magnetic field.
With nothing to sustain them,
the ghosts will eventually fade away.
Here's what I don't understand.
You did change the future.
You stopped the Fisher King
from returning.
The Fisher King had been dead
for 150 years before we even got here,
but once I went back,
I became part of events.
But here's the thing,
the messages my ghost gave,
they weren't for you.
They were for me.
That list.
Everyone after you was random,
but you being the next name,
that's what made me confront
the Fisher King.
And saying the chamber will open?
That was me telling me to get inside
and when to set it for.
Smart.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Except that's not why I said them.
CLARA: How do you mean?
I programmed my ghost to say them
because that's what my ghost had said.
And the only reason that I created
my ghost hologram in the first place,
was because I saw it here.
I was reverse engineering the narrative.
Okay. That's still pretty smart.
You do not understand.
When did I first
have those ideas, Clara?
Well, it must have been...
-Wow!
-Exactly!
Who composed Beethoven's Fifth?
-(EXPLOSION)
-CLARA: Doctor, help me!
DOCTOR: Yes, you're
the very next thing on the list.
VIKING: We are Vikings!
(SHOUTING)
You fight or you die.
They are called the Mire.
-You will beg for mercy.
-Ha, ha, ha!
CLARA: The deadliest
warrior race in the galaxy?
One of them, yes. Why?
CLARA: I think this village
Just declared war on them.
DOCTOR: There's gonna be a war.
I hear some news.
We are gonna win the hell out of it.
-GIRL: Why are you here?
-I'm the Doctor,
-and I save people.
-(SCREAMING)