(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
AVERY: April the 1st, 1699.
The good ship Fancy.
Captain's journal.
Eight days we've been
stranded in these waters
and still there is no wind
to fill our sails.
The ship is helpless,
marooned in a silent ocean.
We cannot run and we cannot fight.
All we can do is await our fate.
An enemy lurks out there
in the darkness.
She comes for us
when the ocean is still.
One by one, the crew have been taken.
The men are exhausted with fear.
We cannot last much longer.
I feel an evil presence
lurking in the shadows somewhere,
forever watching me.
I pray for a fair wind that will
carry us away from this accursed place,
but I fear that we are all doomed
to die here.