Ensure all missile systems are aimed
inwards, at the planet's surface.
Earth's shield is now breachable.
The forces of Sontar have
revenge to exact.
This chamber is the heart
of my excavation project.
I've got a plan to get you out of here.
You are recalled. To Division.
I'm Tecteun. The woman you
used to call mother.
You're generating the final
waves of the Flux from here.
Now I release you.
No, no, no!
Don't touch her!
Now, you.
Ood! With me!
She thinks running will help.
We are defenceless!
We're never defenceless.
Ood! Quick. what would happen
if I rip off this conversion plate?
You will be pulled back
into the universe.
I have to get back to Earth.
Can you locate my TARDIS?
Doctor!
Parting so soon?
Neighbourhood went downhill.
And leaving this behind?
I thought we got rid of this lot.
- There's more.
- Follow me.
Did he not say some of these doors
had changed?
Now, which one?
No time like the present!
This is the one. Come on!
- They have all changed!
- Reverse!
What happened to the potato heads?
I'm getting very dizzy now.
It must be a shift in time
rather than space.
I think you might be
getting the hang of this.
- Do not dally!
- Who's dallying?
We must take shelter!
Oh! Please be correct.
Please be true.
I have located your TARDIS, Doctor.
Hurry it along, Ood.
All your erased memories.
All those hidden lies.
Don't you want to explore them with us?
You're not going to leave us, Doctor.
Systems functional.
Exit available.
Watch me.
What in the name of Rayfax
are you doing here?
I really don't know!
Lupari ship, dead Sontarans.
I dunno who you are,
but you're pretty unstable.
Oi, I'm the most
stable person I know.
How are we back here?
Get your hands in the air.
Madam, who are you?
And what are you doing in my tunnels?
Readings for artron energy,
at least two of you have had
proximity to a TARDIS.
Huh. That TARDIS, maybe.
How did that get here?
I presume some of you were with it
and the Doctor in 1967?
Was it true about the Weeping Angels?
How do you know the Doctor?
I'm the leader of human resistance
against Sontaran occupation.
The name's Stewart. Kate Stewart.
I'm here. Where's here?
But also I was...
Yaz! Dan! Kate Stewart!
Kate Stewart! Jericho?
Victorian-looking bloke.
My TARDIS! And a lot of doors. Wait!
Oh!
But, seriously, how am I here?
I'm on Karvanista's ship.
And also...
Doctor!
Still here.
How am I still here?
You are not. And yet you are.
There is danger.
This is not usual.
You're telling me that's not usual.
Seems you are unable
to tear yourself away.
That does not belong to you.
You think we're going to stop?
After all the time you've made me wait.
This is better than
we could ever have hoped.
We have everything we need.
Division.
The power to destroy your universe.
And you.
Peoples of the universe,
the warriors of Sontar offer you hope.
To our long-time foes on battlefield,
we make this offer.
In the face of an event
which may extinguish us all,
we offer the three-fingered hand
of uneasy alliance.
We must join together
to survive this threat against us.
Except Rutans.
Rutans, you remain
hideous scum and must be obliterated.
To our Dalek and Cyber foes,
we now offer the possibility of
an understanding. Negotiation.
To all others, we pledge death.
Under the boots of Sontar!
None of this is possible.
Three places, same time,
three me's, three Doctors, same Doctor,
maybe conversion plate removal
the same moment as contact as Swarm,
outside normal laws of physics.
That's the next move of Sontarans
heading towards us.
Come on Doctor, just concentrate
on the here and now.
Oi! What're you doing?
Disengaging from the fleet.
You're a sitting dog here.
- No, no, no, no!
- Too late, sorry!
Commander Stenck.
Scientific officer Senstarg
reporting, sir,
if you will permit me to speak.
The Dark Energy Camera facility
developed here by the humans
is surprisingly adequate
for our purposes.
Establishing our command here
has proven a wise strategic move,
for which you are to be congratulated.
It was my idea.
Your obsequious congratulations
are noted, Senstarg.
Commander, a Lupari craft has detached
from the inside of the planetary shield.
Where's the biggest concentration
of Sontaran craft on Earth?
- Here! Got it!
- What?
And let's remove that pesky
defensive cloaking.
It appears to be on a trajectory
to crash into us.
You just amped everything past
maximum!
She's insane!
Attention rogue
Lupari ship! This is Sontaran Command.
We have you held in a force field.
Your attempt to crash into us
has failed.
We will bring your ship down
to planetary surface,
where you will be imprisoned,
interrogated and gleefully executed.
You knew they'd do that.
People rarely want to be crashed into.
They tend to take precautions.
Plus, we might get a peek
at their operations.
Win-win.
So, Karvanista,
the two of us are perfect
Sontaran bait.
We get captured
to buy you time for a solo mission.
Has anyone else noticed...
Lots of doors?
You have no escape. It's perfect.
All your lost memories.
- Give me that fob watch.
- Shall I open it?
Shall we see?
I think I shall.
Is this what
you expected, Doctor?
Illogical house. A construction
that makes no sense.
All the memories you've lost,
all the people you've been.
It's all in there.
Contained within that house.
What are you waiting for, Doctor?
Go inside. Take a look.
Meet the selves you've lost.
- No.
- Are you worried what you may discover?
Or how it will break your mind?
I have your past lives,
and your memories.
I can rend them all to dust.
But don't worry, I'll take it slow.
She feels all of it.
I can make her feel so much more.
I could do this forever.
Has anyone else noticed,
lots of doors?
Oi, what's all this?
Those are my notes,
maps and labels relating to these doors.
Madam, they are to be
approached with caution.
I approach everything with
caution. Or abandon. One of the two.
- You okay?
- I am now.
How long's it been for you two?
A few years.
We went all over the world.
She was amazing. She is amazing.
Don't go all soppy on me now, Scouse.
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Thanks for the hologram.
- Who's he?
- Joseph Williamson?
He built all this.
19th century.
Mad Mole? Of Edge Hill?
Always wanted to meet you!
You're on my list.
It's a big list, more of a book,
more of a series of books,
well, a small library. Anyway,
enough of this small talk,
tell me everything, short version.
Likes to chat, doesn't he?
I can't get a word in.
Well, madam. I was inspecting the start
of building work on my land one evening
when I found myself in a
city of the future.
Next day, another part of my land
led me to a different alien vista.
Multiple rips in the fabric of space
and time, in one corner of Liverpool.
I became obsessed,
as you might imagine.
I was able to journey to
far off places,
experience tremendous, terrifying
vista and creatures.
I kept records.
I marked where one world became another.
Structured these tunnels
around those records.
And then, on one journey, I saw...
the end of everything.
The final Flux event.
I believed we would be vulnerable
on the surface.
So I endeavoured to build a city
under the earth,
to protect as many as of us as possible.
I was mocked,
and I fear my efforts
have been for naught.
No, no, no, no, Joseph Williamson,
not at all.
Quite the opposite.
Come here, well done,
Paul Hollywood handshake.
Thank you for everything
you've done, Mad Mole.
So, Kate Stewart, leader of human
resistance. Bring me up to speed.
Sontaran Command is at the Cerro
Tololo Observatory, in Chile,
site of the Dark Energy Camera.
Accessing information
they can't get elsewhere.
Apparently they have a psychic
command centre, and
they're using humans to fuel its work.
I thought if I could get some undercover
operatives into Sontaran Command,
they could tell us
what the Sontarans were doing.
Do you think we might recruit
another participant?
- Someone we left behind?
- We're having the same thought.
How would you get anyone in?
We've discovered a Sontaran weakness,
thanks to a set of raids
on corner shops.
Why are they
raiding corner sh... Oh!
Metabolic processing, lesser gravity,
restorative gas composition,
that would provoke a predilection!
You have any idea
what's she talking about?
Not a clue.
Normal service resumed.
Lots to do.
Let's go. Infiltrate the Sontarans,
stop the Flux,
keep everyone alive,
escape Swarm,
and put myself back together.
Ah! Sorry, forgot to mention, I'm being
trisected across disparate dimensions.
I'm split across three realities now.
It's quite draining, and confusing.
And breaks every known law
of every known everything.
How much danger are you in?
I don't know. It's never happened
to me before.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Well, a bit scared.
Keep going. We start with operation
Sontaran corner shop.
Humans, in these last moments
of your planet's existence,
let our conquest be a reminder that
defiance of Sontar shall always fail.
This pitiful rock
is but a temporary outpost
for the Final Sontaran Offensive.
The imminent cataclysm shall engulf
your planet. Sontaaar Ha!
Move on, soldiers.
I will deal with the site analysis.
Yes, sir!
Company, march!
Sontar Ha! Sontar Ha! Sontar Ha!
Oh dear, Commander Shallo,
drunk on chocolate?
How would that go down
with your superiors?
Who are you?
I've always wanted a little shop.
Right on the corner,
lots of footfall, well stocked.
I'd have a shop exactly like this.
Well, not exactly.
I'd make some changes.
Anyway, have more sweets.
- You're gonna make him sick.
- Sontarans are never sick!
Sontarans shall be both vanquishers
and saviours of the universe.
Your delicious and appealing mouth
snacks wrapped in paper
will never weaken us, or our resolve.
We are invulnerable.
Maybe three more.
Try some of this.
That is delicious.
More scum! Three scum!
We understand you're in need of
psychic operatives.
They break so easily.
Feeble human minds.
We know a couple who are keen
to help the Sontaran cause,
in exchange for unlimited access
to human chocolate.
Maybe even the recipe.
You could make it yourself!
If you transport them to
Sontaran Psychic Command.
What do you say?
Chocolate!
Hello, Miss Brown.
Oh, I say.
You're safe! All of you.
How did you...
You said you were in 1901!
We were split.
And the Angels took you. I didn't
think I'd ever see you again.
I'm glad you're okay.
The good news is,
we can get you back to 2021.
I feel like there might be bad news.
The planet's under alien occupation.
- Angels?
- No, a race called Sontarans.
We need your percipient abilities
in order for you and I
to go undercover on an alien spacecraft.
Does this sort of thing
happen a lot to you?
You'd be surprised.
This is a big ask.
You don't have to come.
Oh, now I'm shut in with the dog.
This plan of yours
had better work.
'Cause you've been nothing but trouble
for me. Ever since we met.
- What?
- I glimpsed a memory of you.
We were together, in the Temple
of Atropos. Division mission.
That's my guess. Am I right?
When I said I couldn't talk to you
about it, I really meant it.
We're locked in.
Pass the time!
How close were we?
Were you my... companion?
I can't talk because it will kill me.
I have a synaptic collider
implanted in my brain.
If I talk about it, the collider will
inject poison directly into my brain.
I'll be dead in three seconds.
Division put that in your head?
There was a time I'd do
anything for you.
But you left me.
I don't have those memories.
I put the whole universe between us.
And you come crashing back in,
as if nothing had ever happened.
Come back to us, Doctor.
You don't get to die yet.
We'll decide when.
What's he doing?
- What do you want?
- You know what we want.
The end of all spatial objects.
And now, here, we have the means.
Control over Division means
control over the final Flux event.
It's so interesting, Doctor.
I look in your mind
and I see what you're most afraid of.
Your biggest fear isn't yourself.
It's the destruction of other things.
It's an obsession.
You want to keep things alive.
You want creatures to breathe and live.
You want species and races to build.
I look into your mind and your hearts
and I don't know why
you want it so much.
And I don't know why you're so afraid
of the opposite.
- Do you?
- Life must win.
But why?
Why is it better?
Why is what you fight for
better than what we will bring?
Because otherwise...
- why are we here?
- You shouldn't be.
That's why we exist.
To correct the error.
There's a balance to the universe.
It exists that way for a reason.
That is your faith.
Ours is different. Ours is true.
And now we will ensure
that the Flux takes apart
your entire universe,
ending with Atropos.
The release of time.
And then we will play.
What do you mean, play?
The final Flux destroys.
We stop it,
wind it back,
and watch it again, and again
and again.
A constant destructive loop.
Why?
Because that is what you did to us.
You and Division left us suffering.
This is how we will repay you.
Suspended,
feeling every death,
every dying particle, on a loop.
And as this happens,
we will summon our Saviour.
Time as witness.
What?
It will be beautiful.
She's right.
See...
You want the universe, Doctor?
The legendary Doctor.
Bit tall for a Sontaran.
And you don't have
the air of a rescue party.
It's time for your interrogation.
Doctor!
Finally, where you belong.
As our prisoner.
And the last of the Lupari.
How you must mourn them.
What do you mean?
My soldiers performed admirably.
Every Lupar on those ships,
airlocked out into space.
Their bodies now scatter the spacelanes.
Every single one, dead.
That is the cost of resistance
to Sontaran might.
Karvanista, I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna kill every last Sontaran...
I look forward to the combat.
Do we have to go with dragging?
I can walk, you know.
No way.
I need to take a break.
I thought you said you were a pilot.
I've been sitting down a lot recently.
And we've been running for...
Well, no idea how long.
Or how far.
Distance and time
seems to all work differently in here.
Look, we can keep searching,
but these landscapes are endless,
I mean, literally, endless.
And I'm pretty sure
your partner's not in here.
There were others,
but now they're gone. It's just me.
You okay?
I had it worked out.
Get in here,
find Bel,
use this communicator to summon rescue.
But I was wrong. About it all.
Bel's not here
and the communicator won't work.
Why have they kept you,
if everyone else has gone?
To them, I'm insignificant.
But I'm not insignificant.
Obviously.
So, how do we get out of here?
Jump in the river.
That was the edge.
When you get to the edge
of one landscape,
you're transported to another.
This thing, this prison,
generates endless multiple landscapes.
But they still have edges.
Guarded by that security system.
And I've been piecing
the connections together.
Nice blaster action.
Where'd you train?
Laser Quest, Fazakerley.
Come on. I need to show you something.
I found this
after I'd been here for a while.
How long did it take to dig this?
Way too long.
It's a bio-form.
It's a combination
of organic and machine.
But these are the internal tech-systems.
I figured systems have a purpose.
And if they're buried,
it's to prevent interference.
So I interfered.
Why're you looking at me like that?
We get trained on what to do
if we're held hostage
in various environments.
The last environment we do
is Passenger forms.
You should teach at the Academy.
These systems, they seem to control
those steps where you came in.
If you disrupt the systems,
the steps become active.
We can make it from here, if we run.
But it self-repairs,
so they're only there a limited time.
I'm all about disrupting the systems.
Gotta be quick!
We're out, nice work!
Now what?
Faster, human scum.
The work must continue.
Commander Shallo promised us
high-calibre recruits.
Let us hope you prove stronger
than the previous feeble specimens.
What is it you want us to do?
Our quantum readers predict
multiple pathways of the timewaves.
We require you to psychically evaluate
all possibilities,
in order to accurately identify
the exact space-time coordinates
of the predicted final Flux event.
You want to know when
and where it will happen.
Correct, human scum.
The ultimate cataclysm which will propel
Sontar to universal domination.
The system will register every response.
The true co-ordinates
will no doubt be an excruciating
and possibly overwhelming psychic load.
Your service to Sontar
will end in success or death.
And the reward for success?
Death.
Activate psychic load.
Where is Kate Stewart?
Your own torture chamber,
on a Sontaran ship,
at the heart of Sontaran Command.
They must rate you very highly.
For now.
I'm protecting their interests.
I've seen a lot of species
make alliances with Sontarans.
It never ends well.
Speaking of species, what are you?
'Cause it is boiling in here.
Any human would be sweating,
or any Sontaran.
And I'm noting dual pulses
in your wrist and neck.
I'm thinking binary demi species,
but they're really rare.
Oh!
Am I right?
'Cause you look really cross.
What's your name?
We haven't been introduced. Do you know,
what this ship really needs is lanyards.
You can call me
Grand Serpent.
Is that what your parents called you?
"Oh, look darling, so cute."
It was a title bestowed on me.
Yeah. I'll bet you'll be making
lanyards with that on for years.
Let me guess,
exiled,
or fleeing,
ex-leader,
or dictator...
You've got that air of entitlement.
...probably responsible for any number
of genocides. How am I doing?
I will be the one
interrogating you, Doctor.
And I was a beloved ruler.
Whoa! Ego klaxon!
So what's the plan here,
let the Sontarans do the dirty work,
then betray them or eradicate them,
then rule over
a semi-grateful human race.
How am I doing at guessing?
Feels weird.
Feeling weird a lot today
but that feels different.
Are you...
How rude!
Are you trying to kill me right now?
Binary-demi species,
with inter-body bio-projection
kill by suffocating
the target from within,
using their own lesser-dominant,
often more deadly form.
Surrender to death.
I'd rather not,
'cause you've got two problems.
One,
I'm not fully here.
Split across three places.
You can't get a full physical lock on me
because I can't even get one on myself.
And two...
Well, two...
Hi! Please stop torturing me.
Like, immediately.
Hi! Wow, you're cute.
Thanks. So are you.
What have you done to me?
Put you on the very naughty step.
Frozen.
Whoa.
There's two of you.
I know.
Now, we all know
that bio-projection duo-imaging
is subject
to very painful sonic locking...
So subject to it.
Sorry if that hurts.
You're caught in its lockfield now.
Taste of your own medicine, I'm afraid.
That's what I would've done.
That's what you did do.
Come on, you lot. He's going to be
stuck in there for a while.
I've got such a crush on her.
Come on.
Not long before they detect us in here.
You should be getting
the data stream now.
I'm not putting you to work,
we're a team.
Hi. Did you get it?
Are you done? We have to go.
Very quickly.
We have to go. Quick smart.
What? How are you...
I'll tell you while we're running.
Intruders!
Halt and face your inevitable death!
In the doghouse, are you?
Go away.
Now then.
Be nice or you won't get a biscuit.
"Fetch your dog." And I have.
Wow, that Nepal fella was good,
after all.
Is he okay?
Sontarans killed all of his people.
Splinter group 1,
Jericho and Claire, in place.
Hi, both of you, this is the Doctor.
Well, Doctors. We're receiving the
psychic data from your transmat rings.
But the TARDIS
is still deciphering the information.
I'm sorry it's so painful
but we need you
to hold on a little longer.
Sit tight, keep going, stay safe.
Splinter group 2, Bel!
Thank you.
Wait, childtech! Are you having a...
All right, all right,
- we don't need to announce it, do we?
- Okay.
She's a good, wee helper, though.
As well as the code for the hold lock
beam on the Lupari ship,
there's also a log of all outgoing
Sontaran transmissions.
What kind of transmissions?
...we offer the three fingered hand
of uneasy alliance.
We must join together
to survive this threat against us.
Sontarans never do that.
Why would they ever join up
with Daleks and Cybermen?
That's what I'm thinking.
...of an understanding.
The Sontarans proposing a peace summit?
That doesn't ring true.
And how does them summoning
their enemies connect up to the Flux?
Aw, there's too many questions!
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Good idea.
Contact.
Doctor to Doctor to Doctor,
hoping we can bridge the divide.
Contact.
How are you,
- I mean we, doing?
- Not good.
Don't know how I get out of here.
Don't think I've got the strength.
Focus on the Flux,
it's at the heart of everything.
The TARDIS has been analysing
Flux particles since we came across it,
but it can't fully decode its structure
because it was made
outside of the universe.
Is there something
in what the Ood showed us in Division?
Yes.
It's in the details.
The makeup of the Flux,
the primary material...
Anti-matter. Created outside of
our universe and channelled in.
That's what the Flux is.
They're doing something
with the Flux generation system,
changing part of the trajectory...
Contact broken.
We can't hold on
to this split existence much longer.
You.
There is something different about you.
Increasing psychic load.
It's too much for her!
Quiet, human irrelevance!
She has done it.
What is it, Kragar?
I hope you bring good news for once.
The best, Commander.
We have the exact coordinates
for the final Flux event.
The operation can commence.
Excellent, Kragar!
You shall have the highest honours!
Commander Stenck to all ships.
Stenck to all ships.
You are receiving
new operational directives.
All troops return to ships.
Abandon Outpost Earth.
The Flux Offensive is now active.
The final victory for Sontar
is within our grasp.
The Doctor was in here.
You were interrogating her.
She rescued herself!
Another Doctor, the same Doctor,
in her own TARDIS!
I do not have time
for your delusional witterings.
Our strategy has been activated!
I just need to trace all recent readings
of artron energy around the Earth.
Be quick, if you wish
to survive alongside us.
Of course,
Kate Stewart.
Totally different place.
Must be where the Ravagers keep
the Passenger form until they need it.
But we got out.
This is Vinder calling the Doctor.
Urgent help requested.
Doctor, are you receiving?
Vinder...
Vinder! He's alive?
How do you know Vinder?
Vinder, can you hear me?
You're the one he's looking for.
Tigmi, he's alive!
Boosting the signal.
Vinder, this is the Doctor,
receiving you.
Hurry it up, lad!
Lock into our signal.
We've managed to...
Vinder! Locking on.
Think it was enough?
Can you do it? Can you get him?
Doing it now, few things going on.
Lucky there's two of us. Well, three.
But two in here. Sorry, you talk.
Got to stop the Sontarans,
defeat the Flux,
rescue him, and get Jericho and Claire.
Doctor, Doctor, it's Kate.
The doors down here
are behaving very strangely.
Of course, why wouldn't they be?
Not like we don't have enough to do.
Divide...
...and conquer.
Yaz with me to Kate in the tunnels.
Other me, rescue Vinder.
Return to Command.
Our time grows closer.
I'm not
finished here yet.
Your vendettas are irrelevant.
This planet will soon be
a Flux-ravaged wasteland.
Where is Kate Stewart?
I've never heard of her.
Williamson's Tunnels.
You really
should have said that sooner.
Retro-temporal manifestations.
Yeah.
Can you not say things
like we're supposed to know
what they are?
They're a result of the Flux
in the future, manifested in the past.
Thank you.
When the Flux comes,
it could blow the doors in.
And destroy all my work?
We need to get you home.
We need to get you back
to the 19th century.
It's not safe
and you're too important to history.
Ah! This one should provide
a safe passage home.
Please. This is our battle now,
not yours.
You gave us sanctuary,
you got Yaz and Dan back to me.
You may just have helped save
the universe, never mind the world.
Your work is done.
Madams.
Madam.
Doctor, your existence
is becoming too unstable.
I fear it will destroy you. Refreshment?
Thank you.
I need to stop them.
The final Flux event has begun.
It cannot be prevented now.
Think, Doctor, think.
So what,
you're linked to them,
in service of the Ravagers?
But the Ravagers
don't care about you right now.
They're distracted, by me,
in Division.
Here you are, waiting for a command
that's not gonna come.
Okay,
short fast hop.
Get in! Quick,
TARDIS doesn't like it in here.
Can't stay too long.
Oh.
We've got you back.
You were late.
I wasn't.
I promise. It was his fault.
Don't blame me. I wish
I'd never had anything to do with him.
Hi.
- Missed you.
- Missed you more.
Also...
We're having a baby.
If the universe survives.
Better make sure it does, then.
Yeah.
Claire and Jericho
are in Sontaran psychic command.
It seems the Sontarans
are using human operatives
to find the exact moment and place
the final Flux event will begin.
But, simultaneously, they're organising
a truce meeting
with Daleks and Cybermen.
What?
Here's what I think they're doing,
luring their enemies to the place
they know the final Flux event
will explode.
If they manage to wipe out the entire
assembled armies of Cybermen and Daleks,
having lured them there
to negotiate a truce,
I mean, that would reverberate
across civilisations.
Sontarans as the ultimate vanquishers.
That is a massive power grab.
The biggest swing they've ever made.
But everything
still gets destroyed by the Flux.
That's where it's doubly sneaky
and doubly clever.
How do you combat anti-matter?
With matter.
Anti-matter devours matter.
But matter slows anti-matter down.
Put enough in its way,
and it stops and ceases to exist.
Exactly. The Sontarans are planning
to use their enemies' entire armies
in order to absorb the Flux.
But they have to show up
to lure the others in.
And they have something
no one else has.
Lupari shields.
Matter-generating,
Flux-repellent shields,
to surround the Sontaran fleet.
Saving themselves
while all around them die.
You gotta hand it to them.
Talk about not letting
a good catastrophe go to waste.
They're on course
for the ultimate victory.
Save the universe, claim it as your own
by taking out all
of your enemies at once.
So, do we stop it?
Do we warn the Daleks and the Cybermen?
- Save them to defeat the Sontarans?
- No.
My plan's more risky than that.
I've got tasks for you all.
You've all got jobs.
It's a really good plan.
Quite risky, though.
Can you let me do the explaining?
All right, touchy.
We have to stop the Sontaran plan
with the Grand Serpent.
What did you say?
Did you say Grand Serpent?
Come on.
I don't know how much more
my body can take of this, Ood.
If I could get those Ravagers away,
would you be able to
minimise the final Flux event?
My impact may be minimal, but I'll try.
That's all either of us
can do right now.
Oi! You two.
So, is this where we're going to stay
for the end of the universe?
Atropos will be the final point
of the Flux destruction.
The culmination, where
Time will be unleashed.
You'll be our offering.
The first Time Lord.
A final gift for the Saviour.
Sacrificed to Time on Atropos,
as it falls to the Flux.
Atropos, then.
We know the Sontaran strategy.
You know our counterplan.
We're dropping you three
and other me back into the Lupari fleet.
You know what you have to do?
Timing is going to be everything.
Now, need to get
Jericho and Claire out of danger.
Jericho, Claire,
used the transmat rings now.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Go, Miss. Brown!
Oh, dear.
Sontaran fleet in position.
Lupari shield ships
in wall formation in place.
Prepare for the ultimate betrayal.
Lupari shield craft,
when I give the word,
move the barrier to protect
only Sontaran ships.
Boy, is he in for a surprise.
Welcome,
Dalek and Cyber comrades.
All Dalek battalions are aligned here.
We accept the offer of protection
against the Flux event.
Cyber battalions are amassed.
We accept a truce
for mutually assured survival.
Lupari ships are moving and reforming.
This is a betrayal!
Cyber Fleet trapped
in the pull of the Flux.
What is the meaning of this?
The meaning is victory for Sontar!
Sontar Ha!
I have done all I can, Doctor.
Lupari shield, you are in the wrong
formation. Resume protective placing.
No.
- Where are my soldiers?
- Unconscious.
Don't you think I know
Lupari ships inside out?
Like, how to send
a stun pulse to incapacitate intruders?
And how to remotely control
the fleet formation?
You are not in control.
We are.
And this is for my people.
What is happening?
This is serving commander
Inston-Vee Vinder
of Kasto-Winfer-Foxfell
on a Lupari craft
blasting the hell out of your
comms systems. Whoo!
Blasting Sontaran comms
is the family business!
Right, Tigmi?
All Sontaran ships, evacuate!
I'm afraid my friends just took out
your comms transmitters.
And in seven seconds you'll be in the
gravitational pull of the Flux.
Vinder, Bel, get clear.
- Getting clear, Doctor.
- So clear.
This was your strategy.
Anti-matter slowed
by absorbing army fleets.
You will suffer for this, Doctor!
Doctor to Jericho, I know your
transmat ring's out of service
but get yourself to a transport pod
just out in the corridor.
I'm afraid that my options
for exiting are rather non-existent.
I can't get the TARDIS in
because of the pull of the Flux.
I've lived more in my time with you than
I did during the previous two decades.
Who has had a life like mine?
I have you now, nameless human.
I, sir, am, Professor Eustacius Jericho,
Scourge of Scoundrels.
I wish I'd written that autobiography.
What a good title.
By the wrath of Sontar,
I will now execute you.
I really don't think
you're going to have time.
What an awfully big adventure.
Jericho.
Some of the Flux is going to
make it through the Lupari shield.
- It's not enough!
- We thought about that.
There's a way to deal
with the remnants of it.
- Right. What were you telling me?
- The Passenger form.
Inside, there's endless, endless matter.
Can't you use that to absorb
what's left of the Flux?
Diane, you may just have saved
the rest of the universe.
Told you those things
underestimated me.
We summon and open the Passenger form.
The Flux will be drawn inside it,
mutually-assured extinction.
Yes.
And there it is.
I knew you'd have some use.
Hoover up that Flux for us.
Our Saviour.
I always wondered
what Time would look like.
Oh, way to play to your ego.
Saviour.
We have come to release you.
And yet I'm still encaged in this
pitiful realm of Atropos.
No. Soon the Flux...
- The Flux is extinguished.
- What?
You bring me here
to announce you've failed.
Sure you pressed the right button?
I warned you not to
play games with us, Doctor.
I've been with you the whole time.
Well, most of me has.
So, however much you wanted to
break Time out of prison,
you just have to make do
with visiting hours.
And they didn't even bring you a cake!
We brought you, Doctor.
Take her.
The Timeless Child.
As sacrifice. She is yours.
But how would I reward
your failure, my servants?
Ascension.
Nice look.
Quite fancy that coat.
Oh, I get how that ego appeal
thing works now.
My turn now, is it?
My reckoning.
No.
Oh.
Really?
You can leave here.
But you wont outrun me.
Your time is heading to its end.
No.
It's not.
- You're wrong.
- Nothing is forever.
No regeneration, no life.
Beware of the forces
that mass against you.
And their Master.
What do you mean?
What do you mean, their Master?
I restore you, Doctor.
Reunify you.
But for how long?
You okay?
I'm whole again. Am I?
Yes.
It feels that way.
I had a reckoning with Time.
Wait.
One thing left undone.
I know you're here, Kate.
Time to stop hiding.
Yeah, it's not her
you should be worrying about.
Who are you?
Now, that's the question.
Do you have any idea what
I've been through because of you?
Perhaps you're mistaking me
for someone else.
No.
I've waited a long time for this.
What are you going to do?
Shoot me?
It's better than that.
Open door seven, please, Prentis.
I knew you were skulking down here.
And yet, in your arrogance,
you came alone.
Open door seven.
You want to know who I am?
I'm the man
who understands the pain of exile.
I'm sorry for what
the Sontarans did to the Lupari.
And you think saddling me
with these two will make up for it?
I'm dropping everyone off,
first opportunity I get.
Yeah, we'll see.
Got quite attached to this ship now.
Yeah, we could do a bit of exploring.
Pick up some work, get into trouble.
Get out of trouble.
One family and their dog.
I wish I'd never saved your life.
You're not staying, any of you.
- This is my ship.
- Well, then.
We'll, er, leave you to it.
I should've stayed with the Professor.
You risked your life.
You got the information
that we needed.
Yaz is right.
None of us would be here without you.
Or you, Doctor.
Thank you. As always.
Where would Earth be without you?
Always glad to help.
I like this regeneration.
Hope I meet it again.
I hope so, too.
Look after yourself, Kate Stewart.
Nobody really knows, to this day,
why he built the tunnels.
They're still excavating them now.
You should go and have a look
while you're here.
Dan?
I'll leave yous.
Have a nice evening.
What are you doing?
Wanted to see how you were.
Listen, I've booked a table
at the Rivera tomorrow night.
I thought we could
finally get that drink.
Do you mind if we don't?
I wasn't late.
It wasn't my fault.
Maybe not tomorrow.
I'd better...
Yeah, yeah.
Need a lift anywhere?
Why? Where you going?
No idea.
Want to come?
First left, ninth right,
and then third left.
Bedroom corridor.
Get yourself settled in properly.
Yaz.
I'm sorry.
I didn't let you in.
To what I was doing.
Going after Karvanista.
What I was looking for.
I shouldn't have shut you out.
No, you shouldn't have.
I was looking for...
...information about me.
A life I never knew.
I want to tell you everything.
I'd like that.
Did you say left or right?
Come on, Scouse,
let Yorkshire show you the way.
Do me a favour.
Keep this safe.
Somewhere deep within this TARDIS.
Somewhere I can never find it.
Unless I really ask for it.
Happy Nearly New Year.
- Here we are again.
- Yeah, yeah.
Here we are again.
Exterminate!
Not like this.