(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMEN: Happy birthday!
I said no fuss.
You have to celebrate
your birthday, Nani.
I was the first woman
married in Pakistan.
Now, look at me, in a wheelchair,
and being fed shop-bought cake.
That's a nice cake.
"The first woman married in Pakistan,"
Did you know this?
And I was the first Muslim woman
to work in a textile mill
in South Yorkshire.
Granddad taking you dancing
every Wednesday night.
NANI: Oh!
I so miss that man.
Now, I want to give you these things
before it's too late.
Najia, these are some letters
your father wrote to me
when he was away.
-Don't read the filthy bits.
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
Sonya, this is a present
your grandfather gave me.
I can't remember why, but it's nice.
And, now, Yasmin,
my favourite granddaughter.
What? Mummy, what?
I've told you about that.
I want you to have this.
Thank you. Was it Granddad's?
I can get it fixed, if you like.
It must never be fixed.
Why not?
I don't want to talk about it any more.
Nani, please.
NANI: You won't understand.
I have such stories I could tell you.
And we want to hear them, really.
If you don't tell us, we won't know.
Your life's our heritage.
When you're older, maybe.
DOCTOR: I know what you're asking,
but family history and time travel,
very tricky.
Just for an hour.
-See her from a distance.
-(GRUNTS)
What's the point in having a mate
with a time machine if you can't
nip back and see your gran
when she was younger?
(SCREAMS)
Erm...
Have you got a time or place?
I know she lived in Lahore in the '50s.
-But other than that...
-I mean, I could.
I shouldn't.
Unless... No. Too unpredictable.
-Could what?
-It's a risk.
Oh, like none of our other trips
have ever been risky.
I have apologised for the death-eye
turtle army. Profusely.
I suppose I could loop this into
the TARDIS' telepathic circuits.
This thing's telepathic, too?
Don't call her a thing, Graham.
And, yes, she does have
telepathic navigation, sort of.
Shorthand for a very complicated process
which is way beyond your understanding.
Ta very much.
I only hang around here to be insulted.
Any object amasses all sorts
of fragmentary spatio-temporal particles
through its life.
The TARDIS can read it like date stamps.
What do you two reckon?
Oh, yeah, I love it. Pakistan.
Never been there before.
Another one off the bucket list.
As long as there's no killer turtles.
Yeah, I'm well up for it.
Hmm. One hour. No...
-ALL: Interfering.
-...interfering.
(TARDIS POWERING UP)
Go on. You know you can do it.
Bit of a punt.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: Whoa! Nice!
I thought Lahore was a city.
This ain't a city.
(GASPS)
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
TARDIS readings are all over the shop.
Looks pretty, northern Punjab.
(DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(COW MOOING)
Hey, get off the road!
Really sorry. Bit of a wobble.
What just happened?
Not sure. But I didn't like it at all.
(MOOING)
Sorry, mate, er, we're just getting
our bearings.
We're not from around here.
Yeah, no kidding.
Your Punjabi's not bad
for foreigners, though.
You need to be careful.
These roads aren't safe right now.
We're actually looking for a woman
by the name of Umbreen.
Right, Umbreen.
What for?
-We're family.
-We're friends.
Family friends.
We're on our way to say hello.
Bit of a surprise.
But we agreed...
Er, okay, get in.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
CART DRIVER: Okay?
GRAHAM: Yeah.
GRAHAM: Thank you.
You all right?
I think so. Probably.
I don't know.
Like I intercepted something.
In my brain.
So, what, you're a flower merchant?
Er, pretty much, right now.
-(COW MOOING)
-Why isn't it safe on the roads?
Running transport now, Prem?
Want a ride with us, Sadhu?
I can take one more.
What's wrong with your feet?
You young people,
always such a rush.
Walking served me all my life.
I'll be there, don't you worry.
(CHUCKLES)
We'll be ready.
I'm late. Umbreen's gonna kill me.
You're late!
And who are they?
They're your family, Umbreen.
What?
Oh, my God.
You're Umbreen.
You look amazing.
What are you doing here?
I live here.
On a farm?
But I thought...
It doesn't matter.
I'm so happy to see you.
So, Yaz, you should probably
explain who we are.
Sorry, yeah. Excited.
Uncle Malik.
You know Uncle Malik.
There are loads of Uncle Maliks.
Exactly. Well,
the one from about 15 valleys over,
I'm that Uncle Malik's third cousin's
younger sister, Yaz.
And these are my friends, Ryan,
Graham, and the Doctor.
-Hi.
-Hello.
All the way from England.
You might want to keep that to yourself
right now.
-UMBREEN: Right.
-What?
It's just, we weren't expecting you,
or anyone.
Uncle Malik's not coming to the wedding
as well, is he?
-There's a wedding?
-Which is why we're here.
Bringing wedding best wishes.
Erm, when... When's the big day again?
-Tomorrow.
-YASMIN: Amazing.
I can't wait to meet the groom.
You already have.
Remember me? Car, flowers?
-Marrying Umbreen.
-No.
You can't be.
-You're not my...
-A wedding in the Punjab. Bring it on.
I love a wedding. Don't we, boys?
Oh, yeah, I can go to a wedding
every day if I could. Yeah.
Hey, do you need a singer?
I know all the classics.
-Well, latest hits to you lot.
-Er, don't ever let him sing.
We won't be staying long anyway.
Just wanted to convey our best wishes
and then head off.
MAN: Hi, I thought I saw some people
in the cart.
Sorry about his driving.
My baby brother thinks he can do
everything better than me.
I'm Manish.
Come, all of you. It's being announced!
UMBREEN: Coming, Mum.
Who are they?
What's happening?
MANISH: Everyone's waiting
for the announcement.
But I've got advanced information.
DOCTOR: Okay.
Number one,
the man Umbreen is about to marry
is not my granddad.
-Defo? Totally sure?
-YASMIN: Yes.
For starters, Prem's a Hindu name.
We're Muslim.
And he doesn't look
anything like the photos. It's not him.
And that Umbreen, she's your nan, right?
Yeah, she does look like the photo.
But Prem's wearing the watch
your nani gave you in the future.
So what, she had a secret Hindu
first husband?
Er, Doc, I reckon an hour's
nearly up, mate.
Yeah.
We can't go. I came here for answers.
All I've got is more questions.
I knew this would happen.
MANISH: Can anyone
help me with this?
I'll help. I'm Yaz.
MANISH: Great, thanks, Yaz.
Big moment.
You won't forget this in a hurry.
You're right there.
I shouldn't have come.
I'm too nice.
This is what happens
when you try to be nice.
Who wants to know
what they're listening to in there?
-Yup.
BRITISH NEWSREADER: (ON RADIO)
After much delay
and amid escalating communal violence,
Lord Mountbatten has finally released
the specific details
of the border which will separate
the two countries.
What borders are they talking about?
Pakistan.
Today, India's officially
cut into pieces.
It's the 17th of August.
And still, you want to go ahead?
Nothing changes, Mum.
We knew this was coming.
Sorry, I don't mean to sound stupid,
what year is it, exactly?
Same year you have in England, 1947.
Partition.
We're in the middle
of the partition of India.
MANISH: Three, two, one.
Is it for the celebrations?
Big celebrations. Welcome to the border.
-PREM: Manish.
-Where India ends and our future begins.
PREM: What are you doing?
Yaz, hi. (PANTING)
Quick sidebar, August, 1947, Partition.
The borders have just been announced.
India. Pakistan.
It's not just the land
that gets divided.
Rioting in the cities.
Tens of millions of people
about to be displaced.
More than a million about to die.
Doc, meanwhile, her Nan's about
to get married, but not to her Granddad.
I'm thinking
that hour's well up, now.
You can't know the borders.
It's only just been announced!
The maps were leaked weeks ago.
I got one from my sources.
Your sources must be wrong, because
you've just put my house in Pakistan.
With the other Muslims.
But you get a fresh start.
Manish, you need to slow down.
Pakistan is somewhere for Muslims
if they want to go.
I'm not saying you have to go,
but Pakistan
is being created for Muslims.
Hindus have India, we both feel safe.
Don't reduce it to that, brother.
It's not that simple.
But I get you have a hard decision
if you're married.
The land belongs to everyone,
has done for centuries.
One day doesn't change that.
I love you, brother, but you're wrong.
(GROANS)
(DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Look, demons!
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
I told you this would happen.
I told you these days were cursed!
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BEEPING)
It's gone!
Not far. We'll deal with this. Come on.
-(WHIRRING)
-Find the signal. They didn't go far.
(GASPS)
-(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
-ALIEN: Stay away.
-(SCREAMS)
-(DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(VOICE STOPS)
-Did I get them?
-I don't think so.
They move faster than your bullet.
-What were they?
-PREM: Bhakti!
They killed him.
He was your man on the road.
He's a holy man. A sadhu.
-Everyone knows him as Bhakti.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Umbreen and I asked him
to bless our marriage.
-Why would they kill him?
-DOCTOR: I don't know.
But what I also don't understand is,
you just saw something not of this world
and you took it right in your stride.
Why's that, Prem?
I've seen them before.
Where have you seen them before?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Who are you?
You say you're Umbreen's family,
but clearly you're not.
And you ran at those demons
like you didn't care.
I don't think they're demons.
Why should I trust what you think?
Because we've got experience
with impossible creatures
and because we ask questions like,
"What is this substance on his body?"
And things are getting even weirder.
GRAHAM: You think that's what
they used to kill him?
-(WHIRRING)
-Some sort of fast-dissolving
poisonous dust?
It doesn't read like he was poisoned.
I don't understand.
So, what are we going to tell
the others back there?
They don't have to know.
Hasna already thinks
the marriage is cursed.
Umbreen doesn't need anything else
to worry about, and Manish,
who knows what he thinks these days.
I was away from him for too long.
Fighting in the war.
By the time I got back,
Manish wasn't my baby brother any more.
YASMIN: People grow up.
We all have to find our own way.
Some of us need more guidance
than others.
This fella needs to be laid to rest.
Why don't we go and get the others
to help,
but not let on what happened.
Oh accordion waves.
Which could mean
a dormant octonic engine nearby.
What's she saying?
If I had to guess, I think
we're going demon hunting.
Gold star for Ryan.
Oh, wait. Was I awarding points?
I forgot about the points!
I'm coming with you.
-No.
-PREM: I know this forest.
I can help.
Okay. Yaz!
Be careful what you say back there.
The wrong word in the wrong moment,
you can interfere yourself
out of existence. Do you understand?
You know there are aliens here, right?
In the Punjab during Partition.
And you're worried about me being gobby?
Tread softly.
You're treading on your own history.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-I like this.
Traipsing through the forest, alongside
the British, looking for the enemy.
I've done enough of that.
Although, maybe you're my enemy now,
for the mess you just made
of my country.
Carving it up, slapdash, in six weeks.
Gonna run off home now, are you?
I'll make a note of your thoughts
and pass 'em on to Mountbatten
if I ever bump into him again.
These demon things,
you've seen them before,
or do you reckon they're here
because of the Partition?
I don't know. I need to find out.
Then he's got one up on you
if he's seen them before you.
What's your demon-tracker saying?
It's saying...
Hello.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-What is that?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BEEPING)
It seems like a Transmat
doorway.
(RIFLE CLICKS)
Nice. That was cool.
What. Just. Happened?
We were in the forest, and now we're...
Really not.
Short answer, we got dragged
through a doorway,
-into...
-A demon's lair.
I wouldn't put it quite
like that, but you're getting the gist.
-(WHIRRING)
-Spaceship, though, right?
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BEEPING)
-I can't get a read on anything.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, you're right. It really is.
They can surprise you, demons.
Hey, do you think they're here?
I'm not getting any life signals.
Maybe they're out shopping.
Catching a movie.
Bowling. Some races like bowling.
I'm talking to confront my latent worry.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
I know. I got that now.
Oh, come on!
One of these things must unlock it.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
- (DEVICE WHIRRING)
Hey, that worked. (CHUCKLES)
-What is it?
-Exactly what I wanted.
Craft spec, species, data, bio-ID.
-(GASPS)
-RYAN: What?
What have you seen, Doctor?
This is a Thijarian hive.
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
Thijarians are assassins.
Right, so that's basically
a bad thing, then.
I've heard about them.
Never come across them.
They're one of the ancient species,
evolved themselves into the deadliest
assassins in the known universe.
-(PANTING)
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-He was their target.
-DOCTOR: Why, though?
Why would the Thijarians target
a holy man in the 1940s?
Wait, you said you'd seen them before,
where?
I don't want to talk about that.
It could be important.
I don't want any of this.
I'm supposed to be married tomorrow.
Mate, the Doctor's right.
We can help you,
but you have to trust us.
Where did you see them?
In Singapore.
Our section had found
a boat to escape on.
-(EXPLOSION IN DISTANCE)
-But I'd signed up with Kunal.
I wasn't going to leave
without him at my side.
Kunal!
Kunal?
That's where I saw the demons.
Standing over my older brother's
dead body.
(WHOOSHING)
I lost them in the haze
as the evacuation sounded.
(ALARM BLARING)
(PANTING)
Left his body there.
I couldn't save him.
Why are they here?
How did we bring demons on ourselves?
DOCTOR: I don't know,
but we'll find out.
And we'll protect you. All of you.
What if you can't?
Oh, er, hey, hey. Look at this. Erm...
That was the stuff
that was on the holy man's body.
The stuff that they used to kill him.
Oh, taking a look at that.
(ALARM BLARING)
Over keen, should've thought
about that Uh...
-They're here!
-(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
THIJARIAN: You have desecrated the hive.
-(ALL GROANING)
-The hive is sacred.
Do you have to push your words
into our heads like that?
Because it really hurts.
And, no, we haven't, actually, it's you
who are desecrating this planet.
I know who you are, I know what you do,
and it's not happening here.
Leave these people alone.
They're under my protection now.
You cannot prevent this.
You just watch me.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(GASPING)
Get out of the forest!
What?
Miniaturised Transmat locks. Clever.
Also, confiscated.
See ya!
(BOTH GASP)
-What just happened?
-No idea.
But the Doctor said,
"Get out of the forest." Come on.
(PANTING)
(GASPS) And another one!
Did you know him well?
Bhakti taught me the scriptures.
How did he die?
-We're not exactly sure.
-HASNA: Where's Prem?
And your other friends?
Seeing if they can find out
any more about what happened.
HASNA: Your family, Manish,
cursed.
-Mum!
-This is another terrible omen for you.
Thanks for that.
I'll get the cart, bring his body back.
I'll help you prepare the burial
and pray for your family.
UMBREEN: I don't know what to do
Bhakti had agreed to marry us.
And not many would agree
to a Hindu marrying a Muslim right now.
Then you can't go ahead
with marrying Prem.
UMBREEN: You think I'd give up
that easily?
I've seen a war take our young,
and drought take our old and weak.
Now, men without a clue are imposing a
border like a crack through my country.
Prem is the one certain thing
in my life.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
This must be scrambling your head.
Just a bit.
I thought I knew my nan's story.
She inspired me.
But if this is true,
if this is her life,
then she lied to me.
(SIGHS)
Yeah, but maybe she just didn't
want to tell you everything, you know?
Woman's allowed to have secrets,
even from her granddaughter.
And you've got to remember, Yaz,
that girl in there,
she ain't your nan yet.
It's only later
she'll decide how to tell it.
And I honestly don't know whether
any of us know the real truth
of our own lives.
Because we're too busy living them
from the inside.
So just enjoy, Yaz.
Live this moment
and figure it out later.
-Easier said then done.
-No, no, I get that, but...
Look at us.
The things we're doing with the Doc.
We're in 1947.
-With me nan.
-Yeah.
No one will ever believe us.
-Especially me nan.
-Exactly.
RYAN: (SHOUTING) We've lost the doctor!
Mayday! Red alert!
-Sounds like trouble.
-RYAN: Red alert!
It must be the Doc.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
-We've lost the Doctor!
-She was with us and then gone!
(PANTING)
There she is!
-Get to the barn!
-GRAHAM: What?
Get to the barn, right now!
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-(DEVICE BEEPS)
-What are you...
-Shh.
No, stay out!
-(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
-(ALL GROANING)
THIJARIAN: You disrupt our work.
Good. Now, who are you here for?
We don't answer to you.
THIJARIAN 2: You must leave,
or we will stand over your corpses.
Nothing like getting to the point.
Is it me? Are you here to kill me?
Take me and promise to leave the others.
Prem, no, not going to happen.
DOCTOR: Both of you,
I'm dealing with this.
I've just nicked four of your
Transmat locks out of the forest.
Good trick, by the way.
Forcing people back,
away from the boundary. Clever.
So clever,
I'm using it myself, against you,
locking you out of this farm.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-(DEVICE BEEPS)
You killed the demons.
No, just exiled them for now.
I made a temporary Transmat barrier
around the farm.
I'm hoping it will keep them out
for the next few hours.
Enough time for you to get married
and for us to keep everyone safe.
Are you serious,
after what's just happened?
Can't you see what's happening?
You bring demons to life.
I don't think they're demons.
Well, I do. I'm with Manish.
How many hours?
Twelve. Eighteen at a push.
I can't be sure.
Tonight, we celebrate
and we marry first thing.
And then if we have
to fight them, we will.
Come on.
(BARN DOOR OPENING)
-(BARN DOOR CLOSES)
-Still not interfering, are we?
Oi! The alien assassins started it.
We can't leave now.
If something happens to Umbreen,
your whole timeline could be erased.
No Yaz! We can't have a universe
with no Yaz.
Now, whatever's in here,
might tell us more.
Nobody breathe too deeply.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-(DEVICE BEEPING)
-Whoa!
It's overloaded my sonic!
Too many inputs.
That's never happened before. Oh, think.
Have to go analogue.
I need oil, water, tree bark,
a sauce pan, nine containers,
an old newspaper, a touch of ox spit,
a chicken poo, and a biscuit.
-Bagsy not chicken poo.
-Why a biscuit?
I love biscuits!
I am never, ever getting spit
from an ox ever again,
-no matter how much you need it.
-(LAUGHS)
The ox took a bit of a shine to him.
(LIQUID BUBBLING)
-So, what is it, then?
-Science.
Should break the sample down.
Give us more information.
Only take a couple of hours.
(BARN DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Are you coming or not?
What's that?
Part of my, er, demon-repellent.
-That better be gone by tomorrow.
-Definitely.
So, come on, women with me and Mum,
men over at Prem's house.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BARN DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
This is the best thing ever!
Never did this when I was a man!
(LAUGHS)
Doctor, you and your jokes.
Yeah, that's right.
My references to body and gender
regeneration are all in jest.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
-I'm such a comedian.
-(LAUGHS UNCOMFORTABLY)
Umbreen doesn't think
these are my best work.
But, maybe if you had to prepare
a body this morning,
you wouldn't draw so well either.
So, how long have you known Prem?
Our whole lives.
We grew up here together.
Our families have worked the land
alongside each other for generations.
I can't believe it's happening.
I waited so long for him.
All the time he was away fighting,
I was terrified he wouldn't come home.
But, he did.
And now I see my life mapped out
with him.
Our home, here.
If they let us stay.
Nobody cares what we do here, Mum.
-It's not a city.
-HASNA: I stood outside earlier.
I heard gangs in the distance.
Motor vehicles, gunshots.
It's a long way away.
It's not too late.
I can still find you a good Muslim man.
Are you joking right now?
Look at the misery that follows him.
You don't even have a priest.
What sort of a respectable wedding
will it be?
I don't care about traditions!
I don't care about respectable...
Wait. You're a doctor, right?
That's respectable
You could marry us.
Don't be ridiculous!
-I suppose I could.
-No.
-Doctor!
-I haven't
officiated a wedding since Einstein's.
His parents didn't approve either.
Non-denominational, though.
If your father were alive,
he'd die on the spot.
Everyone is saying it's a new future.
We make our own traditions now.
You're on.
I thought we were not getting involved.
(SOFTLY) Only a teensy bit.
Bust.
Again.
You're cleaning me out, little brother.
You know what they say though, Prem.
Unlucky at cards, lucky in love.
-You think he's lucky?
-Yeah.
-I think he's lost his mind.
-Hey, mate, not on his stag night.
PREM: You'll have to forgive him.
Spends too much time reading pamphlets.
Listening to angry men on the radio.
Do you love me, Prem?
Of course I love you.
Even if sometimes I don't recognise
the brother I left behind.
Kunal would have understood.
He said he was only fighting for you lot
so he could get rid of you.
And now it's happening.
(LAUGHS)
Don't marry tomorrow.
-Umbreen's a good woman.
-You can't live together here.
India's not her home, now.
India's a home to all of us.
We didn't change when a line was drawn.
But we did.
I need air.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
YASMIN: She's going to officiate
knowing he's not my granddad.
Well, if Manish has anything
to do with it,
there won't be anything to officiate.
And these alien assassins,
we still don't know who they come for.
(SIGHS) What happens here?
Why did she never tell her family
about any of this?
This just is the densest
organic material that you can imagine.
It's sort of everything.
Carbon, phosphorous, oxygen, nitrogen,
sulphur, calcium.
Billions of DNA fragments
and loads more.
(TRANSMAT LOCKS BEEPING)
They're breaking the Transmat locks!
Doctor!
(GASPS)
DOCTOR: So, what?
Is it me?
You've come to assassinate me?
-THIJARIAN: We are not assassins.
-DOCTOR: Firstly,
I much prefer it when you're not
making the threatening sound.
So thanks for that, at least.
Secondly, don't lie to me.
I know the stories
of the assassins of Thijar.
-We have changed.
-What?
Changed how?
Our past is no more.
We are no longer assassins.
Now, we are witnesses.
I don't understand.
We honour the lost
as we cannot honour our own.
No. Still not with you.
As the assassins hunted,
the Thijarian world was destroyed.
We returned to find nothing.
This is all that remains of our home.
Our people.
Every ancestor.
All one dust.
I didn't know.
I'm so sorry.
They died unwitnessed, unsaved.
We were too late
to grieve or honour them.
BOTH: But we who returned gave up
100 generations to sift,
to remember the lost dead.
The unmourned.
In time, it was all we knew.
And now we travel beyond, seeking
the unacknowledged dead
across all of time and space.
This is now the Thijarian mission.
To bear witness to those alone.
To see. To bear pain.
Honour life as it passes.
As each one passes,
we commemorate union.
That's what Prem saw you do to Kunal,
what you were doing to the holy man.
But why here? Why now?
Millions will perish,
unseen, unknown,
in the days to come here.
The casualties of Partition.
BOTH: We read the time waves.
But why this family?
Why this land?
(GASPS) Prem.
His time is soon.
How soon?
Give him a day.
Just give him this day, please.
BOTH: We are not gods.
Events sit as they will.
We only witness.
The fixed force of time
cannot be stopped.
I know.
If you didn't kill the holy man,
if you were only honouring his death,
how did he die?
We can show you.
(BOOMING)
(GASPS)
Where've you been?
You've been gone hours.
The Thijarians, they told me everything.
I know what happened.
And I know what happens.
I want to know what happens.
Prem dies today.
-We can't let that happen.
-It has to.
For Umbreen to become your nani,
for you to exist, Prem has to die.
You mean, the Thijarians
have come to kill Prem?
That's not why they're here.
They're not assassins.
They honour those who die alone.
Aliens with compassion.
Umbreen loses her husband
on the day she marries.
Of course
she never wants to talk about it.
I'm sorry, Yaz.
-We should leave.
-YASMIN: No.
I want to be sure she's safe,
whatever happens.
I want to look after my nani.
I'm with Yaz.
Yeah, me, too.
We can't tell them what we know.
(RADIO STATIC)
MAN 1: (ON RADIO) My friends,
I woke this morning
to the sight of smoke over the hills.
More villages burned.
More homes ransacked.
It seems these savage mobs
cannot be satisfied.
(RADIO STATIC)
MAN 2: (ON RADIO)
I urge you to stay safe and stay strong.
Protect yourselves however you must.
Oh.
The flowers don't help much.
You still look
like a schoolboy on manoeuvres.
These are the best clothes I have.
You look great.
No Manish?
He was out early.
He'll be here.
Did you hear the noises in the valley
during the night?
Violence is getting closer.
Who's doing this stuff?
Ordinary people
who've lived here all their lives.
Whipped into a frenzy
to be part of a mob.
And nothing worse than when
normal people lose their minds.
We've lived together for decades.
Hindu, Muslim and Sikh.
And now we're being told our differences
are more important than what unites us.
Like we learned nothing in the war.
I don't know how we'll protect people
when hatred's coming from all sides.
Well,
all we can strive to be
is good men.
And you, Prem,
are a good man.
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHS) I, erm...
I, er...
Come on.
Marriage.
(SIGHS)
This is the spot you choose?
I'm going to be
the first woman married in Pakistan.
-Of course, you are.
-(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
(SOBS GENTLY)
You all right, sweetheart?
I always cry at weddings.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
I know there aren't many certainties
in any of our lives,
but, Umbreen, Prem
what I see in you is
the certainty of having each other.
Something I believe in my faith,
love,
in all its forms,
is the most powerful weapon we have.
Because love is a form of hope,
and like hope, love abides.
In the face of everything,
you both found love with each other.
You believed in it, you fought for it,
and you waited for it.
And, now, you're committing to it.
Which makes you, right now,
the two strongest people on this planet.
Maybe in this universe.
I'm not sure how we formalise this.
(LAUGHS) I am.
Will you?
That's a Hindu thing, isn't it?
Tying the hands together.
Now it can be our thing.
If we want it to be.
UMBREEN: I'm not often lost for words,
but I never thought this day would come.
It's been tough.
People who I wish were here
to celebrate...
They are, Beti.
UMBREEN: The drought
was nearly the end of us.
But we get to have this day
because of Manish.
You were tireless.
When there was hardly any food,
you took none.
When we doubted we'd make it
through to summer,
you kept on.
Night and day,
we worked these fields together.
I am proud to have been your neighbour.
But I'm even prouder, now,
to call you my brother.
You kept us fed, Manish.
Will you let me feed you?
I didn't work this land
for you, Umbreen.
I worked it for my brothers.
One who didn't come back,
and the other I wish hadn't.
-Enough, Manish.
-No
Look at you all.
Don't you understand what's coming?
None of this will make a difference.
I'LL talk to him.
Prem, your turn.
Okay.
-(BARN DOOR CLOSES)
-So...
-And what are you doing?
-You did a Hindu thing with the rope.
Only right I do a Muslim thing, too.
This is your mahr.
Yours to keep forever.
Prem.
I'm sorry.
Cursed.
It's fine.
It's perfect.
This is us, forever.
Our moment in time.
Is that what you used
to shoot the holy man?
-Your brother's rifle?
-(RIFLE CLICKS)
Be quiet.
What happened, Manish?
Did it get out of hand?
Did you scare yourself?
Because you were too young for the war.
You've never fought or killed anyone.
I'm not scared of anything
because this is my time to fight.
Fight for what I believe
Killing a man because he might
marry a Muslim and a Hindu
and then pretend you knew nothing?
Take your friends and leave
if you want to get out alive.
What have you done? Who's coming?
(HORSE WHINNYING)
-(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
-(GASPS)
The future.
(PANTING)
Listen, all of you,
there's armed men heading up the track.
You have to leave now.
They want the land?
I'm not going anywhere. This is my home.
My husband and parents are buried here.
I'm not going to abandon it to thugs.
Where's Manish?
He's leading them here.
He killed the holy man with your rifle.
Of course.
Mum"s right. This is our home. We stay.
If you stay, you'll die.
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
Go to the house.
Get anything essential,
and get back here.
I'll help you.
(BARN DOOR OPENS)
(BARN DOOR CLOSES)
Is that Sheffield
marked on here?
UMBREEN: My dad brought that map
home from the market one day.
One night I said,
"I'll put my finger on this map
and wherever it lands, I'm going to go."”
And you landed on Sheffield?
Such an exotic word. It's in England.
Do you know it?
Stop talking. We have to leave.
They're nearly here.
You need to move out.
-I have to talk to Manish.
-No, Prem.
I'm not leaving you here.
I'll distract them long enough
to be sure you can get away.
Then I'll be right behind you.
It's too dangerous.
He's my brother.
Across the field, over the border,
into the forest. Keep going north.
(SOBBING)
Go.
(BARN DOOR CLOSES)
-You as well.
-I'll come with you.
No.
These are demons I have to face alone.
UMBREEN: Mum! Come on, keep up.
HASNA: I'm running as fast as I can!
Look!
They're checking their land
for people who don't belong.
This is our home.
Everyone's welcome here.
I know what you did to the holy man.
There's nothing holy about a man
who would approve your union.
Better he die than defile himself.
My baby brother,
what happened to you?
Really?
I know you.
We fought together in Siam.
We made a good team. And now this?
I can't let them through, Brother.
We are your people, Prem.
India's your country.
You and Kunal fought for this.
This is not what I fought for.
BOTH: We will watch over him now.
Please, Manish.
Come on.
(GUN FIRES)
She made it out, right?
She got to Lahore?
She lived?
She made it.
This is a terrible design.
Was it a good wedding, at least?
Yeah.
What is the matter, Beti?
You loved Granddad, didn't you?
Of course.
And you're happy
with how your life turned out?
Why would you be asking that?
Just, your journey, so many countries.
So many years.
I can't even begin to imagine
what you've dealt with.
Then you end up in Sheffield,
of all places.
I love Sheffield!
Really?
Well, not quite as exotic
as I thought it would be.
-(CHUCKLES)
-But, it gave us stability,
a life, a home.
And it gave me your mum.
And it gave me you and your sister.
You want to know about the watch?
Really?
No.
Tell me another time.
I love you, Nani.
And I love you too, Beti.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Delivery for the Doctor.
DOCTOR: Something is very wrong here
at Kerblam.
If anything happens to us,
or anyone else here,
you'll have me to answer to.