(GASPING AND SCREAMING)
-What the hell is he doing?
-The controls aren't working.
I don't know where we're going,
but my old hand's very excited about it.
I thought that was just some
freaky alien thing.
-Are you sure that it's yours?
-Well...
-It got cut off. He grew a new one.
-You are completely impossible.
I'm not impossible. Just a bit unlikely.
(SCREAMING)
-Why did the Tardis bring us here?
-Oh, I love this bit.
-I thought you wanted to go home.
-I know, but all the same...
-It's that feeling you get.
-Like you swallowed a hamster.
SOLDIER: Don't move. Stay where you are!
-Drop your weapons!
-We're not armed.
Look, no weapons,
never any weapons. We're safe.
-Look at their hands. They're clean.
-All right, process them. Him first.
Wait! Oi! What's wrong with clean hands?
MARTHA: What's going on?
Leave him alone.
(GRUNTING)
(MACHINE BUZZING)
Something tells me this isn't about
to check my blood pressure.
(SHOUTS)
-What are you doing to him?
-Everyone gets processed.
It's taking a tissue sample.
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
An extrapolator here.
Some kind of accelerator?
(MACHINE WHOOSHES)
-Are you all right?
-DOCTOR: I don't know.
That's...
Arm yourself.
-MARTHA: Where did she come from?
-From me.
-From you?
-How?
-Who is she?
-DOCTOR: Well, she's...
Well...
She's my daughter.
Hello, Dad.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Are you primed to take orders,
ready to fight?
Instant mental download of all
strategic and military protocol, sir.
Generation 5000 soldier, primed
and in peak physical health.
(COCKING GUN) Oh, I'm ready.
-Did you say daughter?
-Mmm. Technically.
Technically how?
Progenation,
reproduction from a single organism.
It means one parent is biological
mother and father.
You take a sample of diploid cells,
split them into haploids,
then recombine them in
a different arrangement and grow,
very quickly, apparently.
(CRASHING) Something's coming.
-SOLDIER: It's the Hath!
-Get down!
(GRUNTING)
We have to blow the tunnel.
Get the detonator!
We're not detonating anything.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
SOLDIER: Grab it!
-SOLDIER: Blow the thing!
-Martha!
No. Don't!
(ALARM BLARING)
You've sealed off the tunnel.
Why did you do that?
-They were trying to kill us.
-But they've got my friend.
Collateral damage.
At least you've still got her.
He lost both his men.
-I'd say you came out ahead.
-Her name is Martha.
And she's not collateral damage,
not for anyone.
Have you got that, GI Jane?
-I'm gonna find her.
-(COCKING GUN) You're going nowhere.
You don't make sense, you two.
No guns, no marks, no fight in you.
I'm taking you to General Cobb.
Now move.
(COUGHING)
(CREATURE GURGLING)
Hold on. I've got you.
Is it your arm, yeah?
(CREATURE MOANING)
Is that a yes?
(MOANS)
Let me examine it. Keep still.
Still, yeah?
No move.
Half fish, half human.
How am I supposed to know?
Is that a shoulder?
Feels like a shoulder.
I think it's dislocated.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm trying to help him.
I am a doctor and he is my patient.
And I'm not leaving him.
(GURGLING)
Now this is gonna hurt.
One, two, three!
(GUNS COCKING)
(CREATURE GRUNTS)
Now then, I'm Dr Martha Jones.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Donna. What's your name?
Don't know. It's not been assigned.
Well, if you don't know that,
what do you know?
-How to fight.
-Nothing else?
The machine must embed military
history and tactics, but no name.
-She's a generated anomaly.
-"Generated anomaly"?
Generated.
Well, what about that? Jenny.
Jenny. Yeah. I like that. Jenny.
-What do you think, Dad?
-Good as anything, I suppose.
You're not what you call
a natural parent, are you?
They stole a tissue sample at gunpoint
and processed it.
It's not what I'd call
natural parenting.
Rubbish. My friend Neris
fathered twins using a turkey baster.
It don't bother her.
Can I extrapolate a relationship
from a biological accident?
Uh, Child Support Agency can.
Look, just 'cause I share
certain physiological traits
with simian primates doesn't make me
a monkey's uncle, does it?
I'm not a monkey...or a child.
-So where are we? What planet's this?
-Messaline. Well, what's left of it.
MAN ON PA: 6-6-3, 75 deceased.
Generation 6-6-7-1 extinct.
Generation 6-6-7-2,
46 deceased.
Generation 6-6-8-0,
14 deceased.
Generation 6...
-This is a theatre.
-Maybe they're doing Miss Saigon.
It's like a town or a city underground.
-But why?
-General Cobb, I presume.
Found in the western tunnels, I'm told,
with no marks.
There was an outbreak of pacifism
in the eastern zone, three generations
back, before we lost contact.
Is that where you came from?
Eastern zone, that's us. Yeah, yeah.
I'm the Doctor. This is Donna.
And I'm Jenny.
Don't think you can infect us
with your peacemaking.
We're committed to the fight
to the very end.
Well, that's all right. I can't stay
anyway. I gotta go and find my friend.
That's not possible.
All movement is regulated.
-We're at war.
-Yes. I noticed. With the Hath.
But tell me,
"cause we got a bit out of circulation,
eastern zone and all that,
so who exactly are the Hath?
(CREATURE GRUNTS)
(ALL GURGLING)
COBB: Back at the dawn of this planet,
these ancient halls
were carved from the earth.
Our ancestors dreamt of a new beginning,
a colony where human and Hath
work and live together.
What happened?
The dream died,
broken along with Hath promises.
They wanted it all for themselves.
But those early pioneers,
they fought back.
They used the machines to produce
soldiers instead of colonists
and began this battle for survival.
There's nothing but earth outside.
Why is that?
-Why build everything underground?
-The surface is too dangerous.
Well, then why build windows
in the first place?
-And what's this mean?
-The rites and symbols of our ancestors.
The meanings lost in time.
-How long has this war gone on for?
-Longer than anyone can remember.
Countless generations
marked only by the dead.
-What, fighting all this time?
-Because we must.
Every child of the machine
is born with this knowledge.
It's our inheritance. It's all we know.
How to fight and how to die.
(MUTTERING AND GURGLING)
Right. So we're here?
(SIGHING)
Does this show the entire city,
including the Hath side?
Yes. Why?
-Well, it'll help us find Martha.
-We've more important things to do.
The progenation machines are powered
down for the night shift,
but, as soon as they're active, we could
breed a whole platoon from you two.
I'm not having sons and daughters
by some great big flipping machine.
Sorry, no offence, but you're not...
Well, I mean, you're not real.
(SCOFFS) You're no better than him.
I have a body, I have a mind,
I have independent thought.
How am I not real?
What makes you better than me?
Well said, soldier.
We need more like you
if ever we're to find the source.
Ooh, the source. What's that then?
What's the source?
-I like a source. What is it?
-The breath of life.
And that would be?
In the beginning, the Great One
breathed life into the universe.
And then she looked at what she'd done
and she sighed.
-"She," I like that.
-Right, so it's a creation myth.
It's not myth, it's real.
That sigh, from the beginning of time,
it was caught and kept as the source.
It was lost when the war started,
but it's here somewhere.
Whoever holds the source
controls the destiny of this planet.
Ah! I thought so.
There's a suppressed layer
of information in this map.
If I can just...
What is it? What does it mean?
See? A whole complex of tunnels
hidden from sight.
Hold on. Look!
That must be the lost temple.
The source will be inside.
You've shown us the way.
And look, we're closer than the Hath.
It's ours.
That's a new map.
There's a different set of tunnels.
Tell them to prepare to move out.
We'll progenate new soldiers
on the morning shift, then we march.
Once we've reached the temple,
peace will be restored at long last.
Call me old-fashioned,
but if you really wanted peace,
-couldn't you just stop fighting?
-Only when we have the source.
It will give us the power
to erase every stinking Hath
off the face of this planet.
Hang on, hang on.
A second ago, it was peace in our time,
-now you're talking about genocide.
-For us, that means the same thing.
Then you need to get yourself
a better dictionary.
When you do, look up genocide.
You'll see a little picture of me there
and the caption will read,
"Over my dead body!"
You're the one who showed us
the path to victory,
but you can consider the irony
from your prison cell.
Cline, at arms.
Oi, oi, oi. All right.
Cool the beans, Rambo.
COBB: Take them.
I won't have them spreading treason.
And if you try anything, Doctor,
I'll see that your woman dies first.
-We're not a couple.
-I'm not his woman.
Come on, this way.
I'm gonna stop you, Cobb.
You need to know that.
I have an army and the breath
of God on my side, Doctor.
-What'll you have?
-This.
-Lock 'em up and guard 'em.
-What about the new soldier?
We can't trust her. She's from
pacifist stock. Take them all.
(LOUD GURGLING)
But I didn't do anything.
(GRUNTS)
I think I just started a war.
More numbers.
They've got to mean something.
Makes as much sense as
the breath of life story.
-You mean that's not true?
-No. It's a myth, isn't it, Doctor?
Yes, but there could still
be something real in that temple.
Something that's become a myth,
a piece of technology, a weapon.
So the source could be a weapon
and we've just given directions
to Captain Nut job?
-Oh, yes.
-Not good, is it?
That's why we need to get out of here,
find Martha and stop Cobb
from slaughtering the Hath.
(STAMMERING) What are you staring at?
You keep insisting you're not a soldier,
but look at you, drawing up strategies
like a proper general.
No, no. I'm trying to stop the fighting.
-Isn't every soldier?
-Well, I suppose, but that's...
That's... Technically.
I haven't got time for this.
Donna, give me your phone.
Time for an upgrade.
-And now you've got a weapon.
-It's not a weapon.
But you're using it to fight back.
I'm gonna learn so much from you.
You are such a soldier.
-Donna, will you tell her?
-Ooh, you are speechless.
I'm loving this. You keep on, Jenny.
(MOBILE RINGING)
-Doctor?
-Martha, you're alive!
Doctor! Oh, am I glad
to hear your voice.
-Are you all right?
-I'm with Donna. We're fine.
-What about you?
-And... And Jenny. She's fine, too.
Yes, all right. And... And...
Jenny. That's the woman
from the machine, the soldier.
My daughter. Except she isn't, she's...
-Anyway, where are you?
-I'm in the Hath camp.
I'm okay, but something's going on.
The Hath are all marching off
to some place that's
appeared on this map thing.
Oh. That was me.
If both armies are heading that way,
there's gonna be a bloodbath.
-What do you want me to do?
-Just stay where you are.
If you're safe there,
don't move, do you hear?
But I can help.
(BUSY SIGNAL BEEPING) Doctor? Doctor?
The doors that have been closed
will be open to us now.
The door to the temple,
to the source and to victory.
COBB: Come the dawn cycle, we march!
ALL: To war with the Hath!
They're getting ready to move out.
We have to get past that guard.
-I can deal with him.
-No, no, no, no.
-You're not going anywhere.
-What?
-You belong here with them.
-She belongs with us.
With you. She's your daughter.
She's a soldier.
She came out of that machine.
Oh, yes. I know that bit.
Listen, have you got that stethoscope?
Give it to me. Come on.
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
-What are you doing?
-It's all right.
Just hold still.
Come here.
Listen, and then tell me
where she belongs.
(HEART BEATING)
(MORE BEATING)
Two hearts.
-DONNA: Exactly.
-What's going on?
Does that mean she's a...
What do you call a female Time Lord?
-What's a Time Lord?
-It's who I am. It's where I'm from.
And I'm from you?
You're an echo, that's all.
A Time Lord is so much more.
A sum of knowledge, a code,
a shared history, a shared suffering.
And it's gone now, all of it.
Gone forever.
What happened?
-There was a war.
-Like this one?
Bigger. Much bigger.
And you fought?
And killed?
Yes.
Then how are we different?
I need to charge it up. I need power.
Do you understand?
(GURGLING)
There's even more.
In 3D! Oh, you're a clever Hath!
So this is where everybody's headed?
(HATH GURGLING)
But look, those tunnels sort of zig-zag.
If I went up and over the surface
in a straight line, I'd get there first.
Why not?
Are these the readings for the surface?
But it doesn't look too bad.
Nitrogen and oxygen about 80-20.
That's fine. Ozone levels are high
and some big radiation spikes.
But as long as
I'm not out there too long...
I have to find my friends.
Come on, then.
Hey.
I'm not supposed to talk to you.
I'm on duty.
Yeah, I know. Guarding me.
So does that mean I'm dangerous
or that I need protecting?
-Protecting from what?
-Ooh, I don't know. Men like you.
Keep quiet and open the door.
I'd like to see you try that.
(WHISPERING) That's the way out.
Don't you dare.
Let me distract this one.
I have picked up a few
womanly wiles over the years.
Let's save your wiles for later,
in case of emergency.
(SQUEAKING)
I was gonna distract him,
not clobber him.
Well, it worked, didn't it?
I still have a copy of that new map.
Just stay there. Don't hurt anyone.
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GURGLING)
You can stay down here and
live your whole life in the shadows
or come with me and
stand in the open air,
feel the wind on your face.
What's it gonna be?
(MOANING)
It's up to you,
but nothing's gonna stop me.
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GASPING)
I knew you couldn't resist it.
(GURGLING)
Er, language!
Come on.
It was the girl. She tricked me.
They... They got away. I'm sorry.
I've waited all my life for this moment.
No one's gonna get in my way,
certainly not this Doctor.
Alarm! We march!
To war!
Wait!
This is it. The hidden tunnel.
There must be a control panel.
There's another one of those numbers.
They're everywhere.
DOCTOR: The original builders
must have left them.
An old cataloguing system.
You got a pen, a bit of paper?
'Cause, do you see?
The numbers are counting down.
This one ends in 1-4.
The prison cell said 1-6.
Always thinking, both of you.
Who are you people?
-I told you, I'm the Doctor.
-The Doctor, that's it?
-That's all he ever says.
-So you don't have a name either?
-Are you an anomaly, too?
-No.
Oh, come off it. You're the most
anomalous bloke I've ever known.
Here it is!
And Time Lords,
what are they for exactly?
For? They're not...
They're not for anything.
-So what do you do?
-I travel through time and space.
He saves planets, rescues civilisations
defeats terrible creatures
and runs a lot.
Seriously, there's an outrageous amount
of running involved.
Great!
COBB: Support 5, with me.
No. What were you saying about running?
That's not mood lighting, is it?
-No. I didn't think so.
-Arming device.
There's more of these.
Always eight numbers,
counting down the closer we get.
(GRUNTS)
Here we go.
DONNA: You'd better be quick.
The general.
-Where are you going?
-I can hold them up.
-No. We don't need any more dead.
-But it's them or us.
-It doesn't mean you have to kill them.
-I'm trying to save your life.
Listen to me, the killing,
after a while it infects you
and once it does you're never rid of it.
-But we don't have a choice.
-We always have a choice.
-I'm sorry.
-Jenny!
SOLDIER: This door, now!
SOLDIER: Right, there she is! Come on!
-Told you. Nothing but a soldier.
-She's trying to help.
You must increase your fire!
-DOCTOR: Jenny, come on!
-I'm coming.
Cease-fire! Cease-fire.
-That's it.
-Jenny, leave it. Let's go!
COBB: You're a child of the machine.
You're on my side.
Join us.
Join us in the war against the Hath.
It's in your blood, girl. Don't deny it.
Jenny, come on!
-That's it!
-Hurry up!
Oh, no, no, no, no.
The circuits moved back.
-Zap it back again!
-The controls are back there.
They're coming!
Wait! Just...
There isn't... Jenny, I can't...
I'll have to manage on my own.
Watch and learn, Father.
No way.
-But that was impossible.
-Not impossible. Just a bit unlikely.
Brilliant. You were brilliant!
Brilliant!
I didn't kill him. General Cobb.
I could've killed him, but I didn't.
You were right. I had a choice.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
I warned you, Cobb.
If the source is a weapon,
I'm gonna make sure you never use it.
One of us is gonna die today
and it won't be me.
It can't be much further.
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(GURGLING)
(COUGHING)
Help me!
I'm sinking! I'm sinking! Help me peg!
Help me! Help me! Help me peg!
Help! I'm sinking!
(CRYING)
(GRUNTING)
(MOANING AND GURGLING)
No!
So you travel together,
but you're not together.
What? No, no, no way.
No, no. We're friends, that's all.
I mean, we're not even the same species.
There's probably laws against it.
-And what's it like, the travelling?
-Oh, never a dull moment.
It can be terrifying,
brilliant and funny,
sometimes all at the same time.
I've seen some amazing things though.
A whole new world.
-Oh, I'd love to see new worlds.
-You will.
-Won't she, Doctor?
-Hmm?
Do you think Jenny
will see any new worlds?
I suppose so.
You mean...
You mean you'll take me with you?
Well, we can't leave you here, can we?
Oh, thank you, thank you, thank you!
-Come on. Let's get a move on.
-Careful, there might be traps.
Kids, they never listen.
Oh, I know that look.
See it a lot round our way.
Blokes with pushchairs and frowns.
You've got dad shock.
-Dad shock?
-Sudden, unexpected fatherhood.
-It'll take a bit of getting used to.
-No. It's not that.
Well, what is it then?
Having Jenny in the Tardis, is that it?
What's she gonna do? Cramp your style?
Like, you've got a sports car, she's
gonna turn it into a people carrier?
Donna, I've been a father before.
-What?
-I lost all that a long time ago,
-along with everything else.
-I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Why didn't you tell me?
You talk all the time,
but you don't say anything.
I know. Just...
When I look at her now, I can see them,
the hole they left,
all the pain that filled it.
Just don't know
if I can face that every day.
It won't stay like that.
She'll help you. We both will.
When they died,
that part of me died with them.
It'll never come back, not now.
I'll tell you something, Doctor,
something I've never told you before.
I think you're wrong.
(LASERS BLASTING)
They've blasted through the beams.
Time to run again.
-Love the running. Yeah?
-Love the running.
(MARTHA CRYING)
(GUNS FIRING)
-DONNA: We're trapped.
-Can't be.
This must be the temple. This is a door.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
And again. We're down to 1-2 now.
-I got it!
-I can hear them.
-Nearly done!
-This can't be a cataloguing system.
They're getting closer.
-Then get back here.
-They're too similar.
-JENNY: Not yet.
-Too familiar.
Now!
Got it!
They're coming.
Close the door.
-That was close.
-No fun otherwise.
It's not what I'd call a temple.
-It looks more like...
-Fusion-drive transport.
-It's a spaceship.
-What, the original one?
The one the first colonists arrived on?
Well, it could be, but the power cells
would have run down after all that time.
This one's still powered up
and functioning.
Come on!
It's the Hath.
That door's not gonna last much longer.
And if General Cobb gets through
down there, war's gonna break out.
Look, look, look, look!
Ship's log.
First wave of human-Hath
co-colonisation of Planet Messaline.
So it is the original ship?
-What happened?
-There's one construction.
They used robot drones
to build the city.
-But does it mention the war?
-DOCTOR: Final entry,
"Mission commander dead.
"Still no agreement on who
should assume leadership.
"Hath and humans
have divided into factions."
That must be it. A power vacuum.
The crew divided into two factions,
then turned on each other.
Start using the progenation machines,
suddenly you've got two armies
fighting a never-ending war.
Two armies who are now both outside.
Look at that!
-It's like the numbers in the tunnels.
-No, no, no, but listen.
I spent six months working as a temp
in Hounslow Library
and I mastered the Dewey Decimal
System in two days flat.
I'm good with numbers.
It's staring us in the face.
What is?
It's the date.
Assuming the first two numbers
are some big old space date,
then you've got year, month, day.
It's the other way round,
like it is in America.
Oh, it's the new Byzantine calendar!
The codes are completion dates
for each section.
They finish it, they stamp the date on.
So the numbers aren't counting down.
They're going out from here day by day
as the city got built.
Yes. Oh, good work, Donna!
Yeah, but you're still not getting it.
The first number I saw back there
was 60-12-07-17.
-Well, look at the date today.
-0-7-24... No.
-What does it mean?
-Seven days.
That's it!
-What do you mean, "seven days"?
-Seven days since war broke out.
This war started seven days ago.
Just a week. A week.
-They said years.
-No. They said generations.
And if they're all like you and
they're products of those machines...
They could have 20 generations in a day.
Each generation gets killed in the war,
passes on the legend.
Oh, Donna, you're a genius!
But all the buildings, the encampments,
they're in ruins.
They're not ruined, they're just empty,
waiting to be populated.
Oh, they've mythologized
their entire history.
The source must be part of that, too.
Come on!
-Doctor!
-Martha!
Oh, I should've known you wouldn't stay
away from all the excitement.
-Donna'!
-Ooh, you're filthy. What happened?
I took the surface route.
(COBB SHOUTING)
That's the General.
We haven't got much time.
We don't even know
what we're looking for.
-Is it me or can you smell flowers?
-Yes.
Bougainvillea.
I say we follow our nose.
(COBB SHOUTING)
Oh, yes!
Yes!
Isn't this brilliant?
Is that the source?
It's beautiful.
-What is it?
-Terraforming.
It's a third-generation
terraforming device.
-So why are we suddenly in Kew Gardens?
-'Cause that's what it does.
All this, only bigger, much bigger.
It's in a transit state.
Producing all this must help
keep it stable before they find...
(CRASHING)
Stop! Hold your fire!
-What is this, some kind of trap?
-You said you wanted this war over.
-I want this war won!
-You can't win. No one can.
You don't even know why you're here.
Your whole history,
it's just Chinese whispers,
getting more distorted
the more it's passed on.
This is the source.
This is what you're fighting over,
a device to rejuvenate
a planet's ecosystem.
It's nothing mystical.
It's from a laboratory,
not some creator.
It's a bubble of gases,
a cocktail of stuff
for accelerated evolution.
Methane, hydrogen, ammonia,
amino acids, proteins, nucleic acids.
It's used to make
barren planets habitable.
Look around you.
It's not for killing.
It's for bringing life.
If you allow it, it can lift you out
of these dark tunnels
and into the bright, bright sunlight.
No more fighting, no more killing.
I'm the Doctor
and I declare this war is over.
What's happening?
The gases will escape and trigger
the terraforming process.
-What does that mean?
-It means a new world.
No!
Jenny. Jenny. Talk to me, Jenny.
Is she gonna be all right?
A new world.
It's beautiful.
Jenny, please hold on.
You need to hold on, do you hear me?
We've got things to do,
you and me, eh? Eh?
We can go anywhere.
Everywhere. You choose.
That sounds good.
You're my daughter
and we've only just got started.
You're gonna be great.
You're gonna be more than great.
You're gonna be amazing.
Do you hear me, Jenny?
Two hearts.
Two hearts, just like me.
If we wait, we just wait...
There's no sign, Doctor.
There's no regeneration.
She's like you, but maybe not enough.
No. Too much.
That's the truth of it.
She was too much like me.
I never would.
Have you got that?
When you start this new world,
this world of human and Hath,
remember that!
Make the foundation of this society
a man who never would!
It's happening. The terraforming.
Build a city nice and safe underground,
strip away the top soil and there it is.
-And what about Jenny?
-Let us give her a proper ceremony.
I think it would help us. Please.
Jenny was the reason
for the Tardis bringing us here.
It just got here too soon,
which then created
Jenny in the first place.
Paradox. An endless paradox.
-Time to go home.
-Yeah. Home.
(TARDIS RUMBLING)
-Are you sure about this?
-Yeah. Positive.
I can't do this any more.
You'll be the same one day.
Not me, never.
How could I ever go back to
normal life after seeing all this?
I'm gonna travel with that man forever.
-Good luck.
-And you.
-We're making a habit of this.
-Yeah, and you'd think it'd get easier.
All those things you've
been ready to die for.
I thought for a moment there
you'd finally found
something worth living for.
Oh, there's always something
worth living for, Martha.
-Bye, Doctor.
-Goodbye, Dr Jones.
Hello, boys.
(WHOOSHING)
The shuttle.
Jenny, what are you doing? Come back.
Sorry, can't stop.
What are you gonna do? Tell my dad?
-But where are you going?
-I've got the whole universe.
Planets to save,
civilisations to rescue,
creatures to defeat
and an awful lot of running to do.
(CAR HONKING)
-Agatha Christie.
-What about her?
-That's me.
-No!
Murder!
Chief Inspector Smith
from Scotland Yard,
known as the Doctor. Miss Noble is
the plucky young girl that helps me out.
I say.
There's a murder, a mystery
and Agatha Christie.
So? Happens to me all the time.
Show yourself, demon.
No!
There's nowhere to run.
The thrill is in the chase,
never in the capture.
Oh, my God.
If anyone can solve this, it's you.