(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
KAHLER-JEX: Traditionally, revolutions
begin with a gunshot or a call to arms.
But when future historians look back
to find the seed
of the golden age of the Kahler,
they'll see it began here,
began now, with an idea.
The intention is to create
a living weapon,
a multi-faceted war machine
that doesn't tire, doesn't malfunction.
The subjects were chosen
from our last remaining
military academy,
as they had to be healthy
and resilient enough
to survive the procedures.
A degree of duplicity was
necessary to secure their participation.
They were told they'd been
selected for peace-keeping missions
on off-world colonies.
All weaponry, radar and intel
will be literally fused with the host
so that soldier and artillery
are one.
(BEEPING)
Subject 6. Kahler-Tech.
The idea made flesh.
(POWERING UP)