River?
Follow that ship!
Has Dr Song explained
what we're dealing with?
AMY: Doctor...
what's it going to do to me?
Amy, not the eyes, look at the Angel,
but don't look at the eyes.
OCTAVIAN: The Angel, as far as we know,
is still trapped in the ship -
our mission is to get inside
and neutralise it.
DOCTOR: Don't you see? All that radiation
spilling out, the drive burn.
The crash of the Byzantium
wasn't an accident -
it was a rescue mission for the Angels.
We're in the middle of an army.
The statues are advancing
on all sides.
RIVER: There's no way up, no way back,
no way out.
I'm about to do something
incredibly stupid and dangerous.
When I do, jump.
- On my signal.
- What signal?
You won't miss it.
Up! Look up!
- You OK?
- What happened?
- We jumped.
- Jumped where?
Up, up, look up!
- Where are we?
- RIVER: Exactly where we were.
- No, we're not.
- Move your feet!
Doctor, what am I looking at? Explain.
Oh, come on, Amy, think!
The ship crashed
with the power still on, yeah?
So what else is still on?
The artificial gravity.
One good jump, and up we fell.
Shot out the grav-globe to give us
an updraught, and here we are!
Doctor...the statues,
they look more like Angels now.
DOCTOR: They're feeding
on the radiation from the wreckage,
draining all the power from the ship,
restoring themselves.
Within an hour, they'll be an army.
They're taking out the lights.
Look at them, look at the Angels.
- Into the ship now - quickly, all of you!
- But how?
Doctor!
It's just a corridor,
the gravity orientates to the floor.
Now, in here, all of you,
don't take your eyes off the Angels -
move, move, move!
OCTAVIAN: OK, men, go, go, go!
The Angels...presumably
they can jump up too?
DOCTOR: They're here...now.
- In the dark, we're finished. Run!
- This whole place is a death trap!
No, it's a time bomb. Well,
it's a death trap and a time bomb.
And now it's a dead end.
Nobody panic.
Oh, just me, then.
- What's through here?
- Secondary Flight Deck.
OK, so we've basically run up
the inside of a chimney, yeah?
- So what if the gravity fails?
- I've thought about that.
And?
And we'll all plunge to our deaths.
See, I've thought about it.
Ah, the security protocols are still live.
There's no way to override them,
- it's impossible.
- How impossible?
Two minutes.
OCTAVIAN: The hull is breached,
and the power's failing.
CLERIC: Sir, incoming!
AMY: Doctor, lights!
OCTAVIAN: Clerics, keep watching them.
DOCTOR: And don't look at their eyes -
anywhere else, not the eyes.
I've isolated the lighting grid -
they can't drain the power now.
OCTAVIAN: Good work, Doctor.
Yes, good, good, good. Good in many ways.
Good you like it so far...
So far?!
Well, there's only one way
to open this door.
I guess I'll need to route
all the power in this section
- through the door control.
- Good, fine, do it.
Including the lights. All of them.
I'L need to turn out the lights.
- OCTAVIAN: How long for?
- Fraction of a second, maybe longer.
- Maybe quite a bit longer.
- Maybe?
I'm guessing. We're being attacked
by statues in a crashed ship -
there isn't a manual for this!
Doctor, we lost the torches,
we'll be in total darkness.
No other way. Bishop...
Dr Song, I've lost good clerics today.
You trust this man?
- I absolutely trust him.
- He's not some kind of madman, then?
I absolutely trust him.
Excuse me.
I'm taking your word, because you're
the only one who can manage this guy.
But that only works so long
as he doesn't know who you are.
You cost me any more men,
and I might just tell him. Understood?
Understood.
- OK, Doctor, we've got your back.
- Bless you, Bishop.
Combat distance, ten feet. As soon as
the lights go down, continuous fire.
Full spread over the hostiles. Do not stop
firing while the lights are out.
Shotgun protocol -
we don't have bullets to waste.
DOCTOR: Amy, when the lights go down,
the wheel should release.
- Spin it clockwise, four turns.
- Ten.
No, four, four turns.
Yeah, four, I heard you.
Ready!
On my count, then.
God be with us all.
Three...two...one...
fire!
Turn!
AMY: It's opening, it's working.
OCTAVIAN: Fall back!
- RIVER: Doctor, quickly.
- AMY: Doctor!
Doctor!
AMY: What are you doing?
Magnetised the door.
Nothing could turn that wheel now.
Yeah?
- Dear God!
- Ah, now you're getting it!
You've bought us time, though,
that's good, I am good with time.
Doctor!
Seal that door, seal it now!
- We're surrounded.
- Seal it, seal that door.
- Doctor, how long have we got?
- Five minutes, max.
- Nine.
- Five.
Five, right, yeah.
- Why did you say nine?
- I didn't.
- We need another way out of here.
- There isn't one.
Yeah, there is, course there is.
This is a galaxy class ship,
goes for years between planet-falls.
So what do they need?
- Of course.
- "Of course"” what? What do they need?
OCTAVIAN: Can we get in there?
Well, it's a sealed unit, but they
must have installed it somehow.
This whole wall should slide up.
There's clamps, release the clamps!
What's through there?
What do they need?
They need to breathe.
But that's...
That's a...
- RIVER: It's an oxygen factory.
- It's a forest.
RIVER: Yeah, it's a forest,
it's an oxygen factory.
DOCTOR: And if we're lucky,
an escape route.
- Eight!
- RIVER: What did you say?
- Nothing.
- Is there another exit?
Scan the architecture -
we don't have time to get lost in there.
On it! Stay where you are
until I've checked the rad levels.
But trees? On a spaceship?!
Oh, more than trees, way better
than trees. You're going to love this.
Tree Borgs...
trees plus technology.
Branches become cables,
become sensors on the hull,
a forest sucking in starlight,
breathing out air.
It even rains.
There's a whole mini-climate.
This vault is an ecopod running
right through the heart of the ship.
A forest in a bottle
on a spaceship in a maze.
- Have I impressed you yet, Amy Pond?
- Seven.
- Seven?
- Sorry, what?
You said seven.
- No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
OCTAVIAN: Doctor, there's an exit, far end
of the ship, into the Primary Flight Deck.
- Good. That's where we need to go.
- Plotting a safe path now.
Quick as you like!
ANGEL BOB: Doctor?
Excuse me. Hello, Doctor?
Angel Bob here, sir.
Ah, there you are, Angel Bob.
How's life? Sorry, bad subject.
The Angels are wondering
what you hope to achieve.
Achieve? We're not achieving anything.
We're just hanging.
It's nice in here - consoles, comfy
chairs, a forest. How's things with you?
The Angels are feasting, sir.
Soon we'll be able to absorb
enough power to consume this vessel,
this world,
and all the stars and worlds beyond.
Well, we've got comfy chairs,
did I mention?
We have no need of comfy chairs.
I made him say "comfy chairs"!
(LAUGHS) Six.
OK, Bob, enough chat. Here's what I want
to know. What have you done to Amy?
- There's something in her eye.
- What's in her eye?
- We are.
- What's he talking about?
Doctor, I'm five.
I mean, five.
Fine! I'm fine.
You're counting.
- Counting?
- You're counting down. From ten.
- You have been for a couple of minutes.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Well, counting down to what?
I don't know.
We shall take her.
We shall take all of you.
We shall have dominion
over all time and space.
Get a life, Bob.
Oops, sorry again!
There's power on this ship,
but nowhere near that much.
With respect, sir,
there's more power on this ship
than you yet understand.
- (SCREECHING)
- What is that? Dear God, what is it?
They're back.
It's hard to put it in your terms,
Dr Song,
but as best as I understand it
the Angels are laughing.
Laughing?
Because you haven't noticed yet, sir.
The Doctor in the TARDIS hasn't noticed.
- Doctor...
- No, wait, there's something I've...
...missed.
That's...that's like
the crack from my bedroom wall
- from when I was a little girl.
- Yes.
Two parts of space and time
that should never have touched.
OK, enough, we're moving out!
- Agreed. Doctor?
- Yeah. Fine!
- What are you doing?
- Right with you.
- We're not leaving without you!
- Oh, yes, you are. Bishop?
- Miss Pond, Dr Song, now!
- AMY: Doctor, come on!
So, what are you?
Oh, that's bad.
Ah, that's extremely very not good.
Do...not...blink.
Ah...
Argh!
Amy?
Amy, what's wrong?
Why am I not dead, then?
Good and not so good.
Oh, this isn't even a little bit good.
I mean, is that it?
Is that the power
that brought you here?
That's pure time energy,
you can't feed on that, that's not power,
that's the fire
at the end of the universe.
- And I'lll tell you something else...
- ( RUMBLING)
Never let me talk!
- Amy, what's wrong?
- Four.
Med-scanner, now!
Dr Song, we can't stay here -
we've got to keep moving.
We wait for the Doctor.
Our mission
is to make this wreckage safe
and neutralise the Angels.
Until that is achieved...
Father Octavian,
when the Doctor's in the room,
your one and only mission
is to keep him alive long enough
to get everyone else home.
And trust me, it's not easy.
Now, if he's dead back there,
I'LL never forgive myself,
and if he's alive,
I'LL never forgive him.
And, Doctor, you're standing
right behind me, aren't you?
Oh, yeah.
- I hate you!
- You don't.
Bishop, the Angels are in the forest.
OCTAVIAN: We need visual contact
on every line of approach.
How did you get past them?
I found a crack in the wall and told them
it was the end of the universe.
What was it?
The end of the universe.
Let's have a look, then.
- So what's wrong with me?
- RIVER: Nothing, you're fine.
- Everything, you're dying.
- Doctor!
Yes, you're right, if we lie to her,
she'll get all better(!) Right, Amy.
Amy, Amy,
what's the matter with Amelia?
Something's in her eye -
what does that mean?
- Does it mean anything?
- Doctor...
- Busy!
- Scared!
- Course, you're dying, shut up!
- OK, let him think.
What happened?
She stared at the Angel, she looked into
the eyes of an Angel for too long...
Sir! Angel, incoming!
And here.
Keep visual contact -
do not let it move!
Come on, come on, come on,
wakey, wakey!
She watched an Angel climb out
of the screen,
- she stared at the Angel, and, and...
- The image of an Angel ls an Angel.
A living mental image
in a living human mind.
We stare at them to stop them
getting closer, we don't even blink,
and that is exactly what they want,
cos as long as our eyes are open,
they can climb inside.
There's an Angel in her mind!
Three.
Doctor, it's coming, I can feel it.
I'm going to die!
Please just shut up, I'm thinking.
Now counting, what's that about?
Bob, why are they making her count?
- To make her afraid, sir.
- OK, but why, what for?
For fun, sir.
Oh...argh!
Doctor, what's happening to me?
Explain!
Inside your head, in the vision centres
of your brain, there's an Angel.
It's like there's a screen,
a virtual screen inside your mind,
and the Angel is climbing out of it
and it's coming...
to shut you off.
Then what I do?
If it was a real screen, what would we do?
We'd pull the plug, kill the power.
But we can't just knock her out -
- the Angel would just take over!
- Then what? Quickly!
We've got to shut down
the vision centres of her brain,
- pull the plug, starve the Angel.
- Doctor, she's got seconds.
How would you starve your lungs?
- I'd stop breathing.
- Amy, close your eyes!
No, no, I don't want to.
Good, cos that's not you,
that's the Angel inside you, it's afraid!
Do it! Close your eyes!
(BEEPING)
She's normalising.
(SIGHS)
You did it! You did it!
Sir? Two more incoming.
Three more over here.
Still weak, dangerous to move her.
- So can I open my eyes now?
- Amy, listen to me.
If you open your eyes now
for more than a second, you will die.
The Angel is still inside you.
We haven't stopped it -
we've just sort of...paused it.
You've used up your countdown.
You cannot open your eyes.
Doctor, we're too exposed here,
we have to move on.
We're too exposed everywhere,
and Amy can't move,
and anyway that's not the plan.
- RIVER: There's a plan?
- I don't know yet. I haven't finished.
Right! Father, you and your clerics
will stay here, look after Amy.
If anything happens to her,
I'LL hold every single one of you
personally responsible - twice.
River, you and me,
we're going to go and find
the Primary Flight Deck, which is...
...a quarter of a mile straight ahead,
and we'll stabilise the wreckage,
stop the Angels and cure Amy.
- How?
- I'll do a thing.
What thing?
I don't know. It's a thing in progress,
respect the thing. Moving out!
Doctor, I'm coming with you.
My clerics will look after Miss Pond.
These are my best men, they'd lay down
their lives in her protection.
- I don't need you.
- I don't care.
- Where Dr Song goes, I go.
- What?
You two engaged or something?
Yes. In a manner of speaking.
Marco, you're in charge till I get back.
Sir!
Doctor...please, can't I come with you?
You'd slow us down, Miss Pond.
I don't want to sound selfish,
but you'd really speed me up.
You'll be safer here -
we can't protect you on the move.
I'll be back for you as soon as I can,
I promise.
- You always say that.
- I always come back.
Good luck, everyone. Behave,
do not let that girl open her eyes.
And keep watching the forest,
stop those Angels advancing.
Amy, later!
River, going to need your computer!
Yeah.
Later.
Amy, you need to start trusting me -
it's never been more important.
But you don't always
tell me the truth.
If I always told you the truth,
I wouldn't need you to trust me.
Doctor...
the crack in my wall...
how can it be here?
I don't know yet,
but I'm working it out.
Now, listen.
Remember what I told you
when you were seven?
- What did you tell me?
- No, no...
that's not the point.
You have to remember.
Remember what?
Doctor?
- What's that?
- Er, readings from a crack in a wall.
How can a crack in a wall
be the end of the universe?
I don't know, but here's what I think.
One day, there'll be a very big bang,
so big every moment in history,
past and future, will crack.
Is that possible? How?
How can you be engaged
in a manner of speaking?
Well...
Sucker for a man in uniform.
Dr Song is in my personal custody.
I released her from the Stormcage
Containment Facility four days ago
and I am legally responsible for her
until she has accomplished
her mission and earned her pardon.
Just so we understand each other.
You were in Stormcage?
(BEEPING)
What? What is that?
The date, the date of the explosion,
where the crack begins.
And for those of us who can't read
the base code of the universe?
Amy's time!
So...what's happening?
Anything happening out there?
CLERIC: The Angels are still grouping.
Are you getting this too?
- The trees? Yeah.
- What's wrong with the trees?
Here too, sir.
They're ripping the Tree Borgs apart.
And here,
they're taking out the lights.
What is it, what's happening?
Tell me, I can't see.
It's the trees, ma'am.
The trees are going out.
It doesn't open it from here.
But it's the Primary Flight Deck -
this has got to be a service hatch
or something.
Hurry up and open it -
time's running out.
What? What did you say? "Time's
running out” - is that what you said?
Yeah, I just meant...
I know what you meant, hush!
- But what if it could?
- What if what could?
- Time. What if time could run out?
- Got it!
- Angels advancing, sir.
- Over here, again.
Weapons primed, combat distance
five feet, wait for it!
What is it? What's happening?
Just tell me!
Keep your position and, ma'am,
keep your eyes shut! Wait!
The ship's not on fire, is it?
It can't be - the compressors
would have taken care of it.
Marco, the Angels have gone.
- Where'd they go?
- What, the Angels?
- This side's clear too, sir.
- AMY: The Angels have gone?
There's still movement out there,
but away from us now.
- It's like they're running.
- Running from what?
Phillip, Crispin,
need to get a closer look at that.
What are you all looking at?
What's there?
Cracks...cracks in time,
time running out... No, couldn't be.
But how is a duck pond a duck pond
if there aren't any ducks?
And she didn't recognise the Daleks!
OK, time can shift, time can change,
time can be rewritten. Ah! Oh!
It's like...I don't know...
a curtain of energy, sort of shifting.
Makes you feel weird.
- Sick.
- And you think it scared the Angels?
What could scare those things?
- What are you doing?
- Point me at the light.
You can't open your eyes.
Can't open them for more than a second -
that's what the Doctor said.
Still got a bit of countdown left.
- Ma'am, you can't.
- I need to see it.
Am I looking the right way?
I have to be quick.
Very quick!
OK.
It's the same shape!
It's the crack in my wall.
Close your eyes. Now!
It's following me!
How can it be following me?
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
It was the same shape.
Marco, you want me
to get a closer look at that?
Go for it.
- Don't get too close.
- Hang on, what about the other two?
- Why not just wait until they're back?
- What other two?
The ones you sent before.
I didn't send anyone before.
You did, I heard you. Crispin and Phillip.
Crispin and who?
Dr Song, get through, now.
Doctor?
Time can be urwritten.
Amy, there never was
a Crispin or a Phillip
- on this mission, I promise you.
- No, I heard you.
Before you sent Pedro,
you sent Crispin and Phillip,
and now you can't
even remember them.
Something happened,
I don't know what,
and you don't even remember!
- Pedro?
- Yeah, before you sent Pedro.
Who's Pedro?
It's been happening all around me,
and I haven't even noticed!
Doctor, we have to move.
The CyberKing! A giant Cyberman
walks over all of Victorian London,
and no-one even remembers.
We have to move it!
The Angels could be here any second.
Never mind the Angels -
there's worse here than Angels!
I beg to differ, sir.
Let him go.
Well, it can't let me go, sir,
not while you're looking at it.
I can't stop looking at it,
it'll kill you.
It's going to kill me anyway. Think it
through. There's no way out of this.
- You have to leave me!
- Can't you wriggle out?
No, it's too tight. You have to leave me,
sir. There's nothing you can do.
Something's happening!
Pedro was here a second ago,
and now you can't even remember him!
There never was a Pedro -
there's only ever been the two of us here.
No, there were five of us -
why can't you remember?
Listen, listen,
I need to get a closer look
at that...light, whatever it is.
Don't worry, I won't get too close.
No, you can't, you mustn't.
Here, spare communicator.
- I'll stay in touch the whole time.
- You won't.
If you go back there, what happened
to the others will happen to you!
There weren't any others!
There won't be any you
if you go back there.
Two minutes. I promise.
Please, just listen to me!
Sir, there's nothing you can do.
- You're dead if I leave you.
- Yes, yes, I'm dead.
- And before you go...
- I'm not going.
Listen to me, it's important!
You can't trust her.
- Trust who?
- River Song.
You think you know her,
but you don't.
You don't understand
who or what she is.
- Then tell me.
- I've told you more than I should.
Now, please, you have to go,
it's your duty to your friends.
- Just tell me why she was in Stormcage.
- She killed a man.
A good man, a hero to many.
- Who?
- You don't want to know, sir.
You really don't.
Who did she kill?
Sir, the Angels are coming,
you have to leave me.
You'll die.
I will die in the knowledge that
my courage did not desert me at the end.
For that, I thank God
and bless the path
that takes you to safety.
I wish I'd known you better.
I think, sir,
you know me at my best.
Ready?
Content.
There's a teleport! If I can get it
to work, we can beam the others here.
Where's Octavian?
Octavian's dead. So is that teleport,
you're wasting your time.
I'm going to need your communicator.
Hello, are you there?
Hello?
- Hello?
- MARCO: I'm here, I'm fine.
I'm quite close to it now.
Then come back.
Come back now, please.
It's weird looking at it.
It feels really...
(RADIO STATIC WHISTLES)
Really what? Hello?
Really what?
Hello? Hello?!
Hello?
Please say you're there. Hello?
Hello!
DOCTOR: Amy? Amy? Is that you?
- Doctor?
- Where are you? Are the clerics with you?
They've gone. There was a light
and they walked into the light.
Doctor, they didn't even remember
each other.
No. They wouldn't.
- What is that light?
- Time running out.
Amy, I'm sorry, I made a mistake,
I should never have left you there.
Well, what do I do now?
You come to us. Primary Flight Deck,
the other end of the forest.
I can't see! I can't open my eyes.
- Turn on the spot.
- Sorry, what?
Just do it, turn on the spot.
When the communicator sounds
like my screwdriver,
that means you're facing the right way.
Follow the sound.
(WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING BECOMES HIGH-PITCHED)
You have to start moving now.
There's time energy
spilling out of that crack
and you have to stay ahead of it.
But the Angels, they're everywhere.
I'm sorry, I really am,
but the Angels can only kill you.
What does the time energy do?
- Just keep moving!
- Tell me!
If the time energy catches up with you,
you'll never have been born.
It will erase
every moment of your existence.
You will never have lived at all.
Now...keep your eyes shut...
and keep moving!
- It's never going to work.
- (SHOUTS) What else have you got?
River, tell me!
(WHOOSHING, CLANGING)
- What's that?
- The Angels running from the fire.
They came here to feed on
the time energy,
now it's going to feed on them.
Amy, listen to me, I'm sending
a bit of software to your communicator.
It's a proximity detector,
it'll beep if there's something
in your way.
You just manoeuvre
till the beeping stops.
Because, Amy, this is important,
the forest is full of Angels.
You're going to have to walk
like you can see.
Well, what do you mean?
Look, just keep moving.
That time energy.
What's it going to do?
Er, keep eating.
- How do we stop it?
- Feed it.
- Feed it what?
- A big complicated space-time event,
- should shut it up for a while.
- Like what, for instance?
(SHOUTS) Like me, for instance!
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
- What's that?
- It's a warning.
There are Angels round you now.
Amy, listen to me.
This is going to be hard, but I know...
you can do it.
The Angels are scared and running.
And right now they're not
that interested in you.
They'll assume you can see them,
and their instincts will kick in.
All you've got to do is
walk like you can see.
Just don't open your eyes.
Walk like you can see.
You're not moving.
You have to do this.
Now.
You have to do this!
(COMMUNICATOR BEEPS REGULARLY)
(BEEPING SPEEDS UP)
(SHE GASPS)
(BEEPING SLOWS DOWN)
(BEEPING SPEEDS UP)
Argh!
Doctor!
I can't find the communicator!
I dropped it! I can't find it, Doctor!
Doctor...
Doctor!
Don't open your eyes.
You're on the Flight Deck,
the Doctor's here,
I teleported you. See?
Told you I could get it working.
River Song, I could bloody kiss you.
Ah, well, maybe when you're older.
- (ALARM BLARES)
- What is that?
The Angels are draining the last
of the ship's power. Which means...
the shield's going to release!
Angel Bob, I presume.
ANGEL BOB: The time field is coming.
It will destroy our reality.
And look at you all, running away.
What can I do for you?
There is a rupture in time.
The Angels calculate
that if you throw yourself into it,
it will close, and they will be saved.
Yeah, yeah, could do,
could do that. But why?
Your friends would also be saved.
- Well, there is that.
- I've travelled in time.
I'm a complicated space-time event too,
throw me in.
Oh, be serious!
Compared to me, these Angels are
more complicated than you,
and it would take every one of them
to amount to me, so get a grip.
- Doctor, I can't let you do this.
- No, seriously, get a grip.
- You're not going to die here!
- No, I mean it.
River, Amy, get a grip.
Oh, you genius!
Sir, the Angels need you
to sacrifice yourself now.
Thing is, Bob, the Angels are draining
all the power from this ship,
every last bit of it.
And you know what?
I think they've forgotten
where they're standing.
the gravity of the situation.
Or to put it another way, Angels...
You hold on tight
and don't you let go for anything.
Night-night.
- Ah, bruised everywhere.
- Me too.
You didn't have to climb out
with your eyes shut.
Neither did you, I kept saying.
The Angels all fell
into the time field,
the Angel in your memory
never existed.
It can't harm you now.
Then why do I remember it at all?
Those guys on the ship
didn't remember each other.
You're a time traveller now, Amy.
Changes the way you see the universe.
For ever. Good, isn't it?
And the crack.
Is that gone too?
Yeah.
For now.
But the explosion that caused it
is still happening...
...somewhere out there.
Somewhere in time.
You, me...handcuffs.
Must it always end this way?
What now?
The prison ship's in orbit,
they'll beam me up any second.
I might have done enough
to earn a pardon this time. We'll see.
Octavian said you killed a man.
Yes, I did.
A good man.
A very good man.
The best man I've ever known.
Who?
It's a long story, Doctor.
Can't be told, it has to be lived.
No sneak previews.
Well, except for this one.
You'll see me again quite soon,
when the Pandorica opens.
The Pandorica. Ha!
(WHISPERS) That's a fairy tale.
Oh, Doctor!
Aren't we all?
- I'll see you there.
- I look forward to it.
I remember it well.
Bye, River.
See you, Amy.
(BEEPING)
Oh! I think that's my ride.
Can I trust you, River Song?
If you like.
But where's the fun in that?
What are you thinking?
Time can be rewritten.
I want to go home.
OK.
No, not like that!
I just... I just want
to show you something.
You're running from River.
I'm running too.
(OWL HOOTS)
- Well!
- Yeah!
- Blimey!
- I know.
This is the same night we left, yeah?
We've been gone five minutes.
I'm getting married in the morning.
Why did you leave it here?
Why did I leave my engagement ring off
when I ran away with a strange man
- the night before my wedding?
- Yeah.
You really are an alien, aren't you?
- Who's the lucky fella?
- You met him.
Ah, the good-looking one,
or the other one?
The other one.
- Well, he was good too.
- Thanks.
So, do you comfort a lot of people
on the night before their wedding?
Why would you need comforting?
I nearly died. I was alone, in the dark,
and I nearly died. And it made me think...
Well, yes, natural. I think sometimes...
Well, lots of times...
...about what I want. About who I want.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
No.
- About who...I want.
- Oh, right, yeah.
No, still not getting it.
Doctor, in a word, in one very simple word
even you can understand...
Uh...! You're getting married
in the morning!
The morning's a long time away.
What are we going to do about that?
Amy, listen to me. I'm 907 years old.
Do you understand what that means?
- It's been a while?
- No, no, no!
I'm 907, and look at me.
I don't get older, I just change.
You get older, I don't,
and this can't ever work.
Oh, you are sweet, Doctor.
But I really wasn't suggesting
anything quite so...long term.
But you're human! You're Amy!
You're getting married
in the morning! In the morning.
Doctor?
It's you. It's all about you -
everything, it's about you.
Hold that thought!
Amy Pond... Mad, impossible Amy Pond.
I don't know why, I have no idea,
but quite possibly the single
most important thing in the history
of the universe is that I get you
sorted out right now.
That's what I've been
trying to tell you!
Come on!
Doctor!
RIVER: And for those of us who can't read
the base code of the universe?
DOCTOR: Amy's time!