The Satanic Nebula.
Or the Lagoon of Lost Stars.
Or we could go to Brighton.
I've got a whole day worked out.
Sorry, but as you can see,
I've got plans.
-Have you?
-Look at me.
Yeah, okay.
No, no, no. Like, no.
-Look at me.
-Yep. Looking.
Seriously?
Why is your face all coloured in?
7:15, meeting me, you are.
Date. Second one.
Got words out. Not in the right
order but hey, maths teacher.
BOTH: Out!
-Are you taller?
-Heels.
What, do you have to
reach a high shelf?
Right, gotta go. Going to be late.
-For a shelf?
-Bye.
(PHONE RINGING)
There you go,
you've got another playmate.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
DOCTOR: Hardly anyone
in the universe has that number.
Well, I've got it.
Yes, from some woman in a shop.
We still don't know who that was.
Is that her now?
There are very few people
that it could be.
(RINGING CONTINUES)
-Don't.
-Why not?
Because if you answer it,
something will happen.
-What?
-A thing.
(SCOFFING) It's just a phone, Clara.
Nothing happens
when you answer the phone.
-(SCREAMING)
-(WORMS SCREECHING)
-Doctor?
-Don't touch it!
-Where are we? How did we get here?
-Who are you?
Sorry, what's going on?
I don't understand.
-What is that thing?
-It's a memory worm.
-What happened to your face?
-DOCTOR: Deletes your memories.
-Did you see her face?
-How did I get here?
DOCTOR: The same way
we all did. But we've all forgotten.
-And who are you?
-DOCTOR OVER INTERCOM: I am the Doctor,
a Time Lord from Gallifrey.
I've agreed to this memory wipe
of my own free will.
CLARA OVER INTERCOM:
I am Clara Oswald, human.
I've agreed to this memory wipe
of my own free will.
Do I really have to
touch that worm thing?
DOCTOR: Yes, you do.
And change your shoes. You're next, Psi.
PSI OVER INTERCOM:
I'm Psi, augmented human.
I have agreed to this memory
wipe of my own free will.
SAIBRA OVER INTERCOM:
I am Saibra, mutant human.
I've agreed to this memory wipe
of my own free will.
(BEEP)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
ARCHITECT:
This is a recorded message.
I am the Architect.
Your last memory is
of receiving a contact
from an unknown agency. Me.
Everything since has been
erased from your minds.
Now, pay close attention
to this briefing.
This is the bank of Karabraxos,
the most secure bank in the galaxy.
A fortress for the super-rich.
If you can afford your own star system,
this is where you'd keep it.
No one sets foot on the planet
without protocols.
All movement is monitored,
all air consumption regulated.
DNA is authenticated at every stage.
-Intruders will be incinerated.
-(RAPID BEEPING)
Each vault, buried deep in the Earth,
is accessed by a drop slot
on the planet's surface.
It's atomically sealed,
an unbreakable lock.
The atoms have all been scrambled.
Your presence on this planet
ls unauthorised.
A team will have been dispatched
to terminate you.
-(POUNDING ON DOOR)
-GUARD: This is bank security. Open up!
ARCHITECT: Your survival depends
on following my instructions.
Open up and you shall be
humanely disposed of.
There's another exit.
ARCHITECT: All the information
you need is in this case.
-What are you doing?
-PSI: Downloading.
Augmented. Nice.
ARCHITECT: The bank of Karabraxos
is impregnable.
GUARD: Please stand away from the door!
We do not wish to hurt you
before incineration!
ARCHITECT: 7he bank of Karabraxos
has never been breached.
You will rob the bank of Karabraxos.
Report.
GUARD: (PANTING) Sorry.
Hello, who is this?
This is Ms Delphox,
head of bank security.
I sent you to investigate
an off-world intruder.
GUARD: Did you?
Well, I was wondering
what we're doing here.
-We found these amazing worms.
-(SQUEAKING)
-(EXHALES)
-(DOOR OPENS)
Unwelcome guests.
We're going to need the Teller.
-(LOW SNARLING)
-Are you hungry, boy?
Okay, okay, okay! Stop, stop, stop!
(PANTING) Far enough.
Augmented human.
Computer augmented, yes?
Mainframe in your head?
I'm a gamer.
Sorry, who put you in charge?
You're a liar.
That's a prison code on your neck.
I'm a hacker slash bank robber.
Good. This is a good day
to be a bank robber.
Mutant human. What kind of mutant?
Like he says,
why are you in charge now?
It's my special power. What's yours?
(SIGHS)
If I touch living cells,
I can replicate the owner.
-Your face, when we first saw you...
-I touched the worm.
CLARA: You can replicate
their clothes, too?
SAIBRA: I wear a hologram shell.
Human cells.
DNA from a customer, maybe?
A disguise to get us in?
We're actually going to do it?
Rob the bank?
DOCTOR:
I don't think we have a choice.
-We've already agreed to.
-(SIGHS)
How long can you maintain
the image for?
For as long as I like.
Question one, robbing banks
is easy if you've got a Tardis.
-So why am I not using it?
-Question two, where is the Tardis?
Okay, that probably should
be question one.
-(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
-(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Banking floor locking down.
They know we're here.
-(WHISPERS) What is that?
-I don't know.
Hate not knowing.
Excuse me, sir, I regret to say
that your guilt has been detected.
(STAMMERS) Well, that's
totally ridiculous.
Is it, sir?
Well then, we will
certainly double-check.
The Teller will now scan your
thoughts for any criminal intent.
Good luck, sir.
-Interesting.
-PSI: What is?
The latest thing in sniffer dogs.
Telepathic.
-(THE TELLER SNARLS)
-It hunts guilt.
-What about our guilt?
-Currently being drowned out.
What's he doing?
If he has a plan,
trying not to think of it.
Ever tried not thinking
about something?
-CLARA: No.
-You may have to.
(ROARS)
Ah, criminal intent detected.
How naughty.
What was your plan?
Counterfeit currency
in your briefcase, perhaps?
No. Not at all. For God's sake...
It really doesn't matter.
We'll establish the details later.
The Teller is never wrong
when it comes to guilt.
-(GROWLS)
-Your account will now be deleted.
And obviously your mind. Supper time.
(THE TELLER SNARLING)
(CUSTOMER GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
DOCTOR: It's wiping his mind,
turning his brain into soup.
Your next of kin will be
informed and incarcerated
as further inducement to
honest financial transactions.
(SCREAMS)
We've got to help him.
He's gone already. It's over.
CLARA: He's in agony. Look at him.
Those aren't tears, Clara. That's soup.
(SCREAMS)
Account closed.
Take him away.
He's ready for his close-up.
(BEEPS)
Apologies for the disturbance.
Everyone have a lovely day.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Deposit booth locking.
Please exhale. Your valuables will be
transported up from the vault.
-(EXHALES)
-(BEEPS)
Well, if he can break
in here and plant this thing,
then why does he need our help?
Depends what the thing is.
Okay, well, I'm no expert
but fuses, a timer,
I'm going to stick my neck out
and say bomb.
Bank schematic? Now?
(BEEPS)
So the man that we captured on
the banking floor wasn't the target?
Four bank visitors just entered
the safety deposit box.
The greatest bank in the galaxy.
Our reputation must remain secure.
The Director will blame us.
We'll be fired.
Fired with pain.
(RAPID BEEPING)
DOCTOR: The floor below
is all service corridors.
The veins and arteries of the bank.
He wants us to blow through the floor.
-We'll die if we do that.
-Well, not necessarily.
There must be a plan.
What if the plan is we're blowing up
the floor for someone else?
What if we're not supposed
to make it out alive?
Ah, don't be so pessimistic.
It'll affect team morale.
SAIBRA: What, and getting us
blown up won't?
-Well, only very, very briefly.
-Er, no, no way.
You can do what you like.
I'm going to take my chances out there.
-CLARA: Psi...
-No, this guy, your mate, is a lunatic.
What do you want, Psi,
more than anything else?
Whatever it is, it's in this bank.
You agreed to rob the most
impregnable bank in history.
You must've had a very good reason.
We all must have.
Picture the thing
you want most in the universe
and decide how badly you want it.
Well?
I still don't understand
why you're in charge.
-Basically, it's the eyebrows.
-(BEEPS)
(PULSING HUM)
(PULSING SPEEDS UP)
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
Nice! Dimensional shift bomb.
Sends the particles
to a different plane.
Come on, then, Team Not Dead.
Open up!
Well, so what are we
supposed to do now?
-What's the plan?
-I don't know.
The Architect set all this up.
It should make sense.
My personal plan is that a thing
will probably happen quite soon.
So that's it? That's your plan?
-Yeah.
-A thing will happen?
A thing. Probably.
Hey, Psi.
Doctor!
DOCTOR: There you go. Thing time.
How does he get the cases here?
By breaking into the bank in advance
of breaking into the bank.
CLARA: Well, how did he do that?
And if he can do that,
why does he need us?
-Not our problem.
-Well, what is our pro-pro...
pro-pro-pro...
-You okay?
-Dry glitch. It's fine.
Guilt is our problem. Guilt in this bank
is fatal. The Teller can hear it.
Ever since that first case was opened,
we've been targets.
The more we know about why we are here,
the louder our guilt screams.
That's why we wiped our memories.
For our own safety.
Now, once I open this,
I can't close it again.
Would it be safer
if only one of us learned it?
-I'm waiting for you to volunteer.
-PSI: Er, why me?
Because you didn't need that memory
worm, did you? You're half-computer.
You can perform a manual delete.
You can clear your thoughts.
PSI: Okay.
(CASE BEEPS)
I don't know what it is.
You may as well have a look.
Well, what are they?
-Not a clue.
-SAIBRA: Hmm, interesting.
-What is?
-You're lying.
PSI: Er, why would he be
lying-lying-lying-lying?
(GRUNTS) Sorry. Stress.
Drains the batteries.
Interface with this.
Do we have time for this?
-Why not? There's no immediate threat.
-(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Warning.
Intruders detected.
I really should stop
saying things like that.
-Intruders detected.
-Clara, step aside.
-Saibra, let's go and investigate.
-Intruders detected. Intruders...
(POWERING UP)
(PSI GROANS)
Storm dust.
You can delete your memories?
Yeah, it's not as fun as it sounds.
I've got a few I wish I could lose.
And I lost a few I wish I hadn't.
No, I was...
I was interrogated in prison.
And I guess I panicked.
I didn't want to be a risk
to the people close to me, so...
You deleted your friends?
My friends, anyone who
ever helped me. My family.
-Your family?
-Of course my family.
How could you do that?
Well, I don't know.
(SIGHS) I suppose
I must have loved them.
-Aren't you going to ask me?
-Why did you lie?
Those hardware things,
you know what they are.
Exit strategy of sorts.
How did you know I was lying?
I've had a lot of faces.
I find them easy to read.
-Quite a gift.
-Gift?
-Got us in here.
-Mutant gene.
No one can touch me.
If they do, I transform.
Touch me, Doctor, and you'll
be looking at yourself.
-I am alone.
-Why?
Could you trust someone who looked
back at you out of your own eyes?
(MOANING NEARBY)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, my God. Why is he even still alive?
I don't know. But someone is watching.
Doctor? However this goes,
whatever happens,
-don't let me end up like that.
-(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Intruders on the service level
Now this, this is a place to hide.
(SCREWDRIVER WHIRS)
Where are we?
(SNARLING)
Nobody move. Nobody say a word!
It's cocooned.
Forced hibernation.
Its power is probably dormant.
(MEN RUNNING AND SHOUTING IN HALLWAY)
Clara, it's locked on to you.
It may still be asleep. Don't wake it.
Okay. How do I not do that?
Keep your mind blank.
Block everything.
Once it locks onto your thoughts,
it won't let go.
(SNARLING)
DOCTOR: It's waking up.
Keep blocking your thoughts,
Clara. Don't think.
-(ROARING)
-This way!
-(GASPING)
-DOCTOR: Saibra!
She's still in there.
How do we get her out?
DOCTOR: It's scanning her brain.
-Then what?
-Soup.
-Then help her!
-(THE TELLER ROARING)
(EXCLAIMS)
-Saibra!
-What should I do?
-How can I get away?
-It's rooting through your brain.
It's tasting all the secrets
stashed inside.
Any moment now, it will finish its sweep
and start feasting on what's left.
And what, then I become one of those
things we saw sitting in a cage?
Yes.
Can you not get me out?
I'm sorry, I don't know how,
once it's locked onto your thoughts.
(ROARING)
Exit strategy.
That means what I think it means, right?
-Atomic shredder.
-Painless?
And instant.
(SNARLING)
When you meet the Architect,
promise me something.
Kill him.
I hate him.
But I can't make that promise.
-(THE TELLER SNARLS)
-A good man.
I left it late to meet one of those.
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
Right. Vault.
That's clear.
What's not clear is what we do now.
Hey... You okay?
No, I'm an amnesiac robbing
a bank. Why would I be okay?
-Because of Saibra.
-What? Saibra is dead.
We're alive. Prioritise if you
want it to stay that way.
Oh, is that why you call
yourself the Doctor?
The professional detachment.
Listen, when we're done here,
by all means,
you go and find yourself
a shoulder to cry on.
You'll probably need that.
Till then, what you need is me!
Underneath it all,
he isn't really like that.
It's very obvious that you've
been with him for a while.
Why?
Because you are really good
at the excuses.
Another gift from the Architect.
Shall we unwrap it?
The unbreakable bank.
We must locate them.
And Director Karabraxos must not know.
When people get fired here, it's messy.
Release the Teller into the tunnels.
-(GRUNTS)
-(BEEPING)
Right, the system looks like
it's time-delayed.
There are 24 lock codes I need to break.
Doctor! He's coming, watch out.
-Psi, how long?
-As long as it takes.
(THE TELLER SNARLING)
It's locked onto one
of our thought trails.
We have to split up,
minimise the brain signals.
What happened to your
professional detachment, Doctor?
-No! No!
-In case it finds me.
-It's my choice.
-You don't use that, okay? Promise me.
Time to run.
Separate.
(THE TELLER SNARLING IN DISTANCE)
(BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Vault locks opening.
Vault locks opening.
Twenty-four, 23,
22,21,
20,19, 1817..
-(THE TELLER SNARLING)
-(PANTING)
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
DOCTOR: Keep your mind clear, Clara.
Keep your mind blank.
(SNARLING)
-(GROWLS)
-(PANTING)
-(SNARLS)
-(SCREAMS)
Clara!
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
PSI: (SHOUTS) Come on!
Come and find me!
Every thief and villain
in one big cocktail.
I am so guilty!
-(GROANS)
-(THE TELLER SNARLS)
Every famous burglar in history
is hiding in this bank
right now in one body!
Come and feast!
(THE TELLER SNARLING)
Clara!
For what it's worth,
and it might not be worth much,
when your whole life
flashes in front of you,
you see people you love
and people missing you.
And I see no one.
-(SCREAMS)
-(THE TELLER ROARS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
...three, two, one.
Failed. Vault unlocking failed.
(GRUNTS)
CLARA: It's not opening!
(PANTING)
Psi.
He died for nothing.
-(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Multiple locks.
Last one's still in place.
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
-(SCREWDRIVER SWITCHES OFF)
-Atomic seal. Unbreakable.
Even for me.
The Architect would know that.
He wouldn't bring us
all this way for nothing.
-And get two people killed.
-Exactly.
-There must be some logic.
-Some logic?
Come on, Architect,
what else have you got?
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Report, please.
What was the disturbance?
Solar storm getting worse.
Interfering with our systems.
-(WARNING ALARM)
-Storm.
Storm’s tripping the system.
That's what he's got, the storm.
How would he know
when a storm would hit?
Of course.
Stupid, stupid Doctor.
Of course, of course.
Of course what?
Whoever planned all this,
they're in the future.
This isn't just a bank heist.
It's a time travel heist.
We've been sent back in time to
the exact moment of the storm
to be in exactly the right place
when it hits,
because that's the only time
that the bank is vulnerable.
(LOCK OPENING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Vault unlocked.
The bank is now open.
Come on.
Explains why we're not here
in the Tardis.
Sorry, what?
The solar disruption would've
made navigation impossible.
The one time the bank is vulnerable
is the one time we can't just land.
Doctor, the code. The code
that was in the last case, look.
-"Tech.”
-Technology.
2-5-1. Find it.
CLARA: "Tech."
It's a neophyte circuit.
I've only ever seen one once before.
It can reboot any system,
replace any lost data.
Psi.
That's what he came for. His reward.
So what did Saibra come for?
-Gene suppressant.
-Hmm.
-She wanted to be normal.
-Everyone has a weakness.
So the big question is this.
-What did we come for?
-PV.
Private vault. Karabraxos's own fortune?
-(SNARLING)
-Intruders are most welcome.
They remind us
that the bank is impregnable.
It's good for morale to have a few
of you scattered about the place,
preferably on view.
Are you ready for your close-up?
If you're thinking of ways to escape,
the Teller will know
before you've even made a move.
You'll never be bothered
by all that thinking again.
-Useful species.
-Last of its kind.
And we've signed an exclusive deal.
Must be noisy inside its head.
Painful
to listen to so much chatter.
So many secrets.
Must drive it wild.
How can you force it to obey?
Oh, everything has a price tag,
I think you'll find.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
The storm's getting worse.
Customers are leaving.
Director Karabraxos will be concerned.
Our jobs will be on the line.
You're scared.
(CHUCKLES) I'm terrified.
I have the disadvantage of
knowing Karabraxos personally.
If you don't like your boss, why stay?
My face fits.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I must take
the Teller to its hibernation.
You two, dispose of our guests.
(BEEPING)
Don't do this.
I'm having a very bad day
and I do not want to be pushed around.
You're wrong.
-DOCTOR: Wrong?
-It's not that bad a day.
And you're being very slow.
Why are you undoing my handcuffs?
-(KEYS JINGLING)
-Saibra?
Yeah.
-PSI: You look like death.
-(LAUGHING)
-It was actually a teleporter.
-Oh, my God!
Good, eh? You think we're dead
so the Teller thinks we're dead
and we played the creature
at its own mind games.
No, no, no, no, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Sorry, sorry, you... You...
You're alive?
Yeah. We're alive.
Look at us, we're all alive.
No, no, no, no. Not dead.
-Alive.
-There's an escape ship in orbit.
It takes you right there.
Oh, and there's this
big blue box. Is that yours?
Well, this is good, I suppose.
You'll be able to resume the mission.
Gene suppressant,
antidote for your condition.
Memory giver. All your yesterdays.
There you go. Job done. Paid in full.
-Clever old Architect.
-Very clever.
-I still hate him.
-Me, too.
-How were you paid?
-I don't know.
There's something in the private vault.
-What's that?
-Supply line.
It's the only option
down to the private vault.
And there's another one for
water, for basic life support.
What, for a private vault?
Someone likes to hang out
with their wealth.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Director Karabraxos.
Excuse us but we've come to rob you.
So if you want to put your hands
above your head or...
or?
You didn't bring any weapons.
(CHUCKLES) That's a bit of an oversight.
-(BEEP)
-Security, Karabraxos here.
-You're Karabraxos.
-One moment.
Director Karabraxos. Is there a problem?
Intruders in the private vault.
Send me the Teller.
I want to find out how they got in
and then I want to wipe their memories.
She's a clone.
It's the only way
to control my own security.
I have a clone in every facility.
-Get on it right away.
-Yes, of course.
And then, hand in your credentials.
You're fired, with immediate effect.
But please, I've been in your service...
Ever since the last one let me down
and I was forced to kill it.
I can't quite believe that you're
putting me through this again.
-(BEEPS)
-My clone.
And yet, she doesn't even protest.
Pale imitation, really.
(LAUGHS) I should sue.
-You're killing her? You just said...
-Fired?
I put all of the used clones
into the incinerator.
Can't have too many of mo/
scattered around.
Sorry, you don't get on
with your own clone?
She hates her own clones.
She burns her own clones.
Frankly, you're a career break
for the right therapist.
Shut up.
Everybody, just... Just shut up.
And what is this display?
Now, as amusing as you are...
Shut up. Just shut up. Shut up.
Shut up. Shuttity up-up-up!
What... What did you say?
What did... What did you say?
What did you say about your own eyes?
De-shut up. Say it again.
How can you trust someone if they look
back at you out of your own eyes?
I know one thing about the Architect.
What is it that I know
about the Architect?
I know one thing, something that
I have known from the very start.
CLARA: What?
I hate him!
He's overbearing, he's manipulative,
he likes to think that
he's very clever. I hate him!
-Clara, don't you see?
-(GONGING)
I hate the Architect.
What in the name of sanity
is going on in this room now?
We're getting sanity judgement
from the self-burner.
Do you mind if I borrow
a little bit of paper?
And what are you doing now?
I'm giving you
my telephone number.
Why?
Well, I thought you might
like to call me someday.
Sorry, I thought we were getting
along famously.
Am I like, misreading
the signals or something?
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Oh, boy, that was a big one, wasn't it?
I think that your bank is about
to close for good, Karabraxos.
If I was you, I'd get going.
Don't mind us.
We'll just stay here and burn.
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
DOCTOR: Hard to know what to take.
The greatest treasures in the
universe and just one suitcase.
(RUMBLING)
Doctor, what's the plan?
Is there a plan?
Well, we can use the shredders
and get us back to the ship.
They're not shredders,
they're teleporters.
That's not the most interesting
thing about them.
-So what is?
-There were six of them.
Hey.
-Give me a call sometime.
-AUTOMATED VOICE: Doors opening.
You'll be dead.
Yeah, you'll be old.
We'll get on famously.
You'll be old and full of regret
for the things that you can't change.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Doors closing.
Doctor, what the hell is going on?
-Are you remembering?
-No, not a thing.
-But I'm understanding.
-What?
What is it? What are you understanding?
I'm not sure yet. I need my memory back
and I think that
there's only one way to do that.
-Which would be?
-Soup.
-Soup...
-(LIFT BELL DINGS)
(SNARLING)
Hello, big man.
-Biggies.
-CLARA: Doctor!
No! No! Let it take me.
Let it read me!
-It's the only way.
-It will kill you.
What have I told you about pessimism?
That's it. That's it.
There are so many memories in here.
Feast on them.
Tuck in.
Big scarf.
Bow tie, bit embarrassing.
What do you think of the new look?
I was hoping for minimalism
but I think I came out with magician.
But the last few days,
there's been a block.
Can you see the block?
Tell me why I'm here!
-Show me why I'm here.
-(SNARLING)
Show me!
-(PHONE RINGING)
-It's just a phone, Clara.
Nothing happens
when you answer the phone.
-Doctor.
-Hello?
You gave me this number.
My name is Madame Karabraxos.
-(STEADY BEEPING)
-I was once
the wealthiest person in the universe.
I need your assistance.
I am dying.
With many, many regrets.
But one, perhaps,
you may be able to help me with.
There's a little detour. It's a job.
I've got to do it for someone. Come on.
-We need to rob a bank.
-What?
Clara, I need worms.
(TARDIS WHIRRING)
The bank of Karabraxos
has never been breached.
-Architect.
-DISTORTED VOICE: Architect.
-(PITCH CHANGING) Architect.
-Architect.
-(DEEPER, DISTORTED) Architect.
Architect.
(SQUEAKING)
DOCTOR: You will rob
the bank of Karabraxos.
DOCTOR: Did you see?
Why we came!
Why we're here!
We had to delete our own memories.
Otherwise, you'd have known
and then she'd have known
because you were mentally linked.
But she's gone now. They've all gone.
They have no power over you now.
You can do exactly
what you want to do now.
Exactly what you've
always wanted to do.
(SNARLS)
(LOCK CLICKING)
It knows the combination.
Of course it does.
It was linked to Karabraxos.
What exactly are we doing here?
That thing killed people.
Well, so might you do
to protect everything you loved.
(DOOR OPENING)
(MOANING)
DOCTOR: There she is.
Not the last of its species.
The last two.
(MOANING)
It's okay.
It's okay. It's all right.
Exit strategy. We've got six shredders.
Exactly.
This wasn't a bank heist.
It never was.
It was a rescue mission
for a whole species.
Flesh and blood. The last currency.
-(RUMBLING)
-Time to go home.
What do you think of that, big man?
(ROARING)
So much mental traffic in the universe.
Solitude is the only peace.
(BOTH MOANING)
DOCTOR: Cesare Borgia,
mucho scary hombre, says to me,
"What do you think of our
leaning tower of Pisa?"
I say, "It looks okay to me."
(ALL LAUGHING)
If you ever need help
with another bank heist...
Yeah, it's not really his area.
See? I don't have your face now.
-Yeah, I kind of miss that.
-Oh, shut up.
7:12 local time, as promised.
Go and enjoy yourself.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
This is a date. You know,
I've just realised I'm going out
for another meal now.
Don't worry, calories consumed
on the Tardis have no lasting effect.
Wha... Are you kidding?
Of course I'm kidding. It's a time
machine, not a miracle worker.
-Bye-bye.
-See ya! Don't rob any banks!
Don't rob any banks what?
Without me.
Course not, boss.
Robbing a bank. Robbing a whole bank.
Beat that for a date.
-You okay?
-Yeah, of course I'm okay.
Why wouldn't I be okay?
I don't know. Every time I see you
it's like you're...
-What?
-In a rush. In a state.
How's you?
-Sorry I'm late.
-Who are you having dinner with?
(PANTING) I can't keep doing this.
I can't do it.
The next few days are all about you.
I promise.
I'm the new caretaker.
-John Smith.
-Welcome to Coal Hill, Mr Smith.
DOCTOR: Thanks.
ROBOTIC VOICE:
Problem. Solution: destroy.