DOCTOR: Planet Earth.
Early in the third decade
of the 21st century.
Population - seven billion.
Seven billion lives,
separate and connected.
From the depths
of the oceans...
(WHOOSHING)
...to the edge
of the atmosphere.
- (RUMBLING)
- (ALARMS BLARE)
Soyuz to Control, we have
automatic system failure.
CONTROL: Copy that, Soyuz.
Can you switch
to ballistic descent
and maintain trajectory?
Negative. I'm way off course.
DMP's failed.
And we have to deploy
the parachute!
(GASPS AND GRUNTS)
Control, do you copy?
(GROANS)
(CRASH)
You, my friend,
are under arrest.
You do not
have to say anything,
but anything you do say
may seriously aggravate me.
Jake, what are you doing?!
Nailed him.
(INDISTINCT
TANNOY ANNOUNCEMENT)
I can't believe
you're letting him walk away.
You can't go round
rugby-tackling kids like that!
You're not a police officer,
Jake.
Yes, I am!
I'm just...on a break.
Getting my head straight.
This really isn't working out,
is it?
Obrigada!
- Close your eyes.
- Why?
Trust me!
You're gonna love this.
This is the most beautiful
river in the world.
OK.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(PLASTIC CRUNCHES UNDERFOOT)
Is this a joke?
It's wrecked.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
I don't know what happened.
Three years ago,
this was paradise.
Gabriela,
there's no way in hell
we're camping here tonight.
(LOUD SNORING)
Every time.
(FLUTTERING)
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
Oh!
Ugh.
(SQUAWKING INTENSIFIES)
(SCREAMS)
TV: Another win for Liverpool
has seen them increase pressure
on their title rivals
Manchester City.
Now, I'm just hearing that
we have some breaking news.
Mate, can you turn that up?
A statement just issued by
the European Space Agency
says they're still unable
to confirm whether
the British astronaut Adam Lang
managed to evacuate
his descent module safely
after it veered off course
and crashed into
the Indian Ocean earlier today.
Although
search and rescue teams
continue to trawl the waters,
the Agency say
they are now treating Adam Lang
as missing, presumed dead.
There are tributes for Mr Lang
on social media
- and his family have asked...
- (PHONE VIBRATES)
...for privacy at what they say
ls a difficult time.
(TV FADES OUT)
(MESSAGE SENT ALERT)
Jamila!
(SHOUT ECHOES)
(CRASH)
What the hell?
That's weird.
Hey!
Don't touch it.
Something's wrong
with the birds.
PHONE: You have arrived
at your destination.
(DOG BARKING)
(BUZZES)
(BUZZES RHYTHMICALLY)
YAZ: I don't think
they're too keen on visitors!
Come on, son, fists down.
There's a good lad.
Now, perhaps you'd like
to tell us
why you're so interested
in that door.
DI Jake Willis.
I've reason to believe
there may be
a missing person
inside that building.
Bit out of your jurisdiction,
this.
Sorry, who are you?
We're the people...
...with a nice big set
of skeleton keys.
Good morning, Suki.
Sleep in?
One day I will get here
before you.
(LAUGHS) But I'm always
ready for work.
Especially work like this.
(YELLING) Need some help
over here!
Hi!
(GASPS) Why is it always
the big lads
that need rescuing?
Oh, thanks.
I normally have my mates
with me.
I gave them all errands.
If you touched Jamila...
Hey, I don't even know
who Jamila is.
She vanished.
And you are the only
- other person out here.
- OK.
But I swear I haven't seen her.
I'm here because of
what's wrong with the birds.
You think I'll buy that?
You should,
because it's the truth.
Look, I'm not armed.
There's nothing in my bag.
Check yourself
if you don't believe me.
How long has she been gone?
I last saw her before
I went to sleep last night.
Stand still.
Have you tried her phone?
Of course I tried her phone.
I tried her on everything.
I just messaged some contacts
on Reddit
to access emergency services
and satellites.
Ooh.
You work out?
I do a lot of running.
I'm Gabriela.
I'm guessing you know that.
No.
Two Girls Roaming?
The travel vlog!
That's me and Jamila.
Sorry. Bit behind. I do a fair
bit of travelling myself.
I'm Ryan.
Need to take that bird.
These markings -
they're not natural.
What are you doing?
Birds are falling
out of the sky.
I'm trying to find out
the reason.
(PHONE ALERT)
That her?
No.
But someone's found out
there was an emergency call-out
this morning.
One mile away.
Ambulancia.
JAKE: So who are you?
Interpol?
Did the ESA send you?
ESA?
European Space Agency.
To find
their missing astronaut?
Your missing person's
an astronaut?
Adam Lang.
Equipment failure
coming back from
the International
Space Station.
It's all over the ne...
You're not even
looking for him, are you?
There's some very unusual
energy patterns
coming from this building.
We're under instructions
- to find out why.
- A man's gone missing
and nobody's doing anything
to find him.
Apart from you.
The police.
Yeah.
(LABOURED BREATHING)
DOCTOR: Right.
Let's put him down.
This is a US naval uniform.
- What's he doing here?
- A US submarine
went missing
in the Indian Ocean.
I've been checking the tide
patterns for survivors.
I'm the Doctor, by the way.
Aramu and Suki.
Nice to meet you both.
You live here?
Work here. That's my lab.
We could get him inside and...
(GASPS)
- Help me!
- It's all right!
You're safe!
- No... No, I'm not...
- What's your name?
Zach Olson.
There was an impact.
Our captain tried to raise
the sub, but it was too late.
It was already inside.
What was already inside, Zach?
(CRUNCHING)
No!
What's on his hand?
Oh, no!
No! No!
OK.
So, with the understanding
that was pretty alarming...
...don't be overly alarmed.
His body just disintegrated.
Yes. Poor man.
How is that even possible?
I don't know.
There's a connection between
all these things. I just...
Argh, I just can't see it yet.
- Between what things?
- A missing submarine,
a dead naval officer
off the coast of Madagascar,
birds going haywire in Peru,
and active alien tech
in Hong Kong.
There's also a talking cat
in Ontario,
but I've ruled him out for now.
What?
You just said...alien.
This is the hospital
the ambulance brought her to.
RYAN: Hello?
Hello?
(DOORS CREAK)
Where are all the staff?
- RYAN: Another one in here.
- What are you doing?
The same as the river.
(CLANG)
Hey! The whole point
of quarantine
is not going in
where it says "quarantine”.
Do you want to find her or not?
(DOORS CREAK)
Tell me that's not her.
(GASPS)
Jamila!
I'm sorry.
Melhor amiga.
Doctor?
I've found something
that you'll wanna see.
Who are you talking to?
How are you calling a doctor?
RYAN: You've seen
these markings before...
(GASPS)
(CRUNCHING)
GABRIELA: Jamila!
Hey, get away from her!
No! She's alive!
- (CRUNCHING)
- (SPEAKS PORTUGUESE)
I don't think that's alive.
We have to help her!
No, Ryan's right.
She's not alive.
Whatever caused her death seems
to still be attacking her body.
- Who are you?
- Doctor, her face.
Yeah. I've just seen the same
thing on a naval officer
- in Madagascar.
- (YELLS)
(CRUNCHING)
Jamila!
Same as Zach on the beach.
No, no, no,
this can't be happening.
Hey, it's OK.
- No, it's not!
- Two identical deaths
on two different continents.
It's even more dangerous
than I thought,
and it's spreading.
Which could mean...
Have you heard
from Yaz and Graham?
(BEEPING)
Hey! Hey.
Whatever is giving off
those weird readings...
...is on the other side
of that wall.
Is on the other side
of this door.
You're welcome.
(SIGHS)
Locked from the inside.
Maybe if we went round
the other way...
Chat, chat, chat, chat, chat.
What the hell's all this?
Exactly what
we've been looking for.
Adam?
Adam!
I told you he was here. I'm
gonna get this stuff off him.
YAZ: Wait! Not until we know
what all this stuff is doing.
No, Yaz is right. You can't
just go blundering in.
You could end up killing him.
How long's that going to take?
We've been in this room
as long as you.
Doctor, we found the source
of the energy.
Plus a kidnapped astronaut.
JAKE: Adam? Can you hear me?
It's Jake. I'm here.
I'm here for you.
I'm here.
Get out.
What?
They'll come!
GRAHAM: Unplug him
and get him out!
You just said that wasn't safe!
The situation's changed!
Get him out!
Yaz, what are you doing?!
Oi!
Guns down, or I'll trash it.
(LABOURED BREATHING)
Hesitation.
- Must be valuable.
- Yaz,
we're out. Yaz, come on.
Lads, keep going!
They're right behind us.
- You came.
- Course I came!
Who are you with?
Can you get backup?
Backup? Why would he
have backup?
He's a copper!
- Ex-copper.
- BOTH: What?
- Can we not do this now?
- YAZ: Look out!
- Down!
- Look out!
I'm on a sabbatical.
That's OK. So's she.
Except I don't go around
announcing I'm police.
Never believe anything he says.
Mate, he's just come halfway
round the world to rescue you.
Thank you!
I scanned this building
for life signals
before I sent you here,
so why didn't these register?
- Doctor?
- Could be the suit
- blocking the scan.
- JAKE: Is she with you?
Uh! Can't get
the breathing apparatus off
to see the face.
Non-terrestrial.
- Same as the weapon.
- Er...
So, who are you?
I'm the backup.
Oh! Adam Lang.
Famous British astronaut.
Famous missing
British astronaut.
Glad you're safe.
- How are you feeling?
- Terrible.
Yeah, you look it.
Hadn't factored you into this.
Focused too much on that cat.
This way. I'll introduce you
to Gabriela once we're inside.
She's having a tough time
as well.
Inside where?!
Probably best
you see for yourself.
Is it like, er,
an optical illusion?
I really don't know.
How long have you and Jamila
known each other?
Five years.
I don't know
what I'm going to do now.
You'll get through it.
Cos you've known me
for how many hours?
We're going to find out
what happened.
And we're going
to put it right.
So you really don't believe
this thing travels?
GABRIELA: No way.
Through the doors!
Past Ryan!
We're not all going to fit
- in there!
- You'd be surprised.
Ryan, this is Jake and Adam.
DOCTOR: Come on, Yaz!
- No.
- Sorry?
There was a device in there.
I couldn't get it free in time.
It looked really important
to them.
I want to go back and get it.
- We don't have enough time.
- You go. Come back for me in,
I don't know,
an hour or something.
It's too dangerous.
We need to know
why Adam was taken there
and what they did to him,
and how this is all connected
to those other events.
I'll come with you. I'm more
than ready to fight something.
One hour.
Hey, I'm Gabriela.
You must be Yaz.
YAZ: Come on.
It's through here.
So the box is the doorway
to this building?
No building.
You're still in the box.
But...the box was smaller
than this.
The inside of the box
- is bigger than the outside.
- That's not possible.
It clearly is,
cos you're in it.
It's a space- and time-ship,
mate.
- Don't be stupid.
- Well, excuse me,
Inspector Morse, but I ain't
the fantasist round here.
Adam, you really
don't look well.
I need to do an MOT.
(GROANS)
- Ow!
- I did say it would hurt.
- No, you didn't.
- Well, I meant to.
It takes a blood sample
for analysis.
So...International
Space Station.
- Was it awesome?
- Really awesome.
Best bits?
Just watching the planet turn
across a day.
The aurora borealis.
Seeing hurricanes start to form
from above.
It just changes how you...
see everything.
(RINGTONE BEEPS)
Incoming call.
SUKI: Is this the Doctor?
Aramu. Suki.
Everything all right?
You said to call if anything
else unusual happened.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
ARAMU: Suki?
This is not an ordinary day.
No. Very not ordinary.
Before you show me unusual,
can me and my friends
make use of your lab?
- SUKI: Where did you go?
- Busy day.
Still can't believe
what we saw earlier.
He's not the first person
to die like that today.
Same thing happened
to a young woman in Peru.
They're linked.
I need to work out how.
Plus, we've got
a sick astronaut
getting sicker by the moment.
So, you two know
each other how?
- We're separated.
- We're married.
Well, one of yous
is in for a shock.
One of us doesn't like
putting the work in.
I came halfway round the world.
Seven months too late.
Boys! Maybe now is not
the moment. Let's get inside.
Come on, son. You can do it.
A few more steps.
DOCTOR: The birds are
looking wrong here, too.
ARAMU: I only saw it
the past few days.
At first I thought
it was OK, you know.
It's not the first bird
to fly off its course.
It's not native to Madagascar?
No.
Hey. Don't get too close.
That's not the only one.
Others...
...have started to come.
DOCTOR: Yes, they have.
But why here?
RYAN: There was a dead bird
in that deserted hospital,
and all over the dumping ground
where Gabriela and Jamila
were camping.
And now they're circling this
beach where Zach washed up.
- Alien birds?
- I don't know.
If I could get hold of one
to analyse it...
Good job I've got one
in my backpack.
Picked it up
when I were in Peru.
That's why you smell
of dead bird!
I thought you'd changed
your shower gel.
GRAHAM: Doc!
Doc, Adam's in a bad way
in there.
I think we made a mistake
by disconnecting him from
all that gubbins in Hong Kong.
Or maybe you just want to
stand out here watching birds.
More like they're watching us.
You go inside.
I'll keep my eye on them.
Let's take a look at Adam.
Let us know
if anything changes, Aramu!
GABRIELA: So I guess
you recognise me.
YAZ: No.
GABRIELA: Two Girls Roaming!
I haven't seen it.
What's the matter
with you people?
(LABOURED BREATHING)
YAZ: In here.
Is that what we came for?
Yeah.
OK, so let's get out of here.
It's connected
into the systems.
I want to see what I can find.
It looks like this lab
is part of a triangulation
of signals
with two other locations.
One's Madagascar.
Hide!
YAZ: That's one
of the creatures Jake shot.
GABRIELA: What is it doing?
Whoa! Where did it go?
What did it just do?
It's a teleport station.
We could follow it.
Are you crazy?
RYAN: So here's your present
from Peru.
Ryan, will you dissect it
for me?
What?!
You must have done it
at school.
Doesn't need to be elegant.
Good! Cos it won't be.
Nice lab.
- Very well equipped.
- Thanks.
Right. First things first.
How are you off
for broad-spectrum antibiotics?
- Yes, but only...
- Great!
- ...a small supply.
- Graham!
Jake. See if you can rig up
an IV.
We need to get some medicine
into Adam,
try and stabilise him.
I have no idea how to do that.
I'll give you a hand.
I've seen a few
intravenous drips in my time.
- Finally it comes in handy.
- I might need
a high-powered microscope,
blood cultures,
rapid genome sequencing,
a spectrophotometer,
and a super-fast incubator.
I've got most of that.
Suki Cheng,
on a Madagascan beach,
excellently equipped
and ready for anything.
Ooh, can I use your computer?
Right. I want to see
what's going on inside Adam.
Gonna use your laptop
to download the readings
I took from him earlier.
- So what is it you do here?
- We're working on
a marine filtration system
connected into
the Crystal Oceans Initiative.
Ah! Hence the water
filtration system.
Micro version, is it?
- You take a lot in very fast.
- Yes, I do.
It's one of my skills.
- (BEEP)
- Ah! Here we go.
Initial blood analysis
for Adam.
You OK, Doc?
I'm sorry, Adam.
Your bloodstream's
been infected
with an alien pathogen,
presumably in Hong Kong.
Is it bad if I don't know
what a pathogen is?
I'm glad you asked that,
cos I...
- I didn't want to look stupid.
- It's a microorganism
that carries disease.
Alien bacteria, which is
latching on to life forms...
...and killing them.
I'm afraid it's inside you,
Adam,
and right now I don't know how
we stop it overwhelming you.
GABRIELA: You really want
to follow that creature.
We're seriously
going to do this?
Yeah.
Without knowing
where we're going?
Yeah.
What's the worst place
we could end up?
Long list.
You don't want to know.
You are crazy!
Two girls roaming...
Ready?
I know you're worried
about your husband, mate,
but he's in good hands
with the Doc.
Just go away.
What did he mean when he said,
"Seven months too late"?
I was supposed to come out
and see him launch.
Say goodbye
as he went off to the ISS.
And you didn't go.
He knew what he was taking on
with me.
I don't do emotions.
And I'm really not good at...
...sticking with things,
you know? Commitment.
Also, I really don't like
foreign travel.
Wow. So you were
quite the catch, then.
Yeah.
He's a lucky, lucky bloke.
My husband is an astronaut.
Do you have any idea
how hard it is
being married to somebody
that impressive?
It sort of sends me
the other way.
I wallow in being unreliable.
Like I'm punishing him.
What for?
Not being honest.
No, sorry, you lost me.
If he's that...impressive,
if he's that amazing...
...which he is...
...he can't love me
the way he says he does.
It doesn't make sense.
Why would he?
Oh, mate.
I don't think he's the one
you're punishing.
GABRIELA: We're still alive.
We didn't die!
Didn't teleport
into an active volcano.
Result!
What do you think this is?
YAZ: Some sort of alien colony.
Look at all this stuff.
What even is it?
If we're on an alien planet,
then what is that?
That...
...is part of a submarine.
SUKI: I've gene-sequenced
blood cultures
from Adam and that bird.
Wow, you are fast.
If I track changes
in the optical density
and confirm the bacteria's
growth rate,
we might be able
to use that data
to genetically engineer
a virus.
That's what I was thinking!
We're so sympa.
(DOCTOR AND SUKI
CHAT QUIETLY)
Hey.
(CRUNCHING)
The antibiotics aren't working!
He's getting worse!
GRAHAM: Doctor!
Doc. Doc.
Aramu says that the birds are
getting really angry out there.
Not surprised, if this is
what their insides are like.
Take a look.
They're full of plastic.
Once plastic gets in the ocean,
birds mistake it for food.
I've seen hatchlings
regurgitate
200 individual pieces.
It's feasting on the plastic
in the birds
and taking them over!
The alien pathogens
attacked the plastic.
The plastic metastasized
as if it was living.
Oh...
Autons?
No, it can't be Autons.
They don't work like this.
Not bacterial.
Come on, brains! Move it along!
(WHISPERS) Did she say "brains”
plural?
How does that explain
what happened to Jamila?
Like, she just got taken over.
Yeah. How does it? It attacks
the plastic in the birds,
but there's no plastic
in humans.
Except...
Oh!
Microfiltration!
Hey, Doc.
That's not a thought -
- that's just a random phrase.
- No, no, no.
That's a very big thought.
The microfiltration system
in the water.
- It filters out...
- BOTH: ...microplastics!
Alien bacteria
homing in on microplastics
because humans
are full of them!
Excuse me,
I'm not full of plastic.
- Full of something.
- I'm afraid you are, Graham.
It's in the air, it's in
your food, it's in your water.
Humans have flooded this planet
with plastics
that can't be fully
broken down, so much so
that you're ingesting
micro particles,
whether you know it or not!
You're poisoning yourselves
as well as your planet.
An alien bacteria
has come to this planet,
and it found a feast.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(YELLS)
Hey, Doc, let's get rid
of this bird,
cos it really, really smells.
No. Look!
What?
See what the bird's natural
enzymes are doing.
Oh, yeah. Clear as mud.
Planet Earth... So clever.
Two strains from Peru
fighting back,
ganging up on the bacteria,
holding it back to allow
natural decomposition!
Come on. Catch me up on this,
please.
Ryan Sinclair picks up
a dead bird in Peru
and might just
have saved the world.
Well, I am here for you guys,
you know.
If we isolate and boost
the enzyme, then splice them,
we'd have one
supercharged virus.
Yes, we would.
Yaz, how are you doing?
Cos we've literally got
the most exciting rotting bird
that I've ever seen.
I don't want you to panic...
...but we followed one of those
things through a teleport,
and now I think
we're on an alien planet.
Well, you don't do things
by halves.
Also, I think we found
the missing submarine.
Not sure how that got here.
Oh, and another thing.
The lab in Hong Kong
was sending data
to two locations.
One in the middle
of the Indian Ocean...
...but the other
is in Madagascar...
...where you are...right now.
Doctor.
Doctor,
did you hear what I said?
Yeah. Thanks, Yaz.
Sit tight.
Suki Cheng...
...out here all alone
in an over-equipped lab.
I should have spotted it
straight away.
RYAN: What's happening?
Where's Yaz?
I was so worried
when you turned up,
when you took him
from Hong Kong.
But you've really helped.
Got even more answers from you
than we did from experimenting
on Adam.
We call the infection Praxeus.
Trust me - it's smart,
it's relentless,
and it knows you're onto it.
Oh, I'm a sucker
for a scientist!
Where did she just go?
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
- (SQUAWKING INTENSIFIES)
- (FLURRY OF WINGS)
We need to get out of here.
(SILENCE)
Have they gone?
- GRAHAM: Doc, come on!
- (FRENZIED SQUAWKING)
- DOCTOR: Take cover!
- GRAHAM: Let's go!
Come on!
DOCTOR: We need to get out!
Don't let them scratch you -
they'll infect you!
- I need to get the samples!
- GRAHAM: Doctor, come on!
This is why I don't go abroad!
- GRAHAM: Let's go!
- Here!
Doc, catch!
Come on!
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
DOCTOR: Head straight
for the TARDIS.
- Quick as you can.
- RYAN: They've seen us!
They're following!
DOCTOR: Just keep running!
In here, all of you.
Come on, Ryan!
Yaz, we're on our way. Locked
in on your comma dot signal.
We're coming for you,
wherever you are.
If Praxeus is being spread
by birds,
it could get around the world
incredibly fast,
attacking and infecting
every living thing.
We may potentially have a cure,
but we don't know if it works.
Test it on me.
No. Too dangerous.
It's too dangerous
if we don't do it.
You said yourself
there's no time.
You need a clinical trial,
a human body,
and now you've got one.
- No.
- We don't have time to argue.
JAKE: Adam, no. No way.
I'm not gonna let you!
ADAM: It's not your choice
to make.
(GASPS)
Yaz.
Look.
Looks like it was
trying to get somewhere
but its injuries were too bad.
I wanna know what they are.
Oh, my God!
DOCTOR: Bioreadings synced
with the TARDIS.
If the antidote works on you,
the TARDIS will make more.
Sure?
Stop faffing about.
(WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
(TARDIS THRUMS)
We've landed.
But where?
Stay in here.
We'll be as quick as we can.
With me.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
God, you look miserable
right now.
DOCTOR: Yaz! Found you.
Thanks for coming to get us.
Eventually!
Look at you, going off on your
own and not getting killed!
Plus, totally found
- an alien colony.
- (WHIRRING)
Sort of.
It is an alien construct,
but it's not an alien colony.
RYAN: Then where are we?
DOCTOR: A long way below
the Indian Ocean.
Beneath a gyre
of plastic pollution.
- We're under the sea?!
- It's a naturally occurring
hot spot where ocean currents
trap pollution.
There are five major gyres
on Earth right now.
Praxeus is attracted
to plastic.
It's built a whole environment
here from the plastic,
a world of pure Praxeus!
This is where it all started.
Seabirds infected with Praxeus
transporting the bacteria
around the world,
transferring it to humans
- when they attack!
- But how does
an alien bacteria
end up in the Indian Ocean
- in the first place?
- (WHIRRING)
There's something else
down here,
and I think it's connected
to our friend Suki.
Come on.
What are you
looking like that for?
Thought I'd discovered
an alien planet on my own.
We're at the bottom
of the Indian Ocean?
How are you feeling?
Dying.
Not allowed.
Dying man's wish.
Stop dodging life.
Please.
YAZ: We followed it
through the teleport...
...and found it here.
DOCTOR: Humanoid.
But not human.
Infected with Praxeus,
but the body
hasn't disintegrated.
Must be due
to the different biology.
I don't get it.
Why were these guys
experimenting on Adam?
Maybe for the same reasons
we are.
To find a cure.
- (CRUNCHING)
- (GROANS)
What does all this stuff mean?
(BEEPING AND WHIRRING)
(ALARMS BLARE)
(GASPS)
DOCTOR: Going somewhere?
Who were they, Suki?
The infected people
in the hazmat suits?
My crew.
I'm the last one left.
Wait. That's a spaceship,
right?
DOCTOR: Well, the back end
of one, yes.
Just when I thought things
couldn't get any madder.
- Ooh.
- How did you get here?
I was going to ask you
the same question,
but I presume that ship is how.
So the question is...why?
Praxeus devastated my planet.
The survivors
were assigned to lab ships
to find an antidote
for the few of us left alive.
You're infected too.
Cellular mutation
is slower for us.
If you're scientists
in lab ships,
please tell me you didn't
bring this infection here
deliberately.
Praxeus breeds in plastic,
and this planet
is saturated in it.
We travelled across
three galaxies to find
the perfect living laboratory.
To use Earth as a Petri dish,
destroying one race to save
the remnants of your own!
But this down here,
this environment,
it wasn't deliberate.
We lost control of the shuttle
on entry.
Crash-landed.
The bacteria flooded out,
irradiated, formed this world.
And a broken spacecraft
sending out pulses of energy
from the bottom of the ocean
was enough to down and frazzle
a returning space capsule.
This is the centre of where
everything's been happening!
Your arm. You've been scratched
by those birds.
You've had a double dose
of Praxeus.
But you showed me
how to find a cure!
Thanks to you, my mission
was successful. They already
have the transmission
of how the cure could work.
No! Suki, the cure is designed
for humans,
and we don't even know
if it works on them.
If you're not human,
who knows what will happen?
Please tell me you haven't
administered it on yourself.
Stay out of my way.
Stay here.
Suki! Listen to me!
We can work together on this.
- Get out of here!
- I wouldn't use that in here.
Not with those reverse-pulse
proton engines.
Very unreliable.
No wonder you crashed.
- Put that thing down!
- Sortable, though.
Organic fuel cells.
Oh, hang on.
I'm having half a thought.
Ooh! This one tickles.
What is it?
Oh! Yes!
You can store anything
in organic fuel cells -
anything vaguely organic!
Look at us, Suki.
- (CRUNCHING)
- Two brilliant scientists -
we can fix this!
Work together, find a cure
for you, and then we can
stop Earth from being
taken over by Praxeus!
(CRUNCHING)
What's happening to me?!
It's spreading!
How do I stop it?
(WHIMPERS)
Help me!
(GASPS)
You OK? Where's Suki?
Succumbed to Praxeus.
But I think this may
give us a way through.
I need a crew in here.
- Count us in.
- Hi.
Turns out...
...it worked.
- Your machine spat this out.
- That's the antidote.
And by the way,
where the hell are we?
Follow me! Lots to do.
Engine vents on. Apparently.
System set to automated
timed venting. I think.
Manual bypass...bypassed.
Dials on full clockwise.
- I said anticlockwise!
- Just testing!
Organic fuel cells
loaded with Praxeus antidote.
Trajectory aligned. Comms off.
Spatial regulators disabled.
Organic fuel cells filled
with Praxeus-killing virus,
as tested on Adam, check.
Autopilot system set
for the Earth's stratosphere,
check. All systems set
for automation.
No idea what any of this means,
but is that literally
the controls for up, down,
left and right?
Yeah.
Adam Lang, your job is so easy!
Shuttle initiating
autopilot take-off.
Gold stars
for my apprentice engineers.
What is actually happening?!
Once the ship
is in the stratosphere,
the engines discharge the virus
in one superpowered burst,
dispersing it around the world,
killing Praxeus stone dead.
Hopefully.
Only one tiny flaw in the plan.
Send this into the atmosphere,
it'll rip a hole in this world,
and we'll be crushed under
the entire Indian Ocean.
That's more than a tiny flaw,
Doc!
And that's why
I set the autopilot.
So everybody out, now.
Go!
- What was that?
- Autopilot failure.
It can't connect.
It's gonna work, though, right?
I don't know. It might not.
But it's definitely going
to take off.
We need to get out of here!
JAKE: What if it doesn't work?!
Too late to fix! Come on.
Got to be fast taking off!
Where's Jake?
- Where's Jake?!
- YAZ: He was right behind us.
JAKE: Are these comms on?
Spacecraft to blue box -
can you hear me?
Jake, what are you doing?!
Manual pilot making up
for broken autopilot.
Any idiot can fly a spaceship,
right?
Jake...
I don't want this.
Maybe 7 do.
Maybe I need this.
You're entering
into the stratosphere!
Yeah, that really doesn't
mean anything to me!
But if I was a betting man -
and my husband would tell you
I really am -
I'd say the automatic release
is bust.
Tell me what I need to do!
The controls by your right hand
will vent the antidote.
You need to flick
the three switches at once.
I'm going to give it a go!
The ship's gonna break up.
DOCTOR: Jake, you have to wait
until the shuttle's
in the right position.
Adam?
Adam!
I'm sorry I wasn't
at the launch.
This is me not dodging.
Don't say
I never listened to you!
DOCTOR:
Shuttle's in position, Jake.
Dispersing antidote...
.I think.
DOCTOR: Jake, you've done it!
Antidote particles
being dispersed into
the jet streams.
Hope it works!
Ship's very knackered!
About to blow!
You can save him, right?
Oh...
(EXPLOSION)
(ALARMS BLARE)
Doc, come on!
(TARDIS THRUMS)
I hate you.
Yes, I can save him.
Just...
if I materialise around him
in the millisecond
before the ship breaks up.
Nice work, Doc.
What can I say?
I'm a romantic.
DOCTOR: I guess
this is goodbye, then.
YAZ: Keep the planet safe
for us.
Cos we'll be coming back,
so it'd better be in good nick.
Or we'll know who to blame!
- Thank you.
- Our pleasure. Really.
Although I have to say,
worst thing about
saving the human race -
nobody knows it was me.
Least I could get was a statue!
So what's the plan now
for you two?
Dunno.
Spend some time together.
We never had a honeymoon,
because he didn't want
to go abroad.
Maybe now's the time.
- I'll come with you!
- How's that a honeymoon
if you're with us?
We can vlog about it!
What you gonna call it?
Three Id jots Roaming?
I like it! It's snappy!
And factual.
Yeah, you guys can go now.
We'll take the planet
from here.
Hey!
Come find us some time.
DOCTOR: Planet Earth.
Seven billion lives,
separate and connected.
From the edge of
the atmosphere
to the depths of the ocean.
DOCTOR: Welcome to Aleppo!
MAN: Your worst fears.
My creativity.
Who are you?
Get everyone out.