BILL: What happened to the Doctor?
The Doctor took you to safety.
He paid a price.
You're blind.
It's temporary.
-Look at me!
-Nardole, I can't. I really can't.
I can't look at anything ever again.
I'm still blind.
MAN: Death is an increasing problem.
With over a billion intelligent species
active in this galaxy alone,
it is an ever greater challenge to know
how to kill all of them.
On this planet, we are proud to serve
as executioners
to every living thing.
The destruction of a Time Lord,
however, is a particular honour.
This technology is precisely calibrated.
As you can see,
it will stop both hearts,
all three brain stems,
and deliver a cellular shockwave
that will permanently disable
regenerative ability.
I know how it works.
You certainly will in a moment.
Following termination,
the body will be placed
in a quantum fold chamber
under constant guard
for no less than a thousand years.
In case of, shall we say, relapses.
Life can be a cunning enemy.
An additional stipulation
of the fatality index
is that the sentence must be carried out
by another Time Lord.
Apologies for our choice,
but your people are not easy to come by.
Oh, Doctor?
I didn't expect you.
Thought you'd retired.
Domestic bliss on Darillium.
That's the word among the Daleks.
What happened?
Oh, I see.
My condolences.
The prisoner will kneel.
Right.
Thank you.
They can't know I'm blind, Missy.
No one can know.
Memories are so much worse in the dark.
The quantum fold chamber is prepared.
Great.
The sentence will be carried out.
Executioner?
Please, I'll do anything.
Just let me live.
(DEVICE TRILLS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Hello?
Hello? Who's there?
CARDINAL ANGELO: Good evening, Doctor.
We have come here today,
direct from the Vatican.
All right, that's nice.
Well, if you've got a collecting tin,
I'm sure I can find something.
Uh, leaky roof, is it?
Oh, no. (CHUCKLING)
No. No, no. No, no, no. Stop talking.
Stop now. Please, just listen to them.
Sounds important.
We have come here to see you,
because your services of wisdom
are recommended at the highest level.
As you can see,
this is a personal recommendation
of Pope Benedict IX...
...in 1045,
(CHUCKLES)
Pope Benedict.
Lovely girl. What a night.
I knew she was trouble,
but she wove a spell
with her castanets.
Doctor, on behalf of every human soul
in this world,
of any creed, of any faith,
with the utmost respect
and in complete secrecy,
His Holiness, the Pope,
the Bishop of Rome,
request most urgently
a personal audience.
Well, if he was so keen to talk to me,
why didn't he just come here himself?
He is here.
He's standing right in front of us.
Hello.
Uh, the Pope. I'm sorry
that I didn't recognise you there.
You don't do this.
The Pope doesn't zoom around the world
in the Popemobile surprising people.
Why would you do that?
-(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
-Mmm-hmm.
Extremis.
CARDINAL ANGELO:
There is an ancient text
buried deep in the most secret
of the Vatican libraries.
Text older than the church itself.
The language of this text is lost to us.
But thanks to the work
of an early Christian sect,
the title has survived.
Okay, so, what's the title?
Oh, yes, I can see
that it says, uh, "Veritas”.
Oh. Hmm.
Literally, "the Truth”.
Obviously, this sect,
they understood the language.
CARDINAL ANGELO: It died with them.
And all copies of their translation
disappeared shortly
after their mass suicide.
Few months ago,
after many centuries of work,
the Veritas was translated again.
Right. And?
DOCTOR: What did it say?
No one knows.
Everyone who worked on the translation
and everyone who subsequently read it
is now dead.
Dead, Doctor, by their own hand.
The Veritasis a short document.
A few pages only.
And yet contains a secret
that drives all who know it
to destroy themselves.
Confirmed suicides, all of them?
In every case, beyond doubt.
DOCTOR: All bodies recovered?
Except one. But we naturally assumed...
DOCTOR: Assume nothing.
Assumption makes an
ass out of you and umption.
Cardinal, one of your
translators is missing.
Doctor, those translators
were devout believers.
They took their own lives
in the knowledge that suicide
is a mortal sin.
They read the Veritas and chose hell.
Dottore...
(IN ENGLISH) Will you read the Veritas?
-Loo through there.
-Oh, ta.
I thought you moved out from here.
Yeah, slightly didn't work out.
(CHUCKLES)
Second attempt on the way.
Did I hear voices?
I thought you were going out
with Harry tonight.
-Howard.
-I don't like knowing the names,
I only get attached.
Did you bring someone home?
(HESITANTLY) Yeah.
I'm a grownup, I can do that, can't I?
Of course not. I have very strict rules
about men.
Probably not as strict as mine.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
Oh, hello, are you Moira?
-(MOUTHING)
-Oh, you're a girl.
Mmm. I'm Penny.
Oh. Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, I see. Oh, I'm sorry.
Here's me thinking she dragged
some poor terrified man home.
-(PENNY LAUGHS)
-Well, phew!
-Oh, phew.
-(BILL CHUCKLES)
Right, you two. I'm off to the pub.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
-(DOOR SHUTS)
-Well...
Alone at last.
(CHUCKLES)
(WHOOSHING)
Oh, God. What was that?
The, uh...
...pipes.
It's... It's the... The pipes
in... In my bedroom.
Be warned. Sometimes I shout at them.
Wha...
Are you okay?
Yeah, sorry,
I'm just not quite used to...
...all of this.
Well, whatever this is,
and actually, it's not anything yet,
it is absolutely nothing
to feel guilty about.
-Okay?
-Okay.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
That was the Pope.
Bill, that was the Pope.
Yeah, yeah, give me a minute.
I am about to have a truly awesome word
with someone.
-Oh, my God.
-No, Penny, wait.
(GASPS)
-(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
-(GROANS)
You're all going to hell.
-(DOOR SHUTS)
-Doctor.
Here's a tip.
When I'm on a date,
when that rare and special thing
happens in my real life,
do not, do not under any circumstances
put the Pope in my bedroom.
Okay. Now I know.
Air cleared. Nardole will explain
what's going on.
Uh, Doctor?
(CLEARS THROAT) It, uh...
I think it's pretty serious.
-What's happened?
-Well... (STUTTERS)
You know the Vatican?
-Yeah.
-The one in Rome.
NARDOLE: That's in Italy.
-BILL: Yeah.
-And what is that?
NARDOLE: Where the Pope lives.
DOCTOR: It's a sort of, uh,
a reading aid.
It looks dangerous.
Completely deadly.
But, uh, you know,
swings and roundabouts...
Pope Benedict said that you were more
in need of confession
than any man breathing.
But when the offer was made,
you replied it would take too much time.
On behalf of the Catholic Church,
the offer stands.
You seem like a man with regret
on his mind.
(CROW CAWS)
Have you requested a priest?
MISSY: Oh, I haven't.
Apparently, I have.
I shall seek consultation.
-(WRISTWATCH TRILLING)
-(SIGHS)
There are 412 precedents
in the fatality index.
Divine intervention therefore
is permitted for a maximum
of five minutes.
Five minutes.
The executioner may now discuss
his immortal soul
and any peril there unto.
MAN: Greetings, sinner.
Only in darkness are we revealed.
I never sent for you.
MAN: Goodness is not goodness
that seeks advantage.
Good is good in the final hour.
In the deepest pit, without hope,
without witness.
Without reward.
Virtue is only virtue in extremis.
This is what he believes.
And this is the reason above all,
I love him.
My husband. My madman in a box.
My Doctor.
Your missus wouldn't approve.
How the hell did you get here?
Followed you from Darillium
on the explicit orders
of your late wife, River Song.
Warning, I have full permission
to kick your arse.
Okay. So, you're blind
and you don't want your enemies to know.
I get it. But why does it have to be
a secret from Bill?
Because I don't like being
worried about.
Around me, people should be worried
about themselves.
-Yeah, shall I tell you the real reason?
-No.
Because the moment you tell Bill,
it becomes real.
And then you might
actually have to deal with it.
Good point. Well made.
Definitely not telling her now.
You're an idiot.
Everyone knows that.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(TRANSLATING)
Here you must go without me.
Cardinal Angelo will conduct you
to the library.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
CARDINAL ANGELO: (TRANSLATING)
May God light your path.
Well, we could certainly give it a go.
The entrance to the Hereticum.
The library of forbidden
and heretical texts.
First instituted by your old friend,
Pope Benedict,
who still guards the door.
NARDOLE: You old dog.
(GASPS)
(BATS SQUEAKING)
CARDINAL ANGELO:
Very few know this place exists.
The library of blasphemy.
The Hereticum.
Harry Potter.
Language.
Please stay close to me.
The layout is designed
to confuse the uninitiated.
Sort of like religion, really.
You happy in those shades?
Not dark enough for ya?
In darkness, we are revealed.
Remember, sinner,
in darkness we are revealed.
I regret, gentlemen,
this consultation is over.
I regret it, too.
The sentence must now be carried out.
Well, take a few more minutes
if you like.
Knock yourself out. Actually, do...
Do that. Knock yourself right out.
I'll be good, I promise.
(STUTTERING)
I'll turn. I'll turn good. Please.
Teach me. Teach me how to be...
(VOICE BREAKS) ...good.
Without hope.
Without witness.
Without reward.
Who was your date, then?
Uh, Penny. Uh, it's a long story.
CARDINAL ANGELO: The very centre
of the Hereticum.
Home of the Veritas
for over a thousand years.
Truth in the heart of heresy.
CARDINAL ANGELO: And death
in the heart of truth.
You'd be wizard at writing
Christmas crackers, you two.
NARDOLE: Doctor.
BILL: What's that?
I don't know.
Oh, look, it's er, a mysterious light
shining round a corner
approximately 10 feet away.
CARDINAL ANGELO: Hello.
Who's there?
Doctor?
This library is forbidden.
-No, wait!
-Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Speak!
Speak to me!
What's through there?
What's through that door?
There's no door there. It's a wall.
Impossible. Quite impossible.
Let's take a look at the Ver/tas.
I have a feeling the answers
might be there.
I have to check if there
is a breach in the wall.
I'll unlock the cage in a moment.
Sure.
Oh, my God!
What's wrong?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, hang on.
I think there's someone in there.
Yeah, we are very slightly getting that.
MAN: I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I sent it.
Sent what?
I sent it, yes.
Sent what? Where?
No, stop!
You'll just get lost.
Cardinal Angelo, someone just broke
into your book cage.
(CRIES OUT)
Priest, by the look of him.
Shot out the lock.
Oh, well, he hasn't got far.
So much for your
forbidden library, Cardinal.
Doctor, look at this.
Must have been his.
Laptop.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Hey, there's Wi-Fi down here.
Of course there's Wi-Fi. It's a library.
Reading chair with a safety belt.
What's CERN?
-CERN?
-BILL: Yeah.
DOCTOR: The European Organisation
for Nuclear Research.
The largest particle physics laboratory
on this planet. Why?
Because four hours ago, someone,
that priest presumably,
emailed them a copy
of the Veritastranslation
from this computer.
BILL: Remember what he said.
He said, "I sent it."
He sent the Veritas.
-And CERN have just replied.
-What'd they say?
"Pray for us."
When do a bunch of scientists
ask for prayers?
The same time anyone does.
When they're very, very afraid.
Particle physicists and priests.
What could scare them both?
He's been down here for a while,
that guy. Whoever he is.
I'd guess the missing translator.
-That's promising.
-"Promising"?
Yeah. At least one person
read the Veritas and lived.
-(GUNSHOT)
-(BILL GASPS)
Go and see if he's all right.
Both of you.
I think we know he isn't.
We know nothing of the kind.
He might need help.
Might have useful information.
He's about 50 feet that way.
-Are you trying to get rid of us?
-Why?
Because you're sending us into the dark
after a man with a gun.
-Ah, well, I thought of that.
-Thank you.
Nardole, make sure you walk
in front of Bill.
Oh, great.
Are you gonna read this?
Is that why you're sending us off?
-I won't read this without you.
-Really, he won't.
-Promise?
-Trust me.
We'll shout if we need you.
DOCTOR: Me too.
BILL: Does it give you the fear
when he says, "Trust me"?
NARDOLE: If I worked here,
I'd cross meself.
NARDOLE: Bill, stay close by me.
There's a man with a gun.
Uh-uh-uh.
Yeah, you don't
actually have to do that.
In fact, don't you dare do that.
Uh-uh-uh, Bill.
You're to walk behind me now,
like the Doctor said.
(SCOFFS) Yeah. Totally not happening.
Okay, Bill. Miss Potts.
I'm the only person you've ever met
or will ever meet
who is officially licensed
to kick the Doctor's arse.
I will happily do the same to you
in the event
that you do not align yourself
with any instructions I have issued,
which I personally judge to be
in the best interest
of your safety and survival.
Okay, Bill?
-Okay.
-Good-o!
Nardole?
Are you secretly a badass?
Nothing secret about it, baby doll.
(YELPS)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS) Well,
that answers that question.
BILL: It's an opening
like we saw before.
NARDOLE: Yeah, like a portal.
-You're right.
-About what?
It would be stupid to go and look.
(TRILLS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Cardinal Angelo.
I could do with your help here.
I'm not absolutely sure
how this is going to work.
Either it's going to temporarily
fix my eyesight
or it's going to burn out my brain.
Just, uh, give me a moment.
-(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
-(GASPING)
(GROANS)
MISSY: I am your friend.
Makes no difference.
MISSY: I know it doesn't.
I know I'm going to die.
I have to say it. The truth.
Without hope.
Without witness.
Without reward.
(VOICE FALTERS) I am your friend.
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
On my oath as a Time Lord
of the Prydonian Chapter,
I will guard this body
for a thousand years.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
-Hello.
Who are you?
Do you have clearance for floor three?
Floor three of what?
Of what?
The Pentagon.
(MUMBLES INDISTINCTLY)
So, the Pentagon is through there.
Yeah.
(STUTTERING) And the Vatican
is through there.
Huh. I wonder what's through here.
What is this?
-How is this possible?
-NARDOLE: Alien technology.
Let's see what else they got.
Ooh. Bill, come and take a look at this.
(PANTING)
Oh, hello.
Are... Are you coming?
Coming where?
Uh, we are all in the cafeteria.
You mustn't miss it.
Why?
We're all going together when we go.
(LAUGHING) Come on!
(GASPING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GROANING)
Cardinal. It worked! I can see.
Not well enough. Not yet.
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Think about the universes.
Whatever you need,
you can always borrow.
As long as you pay it back.
I just borrowed from my future.
I get a few minutes of proper eyesight
but I lose something.
Maybe all my future regenerations
will be blind.
Maybe I won't regenerate ever again.
Maybe I'll drop dead in 20 minutes,
but I will be able to read this.
Now, I have no idea
how that is going to affect me.
So, I'd be a bit stupid
to reject the precautions provided.
Could you help me, please?
Could you help me?
(BUCKLES CLICKING)
Now, I've read a lot of books that
this chair would be quite useful for.
Moby Dick. Honestly, shut up
and get to the whale.
Have you invited friends and family?
-(GASPS)
-(BREATHES HOARSELY)
Oh, it's the old, old story.
They never look so good in the morning.
Goodbye to the truth.
I came a long way to read that book.
Two thousand years at the last count.
If you don't want me to read it,
you could've stopped me
any time you wanted.
Why the play acting? This is not a game.
This is a game.
DOCTOR: Good, because I win!
(GRUNTS)
MONK: Doctor!
-Doctor!
-(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HOARSELY)
Doctor, we have the Veritas.
(PANTING)
Come, come, come, come.
BILL: CERN.
NARDOLE: Where what's-his-name
sent the Veritas.
Ladies and gentlemen.
(GLASS CLINKING)
Your attention, please!
I've been around everywhere
and I've checked everything.
It's all ready to go.
Five minutes.
Last orders, please.
(CRYING)
WOMAN: Cheers.
(WHISPERING) Look under the tables.
(TICKING)
Oh, my God.
(KEYS CLACKING)
(SIGHS) Oh, no.
(GRUNTS) Oh, no!
No! Not yet!
No!
No, no, no, no!
(HOARSE GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
In vino veritas.
Why are you doing this?
You've got explosives.
We're saving the world.
You know, we should go.
We should probably even run.
How is blowing yourselves up
saving the world?
Because this isn't the world.
-This isn't what?
-Bill, time. Tiny bit running out.
You haven't read it?
You haven't read the Veritas?
Sorry, I'd love to but must dash.
Choose a number.
Any number. Both of you.
Now.
And say it when I tap this table.
(BANGS TABLE)
BOTH: 36.
Try again. Keep going.
(BANGS TABLE)
BOTH: 17.
-Huh?
-MAN: Again.
Don't stop. Every time I tap the table.
(BANGS TABLE)
BOTH: 9.
BOTH: 48.
BOTH: 1035.
BOTH: A million.
BOTH: Seven billion and seven.
(LAUGHS)
67.
-(BANGS TABLE)
-BOTH: 905.
ALL: 20,460.
-(BANGS TABLE)
-ALL: Twelve.
-ALL: Four.
-(BANGS TABLE)
-ALL: 87.
-ALL: 702.
What is this? How are you doing that?
MAN: It's a test.
It's a shadow test.
Oh. I'm really very sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
ALL: Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one!
Okay, what was that about?
Those numbers, how did they do that?
Ooh.
Oh!
-You okay?
-No.
Yes.
No!
-(WHIMPERS)
-BILL: Someone's been through here.
Could be the Doctor.
Those things.
What do they look like?
-Projectors.
-Exactly.
-Yeah, they're projecting the portals.
No, they're not.
They're projecting everything.
Those worlds, they're all projected.
The Pentagon, the Vatican, CERN...
-They're not real?
-No, no! They're holograms.
They're holographic simulations
and the people in them, too.
Sorry, what?
You know, like the holodeck on Star Trek
or a really posh VR without a headset.
Through there, those places,
that's basically Grand Theft Auto.
It can't be.
It is! Look at the tech!
It definitely is!
What? Sorry,
you're not making any sense.
When did we end up in a computer game?
When did that start?
I... I don't know. Maybe when we arrived
at the Vatican?
But I programmed the TARDIS myself.
We were on target,
we went to the Vatican,
the real one, I'm sure of it.
Oh.
Oh?
Those machines, they...
...project the simulations.
Yeah?
And I'm just wondering...
What happens if
we move outside
the light of the projector.
Don't let me be right.
Please don't let me be right.
(EXCLAIMS)
I'm part of it!
I'm part of the simulation!
Bill, I'm not real!
(SCREAMS) Bill!
Nardole!
(GASPS SOFTLY)
Doctor.
Doctor?
(DOOR CREAKING)
-Bill, is that you?
-(GASPS)
Hello, Doctor.
Is that the president?
It was.
BILL: I take it he read the Ver/tas.
So did 1.
Well...
I listened to it.
There's this thing on here that reads
aloud to you. It's very useful.
Who needs Nardole?
Where is Nardole?
I need to know what's real
and what isn't real.
-Don't we all?
-Don't play games.
Tell me.
Uh...
The Veritastells
of an evil demon
who wants to conquer the world.
But to do it,
he needs to learn about it first.
So he creates a shadow world.
A world for him to practise conquering.
Full of shadow people
who think they're real.
There was a... A thing.
The shadow test?
If you're in doubt
whether you're real or not,
the Veritas invites you to write down
as many numbers as you like.
Of any size, any order.
And then turn the page.
All the same numbers in the same order.
Yes.
Let's bring the story up to date, Bill.
Imagine an alien life form
of immense power
and sophistication,
and it wants to conquer the Earth.
So it runs a simulation.
A holographic simulation
of all of Earth's history
and every person alive on the surface,
a practice Earth,
to assess the abilities
of the resident population.
Especially the ones
smart enough to realise
that they are just simulants
inside a great big computer game.
But... But this is... This... This...
This... This is real. I... I feel it.
Computers aren't good
with random numbers.
If you ask a computer-simulated person
to generate a random string of numbers,
it won't truly be random.
If all the simulated people
are part of the same computer program,
then they'll all generate
the same string.
The exact same numbers.
The... The numbers...
I said them, too.
I know.
So did 1.
The trouble is,
when simulants develop enough
independent intelligence
to realise what they are,
there's a risk they'll rebel.
Those deaths...
They weren't suicide.
Those were people...
(SIGHS)
...escaping.
It's like, um, Super Mario.
Figuring out what's going on.
Deleting himself from the game
because he's sick of dying.
No, I'm real. I feel real.
Those pretend people
you shoot at in computer games...
-Now you know.
-Know what?
They think they're real.
They feel it.
We feel it.
(GASPING)
(VOICE BREAKING) Help me.
Help me.
Bill, what's happening to you?
Save me.
DOCTOR: Bill, are you there?
She was not real.
You are not real.
No, I'm not. I'm a shadow.
A puppet doctor for you
to practise killing.
We have killed you many times.
Then what are you waiting for?
Why don't you kill me now?
You suffer.
Pain is information.
Information will be gathered.
Turn me off.
I have nothing.
Not even hope.
Without hope.
Without witness.
Without reward.
Funny.
I don't believe much.
I'm not sure I believe anything.
But right now...
...belief is all I am.
Virtue is only virtue in extremis.
I take it that your intention
is to invade the Earth.
The simulations have been run.
The Earth will be ours.
Well, consider this a warning.
On the eve of war,
I am the Doctor.
I._..
...am what stands between you and them!
You are not the Doctor.
You are not real.
You don't have to be real
to be the Doctor.
As long as you never give up.
Long as you always trick
the bad guys into their own traps.
And here's the trap you fell into.
Your simulation is far too good.
See these?
They're set to record.
I'm blind, you see.
So I'm psychically wired into these.
So my memory print
of the last few hours
will still be intact on here.
Information about you.
You are not real.
There is nothing you can do.
There's always one thing
you can do from inside a computer,
even if you're a jumped up
little sub-routine, you can do it.
You can always...
...e-mail.
What are you doing?
I'm doing what everybody does
when the world is in danger.
I'm calling the Doctor.
Pressing send.
(GLASSES CHIME)
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
I'm doing it, I'm doing it.
The essay, I'm doing it.
-Are you on a date?
-No.
-Are you sure?
-I think I'd kind of notice.
What about Penny?
Do you know a girl called Penny?
-Well, yeah.
-What's she like?
Out of my league.
-No.
-Sorry, what?
-No?
-No.
What does that mean, "no"?
It means I'm a scary
handsome genius from space
and I'm telling you, no,
she's not out of your league.
Okay, well,
maybe I'll call her tomorrow.
-Call her tonight.
-Tonight?
Something's coming, Bill.
Something very big.
And something possibly very, very bad.
And I have the feeling
that we're gonna be fairly busy.
Call her tonight.
Listen.
If it comes down to it,
if you're all I've got left,
then I need your help.
You said you were my friend.
Oi! Get off!
I've just been executed.
Show a little respect.
She's... She's alive.
I was just a bit sleepy, all right?
Let's not split hairs. Shut up.
Night-night.
DOCTOR: Of course she's not dead.
She's a friend of mine. I may have
fiddled with your wiring a little bit.
You swore an oath.
I swore an oath I'd look after
her body for a thousand years.
Nobody mentioned dead.
You cannot do this.
You will not leave this planet alive.
Do me a favour,
the fatality index,
look up "The Doctor”.
You have an entry
just like any other sentient being.
Under "cause of death".
(BEEPING)
(DEVICE TICKING)
You do seem to have, uh,
an impressive record
of fatalities credited to you.
(CHUCKLES)
(DEVICE TICKING RAPIDLY)
A truly remarkable record.
Where are you going?
He's unarmed.
-You are unarmed.
-Always.
(DEVICE TICKING RAPIDLY)
You stand alone?
Often.
You're the one who should be afraid.
Never.
Have a nice day then.
Nardole, help me move Missy
to the vault.
DOCTOR: Something's coming, Missy,
and I'm blind.
How can I save them
when I'm lost in the dark?
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Tell me what you see.
BILL: It's a 5,000-year-old pyramid.
One little problem,
it wasn't there yesterday.
DOCTOR: Those creatures in
that pyramid, they have studied you.
And they have chosen this exact moment
and this exact place.
What's wrong with the Doctor?
DOCTOR: I lied. I've been blind
since Chasm Forge.
Co-ordinate your attacks.
It did not come here in peace.
MONK: We will take this planet
and its people.
Life on Earth will cease
by humanity's own hand.