(CLARA BREATHING HEAVILY)
CLARA: Doctor! Doctor!
DOCTOR: Yes, you're
the very next thing on the list.
Doctor, help me!
Clara, I'm under attack
from four and a bit
battle fleets,
in case you think I'm slacking.
Doctor, I think there's
something in my spacesuit.
That's... That's possible, actually.
You were too long in the spider mines.
CLARA: Okay, explain.
DOCTOR: It's possibly a love sprite.
Sucks your... Sucks your brain out
through your mouth, hence the name.
-It's halfway up my leg.
-Don"t worry, it's just hungry.
CLARA: Doctor...
DOCTOR: Describe the four
most interesting stars you can see.
There's a blue one. Quite big.
Two little yellowish ones just below.
Colour of whisky, smaller one blinking?
Yes. It's in the back of my neck.
I can feel it.
Great!
So asphyxiation would kill you first.
Can you see a nebula?
Can you see a nebula
in a sort of wing-shape,
-bit green at the end?
-(EXPLOSIONS)
-Yes. Yes, I can.
-Great.
I've seen it, too.
I wonder where it was.
Doctor.
(SCREAMING) Doctor!
(GRUNTING)
(CLARA COUGHING)
(SQUELCHES)
(EXCLAIMS)
(COUGHING)
(EXHALES)
How did we do?
Oh! Not a word about
my spot-on materialization skills.
What about all the Philosians?
Are they safe?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
Well, I lured their attackers
halfway across the universe
and drained their weapons banks.
Not to mention,
I also saved a school teacher
from having her brains devoured
and being asphyxiated in deep space.
So now, if you don't mind,
I'm gonna go outside
and wipe my boot on the grass.
(DOOR OPENS)
What's to stop them rearming
and trying again?
Nothing.
But the Philosians will be
ready for them this time.
It's the best I could do, Clara.
I'm not actually the police.
That's just what it says on the box.
You are always talking about
what you can and can't do,
but you never tell me the rules.
We're time travellers.
We tread softly.
It's okay to make ripples
but not tidal waves.
You are a tidal wave.
Don't say that.
(SWORDS WHOOSHING)
CLARA: Doctor.
No, no, not Vikings.
-(SWORDS WHOOSHING)
-I'm not in the mood for Vikings.
-You're coming with us.
-DOCTOR: No.
I'm not. And you want to know why?
(VIKINGS GROWLING)
On my face, right now,
more advanced technology
than your species will manage
over the next nine million years.
-Clara.
-Yeah.
We're going with the Vikings.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(HORN BLOWING)
(CHEERING)
ASHILDR: You're back. All of you.
Are all of you back?
I'm told so. I haven't counted.
-I'm back.
-(LAUGHS)
I had a dream you'd all died.
It was so real
I thought I made it happen.
Well, if ever does, I'm sure you'll find
some way to blame yourself.
I wish none of you had to go.
CLARA: Plan, Doctor? Any time soon.
-I do have a plan.
-Yeah, that's what you keep saying.
For two days on a longboat.
Well, only because
you were looking worried.
Well, only because you kept saying,
"I do have a plan.”
-I do have a plan.
-There you go.
(INHALES)
You all right? Do you know her?
Never seen her before in my life.
Okay, so why are you staring?
I don't know. Nothing, probably.
Too much time travel. It happens.
What happens?
People talk about premonition
as if it's something strange.
It's not.
It's just remembering
in the wrong direction.
DOCTOR: Okay, plan.
We meet the boss-man
and we do the usual.
-Which is?
-Replace him.
-Father.
-CLARA: That one.
To the primitive mind,
advanced technology can seem like magic.
It's gonna be the yo-yo again, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's in my pocket somewhere.
VIKING: We have travelled far.
We have fought...
How did you do that?
Magic.
...many miracles and much treasure.
-(ALL EXCLAIMING)
-How dare you insult our chief?
I am very, very cross with you.
I am very disappointed!
I have taken human form
to walk among you.
Who are you, old man?
Do you not recognise the sign of Odin?
VIKING: You are not Odin.
And that is not Odin's sign.
Oh, and you would know that how exactly?
Have you met Odin?
Do you know what Odin looks like?
(THUNDERCLAP)
ODIN: Oh, my people.
I am Odin.
And now, your day of reward
has finally dawned.
Do not believe this foolish trickery.
It's supposed to do that.
Your mightiest warriors
will feast with me tonight
in the halls of Valhalla.
Stay still.
Stay very, very, still.
CLARA: That's not really Odin, is it?
He doesn't even know yo-yo.
(VIKINGS SCREAMING)
CLARA: So, this is an invasion?
No, this is a harvest.
The strongest, the fittest...
The weak and the young
they leave behind.
(GRUNTS)
-We have to help them.
-We have to not get chosen.
Clara. Clara!
Have you still got the eye-patch thing?
(WHISPERS) Clara...
(WHISPERING) Point it at my chains
and think the word "Open."”
Say it with your mind.
DOCTOR: Clara!
Clara!
(CHAINS CLINKING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
MAN: Welcome to Valhalla, my ladies.
(VIKING GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
No, wait. Wait!
There's nothing to fear, strange men.
We are Odin's chosen.
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(METAL RATTLING)
The wall! It moves!
(MEN SCREAMING INDISTINCTLY)
Odin. Odin!
Use your blades. Try to jam it.
Come on.
Quick. Pull!
I'm trying!
Quickly!
(WHOOSHING)
VIKING 1: They took half the village.
VIKING 2: Yeah.
VIKING 2: And it was the good half.
They went willingly to Valhalla.
Thus would we all.
I wouldn't.
Well, I wouldn't.
I'm not good with heights.
Oh, stop it.
All of you stop it right now.
Homo sapiens, you are
an intelligent species.
Stop lying to yourselves.
Choose your words carefully, false Odin.
Yes, I am a false Odin.
That's exactly right. I lied.
The big fella in the sky, he lied, too.
You all know it.
Because what's the one thing
the gods never do?
Gods never actually show up.
Guess what?
You got raided.
Guess what else?
I lost someone who matters to me.
So did 1.
Why are we still alive?
ODIN: Because of this.
Explain.
CLARA: I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to make you afraid.
I have no reason to fear you.
Except you've already analyzed that.
And you know it's a technology
from a civilisation
vastly more powerful than your own.
And you will have
also noticed that, um...
I'm wearing a spacesuit.
So I'm not from around here.
And it's highly unlikely
that I will have come alone.
You see, you haven't killed us
because killing us would start a fight
you didn't come here to have.
And you're not sure you could win.
Ooh! Hello.
Time for your medication?
Adrenaline testosterone.
Extracted from the finest warriors.
(GULPING)
(EXHALES)
Nectar!
Okay, you must have Vikings
to make warrior juice.
-Nice.
-They what?
CLARA: Why play God?
What is a God
but the cattle's name for farmer?
What is heaven
but the gilded door of the abattoir?
You're not a farmer.
You're a thief caught in the act.
I don't understand. Mashed up?
-What are you saying?
-Hush.
Go. Now.
Go find Vikings on other planets.
The universe is full of testosterone.
Trust me, it's unbearable.
We won't follow you. See?
We don't need to fight.
War is our way.
Ask yourself,
is this a war you really want?
ASHILDR: Yes!
You'll pay for what
you have done here today.
I am a Viking. Ashildr.
Daughter of Ionhar.
You have mocked our Gods,
killed our warriors.
And we'll crush you
on the field of battle.
-That's better.
-You were about to leave.
You almost had me talking.
Talk is for cowards.
-No, no, no. Listen to me.
-I accept your challenge.
-We will crush you.
-Oh, please. Shut up.
Shall we say, this time tomorrow?
Ten of my warriors
versus the best of your village.
-You will beg for mercy.
-(LAUGHS)
I will send you back.
You can inform your people
of their impending destruction.
-CLARA: Why are you doing this?
-Why else?
The joy of war.
Can't you see it on my face?
(BEEPS)
(GRUNTS)
-Clara.
-My child.
Clara! Clara!
I'm not a hugger.
-Ah. This is...
-Oh! No.
Where are the others?
I'm sorry, Father.
I looked them up
at my 2,000 year diary.
-They are called the Mire.
-Okay, Listen.
They are one of the deadliest
warrior races in the entire galaxy.
-Okay.
-But they are practical.
They get what they want
and then they go.
You persuaded them to go, didn't you?
I knew that you would.
The deadliest warrior race
in the galaxy?
One of them. Yes, why?
Because I think this village
just declared war on them.
They're coming here tomorrow,
10 of them,
to kill everybody in the village.
Ashildr, is this true?
It's my fault.
Not every misfortune that befalls
this village is down to you.
She thinks she brings us bad luck.
What bad luck?
You haven't had any bad luck.
You're fine.
-We're about to be attacked by...
-DOCTOR: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
With a whole day to spare.
So, leave.
Hop it. Take off.
Into the woods, split up, hide.
Hang about there for a week,
come back home.
Make puddings and babies.
That's basically what you do, isn't it?
We cannot leave this village.
Yes, you can.
Just pick a direction.
Fly like a bird, run like a nose.
It's probably a Vikings' saying,
I haven't checked that.
No. We will fight.
(VIKINGS AGREEING)
DOCTOR: Really?
Well, I don't know if you remember,
but they actually took away
all your fighters.
So, uh, what are you?
Farmers, fishermen,
web designers. Maybe not that last one.
(WEAPONS CLANKING)
We are Vikings!
(ALL CHEERING)
Okay. (CLAPS)
Tell me this.
How many people here
have actually held a sword in battle?
By show of hands.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, baby.
The Mire are coming
for each and every one of you.
-(SWORD CLANKING)
-So, what're you gonna do?
Raise crops at them?
If necessary.
I think he was being sarcastic.
We're not cowards. We do not run.
And a death in battle
is a death with honour.
ALL: Aye.
(BABY CRYING)
DOCTOR: Do babies die with honour?
I am afraid, Mother.
Hold me, Mother.
I'm afraid.
Um, he speaks baby.
DOCTOR: Turn your face
towards me, Mother, for you're...
(SCOFFS)
You're beautiful...
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
And I will sing for you.
I'm afraid,
but I will sing.
Babies think that laughter is singing,
did you know that?
I applaud your courage,
but I deplore your stupidity.
And I will mourn your deaths,
which will be terrifying,
painful and without honour.
Stay.
You could help us. I know you could.
I told you to run.
That's all the help you need.
That's all the help you're getting.
The Earth is safe,
humanity is not in danger.
It's just one village.
Just one village?
Suppose I saved it, by some miracle,
no TARDIS, no sonic...
Just one village defeats the Mire.
What then?
Word gets around,
Earth becomes a target
of strategic value
and the Mire come back.
And God knows what else.
Ripples into tidal waves,
until everybody dies.
(BABY CRYING)
-What's it saying?
-She.
She's afraid.
Babies sense danger. They have to.
Tell me.
Mother, I hear thunder.
Mother, I hear shouting.
You're my world,
but I hear other worlds now.
Beyond the unfolding of your smile...
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
...is that other kindness.
I'm afraid. Will they be kind?
The sky is crying now,
fire in the water,
fire in the water.
You just decided to stay.
(CRYING STOPS)
The baby stopped crying.
So, when I say "Move," you move.
When I say, "Jump,” you say, "How high?”
Unless, of course,
there's a gap of some kind
which, of course, means
you jump horizontally.
Yes, what is it, Lofty?
Sir, my name's not actually "Lofty."
It's Br...
No, it's not. It's Lofty.
I've got too much to think about
without everybody
having their own names.
So, it's Lofty.
You're Lofty, you're Daphne.
You're Noggin the Nog.
Z7Z Top.
And you're, uh...
Heidi.
So, we'll try that again.
Lofty?
-What is it?
-Sorry, sir. It's just...
Why aren't we practising
with real swords?
Yes, perhaps, you'd like
to field this one, Limpy.
Because we can't be trusted with them.
That's right. Yes.
You'll be given your real swords back
when you can prove
that you can wave them around
without lopping bits off yourself.
Heidi!
Why are your eyes closed?
Sorry, sir, just not that good
with the sight of blood.
No, of course you're not.
Swords against those creatures...
That won't work, will it?
He's just warming up.
He hasn't got a plan, yet,
but he will have.
And it'll be spectacular.
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
Enough theory.
I'm handing out the real swords.
(LAUGHS)
-(HORN BLOWING)
-(PEOPLE BUSTLING)
That could have gone better.
(EXCLAIMS)
Morning.
What happened?
The big bang?
Dinosaurs, bipeds,
a mounting sense of futility.
More recently,
Chuckles hit Lofty over the head,
on his helmet with a sword,
which knocked him out,
there was a little blood,
which you saw, and did that.
Only the first time, you did it,
you knocked a torch into some hay,
which spooked a horse
who kicked open the gate, and I'm sure
that you can fill in the rest.
(THUNDERCLAP)
Weird sounding thunder.
That's not thunder.
It's the weapon forges of the Mire,
making sure we hear them.
-Well?
-Well...
Heidi faints at the mention of blood,
not just the sight any more.
He's actually upgraded his phobia.
Chuckles...
He questions every single order
you give him,
which is gonna be a little...
A little bit difficult,
a little bit tricky
in the heat of battle.
I keep waiting to hear
what your real plan is.
Teaching them to fight,
that's the only plan I've got.
Turning them into fighters?
That's not like you.
-Yeah, I used to believe that, too.
-(LAUGHS)
-What happened?
-You.
Oh, Clara Oswald.
What have I made of you?
It doesn't matter
how well you train them,
it's not gonna make a difference.
They'll die fighting, with honour.
To a Viking,
that's all the difference in the world.
A good death?
Is that the best they can hope for?
A good death is the best
anyone can hope for,
unless you happen to be immortal.
-Sorry.
-CLARA: No problem.
DOCTOR: Good night.
CLARA: You've made an impact there.
-Stop it.
-What, she's nice.
-I'll fight you for her.
-The human race.
You're obsessed.
-You all need to get a hobby.
-I've got a hobby. Thanks.
It's you, by the way.
Well, get a new one.
-Not this.
-Tomorrow it's gonna be a bloodbath.
Don't even ask.
These people all died hundreds of years
before you were even born.
-I'm not running.
-I have a duty of care.
No, you don't
because I've never asked for that.
Every time we do something like this,
I keep thinking,
"What if something happens to you?”
Well, stop thinking about me.
And start thinking about them,
because you're missing something.
-What?
-How're you gonna win?
You always miss it,
right up until the last minute.
So, put down your sword,
stop playing soldier, and
look for it.
Start winning, Doctor.
It's what you're good at.
ASHILDR: So,
we meet again, fake Odin.
Valhalla burns around you.
Your army is destroyed.
-And now, it is time for you to die!
-(CLEARS THROAT)
-How long have you been there?
-Is that for a puppet?
Oh, I love puppets.
I make puppets sometimes when I'm...
Frightened.
When the raiding parties go out,
I make up stories about their battles.
Because if you make up the right story,
you think it will keep them safe
and they'll all come home.
That's okay.
You're not the first person
to ever have done that.
-Why are you here?
-I'm looking for something I'm missing.
What do you think
our chances are tomorrow?
We'll be cut down like corn.
By this time tomorrow,
every single one of us will be dead.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
-You could go.
-There's nowhere for me except here.
This is my place.
The sky, the hills, the sea,
the people...
Is there nowhere like that for you?
Oh, I like a nice view
as much as anyone.
-But...
-Can't wait for the next one.
I pity you.
I will mourn for you.
I know which I'd prefer.
You think they are all idiots,
don't you?
What, you mean,
the rest of the universe?
Um, basically, yes, I do.
But they're kind and brave and strong.
-And I love them.
-Good.
Good, but that won't save you.
I've always been different.
All my life, I've known that.
The girls all thought I was a boy.
The boys all said I was just a girl.
My head is always full of stories.
I know I'm strange.
Everyone knows I'm strange.
But here, I'm loved.
You tell me to run to save my life.
I tell you that leaving this place
would be death itself.
I cannot keep you safe.
I do not have the strength.
But I will try to
till the last beat of my heart.
(BABY CRYING)
If you seek to mock me in this moment...
No. No.
No, you go ahead.
You cry all you like.
Speaking of cry, is that...
Is that baby getting closer?
(BABY CRYING)
Why is Lofty stealing the baby?
That's his child.
Oh.
-Where is he taking her?
-ASHILDR: The boathouse.
He takes her to the boathouse
when she won't settle.
She likes the fish.
Why would she?
Fire in the water.
Fire in the water. Fire...
Fire in... Fire in the water.
Fire in the water! That's it!
That's it. That's it.
That's what I've been missing.
Clara, I found it!
Clara! Clara!
(BABY CRYING)
Lofty! Oh!
I had no idea that that was your baby.
Hello, baby.
I had no idea this was
your junior parent.
I'm trying to settle her.
She likes all the fish.
Okay, you're shouting. What's happened?
You trapped your finger
in something again?
Chuckles, bedtime is cancelled.
Everybody off the hard stuff.
We have a long night's work ahead of us.
I'm gonna need a blacksmith.
Who's the blacksmith?
I'm the blacksmith.
What? Are you the blacksmith?
And you got a baby, too.
-He's been at it hammer and tongs.
-Doctor, explain. What's happening?
There's gonna be a war tomorrow.
And here's some news, this just in.
We're gonna win the hell out of it.
-How?
-Ashildr, this is your village,
and you will never have to leave it.
I swear.
Seriously, how?
I told you
that we were basically doomed.
Did no one in this two-horn town
think to mention that you had eels?
-Eels?
-I give you fire in the water.
Electric eels.
Yes. Yes.
I know exactly how you feel.
Well, not exactly.
She needs changing.
-Plan, then?
-And it is a doozy.
We need to pull that silvery stuff
out of Clara's spacesuit.
We can use it
to magnify the electrical charge.
And stop looking confused, look happy!
Winning is all about
looking happier than the other guy.
Always walk briskly,
it makes you a moving target.
Uh... Oh, that's for Lofty! Lofty!
And talk with confidence.
Even if you are terrified.
Act as if you know their plan,
and sometimes,
if you are very lucky,
they'll actually tell you it.
Ah. This is for Ashildr.
Then, we deploy the anvil.
Now, at this stage,
getting one of their helmets is key.
We get a helmet
and this is over.
Then we can mop up the rest
using Ashildr's monstrosity.
That is rubbish.
I know.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(VIKINGS CHEERING)
Hey! Hello, hey.
I'm the Doctor. It's lovely to meet you
to face to, uh... Convincing hologram.
You could always go...
(IMITATES BUZZING) ...and get rid of it.
No? No, on second thoughts, don't.
That, that... That suits you.
It is time to fight.
DOCTOR: No, no, no.
We decided against that.
We thought we'd just have a party!
(ALL CHEERING)
ODIN: Let me put it another way.
You fight or you die.
We are unarmed.
There isn't a single weapon
in this room,
which I'm sure
your systems are telling you that.
You wouldn't open fire
on unarmed civilians, would you?
It wouldn't be the first time.
(METAL CLINKING)
Chuckles, now!
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(SCREAMING)
Chuckles, switch!
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
-Chuckles, off!
-Oh!
Don't move!
Go!
CLARA: How's it going?
Reversing the polarity
of the neutron flow.
I bet that means something.
It sounds great.
Ashildr!
-Are you ready?
-I'm scared.
You were born for this.
(INHALES)
Show them a story
they will never forget.
(LASERS FIRING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(ROARS)
(GRUNTING)
What is this beast?
(LASER GUN FIRING)
It's impossible!
MIRE: Withdraw! Withdraw!
Stand and fight!
(ROARING)
Withdraw!
DOCTOR: See how they run!
Cowards!
Withdraw!
That enough, Ashildr, story's over.
Happy ending.
(ROARING)
(TRUMPET BLARING)
(LAUGHING)
(FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
-What trickery is this?
-DOCTOR: Ha!
Says the man with a fake face!
Well, you see, that's the trouble
with viewing reality through technology.
It's all too easy
to feed in a new reality.
Have you got it? Great.
A story to save a town.
And a puppet from a nightmare.
You see, you've just seen the world
through the eyes of a storyteller.
The mighty armies of the Mire,
brutal, sadistic, undefeated.
Even I believed the stories.
But after today, no one will again.
An army like yours, it lives or dies
on its reputation, its story.
And today, you were sent packing
by a handful of farmers and fishermen.
-(LAUGHING)
-Not to mention the whole,
wetting your pants and running away
from a puppet debacle...
(LAUGHING) See,
that was really funny.
That was hilarious.
It's just lucky
that nobody recorded that.
-Wait a minute, we did.
-(RECORDER BEEPS)
Cowards/!
You see, all it needed
was the Benny Hilltheme.
-The Benny Hilltheme, yes.
-(LAUGHS)
Now you see, we could just keep this
as a funny little film,
and play it every year
at the Christmas party or,
I could upload it to the galactic hub
and get a second opinion.
So the question you need
to ask yourself is this.
Just how important is
your reputation to you?
Here's a little sneak preview,
piped straight into your helmets,
free of charge.
(RECORDER BEEPS)
-(BENNY HILL THEME PLAYING)
-Ah, wait.
-Cowards...
-(LASERS FIRING)
-DOCTOR: If you don't leave right now...
-(RECORDER BEEPS)
...I'll put it out there for all to see
and no one will fear you again.
This humiliation will not go unpunished.
We will meet again.
Oh, I hacked your teleporter, sorry.
(VIKINGS CHEERING)
(LAUGHS)
You did it, Ashildr.
You did it.
You saved us all!
Ashildr?
Get the helmet off her. Get it off now.
(GRUNTING)
Ashildr...
No pulse.
I think...
Doctor, is she dead?
(ALL GASPING)
I'm sorry.
(WHIMPERING)
I'm really, terribly sorry.
-Heart failure, yeah?
-Yeah.
I plugged her into the machine.
Used her up like a battery.
(SIGHS)
I'm so sick of losing.
You didn't lose.
You saved the town.
I don't mean the war.
I'll lose any war you like.
I'm sick of losing people.
Look at you with your eyes,
you're never giving up to anger,
and your kindness.
One day, the memory
of that will hurt so much
that I won't be able to breathe,
and I will do what I always do,
I'll get in my box
and I'll run and I'lW run...
In case all the pain ever catches up,
and every place I go, it will be there.
You did your best.
She died. There's nothing you can do.
I can do anything.
There's nothing I can't do.
Nothing.
But I'm not supposed to.
Ripples, tidal waves, rules.
I'm not supposed to.
Oh.
(EXCLAIMS)
What? What's wrong?
My face...
Who frowned me this face?
Why this one? Why did I choose...
This face?
CLARA: Doctor?
What's wrong with your face?
I think I know why I chose it.
It's like I'm trying
to tell myself something.
I think I know what I'm trying to say.
Just someone,
not the whole town.
Just save someone.
Come with me...
I know where I got this face
and I know what it is for.
Okay, what's it for?
To remind me,
to hold me to the mark.
I'm the Doctor, and I save people.
And if anyone happens to be listening,
anyone have a kind of
a problem with that,
to hell with you!
(GRUNTS)
What's he doing?
Saving her, I think.
(WHOOSHING)
It's from the Mire helmet,
battlefield medical kit.
I've reprogrammed it for human beings.
It's gone. It's inside her.
It's repairing her.
It won't ever stop repairing her,
if it works.
Come on, Ashildr.
Come on. The story's not over yet.
Daughter...
(SNIFFLES) Listen to me.
This town has lost so much.
If we lose you, too,
there'll be nothing left.
(GASPS)
-(WHEEZING)
-Ashildr.
She'll be conscious in a day.
Up and about in three.
No swimming for a week.
Now, we going to need a long boat
and some of your best rowers.
We're two days sail from the TARDIS.
Come on, Clara!
No, wait, no.
She'll want to see you when she wakes.
Oh, no. Well, she'll see me
often enough once she understands.
Understands what?
Second dose.
-When she needs to take this?
-No, no, no.
It's not for her.
-Then who is it for?
-Ah, whoever she wants.
ASHILDR: Doctor...
-Thank you.
-DOCTOR: Ah...
Don't thank me yet, Ashildr.
Not yet.
CLARA: Okay, it's official.
Silence is even worse
in a Scottish accent.
Are you going to tell me
what you are brooding about?
It won't stop.
The repair kit I put inside of Ashildr,
long ago...
-It will just keep fixing her.
-Well, good.
I'm not sure,
but it is entirely possible
she has lost the ability to die.
-The ability?
-Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Dying is an ability, believe me.
Barring accidents, she may
now be functionally immortal.
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
If the repair kit
never stops working, then...
Why did you give her two?
Immortality isn't living forever,
that's not what it feels like.
Immortality is everybody else dying.
She might meet someone
she can't bear to lose.
That happens.
I believe.
-(MACHINE INITIALISING)
-I was angry.
I was emotional.
Just possibly,
I've made a terrible mistake.
Maybe even a tidal wave.
Time will tell, it always does.
CLARA: Whatever you did for Ashildr,
I think she deserved it.
Yes. Yes, she did.
But Ashildr isn't just human any more,
there's a little piece of alien
inside her.
So in a way, she's...
In a way...
She is a hybrid.
-(HORSE NEIGHING)
-Whoa!
-KNIGHTMARE: Stand and deliver.
-(SCREAMING)
If I didn't know better,
I'd say this was a robbery.
The most wanted in the land.
Now is not time to be showing off.
GIRL: Could it be we are looking
for the same prize?
The eyes of Hades.
Who is this? Your sidekick?
I'm not a sidekick.
GIRL: Come on, sidekick watch me run.
MR FANSHAWE:
There is an intruder on the premises!
-What're you doing?
-It's kill or be killed.
DOCTOR: You're playing with fire!
Do you have a cat?