New Year's?
Every year, every New Year's
Eve, Jeff, you promise me
that you'll work,
and then you play me for
the fool that I clearly am.
And then just at the last
minute, when you know,
you know I have plans,
you leave me high and dry on
my own on New Year's Eve,
working in a business
that you know I hate.
But not as much
as I hate you, Jeff.
And I do hate you.
I wish I'd never employed you.
Er, so, yeah, can you call
me back when you get
a chance? Thank you. Oh.
- Oh.
Stop it. Go away.
Oh, erm, hiya, Nick.
Er, happy Nearly New Year,
Sarah.
- Here we are again.
- Yeah, yeah.
Here we are again.
- No Jeff?
- Er, no.
- Er, astonishingly no.
No Jeff.
It's become a little bit of
a tradition now. Oh. My God!
- Sorry, are you busy
on your phone?
- Oh, sorry, no.
Just, er, my phone's broken,
the button, and I can't
put it on silent.
Obviously, everyone's
sending me
messages and texts
and pictures from their night
and, unsurprisingly, I don't
really want to see them.
Much better being here.
You know, instead of
all of those parties...
- ...and people, and drinks.
Yeah. I mean, it's not,
though, is it?
I'm not really one
for New Year's.
Yeah. No, I know that. Yes.
So you want
to access your unit?
Yes.
Yeah. So...
Can you remind me of
the list of things
that can't be stored?
Yes.
Stolen or illegal goods,
tyres, animals, humans,
dead or alive in any cases,
cash, plant, food, cars,
guns or ammunition,
or any material that is
in any way toxic, hazardous
or radioactive, and a shop.
Promise you I don't have
a shop.
Very good. Here's your keys.
And when you say hazardous--
When I say hazardous?
Well, I suppose
I'd ask myself,
"If I set fire to this item,
"will it have potentially
explosive or, er,
devastating consequences?"
So this...
...would be OK?
- Well, that's a board game.
- Yes.
Is it a toxic, hazardous,
or radioactive board game?
- There's loads of paper
in there.
- Here's your keys.
I hear loads of storage places
have access codes now.
Yes, Nick, they do.
And they also have the money
to upgrade their systems.
Whereas I have no money,
just a dilapidated building,
my rival straight across
the road, and you as
my only customer.
As valued a customer
as you are, Nick.
Platinum loyalty card member,
that's me.
I'll be off to my unit.
Yeah.
Won't be long.
See you next year.
Er, have you been
practising that?
Yes.
Ready?
- Ready.
When I set this going,
the TARDIS will go
into self-reset,
which should, if I've got this
right, which I'm sure I have,
clear out all the Flux debris,
minimise the number of doors,
and be back
to fully functioning.
But it will be out of service
for a little bit.
How long is a little bit?
I'm not sure.
But that's why we're landing
on the sentient beaches
of San Munrovar.
We'll be playing chess with
the fish, drinking mocktails
with the lobsters.
Once I throw the last lever,
we'll have seven seconds
to get out.
We don't want to be in here
when it's resetting
because, well...
we'd die.
Here we go.
Go! Go, go, go, go!
Where's the beach?
- That's supposed to be
like that, is it?
- Not sure.
Never had to do this before.
Are you sure we're
in San Munrovar?
Er...
No.
Cos it doesn't look
very beachy to me.
Ah. Manchester.
- Of all places!
- What?
Sorry.
New Year's Eve 2021.
Nine minutes to midnight.
TARDIS will be sorted soon.
Come on, there'll be
a party on somewhere.
Temporal disturbance.
Two floors above.
Because of the TARDIS?
Don't think so.
Cloaked signal.
Should check. Come on.
Mancs. New Year Mancs.
Doesn't she understand?
Sarah?
Identify.
I'm Nick.
Mammy, it's four minutes
to midnight.
Every year.
Why are you calling me now?
The lines will all be busy
at midnight.
No, they won't,
because it's not 1973.
Are you still at work?
New Year's Eve is
the best time to meet a man.
- I'm not trying to meet...
- I met your father
- on New Year's Eve.
- You did not.
January 9th, same thing.
Literally not the same thing,
Mammy.
Anyways, who says
I even want to meet a man?
And the only reason
I'm working tonight
is because I had
to keep on stupid Jeff
at the stupid place
that I inherited
from your stupid uncle.
Obviously, no offence,
God rest his soul.
Your Uncle Barry was a saint.
Oh.
Listen, Mam, I have to go.
I've got a customer.
So, yeah, just call me
at the bongs, will you?
The lines will all be busy.
No, they won't.
I don't like calling
on the bo--
Oh, just go away
with your stupid having fun.
Stupid party, stupid drinking,
stupid everyone pairing up,
just die, everyone.
Oh, no.
Dalek. Multiple weapon blasts.
Was that the time disruption?
What's a Dalek?
Deadliest killing machine
in the universe.
You all done, Nick?
I am not Nick.
This area is now under
Dalek control.
What's going on?
Exterminate!
Dalek!
You'll answer for that.
DALEK:
Daleks answer to no-one.
Daleks answer to me. Why are
you killing these people?
Shouldn't we just go?
I'm using my sonic
to jam its weapon systems.
Sonic device
will not override my weapons.
Yes, it does.
Cos I've used it before.
Correct.
Daleks learn.
Exterminate!
Not like this.
- But that's a board game.
- Yes.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Are you OK?
Not sure.
- I feel like
I've just had this...
- Here are your keys anyway.
- Most places have...
- Access codes,
yes, I know.
No need to go on about it.
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm just a bit spaced out.
Been working too hard.
I'll go to my unit.
Yes, you will.
You will.
- Oh, my God.
See you next year.
Oh. Have you been
practising that?
Where's the beach?
Whoa.
Anyone else got
a proper déjà vu?
Yeah.
Didn't we just get
exterminated?
Lad by the storage unit.
Wait. Did I--
Exterminate!
Sarah.
No. No, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What the...
Oh, God!
I'm gonna need
a weapon. A weapon.
Jeff.
He's not here.
He should be here.
We've gone back in time.
Dalek incoming.
Two people in this building
about to die
unless we stop it.
So why isn't he here?
Sarah.
Look. All right.
Fifth floor. I've got to go.
Do not move.
You're real.
Correct.
Exterminate!
Jeff. "Temporary storage,
you said it was OK."
Honestly, I said one unit.
Honestly, give that man an
inch and he takes a corridor.
What?
No animals, alive or dead.
Oh, my God. Holiday goods!
They're probably stolen.
Oh. Jeff! Food?
Ugh! Gross.
I just need something I can
use as a weapon.
Mam, now is really not
a good moment.
The lines
will all be busy at midnight.
No, they won't, Mammy.
- Are you still at work?
New Year's Eve
is the best time
to meet a man.
Mam, I'm gonna have to call
you back at the bongs, OK?
Look. No.
Just no. OK?
Cos this is my premises,
and you, sir,
are trespassing. OK?
So just...
just... just shoo.
- Just go. Just... just...
just get.
Increased
fear levels detected.
I mean, well, obviously.
And how did you even find me?
I changed at what I did.
I anticipated
your change.
Please, please don't kill me.
Exterminate!
No!
Second time I've failed
to save him.
Second time the Dalek's
been cleverer than us.
Doctor, look.
It got both of them.
It's ahead of us.
Way ahead of us.
Correct, Doctor.
Dalek strategy is supreme.
Says you.
So there's no point
making a run for it?
The entrance has been
secured. There is no escape.
If it's any consolation,
we'd have been shot
before we got there anyway.
So we're dead.
Second time round.
The inferior human
- is correct.
- Oi! Who are you
calling inferior?
You. Assessment has been made.
Pretty smart, Daleks.
We've been here before.
But time reset.
So we're still alive.
You failed.
My mission
was completed.
There was
a disruption with time.
This moment is the correction.
There is no escape.
Exterminate!
What?
Oh, no, you don't.
- Time loop.
Groundhog Day.
Same difference.
Gotta go get that lad.
Ooh. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Oh, my God, Nick,
we have to get out of here.
- That's what I was coming
to say to you.
- What?
No, no, no. We're stuck in a
time loop with killer robots.
OK. Yeah, that makes sense.
Does it? Cos I actually
thought I was losing my mind.
No. Because I've been killed
twice by a robot.
Oh, my God, me too.
Which is crazy, because
I'm still alive, right?
But I was coming back to
save you on the second time.
- You did what?
- But you weren't there.
Guess that's because you were
coming up to save me, right?
Yeah. Yeah. That was it. We
must have missed each other.
Who are they?
Hi, I'm the Doctor.
This is Yaz and Dan.
How'd you get in here?
Wait. Are you from
building control?
Are you from the council?
Yes. We're here
to control your building.
And three of you, on New
Year's Eve? You make me sick.
Building control never sleeps.
We're the rapid response unit.
And we really need to get you
to safety. Like, right now.
Wait, have you got something
to do with that robot?
No. And it's a Dalek.
Oh, my God, you know its name.
Are you-- Is it your robot?
Cos, you know, we've died,
like, two times so far.
We have died, OK?
And I know that sounds mad
cos obviously I'm alive,
saying it, but still--
At any point you can just
jump in and say something now.
I'm trying to work out which
one is most unlikely.
Time loop with robots,
or three people from the
council working on New Year's.
We're here to help, we're also
stuck in the time loop.
The robot isn't a robot,
it's a Dalek.
It's a living mutant creature
inside weaponised
battle transport.
It will kill everything
not within its own image.
And then what does it want
with us? Why is it here?
I don't know. All I know is
we don't know have much...
- ...time.
- Get behind me, Sarah.
- What are you doing?
- I'm being chivalrous.
- You look patronising.
- OK.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Everybody, into my
storage unit. Over here!
- Where's the exit?
- What do you mean?
Where's the way out?
No. The other way out.
So we can escape.
There isn't another way out.
- What?
- It's a storage unit.
Not a great plan,
was it?
- But we're not dead.
- From now on,
I'm in charge of the plans.
And there's always
another way out.
Somehow.
You just have to find it.
Surrender!
There is no escape!
Daleks are patient.
- I will wait.
- Show me your phone.
- What do you want
with a phone?
- That's what I was
worried about.
- What were you worried about?
Shh, I'm working.
How did you even
get into this building?
If we told you,
you'd never believe us.
Nick, why have you got
all those names
on the shelves?
They're just ex-girlfriends.
They're what?
Oh. This is where I keep stuff
from women I split up with.
You know, just in case
they ever ask for it back.
I don't want it in my eyeline,
you know, at home.
I have a very small flat.
I said it's a flat.
But it's more like
a box room with a door,
and a toilet with, like,
a kitchenette on the top
of the toilet.
You have
a lot of ex-girlfriends.
- They're alive still,
aren't they?
- Of course. Oh, God.
Yeah. No, not all of them
were serious. Some
were just, like, a few days.
Man, you are weird.
- What?
- Bit harsh.
Bit harsh?
He comes here, here,
every New Year's Eve, which
is weird enough in itself.
And do what?
To do all of this.
That is weird.
- He is standing right there.
- It's fine.
No, it's not fine.
It's not fine. You're the
reason that I'm here.
You're the reason that I am
trapped in a time loop
with a... a robot...
- Dalek!
- I'm with
stupidly named robots
and people I don't even know.
All so... what?
Why? So you can
catalogue your Monopoly?
Just throw stuff away!
Erm...
Yeah.
No, no, no, no, no!
No! No, no, no, no, no!
- Get back in here.
- Take me.
You can take me.
But just let them go.
Don't try and reason with it.
- You're right, this is
all my fault.
- What?
You wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for me.
- No.
- So you can let them...
- It's OK. It's OK.
- He did that for us.
- He did it for me.
- It's OK.
- For me. But it's not
his fault.
Oh, my giddy aunt. What the--
Mammy, please,
now is not the time!
But the lines
will all be busy at midnight.
No, they won't! Goodbye!
Let's focus on
what we can do now.
You know I said there's always
another way out?
- Yeah.
- There isn't.
Solid concrete walls,
thick ceilings,
took a long time
to resonate through those.
And nothing of any use in here
unless you want
to play Monopoly.
Our resources in defeating
the Dalek are limited
to non-existent.
Do you have anything we could
use to defeat the Dalek?
It really is a matter
of life and death.
Yeah, I mean,
four floors up.
I mean, there's a mad stash
of stuff four floors up.
But we're on this floor!
This time...
Doctor.
Very persistent, your Dalek.
How do we get out of here?
I don't think we do.
But we get another go.
Except, we'll have less time.
What?
I felt it the second time,
but this time I'm certain.
Time on your phone proved it.
We're coming back
a minute later each time.
Last time, it was
eight minutes to midnight.
This time, seven. I think
the next is gonna be six.
The time loop's shortening
on each reset.
Is that a good or a bad thing?
Not sure. Definitely one
or the other. Depends on
your outlook.
Less time for the Dalek to
find and exterminate us,
equally less time for us to
figure this out and defeat it.
Whatever's causing the
time loop can't sustain it.
It must be under
some sort of pressure.
That's why it's decreasing.
Either way,
the loop repeats,
time repeats, so we need
to be the variation.
We need to be unpredictable
so the Dalek can't guess
what we're gonna do next.
Next time, we don't come
back here. That's what
he'll be expecting.
Go straight to the
fifth floor, see what that
mad stash has to offer.
But what about Nick?
Surrender!
Congratulations.
The most evil creature in the
universe has successfully
vanquished an old door.
Silence.
No chance. You just can't seem
to get rid of us, can you?
We have learned.
We will exterminate all life
here until the closure
of the time loop.
All necessary calibrations
have been made.
The target will be executed.
Targeted execution of who?
You, Doctor.
I was worried
you might say that.
So it is your fault.
You've killed us twice.
Yet we're still alive.
Why do you think
it's gonna work this time?
We are relentless.
Your ultimate extermination
and execution is inevitable.
You are trapped, Doctor.
Not trapped. Never trapped.
You won't win. You never win.
Incorrect! Exterminate!
Lift. Fifth floor.
Do not move!
I am very much
going to move!
Just passed reception.
Patterns indicate
that's where the Dalek's
starting this time.
And the time loop's shortened
by a minute. Every time
one minute less.
This is tricky.
It seems that the time loop
only extends to the radius
of this building.
If we can stay alive
and be outside the building
when midnight hits,
we might stand a chance
of getting clear of this.
Second Dalek signal.
In a different part
of the building.
- That's either an echo or...
- There's two of them.
What are you doing?
I'll keep the one
in reception busy.
You two, try and figure out
how to stop all this.
If I manage to stay alive,
I'll see you up there.
If not, I'll see you in
the next loop. So there'd
better be a next loop.
Dan, you don't have
to do this.
I know.
But you saved
the entire universe last week.
I think I owe you one.
Look after each other.
Oh. You're here. I was
worried you wouldn't be here.
Sorry you got killed,
you know.
But you should not
have done that, though.
Especially not because
of anything
that I may or may not
have said,
or made you feel or whatever.
Erm, anyways, I've got a plan.
We're gonna get out of here.
- What about the others?
- Oh. Literally,
not our problem.
They'll be fine. Honestly.
It's probably their fault
that the robots are here
in the first place, actually.
So, that's what I was
thinking. So, yeah. Come on.
- Wait. But--
- Don't have time to explain.
Identify!
All right, mate?
Are you new here?
DALEK:
I arrived 1.93 rels ago.
Yeah, well, I've, erm, I've
got some stuff I need storing,
and I just wanted
to see what was available.
DALEK:
Daleks do not store stuff.
Well, you're in the wrong
job then, aren't you?
What are you,
some kind of automated staff?
How does this work?
DALEK:
Desist! Do not approach!
I'd get a friendlier voice,
though. This one's
a little bit grating.
What kind of a welcome
is that, eh?
I'll report you
to your manager!
DALEK:
Daleks do not have managers!
Yeah, well, maybe that's
part of your problem!
Artron energy particles
detected!
You are a friend of the
Doctor. Analysis concludes
this is a delaying tactic!
Took you long enough.
Exterminate!
What the hell is that?
And what's all this stuff?
Do you know no-one is paying
for anything on this floor?
If Jeff is sub-letting
this place,
honestly, I'll actually...
This is crazy.
And he knows
I never come down here.
This is unbelievable.
Please don't tell anyone from
the Council about this.
- They're not from the council.
Oh, yeah. Hard to keep track.
Oh, Mammy, please don't
call before midnight.
How many times?
No, the lines won't be busy.
What do you mean?
I haven't spoken to you
since August.
- I know.
- Shh! Sarah, quiet.
I'll call you back!
The robot's over there.
They must be trying
to hunt us down.
The escape's over that way,
through the corridor.
Listen, I erm--
I lied to you earlier on.
I... I didn't come and try to
save you that second time.
Right.
Yeah. I went to find a weapon
on Jeff's, on the fifth floor.
- Right. Guess that's
a valid approach.
- Yeah.
But, like, I'm sure
that had I found a weapon,
and not been killed,
then I absolutely
would have come to save you.
Probably.
Except I would've been dead.
Yeah, admittedly,
that was a flaw.
But that's why-- that's why
I came to save you this time.
Thanks.
I really appreciate you trying
to save me.
You know, not many people
would have done that.
Some close friends
and family included, actually.
We should get going.
Don't want to get killed.
We're never gonna get
that moment on the beach,
where you tell me everything
that happened to you, are we?
- 'Course we will.
Interesting.
Not sure these are
particularly useful resources.
Ew!
Who eats beans and then thinks
these could just do
with being a bit beefy?
Nobody, by the looks
of things. These are
three years out of date.
Huh.
I think Jeff might live here.
Oh, Jeff.
You bad, bad man.
Yaz, this is the sort of stuff
about which you would
ask yourself,
"If I set fire to this,
will it have explosive
"and potentially
devastating consequences?"
And the answer is "Yes."
Surrender, Doctor!
Here it is.
Oh. It's blocking our exit.
Why do you always put
your stuff into storage
just before midnight
on New Year's Eve?
Feels a little over-organised.
That's the time
I know you'll be here.
Jeff always lets you down.
I have
an embarrassing crush on you.
- Oh--
- No. I don't mean
the crush is embarrassing,
I mean
the time.
It's an embarrassing time
to let you know...
now.
And so why are you saying
it to me like this, now?
Cos I'm going to be killed
by aliens in a minute.
Again. I guess.
I'm just--
I'm just worried that
one of these times
I won't make it back.
- How long has this been
going on for?
- Three years.
Oh, my-- What?
Three years?
- That is so stalkery.
- I--
I prefer unrequited. Or shy.
Stalkery would be
if I was menacing you.
Or said anything about this
at all. Which I haven't.
- No.
- And wouldn't.
- If I wasn't going to--
Exterminate!
No!
You're gonna be sorry
for that.
Daleks are never sorry.
Oh, God.
Come on, door, I know
I haven't opened you in years,
but work with me.
Exterminate!
You will
not escape us, Doctor.
DALEK 2:
You will never escape us.
So there are two of you.
Bad news.
Bad news on top of previous
bad news. Not my favourite
New Year's Eve.
Your attempts
to evade us are futile.
Agree to disagree.
Why have you created
a time loop?
We did not create
the time loop.
The time loop was
created by your TARDIS.
We caused it with the reset.
Dalek command
identified the energy pattern
of your TARDIS
and dispatched Daleks
to execute you
for your actions
against the Dalek race.
Which particular actions?
DALEK 1:
Using the Flux to destroy
the Dalek war fleet.
That wasn't my idea.
That was a Sontaran
stratagem that I hijacked.
You are responsible
for the destruction
of millions of Daleks.
Your death is the priority
of the Dalek race.
We will not stop!
- Exterminate!
We made it back. I'm alive!
Alright, don't get cocky.
Reception. Take the stairs!
I mean, a "thanks"
would be nice.
Oh, OK.
Er, where were you?
Well, I can explain.
We had a deal.
Meet on the fifth floor!
Yes, yes. Fair. Fair.
But, erm...
Yeah, OK, so I did desert you.
I did. But to be fair to me,
I was trying to not
get killed, again, so.
And we almost got out.
Well, er, I almost did.
I, I got to the door,
but then it zapped me.
Well, actually, it zapped--
it zapped us.
Oh, my God. Nick.
Oh, God.
I have to go get to him.
No, no, you have to stay here.
There's more than one of them.
I'm not just gonna wait
for him to get killed.
I don't care if he's a weirdo.
And he is.
He is a weirdo, you know, but,
but he's decent.
And he's got a good heart.
My friend Lauren
actually says that
good-hearted weirdos
are actually the keepers, so--
What?
No, nothing.
Oh. No.
We need to stay here
and come up with a plan.
- I can fix this.
- Well, then, why haven't you?
You haven't done a very
good job so far, have you?
Oi. I don't see
you coming up with solutions.
Yeah, cos it's not my fault,
is it? It's hers.
There's no point us all
sticking together
if we keep on dying.
Multiple times.
Including the time
you followed your own plan.
Didn't go well, did it?
Please, you need to trust me.
Do as I ask and stay here.
No, you don't understand.
Nick doesn't survive past
five to.
So, if he doesn't survive
this time,
then there's not gonna be
another five to.
It'll be four minutes to.
And then he'll be dead,
properly.
That's right, isn't it?
Stay here.
Together.
- Do not move!
No, I'm gonna move.
Do not move!
Two of you now.
That's not right.
Daleks are supreme!
OK, come on, then.
You got me again.
Say it.
- Exterminate!
I'm not dead.
I can make it to midnight.
I can make it out!
You think you can kill, Rasta?
Oh. Nick, what happened here?
Don't worry. I dealt with 'em.
I took 'em out. They're not
coming back. You're welcome.
I mean, they will. Cos the
fact that there's two of them
means they've found
a way of keeping
inside the time loop.
So, what did you do?
It was a lot
of strategic analysis,
weapons assessment
and battle-ready thinking.
- Did you duck?
- Yeah.
- Nice.
You saved him.
I saved myself, actually.
Er, yeah. No.
What really happened?
Yeah.
Nick took two of them out.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Two top level ones, as well.
They were the same as
the others. Don't milk it.
If there's two there now,
that could mean there's
more on the way, right?
Knowing Daleks.
Yeah. Listen, we need to be
strategic, and we need
to work together.
The Daleks have learned, and
applied it across the loops.
- We need to do the same.
- Yeah, but if we get rid
of them,
then we can get out.
There's a door downstairs
in the basement,
without that force field-y
thingy on it.
We have to think longer term.
As in four minutes
longer term.
Exactly. We don't get out this
time, but we formulate a plan
which guarantees we make it
out before the loop closes.
How would you feel about
destroying this place?
I mean, I'd have to talk
to my insurance providers.
I don't think you'll be
covered for an act of Dalek.
I mean,
this place is all I have.
But if you don't get out,
you won't have anything.
Who is he? Why is he talking?
Oi, you. No dissing my mate.
That's my job.
- Thanks, Sheffield.
- Shh.
How would the plan work?
Next loop,
we have four minutes.
If we divide,
that's four minutes each
times five, that's 20 minutes.
And we know
there's a stash of toxic
and combustive materials
on the fifth floor.
Ah, the fifth floor's too far
up to lure all the Daleks in,
be sure they're destroyed,
get back down here
and out the rear exit.
Yeah, well, there could be
more of them in
the basement. And Jeff has
all of this stuff down there,
even though I
explicitly said to him not
to have any more stuff
in there. Honestly.
Look, if we're going
to divide up,
some of us could go upstairs
to the fifth floor,
get Jeff's stuff,
bring it down
and then wrap it round
his other stuff downstairs.
But won't the Dalek things
just find us?
I can make the Daleks think
we're somewhere else.
I can use my sonic
to bounce our life signals
off the walls,
sort of sonic ventriloquism.
It's my party trick.
If I can do it long enough
to confuse the Daleks,
we can lure them to wherever
we want them to be.
Ah, but I'm gonna need
an ignition trigger.
- Oh, my God, are you serious?
Two birds, one stone.
Or two Daleks, one phone.
Yeah, no, the other
one's better.
Can you get your mom to call
at exactly ten seconds
to midnight?
- Absolutely not.
She's not doing that.
Not even if her daughter's
life depended on it?
If our lives depend
on my mother
ringing me at a time
I actually ask her to,
honestly we're all dead.
I'll try, I'll try.
So we're good?
We make this work
next time round.
But we've failed to do this
the last five times.
And this time,
we have even less time.
What makes you think that this
is gonna work?
Because, something
seems impossible,
we try, it doesn't work,
we try again.
We learn, we improve,
we fail again, but better.
We make friends, we learn
to trust, we help each other.
We get it wrong again,
we improve together.
Then, ultimately, succeed.
Because this is what
being alive is.
And it's better than
the alternative.
So, come on,
you brilliant humans.
We go again. And we win.
Deal?
Deal.
- Deal.
Exterminate!
I'm so tired.
What? Oh, come on!
No, no, no, no.
That's not fair!
Daleks are not fair.
Daleks are unstoppable.
Alright, cool.
Oh.
Oh, man.
I got away last time.
I can't execute the plan
in time if it's dark.
- Stay here.
- No, what...
Stay here. I need to know
where you are. We've
only got four minutes.
Stop leaving us all the time.
We're all worried. But I'm
trying to keep everyone safe.
Have you ever told her?
Told her what?
How you feel about her.
I don't know what you mean.
Yeah, you do.
Is it that obvious?
Well, maybe not
to a good-hearted weirdo.
I spent four years
travelling the world with you.
I saw it then.
You didn't half cane
looking at that hologram.
I didn't.
I mean, just that--
She just--
I don't know what to do, Dan.
I've never told anyone.
Not even myself.
Just tell her.
It's not that easy.
Look, I took way too long
to tell to tell somebody
that I liked them.
And then the universe ended
and everything got messy.
I wouldn't want that to
happen to you, Sheffield.
Dan.
Don't move.
There's one behind you, Yaz.
Doctor!
DALEK:
The Doctor cannot save you.
The Doctor
will never save you!
I'm sorry.
I'll fix this.
Incorrect.
Exterminate!
I'm angry now.
Exterminations will do that.
Right.
Why would he cordon this
stuff off? Let's have a look.
Oh. Oh!
Oh, Jeff. You bad, bad man.
Dan, come and help me
with this. Yaz, go get
Sarah and Nick.
Bring them down here.
What about all the stuff
on the fifth floor?
Just bring them down here.
Sorry.
No time. Really, no time.
My actions
are catching up with me.
Time is catching up with me.
I will not let you die because
of decisions I've taken.
Please go, get the others.
Right.
She likes you.
I like her, too.
No, I mean...
she likes you.
I don't understand
what you're saying, Dan.
I think you do.
But, for some reason,
you pretend to me...
and to her, that you don't.
- Halt!
- In your dreams, mate!
Sorry you're going to be
losing this place.
Oh, God, I'm not.
It was, erm, you know,
it was a family obligation.
And then everyone was
grieving, and then I sort of
stepped in to help.
Sort of became my life,
really,
- when I wasn't looking.
- Right.
In that way that life does,
you know.
So who named it Elf Storage?
Oh. Elf? No, it's--
- Erm, the "S" fell off.
- Right.
But if this place blows up,
I mean, you're gonna
lose all your stuff.
Yeah, I feel like
I'm done with it.
They're never asking for
their stuff back, are they?
All my exes?
No, they're really not.
And what are you gonna do
without this place?
God, I just think--
I don't know. Always
sort of wanted to travel.
Yeah, I had this, erm--
Yeah, I had this
romantic notion, I suppose,
that I would go travelling
the world with someone.
But, erm, I never really...
never really had someone
to do it with.
You two, come on! Out of time.
- But this is the plan.
- Basement now.
- Out of--
No human presence.
Life signals
in sub-ground level space.
Analysis suggests
the Doctor's survival plan
centres on that location.
So, wait. Am I getting my
mother to ring now or what?
I don't know any more!
Oh, great. Well done.
Why has the plan changed?
The plan hasn't changed.
Are those fireworks
in those boxes? Jeff.
If we're to stand
the best chance,
we need to be
one loop smarter than them.
The Daleks will learn
based on the information
we give them
in the whole of the next loop.
That last-but-one loop
becomes a decoy loop.
You give 'em false information
and change what they predict.
Bingo. Decoy plan.
You know the plan,
do the opposite
as soon as it resets.
Then when it resets
for the final minute,
we will have the narrowest
of narrow precious advantages.
Surrender, Doctor!
You took your time.
Not even wearing a watch,
I'm doing it for show.
Still haven't beaten us then?
The time loop
is almost closed.
You cannot escape us.
I can. Cos we've got
a brilliant plan.
Haven't we got
a brilliant plan?
Yeah.
See? Worried now.
Daleks are not worried.
You should be.
Exterminate!
Exit
the ascension device!
Sorry. Important stuff to do.
Really important stuff!
Oh, hey, Mam.
Hello!
Er, yeah, just rang to say,
"Happy New Year," really.
Er...
And I miss you.
And I love you.
Yeah, cos I'm not really sure
I say that enough.
Are you drunk?
No, I'm not drunk, Mammy.
Oh, God, are you ill?
No, I'm not ill.
Do you know what?
Happy New Year.
I love you, but I have to go.
Male human located.
He has returned to the
subsection of the facility.
The objects in this unit
have been placed as a barrier.
Male human
is behind its belongings.
What are you gonna
do now then?
Ah.
Thanks for the therapy.
Explain!
Ex. Terminated.
Top floor. Electricals,
womenswear, fish tanks.
Locating the Doctor.
Hey, you want to join?
Explain!
Oh, just having some
beef and beans.
Might put on the Hootenanny.
What about you? Any plans?
Seeing friends?
Daleks do not
have friends!
Yeah, well, you've only got
yourselves to blame for that.
You will
never escape execution!
Let's see, shall we?
And brace
for the final go-round.
Exterminate!
Mam, don't speak.
I need you to call me ten
seconds before midnight, OK?
The lines will...
Just do it. Bye.
Thanks.
Run!
We'd be so good
on Supermarket Sweep.
Doctor identified!
Exterminate!
Running out of time, Doc.
DOCTOR:
Really aware of that, Dan.
Oh. We've got to go.
We've got to go.
DALEK 1:
The Doctor has deceived us.
Life signals detected
in sub-ground level space.
- Go. I'll be right behind you.
Go!
Haven't seen this much
gunpowder since 1605.
Halt!
Doctor!
The door's
just through here! Oh!
DALEK 1:
Switching to dark vision mode.
Dark vision mode interference!
It is the Doctor.
DALEK 2:
Human life signals detected!
Converge!
We know you are hiding
- within this collection
of objects.
False signal confusion
done. Just answer the phone.
This way!
Where is the Doctor?
DOCTOR:
Everybody get clear! Get down!
Sarah?
DALEK:
Human presence confirmed!
Good fireworks, though.
- Fair play to Jeff.
Wait. We're alive.
You did it. Time didn't reset.
We did it.
Good display.
Just for me, is it?
Ah. Look at you.
So much better.
Thanks for looking after us.
If you did.
Quite mysterious, really.
What did you mean,
when you said your actions
were catching up with you?
Nothing.
Nothing. I don't remember.
I say lots of things.
We all say lots of things
we don't mean.
And some we do.
Do you know
what I have always wondered?
The lost treasure of
the Flor de la Mar.
Whatever happened to that?
Shall we go have a look?
Oh, it's ridiculous.
- Just use the wheels.
- I'm fine, babe.
Oh, my God,
this is the most silliest type
of machoness
- I've ever seen. Oh.
Oh. Hiya, Mammy.
Yeah, we're just about to get
in the taxi to the airport.
Have you got your passport?
Do I have... No, I don't
have my passport, Mammy.
I set fire to it
in a bin last night.
Yes, I have my passport,
of course. I'm a grown woman.
And I ran a business by myself
for almost five years.
Before you burned it
to the ground.
It burned to the ground,
yes, I admit.
But you know what? There's
a lot more to that story
than you know about, so...
Isn't there always?
Well, moral of the story,
I have my passport, so--
- Oh, look.
- Hello, Mary.
Oh. Hi, Nick.
OK, Mam, I'll call you from
the other side of the world,
- OK? Bye.
- Bye.
Bye.
Bye, bye, bye, bye, bye.
- Do not flirt with my mother,
please.
- I was just being nice.
Just being nice.
Well, actually, she still
thinks I'm a madwoman
for travelling around the
world with a man I just met.
- Guess it's a weird
first date.
As opposed to
our actual first date,
where we were killed... Aw.
...where we were killed
eight times by robot aliens.
And saved by a woman
in an old police box.
But was that our first date?
I feel like it was
more of a meet-cute.
Do you? Hmm.
Madam Trine,
Pirate Queen?
She killed my father
and she released the demon.
Sea Devil.