WOMAN: (ON TV) Orchestrations
were arranged by Sir Rhodri Fenning
and Dame Evelyn Blish is a member
of the Kings Lynn players.
So tune in again next week for more
from the What's My Line? team.
And that brings us to the end
of programming for today.
So, from all of us here at Alexandra Palace,
a very good night.
£200 overdrawn.
I need a miracle.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(CHATTER ON THE RADIO)
He's a caution, that one.
He does make me laugh.
Oh, our lord and master.
-Rita, I'm off out.
-Dad.
Oh, how many times, son? We'll see.
But everyone's getting a telly, Dad,
even Mr Gallagher.
And the Bells at number 67.
Well, perhaps we'll get one
for the Coronation.
If you're lucky. We'll see.
Don't wait up.
I heard they rot your brains.
Rot them into soup
and your brain comes pouring
out of your ears.
That's what television does.
Mr Magpie?
-Oh , Mr Magpie?
-Eh?.
-Whoo-hoo! Can you hear me, Magpie?
-Yes.
-I must be dreaming.
-Oh, no. This isn't a dream.
-I'm going doolally, then.
-Not at all sweetheart.
Now, are you sitting comfortably?
Good, then we'll begin.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(MAGPIE GROANING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
I thought we'd be going for the Vegas era.
You know, the white flares
and the chest hair.
You are kidding, aren't you?
If you wanna see Elvis,
you go for the late '50s.
The time before burgers!
When they called him "The Pelvis"
and he still had a waist!
What's more, you see him in style!
(IMITATING ELVIS) You going my way, doll?
Is there any other way to go, daddy-o?
Straight from the fridge, man!
Hey, you speak the lingo!
Yeah, well, me and Mum, Cliff Richard
movies every Bank Holiday Monday.
cliff! I knew your mother
would be a cliff fan.
-Where we off to?
-Ed Sullivan TV studios.
Elvis did Hound Dog on one of the shows.
There were loads of complaints.
Bit of luck, we'll just catch it.
And that would be the TV studios in,
what, New York?
That's the one!
(ROSE LAUGHING)
Digging that New York vibe!
Well, this could still be New York.
I mean, this looks very New York to me.
-London-y New York, mind, but...
-What are all the flags for?
(MUFFIN THE MULE THEME ON TV)
Smashing! Smashing, innit?
You'd have thought
they was in the room with ya, eh?
Fair do's, Tommy, you had a point.
New television.
There, that should cheer you up a bit, Rita?
Give us a smile, then, eh?
I can't. Nothing's the same anymore.
Not with her...
-Stop going on about it!
-But her face, Eddie.
What happened to her? That awful face.
I said stop it!
(THUMPING)
She's awake. I think she's hungry.
There you go, sir.
All wired up for the great occasion.
Great occasion? What do you mean?
Where you been living, out in the colonies?
The Coronation of course!
And what Coronation's that, then?
What do you mean? The Coronation!
It's the Queen's! Queen Elizabeth!
-Oh! Is this 19537
-Last time I looked.
Time for a lovely bit of
pomp and circumstance. What we do best.
Look at all the TV aerials.
Looks like everyone's got one.
That's weird. My mum said tellies were
so rare, they all had to pile into one house.
Not round here, love.
Magpie's Marvellous Tellies.
-Only five quid a pop!
-Oh, but this is a brilliant year, classic!
Technicolor! Everest climbed!
Everything off the ration!
A nation throwing off the shackles of war
and looking forward to a happier,
brighter future!
WOMAN: Someone help me, please! Ted!
Leave him alone! That's my husband!
-WOMAN: Please!
-What's going on?
-0i! What are you doing?
-Police business. Get out of the way, sir.
-Who did they take? Do you know him?
-Must be Mr Gallagher.
It's happening all over the place.
They're turning into monsters.
Tommy! Not one word. Get inside now!
Sorry, I'd better do as he says.
DOCTOR: All aboard!
Operation Market Stall. Go! Go! Go!
Lost them. How did they get away from us?
I'm surprised they didn't turn back
and arrest you for reckless driving.
Have you actually passed your test?
Men in black? Vanishing police cars?
This is Churchill's England,
not Stalin's Russia.
Monsters, that boy said.
Maybe we should go and ask
the neighbours.
That's what I like about you,
the domestic approach.
Thank you.
Hold on. Was that an insult?
MAGPIE: I've finished it as you instructed.
-That's awfully good of you, Mr Magpie.
-So you'll go soon?
-You'll leave me?
-We'll see.
If you're a very good boy.
Please. You're burning me. Inside.
Behind my eyes. It hurts.
Even my memories hurt.
I just want things
back like they used to be.
Oh, but this world of yours
is busy, busy, busy,
forging ahead into a brand-new age.
You can never go back. That's your tragedy.
But now the time is almost ripe, Magpie.
Cometh the hour, cometh the man.
Or lady.
(STAIRS CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
Gran? Gran, it's me. It's Tommy.
I'm gonna come in, Gran.
Stand back. Just don't...
-I'm sorry, but I've got to come in.
-What do you think you're doing?
We gotta try and help her, Dad.
Give me that key.
I said give me that key right now.
And don't think I've finished with you.
All the warnings I've given you
and every time,
every time, you disobey me.
-We can't just lock her away.
-Excuse me, sunshine, I am talking.
And you can forget that college nonsense.
You're gonna come and work alongside me.
Get your hands dirty for once.
(THUDDING)
Oh, Lord! Won't she ever stop?
There, there, Rita, my sweet.
Business as usual.
Now, let's get these up all over the house
in honour of Her Majesty.
But, Eddie, what if she's dying?
I am talking!
(SCOOTER ENGINE HUMMING)
That's better.
A little bit of hush.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
-Hi!
Who are you, then?
Let's see, judging by the look of you,
family man, nice house, decent wage,
fought in the war, therefore,
I represent Queen and country!
Just doing a check of her forthcoming
Majesty's subjects before the great day.
Don't mind if we come in?
No, I didn't think you did. Thank you.
Not bad, very nice, very well kept.
-I'd like to congratulate you, Mrs...?
-Connolly.
Now then, Rita. I can handle this.
This gentleman's a proper representative.
Don't mind the wife. She rattles on a bit.
Well, maybe she should rattle on
a bit more.
I'm not convinced you're doing
your patriotic duty.
Those flags, why are they not flying?
There we are, Rita, I told you.
Get them up. Queen and country.
-I'm sorry.
-Get it done. Do it now.
-Hold on a minute. Hold on a minute.
-Like the gentleman says...
You've got hands, Mr Connolly.
Two big hands.
-Then why is that your wife's job?
-Well, it's housework, innit?
-And that's a woman's job?
-Course it is.
Mr Connolly, what gender is the Queen?
She's a female.
And are you suggesting the Queen
does the housework?
-No, not at all.
-Then get busy!
Right. Yes, sir.
You'll be proud of us, sir! We'll have
Union Jacks left, right and centre!
Excuse me, Mr Connolly. Hang on a minute.
Union Jacks?
-Yes, that's right, isn't it?
-That's the Union flag.
It's the Union Jack
only when it's flown at sea.
Oh, I'm sorry. I do apologise.
Well, don't get it wrong again.
There's a good man. Now get to it!
Right, then, nice and comfy.
At her Majesty's leisure!
-Union flag?
-Mum went out with a sailor.
(CHUCKLING) I bet she did.
Anyway, I'm the Doctor and this is Rose.
And you are?
-Tommy.
-Well, sit yourself down, Tommy.
Have a look at this. I love telly, don't you?
-Yeah, I think it's brilliant.
-Good man.
Keep working, Mr C!
Now, why don't you tell me what's wrong?
-Did you say you were a doctor?
-Yes, I am.
Can you help her? Oh, please.
Can you help her, Doctor?
Now then, Rita, I don't think
the gentleman needs to know.
-Oh, the gentleman does.
-Tell us what's wrong, and we can help.
It's all right. It's all right. Come here.
Oh, its okay. It's all right.
Hold on a minute.
Queen and Country's one thing,
but this is my house.
What the... What the hell am I doing?
Now you listen here, Doctor.
You may have fancy qualifications,
but what goes on under my roof
is my business.
-Not if people are being bundled into...
-I am talking!
And I'm not listening!
Now you, Mr Connolly,
you are staring into a deep, dark pit
of trouble if you don't let me help.
So I'm ordering you, sir,
tell me what's going on!
(THUDDING)
She won't stop.
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
She never stops.
We started hearing stories,
all round the place.
People who have changed.
Families keeping it secret
'cause they were scared.
Then the police started finding out.
We don't know how, no one does.
They just turn up.
They come to the door and take them.
Any time of the day or night.
Show me.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Gran, it's Tommy.
It's all right, Gran. I've brought help.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
Her face has completely gone.
Scarcely an electrical impulse left.
Almost complete neural shutdown.
It's just ticking over.
It's like her brain's been wiped clean.
What are we gonna do, Doctor?
We can't even feed her.
-We've got company!
-It's them. They've come for her!
What was she doing before this happened?
Where was she?
-Tell me, quickly, think!
-I can't think. She doesn't leave the house.
-She was just...
-Hold on a minute!
There are three important,
brilliant and complicated reasons
why you should listen to me.
-One...
-Doctor!
Leave her alone. You'll hurt her! Mum!
Come back. Don't hurt her.
-Back inside, Rita.
-She's my mother!
Back inside now, I said!
(CRYING)
Hell of a right hook.
Have to watch out for that.
Don't fight it. Back inside.
-Rose, come on!
-EDDIE: Get back inside.
TOMMY: But they took her.
EDDIE: Don't fight it.
Rose! We're gonna lose them again!
But they took her!
That was Gran and they took her!
EDDIE: Come on, back inside, lad.
TOMMY: How did they know?
How did they find her? Who told them?
You! Get the hell out of my house!
I'm going. I'm done.
Nice to meet you, Tommy.
Mrs Connolly.
And as for you, Mr Connolly,
only an idiot hangs
the Union flag upside down.
Shame on you.
Oh, very good.
Very good.
Stay where you are!
I'm sorry, miss. I'm afraid you're too late.
I was just about to lock the door.
Yeah? Well, I wanna buy a telly.
-Come back tomorrow, please.
-You'll be closed, won't you?
-What?
-For the big day?
-The Coronation?
-Yes, yes, of course. The big day.
I'm sure you'll find somewhere to watch it.
Please go.
Seems to me
half of London's got a television,
since you're practically giving them away.
-I have my reasons.
-And what are they?
(STATIC)
Hungry!
-What's that?
-It's just the television.
One of these modern programmes.
Now, I really do think
you should leave right now.
Not until you've answered my questions.
How comes your televisions are so cheap?
It's my patriotic duty.
Seems only right that as many folk
as possible get to watch the Coronation.
We may be losing the Empire,
but we can still be proud!
Twenty million people
they reckon will be watching.
Imagine that.
And 20 million people can't be wrong, eh?
So why don't you get yourself back home
and get up bright and early for the big day?
No, I'm not leaving
till I've seen everything.
I need to close.
Mr Magpie,
something's happening out there.
Ordinary people are being struck down
and changed
and the only new thing in the house
is a television.
Your television. What's going on?
I knew this would happen.
I knew I'd be found out.
All right, then, just you and me.
You gonna come clean, then?
What's really in it for you?
For me? Perhaps some peace.
-From what?
-From her.
Well, that's just a woman on the telly.
That's just a programme.
What a pretty little girl.
-Oh, my God. Are you talking to me?
-Yes.
I'm talking to you, little one.
Unseasonably chilly for the time of year,
don't you think?
-What are you?
-I'm The Wire.
And I'm hungry!
Magpie, help me!
Just think of that
audience tomorrow, my dear,
all settling down to watch the Coronation.
Twenty million people.
Things will never be the same again.
I'm sorry. So sorry.
Help me!
Good night, children, everywhere.
Start from the beginning.
Tell me everything you know.
Well, for starters,
I know you can't wrap your hand
round your elbow
-and make your fingers meet.
-Don't get clever with me.
You were there today at Florizel Street,
and now breaking into this establishment.
Oh, you're connected with this.
Make no mistake.
Well, the thing is,
-Detective Inspector Bishop...
-How do you know my name?
It's written inside your collar.
Bless your mum. But I can't help thinking,
Detective Inspector, you're not exactly
doing much detective-inspecting, are you?
I'm doing everything in my power.
All you're doing is grabbing those faceless
people and hiding them as fast as you can.
Don't tell me, orders from above.
Coronation Day, the eyes of the world
are on London Town,
so any sort of problem
just gets swept out of sight.
The nation has an image to maintain.
But doesn't it drive you mad,
doing nothing?
Don't you want
to get out there and investigate?
Course I do.
But...
with all the crowds expected,
we haven't got the manpower.
Even if we did,
this is beyond anything we've ever seen.
I just don't know anymore.
Twenty years on the force,
I don't even know where to start.
We haven't the faintest clue
what's going on.
-Well, that could change.
-How?
Start from the beginning.
Tell me everything you know.
We started finding them
about a month ago.
Persons left sans visage.
Heads just...blank.
Is there any sort of pattern?
It's spreading out from North London,
all over the city.
Men, women, kids, grannies.
Only real lead is
there's been quite a large number in...
Florizel Street.
Found another one, sir.
Oh, good man, Crabtree.
Here we are, Doctor.
Take a good look.
See what you can deduce.
-Rose.
-You know her?
Know her? She...
They found her in the street apparently,
down by Damascus Road. Just abandoned.
That's unusual. That's the first one
out in the open... (FADES OUT)
...we'll have Torchwood
on our backs then, make no mistake.
-They did what?
-I'm sorry?
-They left her where?
-Just...in the street.
In the street. They left her in the street.
They took her face and just chucked her out
and left her in the street.
And, as a result, that makes things...
simple, very, very simple.
-Do you know why?
-No.
Because now, Detective Inspector Bishop,
there is no power on this Earth
that can stop me! Come on!
The big day dawns.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
You've had your fun with your little Doctor.
But now you're left with me, Rita,
so you'll behave yourself.
And smile.
Here we go, everyone, here we go!
Grub's up. Grub's up. Tuck in, everyone.
Tuck in. Take a sandwich.
Oh, here we go, it's starting.
Look, look. Go and take your places.
Sit down. Sit down. There we are.
MAN: (ON TV) ...in front of the palace...
WOMAN: Rita, love, just look at
that telly-box, then! Innit marvellous?
The picture's so clear!
Here, Bet, I says to Rita, I says,
"You didn't need
to get your hair done special, love.
"The Queen won't be able to see you!"
Where's your old mum, then?
She can't go missing it.
Sorry, Mum can't make it down.
Aw, bless her.
Maybe we could pop up and see her later.
Maybe you could. It's a good idea.
What do you think, Dad?
Maybe Aunty Betty can go
and see Gran later.
Oh, he loves his Gran, this one.
Proper little mummy's boy all round.
Oh, you know what they say about them.
Eddie, you want to beat that out of him.
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I'll get it.
...will first appear
in about 10 minutes' time
riding in the gold coach of state.
Tommy, talk to me.
I need to know exactly what happened
inside your house.
-What the blazes do you think you're doing?
-I wanna help, Dad!
-Mr Connolly.
-Shut your face, you.
Whoever you are.
We can handle this ourselves!
Listen, you little twerp.
You're hardly out of the blooming cradle
so I don't expect you to understand,
but I've got a position to maintain.
People round here respect me.
It matters what people think.
Is that why you did it, Dad?
What do you mean? Did what?
You ratted on Gran.
How else would the police know
where to look?
Unless some coward told them.
How dare you?
You think I fought a war
just so a mouthy little scum like you
could call me a coward!
You don't get it, do you?
You fought against fascism, remember?
People telling you how to live.
Who you could be friends with.
Who you could fall in love with.
Who could live and who had to die.
Don't you get it? You were fighting
so that little twerps like me
could do what we want, say what we want.
Now you've become just like them.
You've been informing on everyone,
haven't you?
Even Gran.
All to protect your precious reputation!
Eddie, is that true?
I did it for us, Rita.
She was filthy! A filthy disgusting thing!
She's my mother.
All the others you informed on,
all the people in our street, our friends.
I had to.
I did the right thing.
The right thing for us or for you, Eddie?
You go, Tommy.
Go with the Doctor and do some good.
Get away from this house. It's poison.
We've had a ruddy monster
under our roof all right,
but it weren't my mother!
EDDIE: Rita!
Tommy.
-What was all that, then?
-That was...
That was the sound of something ending.
And about time, too. Everyone all right?
Smashing.
Nothing's gonna spoil our big day, is it?
Tommy, tell me about that night,
the night she changed.
She was just watching the telly.
Rose said it. She guessed it straightaway.
Of course she did.
All these aerials in one little street.
How come?
Bloke up the road, Mr Magpie,
he's selling them cheap.
-Is he, now?
-Come on!
BISHOP: Here! You can't do that.
Shop!
If you're here,
come out and talk to me, Magpie!
-Maybe he's out.
-Looks like it.
Oh, hello.
This isn't right. This is very much not right.
Tastes like iron. Bakelite.
Knocked together with human hands, yes,
but the design itself...
Oh, beautiful work. That is so simple.
That's incredible.
It's like a television, but portable.
A portable television!
It's not the only power source in this room.
TOMMY: Gran.
I'm on my way.
What do you think you're doing?
I want my friend restored
and I think that's beyond
a little backstreet electrician, so tell me,
who's really in charge here?
Yoo-hoo. I think that must be me.
Oh, this one's smart as paint.
Is she talking to us?
I'm sorry, gentlemen, I'm afraid
you've brought this on yourselves.
May I introduce you to my new friend.
Jolly nice to meet you.
Oh, my God, it's her.
That woman off the telly!
-No. It's just using her image.
-What?
-What are you?
-I'm The Wire.
And I will gobble you up, pretty boy.
Every last morsel!
And when I have feasted,
I shall regain the corporeal body,
which my fellow kind denied me.
Good Lord. Colour television.
-So your own people tried to stop you?
-They executed me,
but I escaped in this form
and fled across the stars.
And now you're trapped in the television.
Not for much longer.
Doctor, is this what got my gran?
Yes, Tommy. It feeds off
the electrical activity of the brain,
but it gorges itself
like a great, over-fed pig.
Taking people's faces,
their essence as it stuffs itself.
-And you let her do it, Magpie.
-I had to.
She allowed me my face.
She's promised to release me
at the time of manifestation.
-What does that mean?
-The appointed time.
My crowning glory.
Doctor, the Coronation!
For the first time in history,
millions gathered round a television set.
But you're not strong enough yet, are you?
You can't do it all from here.
That's why you need this.
You need something more powerful.
This will turn a big transmitter
into a big receiver.
What a clever thing you are.
But why fret about it? Why not just relax?
Kick off your shoes
and enjoy the Coronation.
Believe me, you'll be glued to the screen.
-Doctor!
-Hold on.
Hungry!
Hungry.
The Wire is hungry! Oh, this one is tasty!
Oh, I'll have lashings of him. Delicious!
Ah!
Armed?
He's armed and clever.
Withdraw! Withdraw!
The box, Magpie, the box!
Hold tight!
Conduct me to my victory, Magpie.
Hungry! Hungry!
Feed me/
-Oh, she's so lovely!
-RITA: Beautiful.
Makes you forget all your troubles.
Everyone all right for pop?
Tommy, wake up! Tommy, come on!
-What happened?
-Where's Magpie?
We don't even know where to start looking.
It's too late.
Never too late, as a wise person once said.
Kylie, I think. The Wire's got big plans.
It'll need... Oh, yes, yes.
She's gonna harvest half the population.
Millions and millions of people.
And where are we?
-Muswell Hill.
-Muswell Hill. Muswell Hill! Which means...
Alexandra Palace!
Biggest TV transmitter
in North London. Oh!
-What's why it chose this place, Tommy!
-What are you gonna do?
I'm going shopping.
This what you want?
Perfect! Right, I need one more thing.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Got it. Let's go.
Her Majesty is wearing...
I can't do this!
Please! Please, don't make me.
The time is at hand. Feed me!
Feed me/
There!
Come on!
Wait, wait, wait. Where do we think we...
Oh, I'm very sorry, sir.
-Shouldn't you be at the Coronation?
-They're saving me a seat.
-Who'd he think you were?
-King of Belgium apparently.
(CROWD CHEERING ON TV)
WOMAN: (ON TV) ...will wait there a while.
But he will go on
ahead of Her Majesty into the Abbey...
Keep this switched on.
Don't let anyone stop you, Tommy.
Everything depends on it, you understand?
MAN: (ON TV) Her Majesty moves across...
You'll get yourself killed up there!
Your Majesty!
Feed me/
(LAUGHING)
Ah! Feast!
Feasting! The Wire is feasting!
It's too late. It's too late for all of us!
I shall consume you, Doctor!
I won't let you do this, Magpie!
Help me, Doctor! It burns!
It took my face,
my soul!
You cannot stop The Wire.
Soon, I shall become manifest.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
No more. No more of this.
You promised me peace.
Then peace you shall have.
(MAGPIE SCREAMING)
Been burning the candle at both ends?
You've over-extended yourself, missus.
You shouldn't have had a crack
at poor old Magpie there.
(EXCLAIMING)
Rubber soles, swear by them.
Oh, dear. Has our little plan
gone horribly wrong, Doctor?
...coat of shimmering cloth of gold
lined with a crimson silk...
(ON TV) ...are you willing to do the same?
No!
It's closed down, I'm afraid,
and no epilogue.
(THE WIRE SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(GOD SAVE THE QUEEN PLAYING ON TV)
-What have I missed?
-Doctor! What happened?
Sorted. Electrical creature. TV technology.
Clever alien life form.
That's me, by the way. I turned the receiver
back into a transmitter
and I trapped The Wire in here.
I just invented the home video
30 years early.
Betamax.
Oh, look!
God save the Queen, eh?
(PEOPLE CHEERING ON TV)
Here's my grandson. Oh, son!
Oh, my goodness.
This was never your house.
It's in my mother's name.
And on her behalf, I'm telling you,
out.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
We could go down the Mall,
join in with the crowds.
No, that's just pomp and circumstance.
-This is history, right here.
-The domestic approach?
DOCTOR: Exactly.
Will it... That thing...
is it trapped for good on the video?
Hope so.
Just to be on the safe side, though,
I'll use my unrivalled knowledge
of trans-temporal extirpation methods to
neutralise the residual electronic pattern.
-You what?
-I'm going to tape over it.
Just leave it to me. I'm always doing that.
Tell you what, Tommy.
You can have the scooter. Little present.
Best keep it in the garage
for a few years, though, eh?
Good riddance.
Is that it, then, Tommy?
New monarch, new age, new world.
-No room for a man like Eddie Connolly.
-That's right.
He deserves it.
Tommy, go after him.
-What for?
-He's your dad.
-He's an idiot.
-Course he is. Like I said, he's your dad.
But you're clever,
clever enough to save the world
so don't stop there.
Go on.
We've gone beyond the reach of
the Tardis' knowledge. Not a good move.
Entering Nightshift.
This writing is old.
Impossibly old.
-People! Look at that, real people.
-That's us. Hooray!
The Beast and his armies
shall rise from the pit...
Whatever it is down there,
it's not a natural phenomenon.
We could revolutionise modern science.
We could use it to fuel the empire.
Or start a war.
-That's a black hole.
-But that's impossible.