WOMAN: Can you hear me?
MAN: Thief!
- Let me back in!
- How did you get out there?
- Seeing a friend.
- I'll chop your hand off!
I say friend...
We're not that close.
Please, let me back in.
Please! Let me back in fast.
You can't keep stealing
from merchants in the souk.
They know where you're from.
You tell me creating happiness
is important
to my mental well being.
A game like this
makes me happy.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Time to go back in your room.
It'll be dark soon.
Have you taken precautions?
Have you told everyone?
Tahira...
We have to keep everyone safe.
Nothing is going to happen,
Tahira.
Of course it is.
I told you to tell them.
I told the doctors,
I told all of you.
They're real.
I understand
they seem real to you.
You need to rest.
Sleep will help.
Sleep is when they'll come.
I can feel them coming.
They'll be here tonight.
Rest well, Tahira.
(SIGHS)
(DISTANT BIRD CALLING)
(FLAME CRACKLES)
TAHIRA: Maryam. Maryam!
MARYAM: Over here.
I told you to lock the doors.
- We don't do that.
- Get everyone out.
(SNARLING)
MARYAM: Oh, no.
(GUTTURAL GROWL)
TAHIRA: I tried to warn you.
(MUFFLED GASP)
Don't struggle.
They like it more
when you struggle.
(ROARS)
- (CLATTERING)
- (GASPS)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GROWLING AND CRUNCHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(THUDDING)
(GASPS)
- Oh.
- (GROWLS)
(TARDIS THRUMS)
DOCTOR: Here we are -
Sheffield.
YAZ: Is it the right day?
- It's the right day.
- In the right year?
The day you asked,
in the year that you asked,
at the time that you asked.
You are home.
Everyone meet back here
tomorrow lunchtime?
- Yeah, yeah.
- What are you going to do?
Me? Oh, yeah.
Very busy.
Busy, busy. Maintenance.
Correspondence.
Correspondence
about maintenance.
- (BEEPING)
- Oh!
Oh. OK.
Not the exact right time -
77 minutes out. Late.
What?! (HUFFS)
You sure you're going to be
- all right on your own?
- Oh, you know.
Finally a bit of peace
and quiet.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hmm...
I could always...
Oh, nah.
Maybe I'll just nip
straight to tomorrow lunchtime.
(GROWLING)
What was that?
(BEEPING)
Location for that noise.
Aleppo?
I've got time.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
Sorry, sorry.
Am I late?
It is the right day, isn't it?
Have you been waiting long?
Am I really late?
Yes, yes, yes and yes.
Mum and Dad left hours ago.
Whitby for the night.
Did you cook?
Can you cook now?
Hi, loser.
Hey, no-mark.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(MULTIPLE BOLTS CLANK
AND UNLOCK)
What are you doing here, man?
I got your messages, didn't I?
- It's been months.
- Yeah.
Me phone's been playing up.
- So, are you back?
- Yeah.
Sort of.
Not really. Just a few hours.
I bought chips.
You going to let me in or what?
It's not a good time.
(JOKINGLY) I got chips, though!
(LAUGHS)
GRAHAM: Now, that, gentlemen,
- is a full house.
- What?
Well, I've been practising,
haven't I? On my travels, eh?
I've got to say,
it's great to see you lads.
It don't sound like
I've been missing much, though.
(SCOFFS) Nothin' at all.
I'd rather be on cruises
like you.
Well, let me tell you, Gabe,
those boats, mate,
they are lovely - very calm.
And how's your health now,
Gray, you all right?
Good, Freddie boy, thanks.
Very good.
How are you coping...
...without Grace?
Well, I have to, don't I?
You know.
Travelling helps, mate,
don't it?
Stops me
getting stuck in the past.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
(SIGHS) Aleppo.
1380. Welcome to Syria!
Now...
Oh. (SMACKS LIPS)
They're not here, are they?
"Bimaristan."
It means sick place.
This must be
one of the oldest hospitals
in the world.
Of course, Islamic physicians
were known
for the enlightened way
they treated people
with mental health problems.
But what happened here?
You guys go this way...
Oh! Who am
I supposed to share
all the interesting stuff
with?!
TAHIRA: Is someone there?
Friendly visitors. Visitor.
Where are you?
I'm coming to say hello.
(SOBBING)
I'm the Doctor.
I'm here to help.
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
Stay away!
It's all right.
You're safe, I promise.
No, they took everyone.
What happened here?
- You have to get out!
- Why?
Because there's one still here.
(GROWLING)
(ROARS)
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
What are you?
Leave her alone!
(ROARS)
Stay here!
Gone. That was fast.
(SONIC WHIRS)
(BEEPS)
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Right, lads, ready?
Here we go.
Fastest dealer
in South Yorkshire.
(WHOOSHING)
Can you see?
Can you see it?
I'm trapped.
This is what he did to me.
Help me, Graham.
He's close.
I think you lost count.
Huh?
(FOOTBALL VIDEO GAME PLAYS)
Goes past one...
Goes past two...
It's a screamer!
Top bins! Final seconds...
He's done it. He's a lege.
Ryan Sinclair, FIFA legend.
I've never lost it.
Oh! I've still got it.
I'll make tea.
Your place
ls normally spotless.
This ain't you.
Mate, you ain't been around,
so don't tell me what I am.
All right.
Mate, sorry for not answering
your messages.
(CAN CRUNCHES)
But you ain't yourself.
I'm just finding things
difficult at the moment.
Have you spoke
to anyone about it?
No, and I'm not going to.
All right.
There's something else.
Promise you won't laugh at me.
I can't promise that, can I?
(SIGHS)
Last few days...
...I've been having nightmares.
Dark, messed-up stuff.
And there's this...
...bloke in them.
He keeps recurring,
like he's watching my dreams,
waiting in the dark.
Oh, that's creepy.
That's not the mad bit.
But the past few days...
...I've seen him.
At night. Outside the flat.
Across the hall.
In my room.
The guy that's in your dreams
is in your room?
I knew you'd laugh.
Look at me.
I'm not laughing.
Mate, I've seen
some weird things
while I've been away.
Things you wouldn't believe
are possible.
Would you kip here tonight?
So, can you say
where you've been,
where they sent you?
Madagascar.
California. Hong Kong.
- Gloucester.
- Oh!
They had a thing in Gloucester.
Dad was going on about it.
Something to do with Russians.
It had nowt to do
with Russians.
- How's the new job?
- Sacked.
- Sonya.
- What?
That's the third time!
People are really annoying,
and they hate being told that.
I'm just not cut out
for customer services.
No kidding!
Sonya...
We can stop doing this.
Stop marking it.
I thought it was a good thing.
Yeah.
No, I just don't know whether
an anniversary dinner...
I still think about it.
Do you?
I dream about it sometimes.
Sofa movie after?
What, so you can fall asleep
halfway through?
I do not do that.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC ON TV)
Idiot.
(PHONE RINGS)
SONYA: Hi.
I-I didn't know who to call.
We need help.
(GASPS)
(LAUGHTER)
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(CLOCK TICKS SOFTLY)
(GASPS)
What are you doing?
Hey!
Tibo!
DOCTOR: What is your name?
Tahira.
Have you seen those creatures
before, Tahira?
Not really.
Who are you?
I've never seen you here
before, Doctor.
Well, my brief
is quite wide-ranging.
No signs of those creatures
outside the bimaristan.
So, deliberately targeting
a hospital
of vulnerable people.
The place is silent.
Where is everyone else?
How many people were here?
Maybe 10 or 12 patients.
I'm really sorry...
...but I think those creatures
must have taken them.
Taken them where?
I've no idea,
and why they left you
behind...
How long have you been here?
If it's not
a personal question,
which it is.
A few weeks.
I've travelled a long way.
Seen a lot of things
I wish I hadn't.
My family were killed
when I was seven.
I ran.
Aleppo was safety for me.
They let me in here
because I wasn't doing well.
I promise to keep you safe.
We will work this out.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Ah!
Really sorry.
Message device - someone's
trying to get in touch.
Just in 14th-century Syria.
Is it lunchtime tomorrow
already?
I need your help.
- My mate's been taken.
- What?/
- (PHONE CHIMES)
- Wait. Another call.
- Yaz?
- Doctor,
there was a figure in our flat.
- (PHONE BEEPS)
- Oh, hold on.
(SIGHS) Graham?
Hey, Doc,
I keep seeing these images
of planets,
like they're being projected
into my head.
Mm... Hold on.
Call merge.
I'm going to get you all now,
and I'm bringing
my new friend Tahira.
- ALL: Who?
- I'll be there in a sec.
Ah!
They did leave something
behind.
I knew it.
This will tell us something.
Come on.
I'll explain on the way.
And it might
just blow your mind.
Tahira, this is Ryan,
Graham and Ya-z.
Hi.
Tahira is from Aleppo -
in 1380.
I've explained about the TARDIS
and the fact
that you're from 700 years
in the future.
I'm really not ready for today.
(BEEPING)
No, don't tell me that,
cos you're wrong.
- (BEEPING)
- I'm telling you you are.
- Who is she arguing with?
- The TARDIS.
Because it's telling me,
quite defiantly,
that these two strands of fur
do not exist,
when they're right there!
Those creatures that we saw
aren't registered
in its database.
They've never existed,
will never exist.
Except they must.
Cos if they don't exist,
if they can't exist,
where did they come from
and how?
Tell me what happened
to your mate.
Some guy was in his room.
Don't know how he got in there.
It was like his fingers
were detached from his hand...
...connected to Tibo's ear.
It was draining
something from him.
What did he look like?
He was bald and...
tattooed head.
Whoa. Same bloke
that was in the flat.
And you, the psychic incursion
in your head?
Someone trying to communicate
with you?
GRAHAM: Yeah,
but it was a woman.
She was trapped
inside this, um...
I don't know, I couldn't make
head nor tail of it.
Then I saw these,
um, like, planets.
They were burning,
like she was connected
to them somehow.
Someone is targeting us.
Do you have any idea
where those planets might be?
You get me an A-Z
of the universe,
and I'll be able to stick
my finger straight on...
No, I've got no idea.
Right, then, better idea.
TARDIS telepathic circuits.
- Doc...
- Stop fidgeting, will you?
Ugh! Doc...
Ow! I don't like it.
Are you sure it's safe?
You trust me, don't you?
Have I got to answer that?
Oi!
Is it going to hurt?
No. Probably not.
Maybe. Yeah.
- Ready?
- No!
Focus on the image.
GRAHAM: Whoa! Ouch!
Ah! We found something -
we're moving.
DOCTOR: But where?
(TARDIS THRUMS)
Deep space. Distant future.
Is this what you saw?
GRAHAM: No, nothing like this.
Then, why here?
What did
the telepathic circuits
lock on to?
RYAN: If they were hooked
into your mind,
no wonder we're somewhere dark
and weird.
GRAHAM: Oi!
Do you even know where we are?
Half a galaxy
past the Geskon Straits.
Very little out here.
No civilisations left by now.
It doesn't feel like a ship,
though.
We are in geostationary orbit,
and that would be deliberate,
so why here?
Are we underground?
Is that why it's so dark?
The Doctor reckons
we're in a building,
among the stars.
We've come a long way
from home.
That's impossible. Nobody
can travel across the stars.
YAZ: Unless you're the Doctor.
She's basically the definition
of impossible.
(WHOOSHING)
Oh! Control hub?
Operator activated.
GRAHAM: Oh, now you've got
something there, Doc.
- Yeah, but what?
- There, look.
That is exactly what I saw,
those two objects.
DOCTOR: This must be
a monitor platform.
Observing events in this part
of the solar system.
What are they, like planets?
Looks like they're falling
into each other.
DOCTOR: Colliding.
About to destroy each other.
It's an extinction event.
But they're not colliding,
and they should be.
What's stopping
the final collapse?
Best take a little zoom in.
Whoa! There's something there,
- between those planets.
- RYAN: What sort of something?
DOCTOR: Good question.
Whoa!
The engineering required
to create that
and keep it in place - bravo.
Whoever built that -
round of applause from me.
Doc, can...can you magnify,
like zoom in?
DOCTOR: Why?
Well, I think
there's more to see.
DOCTOR: A tiny geo orb
locked in place.
RYAN: Is there someone
in there?
WOMAN: Are you here?
Is it you?
Th-That's it!
She's trapped.
That's... That's what I saw.
Doc,
- we...we gotta help her out.
- Please!
Hey! Have you seen this?
This whole section
is covered in fingers.
What?! Covered in fingers?
(GASPS)
(SONIC WHIRS)
And there's a signal
coming from them...
...broadcasting into that orb,
- to that girl.
- WOMAN: I'm trapped.
A psychic signal
fed by all this.
But what is it?
(SONIC WHIRS)
- (MECHANICAL HISSING)
- Ah!
This place has so many secrets
to yield.
(SONIC WHIRS)
RYAN: What do you reckon
you've got there?
This tech is powering
this platform,
powering that orb,
keeping it in place
between those two planets.
And at its heart,
a quantum fluctuation lock,
a sequence
of changing combinations,
hundreds of billions
of combinations
every millisecond...
...which would mean that orb...
...IS a prison,
and she's locked in there,
fed by that signal.
A signal of what, though?
Where is Tahira?
Maryam.
(ROARS)
- (GASPS)
-Do you recognise them?
(GROWLING)
The Chagaskas.
Your worst fears,
my creativity.
RYAN: There she is.
Oi, freak-hands,
get away from her.
Plus, you can release
all of these people right now.
And don't you ever
come sneaking
back into my family's flat.
Oh, that's not good.
(WIND HOWLS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Do it right this time.
I won't be calling anyone.
No point.
You're weak.
You run.
Nobody's coming, Yaz.
You're alone in the dark.
(GASPS) Oh, no.
Sonya!
Tibo?
Where you been, man?
We waited for you.
You said you'd be back.
How long you been waiting?
Our whole lives.
What's with all the fire?
The place is burning.
What place?
Earth.
And you weren't here.
I thought we were mates.
(GROWLS)
(SNARLS)
(SIGHS)
Why am I hooked up to this?
Grace...
I'm sorry to tell you,
Mr O'Brien,
your cancer has returned.
What?
No, no, that can't be right.
I-I've had a check-up.
I, um...
Anyway, you're not my doctor.
This time,
it's very aggressive.
Well, how...
How long have I got?
A couple of hours.
Why didn't you save me?
Uh...
Let me... Let me try again.
Now, for most people,
a quantum flux lock
is unbreakable.
100 billion combinations
every millisecond.
But I've got an app for that.
One sonic...connected
to the calculating power
of one TARDIS.
Shouldn't take too long.
And I'm talking myself again,
which means
the others aren't here.
Hello, Doctor.
I've watched you
stumbling round this universe.
I presume
this is all your doing.
Who's that girl in the orb?
And where are my friends?
Who are you?
I go by many names.
My preferred,
my original,
is Zellin.
No.
Zellin's a mythical name,
way beyond this universe.
Zellin was thought to be a god.
I blush.
You can't be.
We immortals need our games,
Doctor.
Eternity is long,
and we are cursed
to see it all.
The Eternals have their games.
The Guardians have
their power struggles.
For me, this dimension
is a beautiful board
for a game.
The toy maker would approve.
And I do like this form -
it's so...small.
To exist within molecules
and atoms is fascinating.
I can shape them,
regrow,
mould my form...
...to provoke fear
from humans...
...as I extract nightmares
from the scared and vulnerable.
- Now, that is a good game.
- Wait.
Are you transmitting
nightmares?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Taking nightmares from humans
and forcing them
into the mind of a girl
you've trapped between planets?
I've seen many races, Doctor,
and the humans
are infinitely fascinating,
infinitely...
...pathetic.
But of course you know that.
We share the same obsession.
We are not the same.
No.
You are so much...lesser.
You know the best part
of humanity?
The thing
that truly sets them apart?
The cruelty of their own minds
directed towards themselves.
The doubt. The fear.
The endless voices
telling themselves
that they're incapable
and unworthy.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Such an exquisite animal.
Built-in pain.
And the repositories
of that pain - the nightmares.
(THRUMMING)
(BEEPING)
I presume that's your doing,
Doctor. Always interfering.
I've watched you
blunder into this.
"Blundering” - top of my CV,
alongside
"plays well with others”
and "excellent tap dancer
in a crisis".
Almost clever!
But not quite clever enough.
DOCTOR: You're sure about that?
Cos, look, your prisoner,
she's free.
I used your own technology
against you.
No, Doctor.
I used your instincts
against you.
What?
I made the Chagaskas,
targeted the humans...
...to entice you here.
I needed someone
from this realm
to break a lock
from this realm.
Only one would do.
You.
No!
ZELLIN: You did find
the right answer.
You weren't asking
the right questions.
My freedom!
ZELLIN: This platform
isn't my technology.
I didn't make this prison.
She was always
the more powerful of us,
the more dangerous.
That's why they imprisoned her.
I just...
...ride in her slipstream.
Release. After all this time.
I don't understand.
Let me make you.
WOMAN: Two creatures
from another realm
descended into a universe
where they were worshipped
as gods.
They saw two planets
and laid a wager.
Which of them could bring
a planet to destruction first?
The gods set to their game,
sowing chaos
through the populations.
Wars began -
between species,
then between the planets
themselves.
The gods delighted
in the carnage.
It passed the time.
But slowly,
the inhabitants of the worlds
grew wise,
realised what these creatures
had done to them.
They unified and fought back
against their so-called gods.
They set their own planets
into a collision course,
and at the heart
of the collision
they laid a prison.
They trapped one creature
between the planets
for eternity.
The other fled,
vowing to return
to release his eternal partner.
ZELLIN: Wake up, Doctor.
Welcome back.
I hope you understand now.
I wasn't torturing her
with nightmares.
I was feeding her
what she needed to stay sane.
The pain of others.
But even gods need
a helping hand, Doctor.
Thank you.
You won't feel a thing
when this all burns.
Yes, they will.
(CHUCKLES)
Where now?
All those nightmares...
I loved them.
Humans?
Earth.
Let's take them all.
ZELLIN: Yes!
Oh, come on!
What do you think it feels like
for them to be such...
...tiny, ephemeral flashes
of existence?
Hmm!
They feel so much.
It must burn them.
I think it does.
THE MASTER: It's buried deep
in all our memories.
In our identity.
Built on the lie
of the timeless child.
(CLOCK TICKS)
DOCTOR: Hmm.
Right. Think this will hold me,
do you?
(SONIC WHIRS)
- (BEEPING)
- Oh!
Argh! Disgusting.
Agh!
I have just had
the maddest dream.
I know. You all have.
Tranquillising
psycho-extraction.
- I need to get Tibo.
- We have to get
everybody safe and back
to their rightful place.
Well, maybe if you stopped
messing around
with those finger things...
Tapped into
the bio-organic code.
Sonic does fingers!
Down.
Stay.
Good dog.
- Ew!
- DOCTOR: Could be useful.
TIBO: Ryan...
Where am I?
All right, mate.
Try not to freak out, yeah?
But you're on
a floating space platform
in a gravitational pull
between two colliding planets
halfway across the universe
cos of the guy who was stealing
your nightmares
through creepy
detachable fingers.
Prank?
No.
Take me through that again.
- (ROARS)
- (GASPS)
RYAN: What are they?
I know why
they didn't attack you.
Because they're yours.
Zellin, that man,
created the Chagaska
from your nightmares.
They wouldn't kill you,
they couldn't -
because you created them.
So, how do you defeat
two rampaging immortals?
Answer - you don't.
Those two planets...
They've spent a millennia
trying to work out
how to do it.
Well, I think
the motivational speech
needs a bit of work, Doc,
if you don't mi...
And also a plan, by the way.
I've got plans crashing
through my brain all the time.
You want a plan? Come to me.
Identifying which plan
is going to work,
that's the tricky bit.
(GASPS)
This is perfect, Zellin.
You've done well.
Take them all.
Hmm!
Billions in one go.
Gorge on their fears.
Why would we rush?
We have so much time...
...to walk in their nightmares.
We can pass eternity here...
...if we take it slow.
Of course.
I've told you,
there are no bogeymen,
nothing to be worried about.
Night-night.
(BREATHES RAGGEDLY)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHOOSHING)
(GASPS)
That's not true.
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
What was that?
I manifested a creature
from a human nightmare.
It's calling across
the time waves.
A pet?
I want to see.
DOCTOR: Oh, nice entrance.
Welcome to Aleppo.
Very beautiful city.
How are you here?
I'm that little bit smarter
than you thought I was.
Now, listen to me -
Earth is not your plaything.
You're wrong about humans.
They're not pathetic.
They're magnificent.
They live with their fears,
doubts, guilts.
They face them down every day,
and they prevail.
That's not weakness.
That's strength.
That's what humanity is.
- Isn't that right, Tahira?
- Yes, Doctor.
Why don't you show them
- how strong you are?
- (GROWLS)
TAHIRA: My Chagaska!
ZELLIN: How can you control it?
(GROWLS)
Literally conquered her fear.
Are you...confronting us?
Yeah!
You immortals -
so entitled, so spoiled.
You never clear up
after yourself.
And you should be
really careful
what you leave lying around.
(RUMBLING)
Sorry. I won't do that again.
Just returning
your lost property.
(SONIC WHIRS)
Thanks for lending
a helping hand.
- Really?
- I couldn't resist.
What's your worst nightmare?
- (WHOOSHING)
- Now, Tahira!
(GROWLS)
- (ROARS)
- (BOTH SCREAM)
TAHIRA: You made
my nightmares real.
Now you can live with them
for all eternity.
Yes! Gods back in their box.
We need to get this
back to the monitor platform...
...and all those people out of
the TARDIS Jacuzzi. Come on!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Slept like a baby last night!
Good, cos you need
all the beauty sleep
you can get.
Oi! Man's still looking fresh.
Oh!
What, you'll be going again?
Yeah.
But you could've told me
the truth about it all.
Would you have believed me?
(INHALES SHARPLY) Nope.
(CHUCKLES)
There's a bit more than
just the world you're seeing.
Do you know
when you'll be back?
Not sure.
Well, don't make it too long.
I need my best mate.
(CHUCKLES) I get a bit lost
without him.
Yeah, I get that too.
Look, I've been looking
at something that might help,
for my mate,
and there's something
I need you to do for me -
and you can't argue.
TIBO: I get down.
And I shut myself off.
And it's like
I'm paralysed with it.
For days, weeks...
It's in control of me.
And I thought I'd try
and do something about it.
I went to the supermarket
just so I could talk
to the cashier,
you know,
get back to human contact.
But I got there...
...and it's
those self-service checkouts!
(GENTLE LAUGHTER)
I haven't said that
to anyone before.
I felt like it was just me.
It's not just you.
(SIGHS)
POLICE OFFICER: Hitchhiking?
No.
Just taking in the view?
Not breaking the law, am I?
OFFICER: No.
Where are you off to?
Away.
It's good there.
- Leave me alone.
- Can't do that.
Why not?
People are worried about you.
No, they're not.
Your sister is.
That's why she called us.
She's worried you've left
and are going to do
something stupid.
I've heard things are tough.
Getting bullied at school.
Grades have gone a bit wonky.
Parents don't get what's up.
You must be feeling
pretty trapped and alone.
I'm feeling way more than that.
(SIGHS)
That's better
than the other way.
What?
Well, feeling things
isn't wrong.
- I don't want your speech.
- I know.
Terrible thing
about being older
is you have all this experience
and nobody
ever wants to hear it.
Cos I know that
there's so much ahead of you.
What if this moment,
where you want to run,
away from everyone,
including yourself,
is just that?
A moment.
What if we find a way
to get you through it
and out of the other side?
I've been where you are.
Moments change.
Help's out there.
As much or as little
as you need.
I'm not listening to you.
Would hard cash
make a difference?
I'll make you a deal.
Look me up in three years.
If I'm wrong,
I'll give you 50 quid.
I mean, I'd say more,
but the pay's rubbish.
Get another job, then.
Can't. Love it too much.
But if I'm right...
...you owe me 50p.
Come on, those are good odds.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hi. Can I help you?
Hi. You won't remember me.
My name's Yasmin.
Yasmin Khan.
I flippin' do remember you.
I've got something for you.
You wanna come in?
GRAHAM: The thing is, Doc,
I worry
about getting sick again.
You know, about the...
...about the cancer
coming back.
And I didn't know
who to say it to,
so I thought I'd say it to you.
You know,
seeing as you're a doctor.
You know, cos once...
...once you have it,
it's with you the whole time.
Not quite a shadow, but...
Hey, don't get me wrong.
I mean, my check-ups,
they're all fine, but it...it
made me think, you know,
and, um, I thought
I should talk about it,
cos those nightmares, I mean...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, they made me realise
that the fear is...is...is
still there, you know.
(THRUMMING)
I should say a reassuring thing
now, shouldn't I?
Yeah, probably.
I'm still
quite socially awkward.
(THRUMMING)
So I'm just going to subtly
walk towards the console
and look at something.
And then, in a minute...
...I'll think of something
that I should've said...
...that might
have been helpful.
(LAUGHS) OK.
Well...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm glad we had this chat, eh?
- Yeah.
RYAN: How long
is this going to last, Yaz?
Hanging out with the Doctor?
I don't know.
Is this our lives?
Going from one place
to the next, ignoring home?
We're getting older,
but without them.
Missing out
bits of their lives.
When we're done,
the Doctor can drop you off
at whatever point you want,
though.
Yeah, but we'll have changed.
They wouldn't have.
It's like we're living
at different rates.
The Doctor said we wouldn't
come back the same.
I was thinking...
Frankenstein.
- BOTH: What?
- Did I interrupt?
Am I interrupting?
- No.
- Cool.
You might need
a change of clothes!
- On we go.
Hi.
(TARDIS THRUMS)
How about writing
the most gruesome,
spine-chilling ghost story
of all time?
- (ALL SCREAM)
- Tales Of The Dead.