NEWSREADER: Solar flare
activity has increased across space lanes 556
and all commercial flights
are advised...
(THROBBING HUM)
(WHOOSHING)
So, it's 200,000, it's a spaceship...
No, wait a minute, space station.
And, er...
Go try that gate over there!
Off you go.
-200,0007 Right.
-200,000.
Adam! Out you come.
-Oh, my God.
-ROSE: Don't worry, you'll get used to it.
-Where are we?
-ROSE: Good question.
Let's see. So, um...
Judging by the architecture,
I'd say we're around the year 200,000.
-Uh-huh, yeah.
-ROSE: And if you listen...
Engines.
We're on some sort
of space station.
Yeah, definitely
a space station.
It's a bit warm in here,
they could turn the heating down.
Tell you what,
let's try that gate. Come on.
Here we go.
And this is...
ROSE: I'll let the Doctor
describe it.
The Fourth Great and Bountiful
Human Empire. And there it is.
Planet Earth, at its height.
Covered with mega-cities, five
moons, population 96 billion,
the hub of a galactic domain
stretching across a million planets,
a million species,
with mankind right in the middle.
He's your boyfriend.
Not anymore.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
DOCTOR: Come on, Adam,
open your mind. You're gonna like this
fantastic period of history,
the human race at its most intelligent.
Culture! Art! Politics!
This era has got fine food,
good manners, the works...
Out the way!
MAN 1: Let's get to it.
Thank you very much, indeed.
Somebody there? That's right. What do
you want, love? Keep it moving.
-I'll be with you lot in a minute. Here you are.
-MAN 2: One at a time!
Now what was it? Kronkburger with
cheese, kronkburger with pa jatos.
Oi! You, mate! Stop pushing.
Get back! I said back!
-Fine cuisine?
-My watch must be wrong.
No, it's fine. That's weird.
That's what comes of showing off. Your
history's not as good as you thought it was.
-My history is perfect.
-Well, obviously not.
They're all human. What
about the millions of planets,
millions of species,
where are they?
Good question.
Actually, that is a good question.
Adam, me old mate,
you must be starving!
No, I'm just a bit time sick.
You just need grub.
Oi, mate! How much is a kronkburger?
Two credits twenty,
sweetheart. Now, join the queue!
Money! We need money.
Let's use a cash point.
(WHIRRING)
There you go, pocket money.
Don't spend it all on sweets.
Well, how does it work?
Go and find out,
stop nagging me!
The thing is, Adam,
time travel's like visiting Paris.
You can't just read
the guidebook, you gotta throw yourself in.
Eat the food,
use the wrong verbs,
get charged double
and end up kissing complete strangers.
Or is that just me?
Stop asking questions,
go and do it!
Off you go, then.
Your first date.
You're gonna get a smack,
you are!
Um, this is gonna sound daft,
but can you tell me where I am?
Floor 139.
-Could they write it any bigger?
-Floor 139 of what?
Must have been a hell
of a party.
-Are you on Satellite Five?
-What's Satellite Five?
Come on, how could you
get on board without knowing where you are?
Look at me, I'm stupid.
Hold on, wait a minute.
Are you a test?
-Some sort of management test kind of thing?
-You've got me.
Well done.
You're too clever for me.
We were warned about this
in basic training.
All workers have to be versed
in company promotion.
Right, fire away,
ask your questions.
If it gets me to Floor
500, I'll do anything.
Why? What happens
on Floor 5007
The walls are made of gold.
And you should know,
Mr Management.
So, this is what we do.
Latest news.
Sandstorms on the New Venus Archipelago,
200 dead.
Glasgow water riots
into their third day.
Space lane 77 closed
by sunspot activity.
And over on the Bad Wolf channel, the Face of
Boe has just announced he's pregnant.
I get it.
You broadcast the news.
We are the news.
We're the journalists.
We write it, package
it and sell it.
600 channels, all coming out
of Satellite Five, broadcasting everywhere.
Something
is wrong.
Something fictional.
Those people.
Nothing happens in the whole Human
Empire without it going through us.
Security check.
Go deep.
VOICE OVER INTERCOM:
All staff are reminded that the canteen area
now operates a
self-cleaning table system. Thank you.
Try this, it's called Zaffic.
It's nice, like, um,
a Slush Puppy.
What flavour?
It's sort of beef.
Oh, my God!
(LAUGHING)
It's like everything's gone.
Home, family...
Everything.
This helps.
The Doctor gave it a bit of a top-up.
Who's back home,
your mum and dad?
Yeah.
Phone them up.
But that's 198,000 years ago.
Honestly, try it.
Go on.
-Is there a code for planet Earth?
-Just dial!
(BEEPING)
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
WOMAN: I'm sorry we're not in.
-It's her.
-Please leave a message. Thanks, bye!
(BEEPS)
Hi!
It... It's me.
I've sort of gone traveling.
I met these people,
and we're traveling together.
But, um, I'm fine.
And I'll call you later.
Love you. Bye.
(LAUGHS)
(KLAXON SOUNDS)
Oi, Mutt and Jeff! Over here!
COMPUTER:
Security check cleared.
No, something's wrong.
I can taste it.
A tiny little shift
in the information.
Someone down there
shouldn't be here.
Double check. Triple check.
Follow them.
Now, everybody behave.
We have a management
inspection.
How do want it? By the book?
Right from scratch, thanks.
Okay. So, ladies, gentlemen,
multisex, undecided or robot,
my name
is Cathica Santini Khadeni.
That's Cathica with a C,
in case you wanna write
to Floor 500, praising me, and please do.
Now, please feel free
to ask any questions.
The process of news gathering
must be open,
honest and beyond bias.
That's company policy.
Actually, um, it's the law.
Yes, thank you, Suki.
Okay, keep it calm.
Don't show off for the guests.
Here we go.
And...
Engage safety.
(HUMMING)
And three...
Two... And spike!
Compressed information
streaming into her.
Reports from every city,
every country, every planet,
and they all get packaged
inside her head.
She becomes part
of the software.
Her brain is the computer!
If it all goes through her,
she must be a genius.
Nah, she wouldn't remember
any of it.
There's too much.
Her head would blow up.
The brain's the processor.
Soon as it closes,
she forgets.
What about all these people
round the edge?
They've all got tiny little
chips in their head
connecting them to her,
and they transmit 600 channels.
Every single fact
in the Empire beams out of this place.
Now, that's what I call power.
COMPUTER: Analysis confirmed.
Security breach.
I knew it. Which one?
It's someone inside
that room. Which one?
Isolating breach.
Come on. Show me. Who is it?
ROSE: You all right?
ADAM: I can see her brain.
-Do you wanna get out?
-No, but this...
This technology, it's...
It's amazing.
This technology's wrong.
Trouble?
Oh, yeah.
(ZAPPING)
That's it! Ho, ho, ho, yes!
She's the liar.
Intercept and scan.
Gotcha!
(GASPS)
Come off it, Suki,
I wasn't even halfway. What was that for?
Sorry.
It must've been a glitch.
Her information's
been tampered with.
There's a second biography
hidden underneath.
- (CREATURE GROWLING)
-Yes, sir. Absolutely, sir.
Yeah, her data was encrypted but there's no
way we could have found her sooner.
-(GROWLING)
-Yeah, sorry, I... Yeah, sorry, sir.
-Yeah, absolutely.
Get her up here! Now!
WOMAN: Promotion.
CATHICA: Come on,
this is it, come on!
Oh, my God, make it me!
Come on, say my name,
say my name, say my name!
Promotion for...
Suki Macrae Cantrell.
Please proceed to Floor 500.
I don't believe it! Floor 500!
How the hell
did you manage that? I'm above you!
I don't know,
I just applied on the off chance.
And they've said yes!
So not fair. I've been applying
to Floor 500 for three years.
What's Floor 5007
The walls are made of gold.
SUKI: Cathica,
I'm gonna miss you.
-Floor 500. Thank you.
-I didn't do anything.
You're my lucky charm.
All right, I'll hug anyone.
(SUKI LAUGHING)
Come on, it's not that bad.
What, with the...
The head thing?
Yeah, well,
she's closed it now.
Yeah, but...
It's everything.
It freaks me out.
-And I just need to...
-(BEEPING)
Ah, if I could just...
(SIGHS)
Cool down,
sort of acclimatise.
How do you mean?
Maybe I could just
go and sit on the observation deck.
Will that be all right?
Soak it in, you know.
Pretend I'm a citizen of the year 200,000.
Do you want me
to come with you?
No, no, you stick
with the Doctor.
You'd rather be with him.
It's gonna take a better man
than me to get between you two.
Anyway...
I'LL be on the deck.
Here you go,
take the Tardis key.
You know, just in case
it gets a bit too much.
Yeah, like it's not weird
in there.
(BEEPING)
Oh, my God.
I've got to go, I can't keep them waiting.
I'm sorry.
Say goodbye to Steve for me.
Bye!
Good riddance.
You're talking like you'll never see her again.
She's only going upstairs.
We won't. Once you go to Floor 500,
you never come back.
-Have you ever been up there?
-Can't.
You need a key for the lift
and you only get a key with promotion.
No one gets to 500,
except for the chosen few.
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(SUKI SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
Who are you?
I'm the Editor.
What's happening?
There are bodies out there.
What's going on?
While we're asking questions,
would you please confirm your name?
My name is
Suki Macrae Cantrell.
I was born 199°'89,
in the Independent Republic
of Morocco.
Liar!
Hobbies include reading
and archaeology.
I'm not an expert or anything,
I just like digging.
Liar!
I want to work for
Satellite Five because
my sister can't
afford university.
And the pay-scheme
Is really good...
Liar!
Let's look at the facts,
shall we?
Ah.
Hidden behind a genetic graft,
but that's still you.
Eva Saint Julienne,
last surviving member of the Freedom Fifteen.
Hmm, self-declared anarchist.
Is that right?
Who controls Satellite Five?
(LAUGHING)
There's the truth.
The Freedom Foundation has been
monitoring Satellite Five's transmissions.
We have absolute proof
that the facts are being manipulated.
You are lying to the people.
Ooh, I love it.
Say it again.
This whole system is corrupt.
Who do you represent?
I'm merely a humble slave.
I answer
to the Editor In Chief.
-Who is he, where is he?
-He's overseeing everything.
Literally everything.
If you don't mind, I'm gonna
have to refer this upwards.
(CREATURE GROWLING)
-What is that?
-Your boss.
This has always
been your boss.
Since the day you were born.
(FIRING GUN)
(SCREAMING)
Give me access.
Give me...
I can learn anything.
Let's try, uh, computers.
From the 21st century
to the present day,
give me the history
of the microprocessor.
Oh, my God.
Look, they only give us 20 minutes
maintenance. Can't you give it a rest?
But you've never been to another
floor? Not even one floor down?
I went to floor 16
when I first arrived.
That's medical, that's when
I got my head done. And then I...
I came straight here.
Satellite Five, you work, eat, and sleep on
the same floor, and that's it, that's all.
You're not management,
are you?
At last! She's clever.
Yeah, well, whatever it is,
don't involve me. I don't know anything.
-Don't you even ask?
-Why would I?
You're a journalist!
Why's all the crew human?
What's that got
to do with anything?
There's no aliens on board.
Why?
I don't know.
No real reason.
-They're not banned or anything.
-Then where are they?
I suppose Immigration's tightened up.
It's had to, what with all the threats.
What threats?
I don't know, all of them,
usual stuff.
And the price of space warp
doubled, so that kept the visitors away.
Oh, and the government
on Chavic Five collapsed,
so that lot stopped coming, you see?
Just lots of little reasons,
that's all.
Adding up to one, great big fact.
And you didn't even notice.
Doctor, I think, if there
was any sort of conspiracy,
Satellite Five
would have seen it.
-We see everything.
-I can see better.
This society's the wrong shape,
even the technology.
-It's cutting edge!
-It's backwards.
There's a great big door
in your head.
-You should've chucked this out years ago!
-So what you think's going on?
It's not just this space station,
it's the whole attitude.
It's the way people think.
The Great and Bountiful Human Empire is
stunted. Something's holding it back.
And how would you know?
Trust me.
Humanity's been
set back about 90 years.
When did Satellite Five
start broadcasting?
91 years ago.
Mum, Dad, keep this message,
okay?
Whatever you do,
don't erase it.
Save it, you got that?
The microprocessor became
redundant in the year 2019,
replaced by a system called,
SMT, that's Single Molecule
Transcription.
No, no, no, no, no!
What are you doing?
Come back, come...
Why are you doing that?
What's Floor 16?
What's down there?
Sorry, um...
Floor 16, that's, um...
What do you cover?
Medical non-emergency.
Right, yeah, wrong floor.
I'm having technical difficulties.
My screen keeps freezing,
locking me out.
No, that's medical. There must be
something wrong with your chip.
Yes!
Yeah, of course, yeah!
I haven't got one.
No wonder you can't
get a screen to work.
What are you, a...
Student?
Yes. Yeah, I'm, um...
I'm on a research project...
From the University of Mars.
The Martian boondocks,
typical.
Yep!
(LAUGHS)
Well, you still need chipping.
So, does that mean, like...
Brain surgery?
That's an old-fashioned
phrase.
But it's the same thing, yes.
Oh!
Okay, never mind.
But if I get a chip,
that means I could use
any computer?
Absolutely.
You'll have to pay for it.
They've stopped subsidising.
Oh, right, sorry.
Wasting your time.
Thanks.
Hold on.
Can I use this?
That'll do nicely.
It all comes down
to two basic types.
Type one, the head chip,
inserted into the back
of the skull, 100 credits.
There's the chip.
Tiny, invisible, no scarring.
Type two is the full
info-spike.
Oh, um, that's the...
-Thing.
-That's the one.
It does cost 10,000.
Oh, well I, um,
I couldn't afford it then.
Not at all.
Turns out you've got unlimited credit.
No, but I...
Well, I couldn't have it done.
I mean, that's gotta hurt,
hasn't it?
Painless.
Contractual guarantee.
No, my, my mate's
waiting upstairs,
I can't have major surgery.
(LAUGHS)
It takes ten minutes.
That sort of money buys
a very fast pico-surgeon.
No, but I...
I couldn't though, no.
Type one, you can interface
with a simple computer.
Type two,
you are the computer.
You can transmit any
piece of information
from the archive
of Satellite Five
which is just about the entire
history of the human race.
Now...
Which one's it going to be?
We're so gonna get in trouble.
You're not allowed to touch
the mainframe, we'll get told off.
Rose, tell her to button it.
You'll just vandalise the place,
someone's gonna notice.
EDITOR: I don't understand.
We did a full security scan,
that man was there when
we found Suki Macrae Cantrell.
There were no
indications about him.
And yet here he is.
Clearly acting
outside the parameters.
Fascinating.
(CREATURE GROWLING)
Yes, sir.
Absolutely.
At once.
Check him.
Double check him,
triple check him, quadruple!
This is nothing to do with me,
I'm going back to work.
Go on then, see ya!
I can't just leave you, can I?
If you wanna be useful, get them to turn
the heating down, it's boiling.
What's wrong with this place?
Can't they do something about it?
I don't know, we keep asking.
Something to do with the turbines.
Something to do
with the turbines.
But I don't know.
Exactly. I give up
on you, Cathica.
Now, Rose, look at Rose,
Rose is asking the right kind of questions.
-Ah, thank you.
-Why is it so hot?
One moment you're worried
about the Empire,
and the next minute,
it's the central heating.
Oh, never underestimate plumbing.
Plumbing is very important.
(CRACKLES)
COMPUTER:
Security scan complete.
-Well, who is he?
-He is no one.
(LAUGHS)
What does that mean?
He is no one.
What, you mean
he has a fake ID?
He has no identification.
But everyone's registered.
We have a census for the entire Empire!
He is no one.
What, he doesn't exist?
-Not anywhere?
-He is no one.
What about the blonde?
-She is no one.
-Both of them?
(CHUCKLES)
Well, we all know what happens
to non-entities.
They get promoted.
Bring them up!
Here we go, Satellite Five.
Pipes and plumbing. Look at the layout.
CATHICA: This is ridiculous.
You've got access to
the computer's core.
You could look at the archive,
the news, the stock exchange...
-And you're looking at pipes?
-But there's something wrong.
-I suppose.
-Why, what is it?
The ventilation system.
Cooling ducts, ice filters.
All working flat out.
Channelling massive
amounts of heat down.
-All the way from the top.
-Floor 500.
Something up there
is generating tons and tons of heat.
Well, I don't know about you,
but I feel like I'm missing out on a party.
It's all going on upstairs.
-Fancy a trip?
-You can't, you need a key.
Keys are just codes,
and I've got the codes right here. Here we go.
Override 215.9.
CATHICA: How come it's giving
you the code?
Someone up there likes me.
(LAUGHING)
I told you it was painless.
No scarring, you see?
Perfect success.
How do I activate it?
It's a personal choice.
Some people whistle.
I know one man who triggers it
with Oh, Danny Boy.
But you're set
on default for now.
That's a click of the fingers.
So, you mean I just...
Click.
-Come on, come with us.
-No way!
-Bye!
-Well, don't mention my name.
When you get in trouble,
just don't involve me.
That's her gone, Adam's given up,
looks like it's just you and me.
-Yeah.
-Good.
Yep.
(BEEPING)
Oh, my God! I'm gonna be sick!
(RETCHING)
Special offer.
We installed the vomit-o-matic
at the same time.
Nano-termites have been placed
in the lining of your throat.
In the event of sickness,
they freeze the waste.
The walls are not made
of gold.
You should go back downstairs.
Tough.
I started without you.
This is fascinating.
(LAUGHS)
Satellite Five contains
every piece of information
within the Fourth Great
and Bountiful Human Empire.
Birth certificates, shopping habits,
bank statements, but you two...
You don't exist.
(CHUCKLES)
There's not a trace.
No birth, no job,
not the slightest kiss.
How can you walk through
the world and not leave a single footprint?
Suki! Suki!
Hello?
Can you hear me? Suki?
-What have you done to her?
-I think she's dead.
But she's working.
They've all got chips in their head,
and the chips keep going.
-Like puppets.
-Oh!
You are full of information.
But it's only fair we get
some information back.
Because, apparently
you're no one. (CHUCKLES)
It's so rare
not to know something.
Who are you?
It doesn't matter,
'cause we're off. Nice to meet you.
Come on!
Tell me who you are.
Since that information is keeping us alive,
I'm hardly gonna say, am I?
Well, perhaps my
Editor-In-Chief can convince you otherwise.
And who's that?
It may interest you to know
that this is not the Fourth Great
and Bountiful Human Empire.
In fact, it's not actually
human at all.
It's merely a place
where humans happen to live.
(CREATURE GROWLING)
Yep. Yep.
Sorry!
It's a place where humans
are allowed to live
by kind permission
of my client.
-(SNAPPING)
-(GROWLING)
What is that?
You mean that thing's in
charge of Satellite Five?
"That thing"”, as you put it,
is in charge of the human race.
For almost 100 years,
mankind has been shaped and guided.
His knowledge and ambition,
strictly controlled by its broadcast news.
Edited by my superior,
your master,
and humanity's quiding light,
the Mighty Jagrafess of the
Holy Hadrojassic Maxarodenfoe.
I call him Max.
(BEEPING)
Create a climate of fear,
and it's easy to keep the borders closed.
It's just a matter
of emphasis.
The right word
in the right broadcast,
repeated often enough,
can destabilize an economy.
Invent an enemy.
Change a vote.
So all the people on
Earth are like slaves?
Well, now,
there's an interesting point.
Is a slave a slave if
he doesn't know he's enslaved?
Yes.
Oh, I was hoping
for a philosophical debate.
Is that all I'm gonna get?
llYeSll?
-Yes.
-(EDITOR LAUGHS)
You're no fun.
Let me out of these manacles.
You'll find out how much fun I am.
Oh, he's tough, isn't he?
(CHUCKLES)
But come on!
Isn't it a great system?
You've got to admire it,
just a little bit.
You can't hide something on this scale,
somebody must've noticed.
From time to time,
someone, yes.
But the computer chip system
allows me to see inside their brains.
I can see the smallest doubt
and crush it.
And then they just carry on,
living the life,
strutting about downstairs
and all over the surface
of the Earth, like they're so individual.
When, of course, they're not.
They're just cattle.
In that respect, the Jagrafess
hasn't changed a thing.
But what about you?
You're not a Jagra... Uh, belly...
-Jagrafess.
-Jagrafess. You're not a Jagrafess.
You're human.
Yeah, well, simply being human
doesn't pay very well.
But you couldn't have done this
all on your own.
No! (CHUCKLES)
I represent a consortium
of banks.
Money prefers
a long-term investment.
Also the Jagrafess
needed a little hand to, um, install himself.
DOCTOR: No wonder,
creature that size. What's its lifespan?
EDITOR: 3,000 years.
DOCTOR: That's one hell
of a metabolism, generating all that heat.
That's why
Satellite Five's so hot.
You pump it out the creature,
channel it downstairs.
Jagrafess stays cool,
stays alive.
Satellite Five is one great
big life-support system.
(DIALLING)
Me again.
Don't wipe this message.
It's just gonna sound like
white noise.
But save it,
"cause I can translate it, okay?
Three,
two,
one, and spike!
But that's why
you're so dangerous.
Knowledge is power,
but you remain unknown. (CHUCKLES)
-(ELECTRICAL WHIRRING)
-Who are you?
(DOG BARKING)
Leave her alone!
I'm the Doctor.
She's Rose Tyler,
we're nothing, we're just wandering.
-Tell me who you are!
-I've just said!
Yeah, but who do you work for?
Who sent you?
Who knows about us?
Who exactly...
Time Lord.
What?
Oh, yes!
The last of the Time Lords.
And his traveling machine.
With his little human girl
from long ago.
-Don't know what you're talking about.
-Time travel!
(SCREAMS)
Someone's been telling
you lies.
Young master Adam Mitchell?
(ADAM SCREAMING)
Oh, my God, his head.
What the hell's he done?
What the hell's he gone
and done?
They're reading his mind,
he's telling them everything.
And through him,
I know everything about you.
Every piece of information
in his head is now mine.
And you have infinite
knowledge, Doctor.
The Human Empire is tiny
compared to what you've seen
in your
T-A-R-D-I-S.
Tardis!
Well, you'll never get your hands on it,
I'll die first!
Well, die all you like,
I don't need ya. I've got the key.
You and your boyfriends!
Today, we are the headlines.
We can rewrite history.
We could prevent mankind
from ever developing.
And no one's gonna stop you.
Because you bred a human race
which doesn't bother to ask questions.
Stupid little slaves
believing every lie.
They'll just trot right into the slaughter house
if they're told it's made of gold.
(MAX GROWLING)
Disengage safety.
(ALARM BEEPING)
What's happening?
Maximum access,
override Floor 139.
And... Spike!
Someone's disengaged
the safety.
Who's that?
-It's Cathica.
-And she's thinking.
She's using what she knows.
Terminate her access.
Everything I told her
about Satellite Five,
the pipes, the filters,
she's reversing it.
Look at that.
It's getting hot.
I said, terminate.
Burn out her mind.
Oh, no, you don't!
You should've
promoted me years back.
She's venting the heat
up here.
The Jagrafess needs
to stay cool,
and now it's sitting
on top of a volcano! (LAUGHS)
(GROWLING)
Yes, I'm trying, sir.
But I don't know how she did it,
it's impossible.
A member of staff
with an idea!
(SHRIEKING)
-What do I do?
-Flick the switch!
(WHIRRING)
(SHRIEKING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Oi, mate!
You want to bank on a certainty?
Massive heat
in a massive body,
massive bang!
See you in the headlines!
(WHOOSHING)
Actually, sir,
if it's all the same to you, I think I'll resign.
Bye, then.
Let go of me!
(RUMBLING)
(CIRCUITS SCRAMBLING)
(SHRIEKING)
Let go of me!
(GRUNTS) Let go of me!
-(CREATURE GROWLING)
-(SCREAMING)
We're just gonna go.
I hate tidying up.
Too many questions.
You'll manage.
You'll have to stay and explain it.
No one's gonna believe me.
Well, they might start
believing a lot of things now.
Human race should accelerate.
All back to normal.
What about your friend?
He's not my friend.
Now, don't...
I'm all right now.
Much better.
And I've got the key.
Look, it's...
And, well...
It all worked out
for the best, didn't it?
You know, it's not actually my fault,
because you were in charge.
It's my house. I'm home.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, my God, I'm home!
Blimey. I thought you
were gonna chuck me out of an airlock.
Is there something else
you want to tell me?
No. Erm, what do you mean?
The archive of Satellite Five.
One second of that message
could have changed the world.
(WHIRRING)
That's it, then. See ya.
-How do you mean, "See ya"?
-As in, goodbye.
What about me?
You can't just go.
I've got my head.
I've got a chip type two.
My head opens.
-What, like this?
-(WHIRRS)
Don't!
Don't do what?
Stop it!
All right now, Doctor.
That's enough. Stop it.
Thank you.
-0
- (CHUCKLES) Sorry, I couldn't resist.
The whole of history
could have changed because of you.
I just wanted to help.
You were helping yourself.
And I'm sorry.
And I've said I'm sorry, and I am, I really am.
But you can't just
leave me like this.
Yes, I can. 'Cause if you show that head to
anyone, they'll dissect you in seconds.
You'll have to lead a very quiet life.
Keep out of trouble.
Be average. Unseen. Good luck.
But I wanna come with you.
I only take the best.
I've got Rose.
ADAM: Rose, Rose!
-Oh, my God!
-ADAM'S MUM: Who's that?
-Geoff, is that you?
-It's me, Mum.
ADAM: Don't come in,
wait there a minute.
Oh, my Lord! You never told me
you were coming home!
ADAM'S MUM: Hold on,
I'll just take my coat off.
I wish you'd told me
you were coming home.
Rose, take me with you.
ADAM'S MUM: I would've
got your favourite tea in.
(THROBBING HUM)
What's that noise?
Have you left
the back door open?
Blimey, there's a draft.
What a surprise!
Oh, let me look at you.
Ah, six months.
It's like I saw you yesterday.
Isn't it funny?
-The time goes by like that.
-(SNAPS)
(HEAD WHIRRS)
Your wish is my command,
but be careful what you wish for.
The day my father died.
Thought it'd be all grim and stormy.
It's just an ordinary day.
Oh, God, this is it.
He can't die on his own!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Can I try again?
Oh, gosh, this is it.
Rose! No!
I did it again,
I picked another stupid ape!
It's not like
I've changed history.
Rose, there's a man
alive in the world who wasn't alive before.
The whole world's different
because he's alive!
Time's been damaged,
and they've come to sterilise the wound.
Rose, get in the church!
(SCREAMING)