(TINKLING)
-What's wrong?
-Man wounded.
Wake him.
He slipped in the bilge water, Captain,
and fell under the rigger.
His hand...
I don't know if he'll survive.
You're a dead man, McGrath.
Same as all the others.
(WOMAN SINGING HAUNTING TUNE)
She's here.
Oh, save our souls.
-I've got to escape!
-Don't go out there! McGrath!
Don't listen, for God's sake.
The siren is a-calling!
(SIREN CONTINUES SINGING)
(McGrath SCREAMING)
Same as all the others.
No sign of a struggle.
No bones or blood.
We're shark bait,
every single one of us.
Stuck on the ocean. Waiting.
Until the wind changes.
(THUMPING)
-What's that?
-That's the creature. It's returned.
Yo ho ho!
Or does nobody actually say that?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
We made no signal.
Our sensors picked you up.
Ship in distress.
-Sensors?
-Yes.
Okay, problem word, 17th century.
My ship automatically...noticed-ish
that your ship was having some bother.
That big blue crate?
That is more magic, Captain Avery.
They're spirits.
How else would they have
found their way below decks?
Well... I want to say
multi-dimensional engineering,
but since you had a problem
with sensors I won't go there. Look.
I'm the Doctor, this is Amy, Rory.
We're sailors, same as you. Arr!
Except for the gun thing.
And the beardiness.
You're stowaways!
Only explanation.
Eight days we've been stranded here,
becalmed.
You must have stowed away
before we sailed.
BOATSWAIN: What do we do with them?
Oh, I think,
they deserve our hospitality.
(PIRATES LAUGHING)
I suppose laughing like that
is in the job description.
"Can you do the laugh? Check.
"Grab yourself a parrot.
Welcome aboard.”
Stocks are low.
Only one barrel of water remains.
We don't need three more
empty bellies to fill.
-Take the doxy below, to the galley.
-Hey.
Set her to work.
She won't need much feeding.
-Rory, a little help?
-Hey, listen, right.
She's not a doxy.
I didn't mean just tell him off.
Thanks anyway.
If you're lucky, you'll drown
before the sharks can take a bite.
If this is just because
I'm a captain too,
you know, you shouldn't feel threatened.
Your ship is much bigger than mine.
And I don't have the cool boots
or a hat, even.
Time to go.
A bit more laughter, guys?
(PIRATES LAUGHING)
Where are the rest of the crew?
This is a big ship, big for five of you.
I suppose the rest of them
are hiding someplace
and they're all going to jump out
and shout boo.
AMY: Boo!
Throw the gun down.
-The rest of you, on your knees.
-Amy, what are you doing?
Saving your life.
Okay with that, are you?
Put down the sword.
A sword could kill us all, girl.
Yeah, thanks. That's actually
why I'm pointing it at you.
(SHOUTS)
(GASPS)
(PIRATES WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTS)
(AMY SHOUTS)
(SHOUTS)
Yarr!
(SCREAMS)
-You have killed me.
-No way. It's just a cut.
-What kind of rubbish pirates are you?
-One drop. That's all it takes.
One drop of blood
and she'll rise out of the ocean.
Come on. I barely even scratched him.
What are you all in such a huff about?
(SCREAMING)
Ow, ah!
Ow.
Ah, Doctor, what's happening to me?
She can smell the blood on your skin,
-she's marked you for death.
-She?
-A demon, out there in the ocean.
-Okay. Groovy.
So not just pirates today.
We've managed to bagsy a ship
where there's a demon popping in.
Very efficient. I mean,
if something's going to kill you,
it's nice that it drops you
a note to remind you.
(SIREN SINGING)
BOATSWAIN: Quickly now.
Block out the sound.
-What?
-The creature.
She charms all her victims
with that song.
Oh, great, so put my fingers in my ears.
That's your plan?
Doctor, come on. Let's go. Let's get
back to the... Oh. Back to the...
The music. It's working on him. Look.
You are so beautiful.
-What?
-Oh! No, I love your get-up.
That's great. You should dress
as a pirate more often, huh?
-Hey, hey, cuddle me, shipmate.
-Rory, stop.
Everything is totally
brilliant, isn't it? Huh?
Look at these brilliant pirates.
Look at their brilliant beards.
I'd like a beard.
-I'm going to grow a beard.
-AMY: You're not!
The music turns them into fools.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, my God.
(SIREN SINGING)
(CONTINUES SINGING)
-I have to touch her. Let me touch her!
-Sorry, but he is spoken for.
(SCREECHING)
(AMY SCREAMS)
Amy! Amy.
Everybody into the hold.
(CONTINUES SINGING)
Rory! Come on.
-Come on.
-Hey! Wait!
RORY: Get off!
-AMY: What is that thing?
-The legend. The siren.
Many a merchant ship laden with
treasure has fallen prey to her.
She's been hunting us
ever since we were becalmed.
-Picking off the injured.
-Like a shark. A shark can smell blood.
Okay. Just like a shark,
in a dress and singing and green!
A green singing shark
in an evening gown.
-The ship is cursed.
-Yeah, right.
"Cursed” is big with humans.
It means bad things are happening
but you can't be bothered
to find an explanation.
She's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
Actually, I think you'll find she isn't.
We have to leave. Right now.
-That crate of yours really is a ship?
-Well, it's not propelled by the wind.
-Show me. Weigh anchor. Make it sail!
-And the gun's back.
You're big on the gun thing, aren't you?
Freud would say you're compensating.
Ever met Freud? No.
-Comfy sofa.
-Leave the cursed one, Captain.
-The creature can have him.
-Yes, please.
We don't want the siren coming after us.
(PIRATE SCREAMING)
-AMY: It's a leech!
-Everyone out of the water!
It's bitten me, I'm bleeding!
She wants blood.
Why does she want blood?
What were you saying about
leaving the cursed ones behind?
DOCTOR: It's okay. We're safe down here.
No curse is getting through
three solid inches of timber.
-(SINGING)
-Ah. Hello again.
-No! No!
-No!
(SCREAMING)
-"Safe"?
-I have my good days and my bad days.
How did she get in?
Bilge water.
She's using water like a portal. A door.
She can materialise
through a single drop.
We need to go somewhere with no water.
Well, thank God we're not
in the middle of the ocean.
RORY: Did you see her eyes?
-Like crystal pools.
-You are in enough trouble.
-The magazine!
-What?
He means the armoury,
where the powder's stored.
-It's dry as a bone.
-Good, let's go there.
-I give the orders.
-Ah.
Worried because I'm wearing a hat now?
-Nobody touch anything sharp!
-AMY: Come on, Rory.
-Quickly, man.
-I... I can't.
-The key is gone, Captain.
-How can it have gone?
Someone else had the same idea.
Barricade the door.
Careful of that lantern.
-Every barrel is full of powder.
-Who's been sleeping in my gun room?
(MUFFLED COUGHING)
You fool! You fool, boy.
What are you doing here?
-BOATSWAIN: Who is he?
-What, he's not one of the crew?
No.
He's my son.
What in God's name possessed you, boy?
Your mother will be searching for you.
When?
Last winter.
Fever.
(AVERY SIGHING)
She told me all about you.
How you were a Captain in the Navy.
"An honourable man," she said.
How I would be proud to know you.
-I've come to join your crew.
-I don't want you here.
You can't send me back. It's too late.
-We're a 100 miles from home.
-It's dangerous here.
There is a monster aboard.
She leaves a mark on men's skin.
The black spot?
(COUGHING)
There's nothing wrong with the boy.
He has no scars.
-Yep. Ignore my last theory.
-He has his good days and his bad days.
It's not just blood. She's coming
for all the sick and wounded,
like a hunter chooses
his weakest animal.
Okay, look. He's got fever.
The siren knows it.
Humans. Second-rate. Damage too easily.
It's only a matter of time
before everyone gets bruised.
My ship.
It can sail us all away from here.
You and me, we fetch it. Let's go.
You're not the Captain here, remember?
(SIREN SINGING)
The water's dangerous.
That's how she gets through.
One touch of her hand
and you're a dead man!
-We're all cursed if we stay aboard.
-It's not a curse.
Curse means game over.
Curse means we're helpless.
We are not helpless!
Captain, what's our next move?
-AVERY: Wait with the boy.
-Captain, we're all in danger here.
I said wait and barricade
the door after we've gone.
-Sure you want to go?
-We have to get Rory and Toby away.
She's out there now, licking her lips,
boiling a saucepan, grating cheese.
Okay. Well, remember if you get an itch,
don't scratch too hard.
We've all got to go sometime.
There are worse ways than having your
face snogged off by a dodgy mermaid.
Do you want to draw lots
for who's in charge, then?
Darkness. Demon.
-You can have first go.
-(AVERY LAUGHS)
-Nearly.
-Phew!
-By all the...
-Let me stop you there.
Bigger on the inside.
Don't mind, do you, if we just
skip to the end of that moment?
Oh, and sorry I lied, by the way,
when I said yours was bigger.
Kitchen that way. Choice of bathrooms
there, there, there.
(COUGHING)
What's wrong?
The most beautiful thing
you've ever seen.
Oh, tell me I didn't really say that.
What's going on?
We're not staying here
to mollycoddle the boy.
The Captain's gone soft.
It's time for us to leave.
What's this do?
That does very, very complicated.
That does sophisticated.
That does whoa, amazing!
And that does whizz, bang,
far too technical to explain!
-Wheel?
-Atom accelerator.
-It steers the thing.
-No! Sort of. Yes.
Wheel. Telescope. Astrolabe. Compass.
A ship's a ship.
Good man.
He told you to wait, you dog.
He's your Captain. A naval officer.
You're honour-bound to do
as he tells you.
Honour-bound?
Do you know what kind of ship this is?
-Do you know what your father does?
-Don't listen to him, Toby.
We sail under the black flag.
The Jolly Roger.
Liar!
-He's no wicked pirate!
-Oh, you think so?
I've seen your father gun down
a thousand innocent men.
This is how the professionals do it.
(ENGINE STALLING)
Um, it's stuck. Not responding.
-Becalmed?
-Mmm-hmm. Apparently. That's new.
-You had to gloat, didn't you?
-I'm not gloating.
I saw that look just now.
"Ha ha. His ship is rubbish."
-True.
-Mmm-hmm.
Get what treasure you can.
I'll meet you in the rowboat.
You're going to remain at your post.
I am not playing games with you, boy.
You put that down.
One more step and I'll use this,
you blackguard.
You don't know how to
fight with a cutlass, boy.
Don't need to, do I?
Ah!
I can't get a lock on the plane.
-The what?
-The space we travel in.
The ocean. Sort of ocean but not water.
The Tardis can't see.
It's sulking because it thinks
the space doesn't exist.
Without a plane to lock onto
we're not going anywhere.
I'm confused.
Yeah, well, it's a big club.
We should get t-shirts.
(EXPLOSIVE RUMBLING)
What's happening?
-You little swabber!
-Congratulations. Made it to the menu.
-Probably shouldn't go out there now.
-You scurvy ape!
Don't shoot!
The powder will blow and kill us all.
Mulligan, what are you doing?
No honour among pirates.
All right. She's had her little sulk.
Now she's heading for
the full-on screaming tantrum.
-Can you fix it?
-Oh!
The parametric engines are jammed.
Orthogonal vector's gone.
-I'm almost out of ideas.
-Almost?
Well, we could try stroking her
and singing her a song.
-Will that help?
-Hard to say. Never has before.
I've lost control of her.
She's about to dematerialise.
We could end up anywhere!
-That sounds bad.
-Yes, it is!
Out! Now!
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
(WHOOSHING)
Okay. Okay. Oh, okay.
Tardis runs off on its own.
That's a bit of a new one.
Bang goes our only hope
of getting them out of here.
Not much of a Captain
without a ship, are you?
Mulligan?
What are you doing? This is mutiny.
She doesn't want me.
She only wants Toby
and the scrawny looking fellow.
He's got the last of the supplies.
We should go after him.
Never mind the damned supplies.
What about my treasure?
(FIRING)
(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
Don't get injured.
Don't get injured!
AVERY: Come out of there,
you mutinous dog!
(SIREN SINGING)
She's inside. She's come for Mulligan.
(MULLIGAN SCREAMING)
No water in here. How did she take him?
You said she uses water like a door.
That's how she enters a room.
I was wrong.
Please ignore all my theories
up to this point.
What? Again?
We're all in danger.
The water's not how she's getting in.
When we were down in the hold,
think what happened.
-You, me, Amy, Rory, leeches.
-She sprang from the water.
Yes, only when it grew still!
Still water. Nature's mirror.
-So... You mean?
-Yes. Not water.
Reflection.
The siren legend. The curse.
-You said curses weren't real.
-Folklore springs from truth.
She attacks ships filled with treasure.
Where else do you get
a perfect reflection?
-Polished metal.
-Hmm.
We must warn them!
-Amy! Open the door!
-Toby, open the door!
Toby!
-Open the door.
-Toby!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We've got to destroy every reflection.
Gold, Silver, Glass.
She could spring from any of them.
Oh, yes, yes. I know, I know.
Very bad luck to break it.
But look at it this way.
There's a stroppy, homicidal mermaid
trying to kill all.
-How much worse can things get?
-Yep.
Help me lug this lot out.
-Where are we taking it?
-The ocean.
No! No.
This is the treasure
of the Mogul of India.
Oh, good. For a moment there,
I thought it was yours.
Doctor! Wait.
Must we do this?
Any reflection, any mirror
and the siren will attack.
We have to protect Rory and Toby.
Go and get the crown from the storeroom.
(SIREN SINGING)
Just wait?
-Not my most dynamic plan, I realise.
-Tardis.
-It's been towed.
-What?
Sorry.
We might be stuck here for a while.
Oh, so you're saying that we should
all just wait here below?
The sea is still calm, like a mirror.
If you go out on deck,
she'll rise up and attack you.
It's okay. The calm won't last forever.
When the wind picks up,
we'll all set sail.
Until it does,
you have to hide down here.
(SIREN SINGING)
I'm sorry about your mother.
You miss her a lot?
Three years. No word from you.
-Toby...
-You promised her.
You promised you'd come home.
And she believed you would,
right up until the day she died.
What made you do it?
What made you turn pirate?
Get some sleep now.
FEMALE VOICE: It's fine.
You're doing fine.
Just stay calm.
It's not one star, it's two.
The Dog Star.
Sirius. Binary system.
I use it to navigate the oceans.
I've travelled far, like you.
Space can be very lonely.
The greatest adventure is having
someone share it with you.
If we get out of this,
I'll take him back to England.
He can't stay with me.
I'm not the father he needs.
Who are you, Henry Avery?
Respected naval officer,
wife and child at home.
How did you end up here,
wandering the oceans
with a band of rogues?
I've set my course now.
Nothing I can do to alter it.
People stared at it for centuries
and never knew.
Things can suddenly change,
when you're least expecting.
-Doctor, um...
-Shh.
What can you see?
Feels like something's out there,
staring straight at me.
(THUNDERCLAP)
Man the sails!
To the rigging, you dogs!
Let go the sails. Avast ye!
Put the bunt into the slack
of the clews.
I swear he's making half this stuff up.
Well, we're going to need
some kind of phrase book.
(GRUNTING)
Toby!
Find my coat.
My compass is inside it, boy.
Heave ho, you bilge rats.
"Rats" was all I could hear.
(SIREN SINGING)
Don't let her take you!
(SINGING)
No!
(TOBY SCREAMING)
Hang on!
No!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
You couldn't give up the gold,
could you?
That's why you turned pirate!
Your commission, your wife, your son!
Just how much
is that treasure worth to you, man?
(GROANING)
Rory! Rory!
-Rory!
-I can't see him. Doctor, I'm going in!
He's drowning. He's drowning!
You go in after him, you'll drown too.
There's only one thing
that can save him now.
-What are you talking about?
-The siren.
The siren, she wants him.
We have to release her.
Doctor, no.
No!
He's drowning. Go find him!
What did you do?
-If he stays in there, he'll die.
-But she'll destroy him.
That thing isn't just a ravenous hunter.
It's intelligent.
We can reason with it. And maybe,
just maybe,
they're still alive somewhere.
-We have to follow her.
-Are you mad?
If we ever want to see them again,
we have to let the siren take us.
We'll prick our fingers.
All agreed?
-Yeah?
-Aye.
-Aye!
(SINGING)
AMY: Where are we?
We haven't moved.
We're in exactly
the same place as before.
-We're on a ghost ship.
-No. It's real.
A space ship trapped in a temporal rift.
How can two ships be in the same place?
Not the same. Two planes, two worlds.
Two cars parked in the same space.
There are lots of different universes
nested inside each other.
Now and again they collide.
And you can step from one to the other.
Okay. I think I understand.
Good. 'Cause it's not like that at all,
but if that helps.
Thanks.
All the reflections have
suddenly become gateways.
Ever look in a mirror and think
you're seeing a whole other world?
Well, this time it's not an illusion.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
-The signal.
-Yes?
-The distress call.
-Uh-huh.
There was a second ship here
all the time.
(SIREN SINGING)
And the siren is on board.
Dead.
You were right, there was something
staring at us the whole time.
How long has this ship
been marooned here?
Long enough for the Captain
to have run out of grog.
I don't understand. If this is the
Captain, then what's the siren?
Same as us.
A stowaway.
She killed it?
Human bacteria.
-What?
-A virus. From our planet.
Airborne, travelling through the portal.
That's what killed it.
Didn't get its jabs.
-Ugh! Look.
-What is it?
Sneeze!
Alien bogies.
(SENSORS BEEPING)
(SIREN SINGING)
-McGrath! He's one of my men.
-AMY: He's still breathing.
My entire crew is here.
-Toby!
-Rory!
The Tardis!
-We have to get him out of here.
-Wait!
His fever's gone.
Ah.
-He looks so well.
-She's keeping him alive.
His brain is still active but all
its cellular activity is suspended.
It's not a curse, it's a tissue sample.
Why get samples of people
you are about to kill?
Help me get him up?
(SENSOR BEEPING QUICKLY, SIREN SINGING)
She's coming.
(GROANING)
(SINGING)
-Anaesthetic.
-AVERY: What?
Her music. The song.
So she anaesthetises people
and then puts their body in stasis.
Avery. No!
(SCREECHING)
(DOCTOR SNEEZING)
Fire. That's new. Uh...
What does fire do? Burn? Yes.
Destroy. What else?
Sterilise! (STAMMERING) I sneezed.
I brought germs in.
Amy, stop. Don't interfere.
Don't touch him.
Anaesthetic, tissue sample, screen,
sterile working conditions.
Ignore all my previous theories!
Yeah? Well, we stopped
paying attention a while back.
She's not a killer at all.
She's a doctor!
This is an automated sick bay.
It's teleporting everyone on board.
The crew are dead and so the sick bay
has had nothing to do.
It's been looking after humanity
whilst it's been idle.
Look at her. A virtual doctor!
Able to sterilise a whole room.
-Able to burn your face off.
-She's just an interface.
Seeped through the join
between the planes.
Broadcast in our world.
Protean circuitry means
she can change her form.
And become a human doctor for humans.
Oh, sister, you are good!
(SCREECHING)
She won't let us take them.
She's keeping them alive but
she doesn't know how to heal them.
I'm his wife, for God's sake!
Why can't I touch him?
Tell her, Amy.
Show her your ring.
She may be virtual
but she's intelligent.
You can't do anything
without her consent. Come on!
Sophisticated girl like you,
that must be somewhere
in your core program.
Look. He's very ill, okay?
I just want to look after him.
Why won't you let me near my husband?
Consent form. Sign it.
Put your hand in the light.
Rory's sick.
You have to take full responsibility.
(GASPING)
He can't breathe. Turn it back on.
What do we do?
I can't just leave him here.
He'll die if you take him out.
Rory? Rory, wake up.
-Where am I?
-DOCTOR: You're in a hospital.
If you leave, you might die.
But if you don't,
you'll have to stay forever.
You're saying
that if I don't get up now...
You can never leave.
-The siren will keep you safe.
-And if I come with you?
Drowning, on the point of death.
-I'm a nurse.
-What?
-I can teach you how to save me.
-Whoa, hold on.
I was drowning.
You just have to resuscitate me.
'lust"?
You've seen them do it loads of times
in films. CPR. The kiss of life.
Rory, this isn't a film, okay?
What if I do it wrong?
You won't.
Okay. What if you don't
come back to life? What if...
I trust you.
What about him, hmm?
I mean, why do I have to be the one?
Why do I have to save you?
Because I know you'll never give up.
We have to send this ship
back into space.
I mean, imagine if the siren got ashore.
She would have to process
every injured human.
What about Toby?
I'm sorry.
Typhoid fever. Once he returns,
it's only a matter of time.
What if I stay with him, here?
The siren will look after him.
I can't go back to England.
And what home does he have now,
if not with me?
Do you think you can sail this thing?
Just point me to the atom accelerator.
(LAUGHS)
RORY: I know you can do this.
Of course, if you muck it up
I am going to be really cross.
And dead.
I'll see you in a minute.
(SENSOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Come on. Come on, Rory.
Not here. Not this way. Not today!
He trusted me.
He trusted me to save him.
You still can. You can still do this.
He believes in you. Come on, Amy!
Come on!
Please, please, please wake up.
Please wake up.
Wake up, wake up!
(AMY SOBBING)
(COUGHING)
Yes!
(GASPING)
Amy.
Amy, you did it. You did it!
I thought I was an excellent pirate.
-I thought you were an excellent nurse.
-Easy, tiger.
Goodnight, Doctor.
Goodnight, Amelia.
You only call me Amelia
when you're worrying about me.
I always worry about you.
Mutual.
Go to bed, Pond.
You can't tell him.
It's his future.
I know.
DOCTOR: Oh, Amelia.
I've got mail.
There's a living Time Lord
still out there.
The house? What's the house?
We walk on his back,
breathe his air, eat his food...
HOUSE: And do my will.
The little boxes will make you angry.
(SCREAMING)
I feel like a nine-year-old
trying to rebuild a motorbike
in his bedroom.
You are not my mother.
HOUSE: Why shouldn't
I just kill you now?