There we go. Perfect landing.
Which isn't easy in such a tight spot.
You should be used to tight spots
by now.
-Where are we?
-The end of the line.
No place like it.
Home?
-You took me home?
-Back to the morning after we left.
So you've only been gone
about 12 hours. No time at all, really.
But all the stuff we've done,
Shakespeare, New New York, old New York.
Yep. All in one night.
Relatively speaking,
everything should be just as it was.
Books, CDs, laundry.
So, back where you were, as promised.
-This is it?
-Yeah, I should probably...
(PHONE RINGING)
MARTHA: Hi, I'm out. Leave a message.
I'm sorry.
WOMAN: Martha, are you there?
Pick it up, will you?
It's Mum. It'll wait.
All right, then.
Pretend that you're out if you like.
I was only calling to say
that your sister's on TV.
On the news of all things.
Just thought you might be interested.
-The details are top secret...
-How could Tish end up on the news?
...but I can tell you that tonight,
I will demonstrate a device
which will...
She got a new job
doing PR for some research lab.
With the push of a single button,
I will change what it means to be human.
REPORTER: Professor! Professor!
Sorry. You were saying you should...
Yes, yes. I should.
-One trip we said.
-Yeah.
I suppose things just kind of escalated.
Mmm. Seems to happen to me a lot.
Thank you. For everything.
It was my pleasure.
(WHOOSHING)
No, I'm sorry. Did he say he was going
to change what it means to be human?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Are you sure it's safe?
There were some issues.
They've been resolved.
I'm confident I'm in no serious danger.
That's comforting, Richard, but it
wasn't just you I was worried about.
Your concern is touching.
The people in that room will represent
billions of pounds worth
of potential investment.
Mr Saxon wants to be sure
they like what they see.
Don't worry.
Our friend will get his money's worth.
You wanted to see the guest list
for tonight, Professor?
Yes, thank you, Letitia.
(SNIFFING)
That's an interesting perfume.
What's it called?
Soap.
Oh, black tie.
Whenever I wear this,
something bad always happens.
It's not the outfit, that's just you.
Anyway, I think it suits you
in a James Bond kind of way.
James Bond? Really?
Oh, look, they've got nibbles!
I love nibbles.
-Hello!
-Tish!
You look great.
So, what do you think?
Impressive, isn't it?
-Very.
-And two nights out in a row for you.
That's dangerously close
to a social life.
If I keep this up,
I'll end up in all the gossip columns.
You might, actually. You should keep
an eye out for photographers. And Mum.
She's coming, too.
Even dragging Leo along with her.
Leo? In black tie? That I must see.
-This is the Doctor.
-Hello.
-Is he with you?
-Yeah.
But he's not on the list.
How did he get in?
He's my plus one.
So this Lazarus, he's your boss?
Professor Lazarus, yes.
I'm part of his executive staff.
She's in the PR department.
I'm head of the PR department, actually.
-You're joking!
-I put this whole thing together.
So do you know what the Professor's
going to be doing tonight?
That looks like it might be
a sonic micro-field manipulator.
He's a science geek. I should've known.
Got to get back to work now.
I'll catch up with you later.
Science geek? What's that mean?
That you're obsessively
enthusiastic about it.
Oh. Nice.
Your father's caused me enough
heartache already with his menopause
-and his trophy girlfriend.
-Yeah, Mum, I know.
It was just something
he said last night.
-Martha.
-Mum.
Oh.
All right, what's the occasion?
What do you mean?
I'm just pleased to see you, that's all.
-But you saw me last night.
-I know, I just missed you.
You're looking good, Leo.
Yeah, if anyone asks me to fetch them
a drink, I'll swing for them.
-You disappeared last night.
-I...
-...just went home.
-On your own?
This is a friend of mine, the Doctor.
-Doctor what?
-No, it's just the Doctor.
-We've been doing some work together.
-All right.
Lovely to meet you, Mrs Jones.
Heard a lot about you.
Have you? What've you heard, then?
Well, you know,
that you're Martha's mother and...
Um...
No, actually, that's about it.
We haven't had much time to chat.
-You know, been busy.
-Busy? Doing what exactly?
Oh. You know. Stuff.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I am Professor Richard Lazarus,
and tonight I'm going
to perform a miracle.
It is, I believe,
the most important advance
since Rutherford split the atom.
The biggest leap
since Armstrong stood on the moon.
Tonight you will watch and wonder.
But tomorrow, you will wake to a world
which will be changed forever.
(DEVICE SCREECHING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Something's wrong. It's overloading.
Somebody stop him!
Get him away from those controls!
If this goes up, it'll take the whole
building with it! Is that what you want?
DOCTOR: Get it open.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I am Richard Lazarus.
I am 76 years old
and I am reborn!
He did it. He actually did it!
That can't be the same guy.
It's impossible. It must be a trick.
Oh, it's not a trick. I wish it were.
What just happened, then?
He just changed what it means
to be human.
Excuse me.
That was the most astonishing thing
I've ever seen.
-Look at you!
-This is only the beginning.
We're not just making history,
we're shaping the future, too.
Think of the money we'll make.
People will sell their souls
to be transformed like that.
And I'll be first in line.
-Richard!
-I'm famished.
Energy deficit. Always happens
with this kind of process.
You talk as if
you see this every day, Mr...?
Doctor. And, well, no, not every day,
but I have some experience
-with this kind of transformation.
-That's not possible.
Using hypersonic sound waves
to create a state of resonance,
-that's inspired.
-You understand the theory, then?
Enough to know that
you couldn't possibly
have allowed for all the variables.
-No experiment is entirely without risk.
-That thing nearly exploded.
You might as well
have stepped into a blender.
You're not qualified to comment.
If I hadn't stopped it,
it would've exploded.
Then I thank you, Doctor.
But that's a simple engineering issue.
What happened inside the capsule
was exactly what was supposed to happen.
No more, no less.
You've no way of knowing that
until you've run proper tests.
Look at me! You can see what happened.
I'm all the proof you need.
The device will be properly certified
before we start to operate commercially.
Commercially? You are joking?
That'll cause chaos.
Not chaos, change.
A chance for humanity
to evolve, to improve.
This isn't about improving,
this is about you and your customers
living a little longer.
Not a little longer, Doctor,
a lot longer.
Perhaps indefinitely.
Richard, we have things to discuss.
Upstairs.
Goodbye, Doctor.
In a few years, you'll look back
and laugh at how wrong you were.
Oh, he's out of his depth.
He's no idea the damage
he might've done.
-So what do we do now?
-Now...
Well, this building must be full of
laboratories. I say we do our own tests.
Lucky I've just collected
a DNA sample then, isn't it?
Oh, Martha Jones, you're a star!
I grew up over there.
Tiny flat above a butcher's shop.
It'll have a blue plaque soon.
-"Richard Lazarus lived here."
-It's gone.
-Destroyed in the war. The bombing.
-Of course.
1940. Do you remember?
Night after night. Explosions.
Guns. Firestorms.
My parents had sent me
to the country by then.
When the sirens went,
we'd go to the cathedral there.
We used to shelter in the crypt.
The living cowering among the dead.
But look what you've built here now.
You've laid the foundations
for an empire.
An empire we can rule together.
What's wrong?
Look at yourself, woman.
-Amazing.
-What?
-Lazarus' DNA.
-I can't see anything different.
-Look at it.
-Oh, my God!
Did that just change?
-But it can't have.
-But it did.
It's impossible.
And that's two impossible things
we've seen so far tonight.
Don't you love it when that happens?
That means Lazarus has changed
his own molecular patterns.
Hypersonic sound waves
to destabilise the cell structure.
Then a metagenic program to manipulate
the coding in the protein strands.
Basically, he hacked into his own
genes and instructed them to rejuvenate.
-But they're still mutating now.
-Because he missed something.
Something in his DNA that's been
activated and won't let him stabilise.
Something that's trying to change him.
-Change him into what?
-I don't know.
But I think we need to find out.
That woman said
they were going upstairs.
Let's go.
It's me who made all this possible.
This is my triumph
and I will not be denied.
Not by you.
Not after everything I've done.
(SCOFFS)
You backed me because you saw profit.
Your concern was financial.
You want the money as much as I do.
We had a plan.
When the device is ready,
I'll be rejuvenated, too.
We could be rich and young and together.
You think I'd waste another lifetime
on you?
Did that process make you
even more cruel?
No, my love, that I learned from you.
You have a gift for it.
Then you'll know that I'll protect
my involvement in the project.
I'm sure Mr Saxon will be interested...
What's going on?
It must just be...
What is it?
I'll be fine in a moment.
It's probably just cramp.
Richard?
Is it some kind of seizure?
What should I do?
I don't understand. What's happening?
Richard?
(GROWLING)
Tish, have you seen Martha
and that Doctor anywhere?
Not since the demonstration.
Do you know anything about him?
Has she ever mentioned him before?
-Not to me.
-The way she followed him...
She's a doctor.
She was just doing her job.
She's not a doctor yet. Never will be
if she doesn't stay focussed.
Look, she's found a bloke. So what?
There's something's going on, Leo.
I can feel it.
Letitia Jones. I'd recognise
the smell of that soap anywhere.
Professor.
I'm sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
You'll have to excuse me
while I take care of Letitia here.
I've been neglecting her.
-This is his office all right.
-So where is he?
Don't know.
Let's try back at the...reception.
-Is that Lady Thaw?
-Used to be.
It's just a shell, had all
the life-energy drained out of her.
Like squeezing the juice
out of an orange.
-Lazarus!
-Could be.
-So he's changed already.
-Not necessarily.
You saw the DNA, it was fluctuating.
The process must demand energy.
-This might not have been enough.
-So he might do this again?
Mmm.
(TISH LAUGHING)
You seem very young to have
such a responsible position.
-Have you much experience?
-Not really.
But the interview panel thought
I had all the necessary attributes.
How perceptive of them.
So, where are you taking me?
Up to the roof. It's a lovely evening.
I thought I'd show you the view.
-It's extraordinary.
-Like a lot of things round here, then.
-I can't see him.
-He can't be far. Keep looking.
You all right, Marth?
I think Mum wants to talk to you.
Have you seen Lazarus anywhere?
He was getting cosy
with Tish a couple of minutes ago.
-With Tish?
-Ah, Doctor.
-Where did they go?
-Upstairs, I think. Why?
-Doctor... I'm speaking to you!
-Not now, Mum!
I think you need one of these.
Thank you. That's very kind of you.
-Do you know that man?
-No. He's a friend of my daughter's.
Perhaps she should choose
her friends more carefully.
Where are they?
The fluctuating DNA
will give off an energy signature.
I might be able to pick it up.
-Got him.
-Where?
But this is the top floor. The roof!
That clock tower is beautiful
all it up like that.
It's Southwark Cathedral.
One of the oldest churches in London.
Been around even longer than I have.
But you're looking pretty good
for your age.
Thank you.
-Can I?
-Of course.
-I still can't take it in.
-I'm still adjusting myself.
I've been working toward it
for so many years,
it's hard to believe
the moment's finally arrived.
And is it like you expected?
I find that nothing's
ever exactly like you expect.
There's always something
to surprise you.
Between the idea and the reality,
between the motion and the act...
Falls the shadow.
So, the mysterious Doctor
knows his Eliot.
I'm impressed.
-Martha, what are you doing here?
-Tish, get away from him.
What? Don't tell me what to do.
I wouldn't have thought
you had time for poetry, Lazarus.
What with you being so busy defying
the laws of nature and everything.
You're right, Doctor.
One lifetime's been too short for me
to do everything I'd like.
How much more I'll get done
in two or three or four.
It doesn't work like that.
Some people live more in 20 years
than others do in 80.
It's not the time that matters,
it's the person.
But if it's the right person,
what a gift that would be.
Or what a curse.
Look at what you've done to yourself.
Who are you to judge me?
Over here, Tish.
You have to spoil everything, don't you?
Every time I find someone nice,
you have to try and find fault.
Tish, he's a monster!
I know the age thing's a bit freaky,
but it works for Catherine Zeta-Jones.
(LAZARUS GASPING)
(FLESH TEARING)
What is that?
DOCTOR: Run!
(LAZARUS GROWLING)
-Are you okay?
-I was gonna snog him!
WOMAN ON PA: Security One.
(ALARM BLARING)
Security One. Security One.
-What's happening?
-An intrusion.
It triggers a security lockdown.
Kills most of the power.
Stops the lifts, seals the exits.
He must be breaking through that door.
The stairs. Come on!
(DOOR BREAKING)
-He's inside!
-We haven't got much time!
Tish, is there another way out of here?
There's an exit in the corner,
but it'll be locked now.
Martha, setting 54. Hurry.
Listen to me!
You people are in serious danger.
You need to get out of here right now!
Don't be ridiculous. The biggest danger
here is choking on an olive.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(ROARING)
LEO: Mum, get back!
Leo!
Over here. This way!
Everyone down the stairs now. Hurry!
No! Get away from her!
Leo? Leo?
Lazarus! Leave them alone.
-Martha.
-Come on, stay with me.
What's the point? You can't control it.
The mutation's too strong.
Killing those people won't help you.
You're a fool.
A vain old man
who thought he could defy nature.
Only nature got her own back,
didn't she?
You're a joke, Lazarus!
A footnote in the history of failure!
(ROARING)
-What's the Doctor doing?
-He's trying to buy us some time.
Let's not waste it. Leo, look at me.
Focus on me. Let's see your eyes.
Okay, he's got concussion.
Mum, you'll need to help him downstairs.
This'll keep the swelling down.
Go, I'll be right behind you.
Tish, move. We need to get out of here.
LAZARUS: It's no good, Doctor.
You can't stop me.
Is that the same arrogance you had
when you swore that nothing
had gone wrong with your device?
The arrogance is yours.
You can't stand in the way of progress.
You call feeding on
innocent people progress?
You're delusional!
It is a necessary sacrifice.
That's not your decision to make.
TISH: We can't get out! We're trapped!
There must be an override switch.
Where's the security desk? Tish!
There.
(DOOR OPENING)
LAZARUS: Peek-a-boo.
Oh. Hello.
-I've got to go back.
-You can't.
You saw what that thing did.
it'll kill you.
I don't care. I have to go.
It's that Doctor, isn't it?
That's what's happened to you.
That's why you've changed.
He was biding us time, Martha.
-Time for you to get out, too.
-I'm not leaving him.
Martha!
(BANGING)
(DOOR BREAKING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
More hide and seek, Doctor?
How disappointing.
-Why don't you come out and face me?
-Have you looked in the mirror lately?
Why would I want to face that, hmm?
-What are you doing here?
-I'm returning this.
-I thought you might need it.
-How did you...
I heard the explosion.
I guessed it was you.
-I blasted Lazarus.
-Did you kill him?
More sort of annoyed him, I'd say.
She'll be all right.
The Doctor and her,
they'll look out for each other.
She turned her back on us,
went in there with that thing.
-For him.
-He must be some guy.
-Maybe she loves him.
-She just met him.
Is your daughter still in there
with the Doctor?
Do you know him?
He's dangerous.
-There are things you should know.
-What things?
(WHISPERING)
What now?
We've just gone round in a circle.
We can't lead him outside.
Come on, get in.
-Are we hiding?
-No, he knows we're here.
But this is his masterpiece.
I'm betting he won't destroy it,
not even to get at us.
-But we're trapped.
-Well, yeah, that is a slight problem.
-You mean you don't have a plan?
-Yes. The plan was to get inside here.
-Then what?
-Well,
then I'd come up with another plan.
In your own time, then.
-Hey!
-Sorry, sorry, sorry.
-Here we are.
-What are you going to do with that?
Improvise.
I still don't understand
where that thing came from. Is it alien?
No. For once,
it's strictly human in origin.
Human? How can it be human?
Probably from dormant genes
in Lazarus' DNA.
The energy field in this thing
must've reactivated them.
-Looks like they're becoming dominant.
-So it's a throwback.
Some option that evolution rejected
for you millions of years ago.
But the potential is still there,
locked away in your genes,
forgotten about until Lazarus
unlocked it by mistake.
-It's like Pandora"s box.
-Exactly. Nice shoes, by the way.
Doctor, what's happening?
Sounds like he's switched
the machine on.
-That's not good, is it?
-I was hoping
it was going to take him
a little bit longer to work that out.
-I don't want to hurry you, but...
-I know. Nearly done.
What are you doing?
Trying to set the capsule to
reflect energy rather than receive it.
Will that kill him?
When he transforms,
he's three times the size,
cellular triplication,
so he's spreading himself thin.
-We're going to end up like him!
-Just one more.
I thought we were going to go
through the blender then.
It really shouldn't take that long
just to reverse the polarity.
I must be a bit out of practice.
Oh, God. He seems so human again.
-It's kind of pitiful.
-Eliot saw that, too.
This is the way the world ends.
Not with a bang but a whimper.
She's here. Oh, she's all right.
Oh, Mrs Jones.
We still haven't finished our chat.
Keep away from my daughter.
-Mum, what are you doing?
-Always the mothers. Every time.
-He is dangerous. I've been told things.
-What are you talking about?
Look around you.
Nothing but death and destruction.
This isn't his fault.
He saved us. All of us.
It was Tish who invited everyone
to this thing in the first place
so I'd say, technically, it's her fault.
(CRASHING)
Leave him.
-Martha?
-Not you, too.
Sorry.
Lazarus, back from the dead.
Should've known really.
Where's he gone?
-That way. The church.
-Cathedral.
It's Southwark Cathedral. He told me.
Do you think he's in here?
Where would you go
if you were looking for sanctuary?
I came here before.
A lifetime ago.
I thought I was going to die then.
In fact, I was sure of it.
I sat here, just a child.
The sound of planes and bombs outside.
The Blitz.
-You've read about it.
-I was there.
You're too young.
So are you.
In the morning the fires had died,
but I was still alive.
I swore I'd never face death
like that again.
So defenceless.
I would arm myself.
Fight back. Defeat it.
That's what you were trying to do today?
That's what I did today.
-What about the other people who died?
-They were nothing.
-I changed the course of history.
-Any of them might've done, too.
You think history's only made
with equations?
Facing death is part of being human.
You can't change that.
No, Doctor.
Avoiding death, that's being human.
It's our strongest impulse, to cling
to life with every fibre of being.
I'm only doing what everyone
before me has tried to do.
I've simply been more successful.
Look at yourself. You're mutating.
You've no control over it.
You call that a success?
I call it progress.
I'm more now than I was.
More than just an ordinary human.
There's no such thing
as an ordinary human.
-He's going to change again any minute.
-I know.
If I could get him up
into the bell tower somehow,
-I've an idea that might work.
-Up there?
You're so sentimental, Doctor.
Maybe you are older than you look.
I'm old enough to know that a longer
life isn't always a better one.
In the end, you just get tired.
Tired of the struggle.
Tired of losing everyone
that matters to you.
Tired of watching everything
turn to dust.
If you live long enough, Lazarus,
the only certainty left
is that you'll end up alone.
That's a price worth paying.
Is it?
I will feed soon.
I'm not going to let that happen.
-You've not been able to stop me so far.
-Leave him, Lazarus.
He's old and bitter.
I thought you had a taste
for fresher meat.
Martha, no.
-What are you doing?
-Keeping you out of trouble.
Doctor, the tower!
Did you hear that?
He's changed again. Keep moving.
We've got to lead him up.
(LAZARUS GROWLING)
Where are they?
Martha?
Doctor!
Take him to the top, the very top
of the bell tower, do you hear me?
-Up to the top?
-Martha?
-And then what?
-Martha, come on!
Hypersonic sound waves, inspired.
There's nowhere else to go.
We're trapped!
This is where he said to bring him.
Right, so we're not trapped, we're bait.
He knows what he's doing.
We have to trust him.
Ladies.
Stay behind me.
If he takes me, make a run for it.
Head back down the stairs.
-You should have enough time.
-But...
Just do it, Tish!
(MARTHA AND TISH SCREAM)
I hope there's a good acoustic in here.
Martha!
(SCREAMING)
Hold on!
Get away from her!
We need to turn this up to 11.
I've got you! Hold on.
Martha!
I'm okay. We're both okay!
Thanks.
It's your Doctor you should be thanking.
-I told you he'd think of something.
-He cut it a bit fine though, didn't he?
He always does. It's more fun that way.
Who is he?
He's...
He's the Doctor.
I didn't know you could play.
Well, you know,
if you hang around with Beethoven,
-you're bound to pick a few things up.
-Mmm.
-Especially about playing loud.
-Sorry?
Something else
that just kind of escalated, then.
I can see a pattern developing.
You should take more care
in the future. And the past.
And whatever other time period
you find yourself in.
-It's been fun, though, hasn't it?
-Yes!
So what do you say? One more trip?
No.
Sorry.
What do you mean?
I thought you liked it.
I do, but I can't go on like this.
"One more trip." It's not fair.
What are you talking about?
I don't want to be a passenger any more,
someone that you take along for a treat.
That's how you still see me.
I'd rather stay here.
Okay, then, if that's what you want.
Right. Well, we've already
said goodbye once today.
It's probably best if you just go.
-What is it?
-Well, I said okay.
-Sorry?
-Okay.
Oh, thank you! Thank you!
Well, you were never really
just a passenger, were you?
(PHONE RINGING)
Hi, I'm out. Leave a message.
Martha, it's your mother.
Please phone me back.
I'm begging you.
I know who this Doctor really is.
I know he's dangerous.
You're going to get yourself killed.
Please trust me. This information comes
from Harold Saxon himself.
You're not safe.
Distress signal. Locking on.
Now that is hot.
If you can't stand the heat...
-The ship's gone mad.
-Who are you?
I'm the Doctor.
Mum, it's me, it's Martha.
Get out of there!
Burn with me.
-I can't stop it!
-That's enough!
Go on, my son.
-That is brilliant.
-I know.
-I'll save you.
-It's your fault.
-What are you?
-Doctor!
We're stuck here.