WOMAN: (AMERICAN SOUTH ACCENT)
When I was a child,
my favourite story was
about a man who lived forever,
but whose eyes were heavy
with the weight of all he'd seen.
A man who fell from the stars.
(BEEPING)
I knew you'd find me eventually.
GUNSLINGER:
Make peace with your gods.
Once they were your gods, too.
Not any more.
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
Am I... Am I the last one?
There's one more.
The doctor.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
DOCTOR: "Mercy. 81 residents.”
Look at this,
it's a load of stones and lumps of wood.
(WHIRRING)
AMY: What is it?
A load of stones and lumps of wood.
RORY: Uh, the sign does say "Keep Out”.
I see "Keep Out” signs as suggestions
more than actual orders.
Like "Dry-Clean Only".
(CRACKLES)
That's not right.
(WHIRRING)
It's a street lamp.
An electric street lamp,
about 10 years too early.
-It's only a few years out.
-That's what you said
when you left your phone charger
in Henry VIII's ensuite.
Doctor, um...
Anachronistic electricity,
"Keep Out" signs, aggressive stares,
has someone been peeking
at my Christmas list?
Doctor...
(PATRONS CHATTING)
Tea.
But the strong stuff.
Leave the bag in.
What you doing here, son?
Son? (CHUCKLES)
-You can stay.
-Sir?
Might I enquire who you is?
Of course. I'm the Doctor, this is...
No need to stand. You see that?
Manners.
Oh, thank you,
but I don't need a new suit.
I'm the undertaker, sir.
(MEN LAUGHING)
I got a question.
Is you an alien?
Well, um... Bit personal.
It's all relative, isn't it?
I mean, I think you're the aliens.
But in this context, yes.
Yes, I suppose I am.
(ALL CLAMOURING)
-AMY: (SCREAMS) Doctor!
-Guys.
AMY: Put him down!
WOMAN: Don't think we won't kill you!
RORY: Leave her alone!
Don't worry, everything is
completely under control.
RORY: Get off me!
DOCTOR: Guys, guys...
DOCTOR: Guys, guys... Oh, okay.
-(SHOUTING)
-MAN: Get out!
Ah!
Ow! (BONES CRACKING)
(GUNS COCKING)
Oh.
He's coming.
Oh, God! He's coming!
Preacher, say something.
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
-Thy Kingdom come...
-(SHUDDERING)
"Thy will be done..."
(GUNSHOT)
You, bow tie,
get back across that line.
Now.
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(EXHALES)
Isaac, he said he was a doctor.
An alien doctor.
Is that a reason
to hand him to his death?
But, Isaac, it could be him.
You know it ain't.
Ma'am.
MAN: Just let him go like that?
He's seen you, boy.
-What was that outside?
-The Gunslinger.
Showed up three weeks back.
We've been prisoners ever since.
See that borderline
stretching round the town?
Woke up one morning, there it was.
Nothing gets past it, in or out.
No supply wagons, no reinforcements.
Pretty soon the whole town's
going to starve to death.
But he let us in.
You ain't carrying any food.
Just three more mouths to feed.
We'll all die even sooner now.
What happens if someone
crosses the line?
Ah, well,
he wasn't a very good shot, then.
He was aiming for the hat.
He shoots people's hats?
I think it was a warning shot.
Ah, no. Yes. I see. Hmm...
What does he want?
Has he issued some kind of demand?
Says he wants us to give him
"the alien doctor”.
But that's you.
Why would he want to kill you?
-Unless he's met you.
-And how could he know we'd be here?
We didn't even know we'd be here.
(CHUCKLES) We were aiming for Mexico.
The Doctor was taking us to see
the Day of the Dead Festival.
-(SIZZLING)
-ISAAC: Mexico's 200 miles due south.
Well, that's what happens when people
get toast crumbs on the console.
Anyway, I think it's about time
I met him, don't you?
Who?
The chap outside said
I could be the alien doctor
but you said I wasn't,
so you already know who it is.
(CHUCKLES) Two alien doctors.
We're like buses.
Resident 81, I presume,
so beloved by the townsfolk
he warranted an alteration to the sign.
Probably because he'd rigged up
these electrics.
And I'm guessing he's in here,
because if half the town suddenly
wanted to throw me to my death,
this is where I'd want to be.
-I don't know what you...
-MAN: It's all right, Isaac.
I think the time for subterfuge
has passed.
Good afternoon.
My name is Kahler-Jex.
I'm the doctor.
The Kahler, I love the Kahler.
They're one of the most ingenious races
in the galaxy.
Seriously.
They could build a spaceship
out of Tupperware and moss.
All right. How did you get here?
My craft crashed about a mile or so
out of town.
I would have died
if Isaac and the others
hadn't pulled me from the wreckage.
And you stayed as their doctor?
On my world I was a surgeon,
so it seemed logical.
And it gave me an opportunity
to repay my debt to them.
(SCOFFS) Listen to him.
Talking like it was nothing.
Tell 'em about the cholera.
Now, Isaac, I'm sure our guests...
ISAAC: Two years after he arrived,
there was an outbreak of cholera.
Thanks to the doc here,
not a single person died.
A minor infection we'd found
a treatment for centuries ago.
No, no, no, what do you call them,
the electrics?
Using my ship as a generator,
I was able to rig up some rudimentary
heating and lighting for the town.
So, why does the Gunslinger want you?
-It don't matter.
-I'm just saying, if we knew that...
ISAAC: America's the land
of second chances.
We call this town Mercy for a reason.
Though there's some round here
don't feel that way.
Now, Isaac, we've discussed this...
People whose lives you've saved are
suddenly saying we should hand you over.
They're scared, that's all.
-You can hardly blame them.
-Them being scared scares me.
War only ended five years back.
That old violence
is still under the surface.
We give up Doc Jex, then we're handing
the keys to the town over to chaos.
Did you try to repair your craft?
Surely someone with your skills...
It really was very badly damaged.
We evacuate the town,
our ship's just over the hills,
room for everyone.
I'll pop out and bring it back here,
Robert's your uncle.
Really? Simple as that?
-No crazy schemes, no negotiations?
-I've matured. I'm 1200 years old now.
Plus, I don't want to miss The Archers.
Oh, so you're not even
a tiny bit curious?
Why would I be curious?
It's a mysterious space-cowboy assassin.
Curious? Of course I'm not curious.
ISAAC: Son?
You still got to get past
the Gunslinger, how you gonna do that?
With a little sleight of hand.
-You okay?
-Yeah, fine, yeah. Keep moving.
Well, next time,
you get to wear Jex's clothes.
(HORSE SNORTING)
Can I borrow your horse, please?
It's official Marshal business.
He's called Joshua.
It's from the Bible.
It means "the deliverer".
-(HORSE SNORTING)
-No, he isn't.
-What?
-I speak horse, he's called Susan.
(SNORTS)
And he wants you to respect
his life choices.
-(NEIGHS)
-Hup!
I, uh... I think he's seen us.
This way!
When this is all done,
do you want us to take you home?
Thank you.
But I have already given
everything I have to the Kahler.
My skills, my energy.
All that was good in me.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
But here, I could start afresh.
I could remember myself and help people.
That's all I ever wanted to do.
End suffering.
Here.
-You're a mother, aren't you?
-How did you know?
There's kindness in your eyes.
And sadness.
But a ferocity, too.
It wasn't exactly straightforward.
It seldom is.
And what about you? Are you a father?
Yes. In a way, I suppose I am.
So, we wait here till the Doctor
comes to pick us up in your ship.
Yes, I know.
I was there when we agreed it.
Yeah, I said that
more for my benefit than yours.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
-(NEIGHS)
Yeah, I know we're in a hurry,
I just want to check something out.
Two ticks.
There's something niggling me.
-(SNORTS)
-Yes, yes, it could be important.
-0i, don't swear.
(ELECTRIC BUZZING)
(SNIFFS)
(SNORTING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
(SNORTS)
Yes, I wear a Stetson now.
-(SNORTING)
-Yes, good point, Susan.
Where is the damage?
(BUZZING)
Ow.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Ah!
(WHINNIES)
(ALARM ECHOING)
That's the alarm on my ship.
Maybe the Doctor wants to
get it working again.
But that wasn't the plan.
He's not following the plan.
Welcome to my world.
(GROANING)
COMPUTER: Security breach.
You have 10 seconds
to enter the pass code
or this vehicle will self-destruct.
Thank you for choosing
Abaraxas Security Software.
Incinerating intruders
for three centuries.
Nine, eight, seven...
Self-destruct overridden.
This is an awful lot of security
for a titchy spacecraft.
Awaiting command.
Tell me everything you can
about the Gunslinger.
-File not found.
-Ah!
Please choose from
technical specifications,
flight recorder, personal files,
maps and charts.
Personal files of Dr Kahler-Jex.
KAHLER-JEX: Names of diseased subjects
can be found on the drop-down menu.
(BEEPING, PEOPLE SCREAMING IN PAIN)
I'm sorry, Amy,
he really should have followed the plan.
(WHIRRING)
Don't shoot! Don't shoot. Don't shoot!
I know who you are.
And who Jex is, too.
Now, what I don't understand is
why you haven't just walked into town
and killed him.
People will get in the way.
Look, you want justice,
you deserve justice,
but this isn't the way.
We can put him on trial. We can...
When he starts killing your people,
you can use your justice.
Isaac says he doesn't care
about my past.
But things may have been uncovered
that even he might struggle to forgive.
So, it's best we beat a hasty retreat.
We? (STAMMERS) I'm coming with you?
It's unlikely the Gunslinger will shoot
if I'm with you.
As far as I can tell,
he's programmed to take innocent lives
only if absolutely necessary.
Oh, well, colour me reassured.
What are you doing?
No more warning shots.
I'll kill the next person
to step over that line.
Make sure it's Jex.
It was stupid of me. I realise that now.
I just thought I'd put you all
in enough danger.
-Perhaps if I left...
-He's lying.
Every word.
Everything he says,
it's all
lies.
This man is a murderer.
-I am a scientist!
-Sit down.
Sit down!
Tell them what you are.
What am I?
A war hero.
Okay.
Somebody want to tell me
what is going on?
The Gunslinger is a cyborg.
-A what?
-Half man, half machine.
A weapon.
Jex built it.
He and his team took volunteers,
told them they'd been selected
for special training,
then experimented on them,
fused their bodies with weaponry
and programmed them to kill.
Okay, why?
Why would you do that, doc?
We'd been at war for nine years.
A war that had already decimated
half of our planet.
Our task was to bring peace.
And we did.
We built an army that routed the enemy
and ended the war in less than a week.
Do you want me to repent?
To beg forgiveness
for saving millions of lives?
And how many died screaming
on the operating table
before you had found your advantage?
War is another world.
You cannot apply the politics of peace
to what I did,
to what any of us did.
But what happened then?
How come you're here?
KAHLER-JEX: When the war ended,
we had the cyborgs decommissioned.
One of them must have got
its circuitry damaged in battle.
It went offline and began
hunting down the team that created it,
until just two of us were left.
We fled.
And our ships crashed here.
So, what do we do with Jex?
-What do we do with him?
-Yeah, I mean, he's a war criminal.
No, he's the guy that saved the town
from cholera.
The guy that gave us heat and light.
Look, Jex may be a criminal
and, yeah, kind of creepy...
And still in the room.
...but I think we should put aside
what he did and find another solution.
RORY: Another solution? It's him or us.
When did we start
letting people get executed?
Did I miss a memo? Doctor, tell him.
Hmm?
Yes.
I don't know. Whatever Amy said.
KAHLER-JEX: Looking at you, Doctor,
is like looking into a mirror,
almost.
There's rage there, like me.
Guilt, like me.
Solitude.
Everything but the nerve to do
what needs to be done.
Thank the gods my people
weren't relying on you to save them.
No! No!
But these people are.
Out! Out! Out!
(GRUNTS)
Oh, you're really letting him do this?
Save us all? Yeah, I really am.
Move!
No, I...
-No.
-Move!
(STAMMERING)
WOMAN: Now what's going on?
Get over that line!
(GROANS)
Hey!
You wouldn't.
I genuinely don't know.
ISAAC: Doctor?
Doctor?
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Let him come back, Doctor.
Or what? You won't shoot me, Amy.
How do you know? Maybe I've changed.
I mean, you've clearly been taking
stupid lessons since I saw you last...
(GUNSHOT)
-I didn't mean to do that.
-(GUNSHOT)
Everyone who isn't an American,
drop your gun.
We can end this right now.
We could save everyone right now!
This is not how we roll and you know it.
What's happened to you, Doctor?
When did killing someone
become an option?
-Jex has to answer for his crimes.
-And what then?
Are you going to hunt down everyone
who's made a gun or a bullet or a bomb?
But they keep coming back.
Don't you see?
Every time I negotiate,
I try to understand.
Well, not today. No.
Today I honour the victims first.
His, the Master's, the Daleks',
all the people who died
because of my mercy!
See, this is what happens
when you travel alone for too long.
Well, listen to me, Doctor,
we can't be like him.
We have to be better than him.
Amelia Pond.
(EXHALES)
Fine. Fine! We think of something else.
But frankly,
I'm betting on the Gunslinger.
(AIR CRACKLING IN DISTANCE)
Jex, move over the line.
Now!
Make peace with your gods.
Kahler-Tech, isn't it?
I remember all your names, even now.
Please, I'd never hurt anyone again.
I'm even helping people here.
Last chance. Make peace with your gods.
ISAAC: No!
(GROANING)
Isaac! Hey.
Isaac? Isaac! Isaac, it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay. We can get you
to Jex's surgery. He can save you.
Listen to me. You gotta stay.
You gotta look after everyone.
It won't come to that, Isaac.
Protect Jex. Protect my town.
You're both good men.
You just forget it sometimes.
Take Jex to a cell.
If anything happens to him,
you'll have me to answer to.
(GRUNTING)
-This has gone on long enough.
-You are right.
You've got until noon tomorrow.
Give him to me or I'll kill you all.
-Oh, my God, you're the Marshal.
-Yeah.
And you're the Deputy.
(BELL TOLLING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
Marshal. Ma'am.
Fella.
-You need to come outside.
-Why? What's wrong?
Just come outside.
And you should put that on.
What's going on?
He in there?
Leave the keys and take a walk.
Time you get back, this'll all be done.
I promised Isaac I'd protect him.
Protecting him got Isaac dead.
Tomorrow, it's gonna get us all dead.
We thought Isaac was right to fight,
but it's different now.
We gotta say, "All right, we lost,"
and give that thing what it wants.
What it wants is to kill our friend.
We don't got any ill feeling
toward the doc.
We just thinking about our families.
Hand him over and we all safe again.
You know I can't do that.
Then we got us a problem.
-Please don't do this.
-Why?
-Reckon you're quicker than me?
-Almost certainly not.
But this, lynch mobs,
the town turning against itself,
this is everything Isaac didn't want.
-How old are you?
-Nearly 19.
That's 18, then.
You're too young
to have fought in the war,
so I'm guessing you've never
shot anyone before, have you?
-First time for everything.
-But that's how all this started.
Jex turned someone into a weapon.
Now that same story's
going to make you a killer, too.
Don't you see?
Violence doesn't end violence,
it extends it.
And I don't think you want to do this.
I don't think
you want to become that man.
-There's kids here.
-I know.
Who I can save if you'll let me.
-He really worth the risk?
-Don't know.
But you are.
(UNCOCKS GUN)
Frightened people.
Give me a Dalek any day.
Fresh coffee, Marshal.
For what it's worth,
I know you're going to save us.
Isaac made you Marshal for a reason.
And if you're good enough for him,
you're good enough for me.
Reckon you should know that.
Thank you.
(EXHALES)
Oi! Get out of it.
Let me guess,
the good folk of Mercy wanted me
to take a little stroll into the desert.
You could turn a blind eye.
No one would blame you.
You'd be a hero.
But I can't, can I?
Because then Isaac's death
would mean nothing,
just another casualty
in your endless bloody war.
Do you want me to hand you over?
Is that what you want?
Do you even know...
You think I'm unaffected by what I did?
That I don't hear them screaming
every time I close my eyes?
It would be so much simpler
if I was just one thing, wouldn't it?
The mad scientist
who made that killing machine
or the physician, who's dedicated
his life to serving this town.
The fact that I'm both bewilders you.
Oh, I know exactly what you are
and I see this reformation
for what it really is.
You committed an atrocity
and chose this as your punishment.
Don't get me wrong, good choice.
Civilised hours, lots of adulation,
nice weather but...
But justice doesn't work like that!
You don't get to decide
when and how your debt is paid!
(EXHALES)
In my culture,
we believe that when you die,
your spirit has to climb a mountain
carrying the souls of everyone
you wronged in your lifetime.
Imagine the weight I will have to lift.
The monsters I created,
the people they killed,
Isaac.
He was my friend.
Now his soul will be in my arms, too.
Can you see now why I fear death?
You want to hand me over?
There's no shame in that.
But you won't.
We all carry our prisons with us.
Mine is my past.
Yours is your morality.
"We all carry our prisons with us.”
Ha!
(NECK CRACKING)
(CLOCK HAND CREAKING)
Help me. Help me to keep...
(MURMURING PRAYERS, INDISTINCT)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(AIR CRACKLING OUTSIDE)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING)
Ready?
(BEEPING)
Disengage. It's a trick.
(FOOTSTEPS CLANGING)
(WHISPERING) Save us, O Lord...
(ALL SCREAMING)
Uh...
Go! Just go.
I can't save them while you're here.
(WEAPON POWERING DOWN)
COMPUTER: Nine, eight, seven...
Self-destruct overridden.
(PANTING)
Deactivate automatic targeting.
Switch to manual.
Right.
-Where is he?
-He's gone.
-Where? Answer me/
-Away from here.
Look up. Any second now you'll see
the vapour trail of his ship.
This is their home,
not the backdrop for your revenge.
Go after him.
Take this battle away from...
KAHLER-JEX: (ON PA) Kahler-Tech!
Kahler-Tech!
Jex! Coward!
-Where are you?
-I'm in my ship.
Jex, what're you doing? Just go!
KAHLER-JEX: Where are you from?
Where on Kahler?
Now? You're asking him this now?
-Gabrian.
-I know it.
It's beautiful there.
-When this is over, will you go back?
-How can I?
I'm a monster now.
So am 1.
Just go! Finish this!
I will find you.
If I have to tear this universe apart,
I don't doubt that.
You'll chase me to another planet,
and another race will be caught
in the crossfire.
Then face me!
COMPUTER: Countdown
to self-destruct resumed.
-Face me!
-No. You've killed enough.
I'm ending the war for you, too.
COMPUTER: Countdown
to self-destruct resumed.
-What's going on?
-Ten...
The countdown. What's going on, Jex?
Thank you, Doctor. I have to face
the souls of those I've wronged.
-COMPUTER: ...five, four...
-Perhaps they will be kind.
-...three, two, one, zero.
-(ALARM RINGING)
(SIGHS)
He behaved with honour at the end.
Maybe more than me.
We could take you back to your world.
You could help with the reconstruction.
I will walk into the desert
and self-destruct.
I'm a creature of war,
I have no role to play during peace.
Except, maybe, to protect it.
Okay, so, our next trip...
Oh! You know all the monkeys and dogs
they sent into space
in the '50s and '60s?
You will never guess
what really happened to them.
Um, could we leave it a while?
Our friends are going to start noticing
that we're ageing faster than them.
Another time. No worries.
(TARDIS DOOR CLOSES)
WOMAN: By the time
the Gunslinger arrived,
the people of Mercy were used to
the strange and the impossible.
(WHOOSHING)
Where he came from didn't matter.
As a man once said,
America is a land of second chances.
Do I believe the story? I don't know.
My great-grandmother must have been
a little girl when he arrived.
But next time you're in Mercy,
ask someone
why they don't have a marshal
or sheriff or policeman there.
"We've got our own arrangement, "
they'll say.
Then they'll smile
like they got a secret.
Like they got their own special angel
watching out for 'em,
their very own angel
who fell from the stars.
AMY: Every time we flew away
with the Doctor,
-we'd just become part of his life.
-Come with me.
But he never stood still long enough
to become part of ours.
-(TYRES SQUEALING)
-Except once.
-Haven't you see them?
-AMY: The year of the slow invasion.
I've recommended we treat this
as a hostile incursion.
There are soldiers all over my house
and I'm in my pants.
We have two lives,
real life and Doctor life.
Our best hope now is each other.
-What do we do?
-Choose?