[horse whinnies]
[♪ instrumental music playing]
[horse blusters]
[breathing heavily]
We sent message to the village.
We thought no one was coming.
But you're not the midwife.
My name is Frau Rani.
-Am I too late?
-[baby crying]
No. Just in time.
We thought we needed help.
Violett was in an awful lot of pain,
but then a miracle. We were so lucky.
But you were born lucky,
isn't that what they say?
Herr Zufall,
the seventh son of a seventh son.
[door squeaks]
With seven sons of your own.
One, two, three, four, five, six…
[gasps] And lucky number seven.
[baby whimpers]
We thought Jonas
would be a wonderful name.
I think it's absolutely terrible.
Let me see.
That's it.
Hello.
I think he needs a stronger name
like Sturm-und-Drang, ja?
I'm sorry, but I don't think
his name is up to you.
I'm afraid it is
because I will be taking little baby.
Danke schön.
You've done a very good job,
but now he's all mine.
Excuse me, I don't think so.
Give me my child back right now.
Violett, isn't it?
Such a pretty name.
Your wife is violets.
[children clamouring] Mama! No, Mama! No!
[crying]
Witchcraft.
Hmm. It's older than that, darling.
Your child is the fountainhead
of a power from beyond this universe.
Boys, get out.
All of you, children, get out now!
-Run!
-[The Rani] That's right.
Waddle away!
[quacking]
And you.
The seventh son of a seventh son.
Hmm?
Such great wisdom.
Like a wise old owl.
[hooting]
Hoot, hoot.
-[owl hoots]
-[quacking]
Quack, quack.
Bye-bye.
[quacks]
Now then, mein Liebchen,
let's get to work.
We have things to do in 160 years' time
with one very special wish.
[ringing]
[yawns]
[Belinda grunts]
-Mmm.
-Morning, darling.
-Morning, sweetheart.
-[chuckles]
[Doctor chuckles]
[sighs]
Oh, this is nice.
You and me.
-[sighs]
-I could stay here forever.
Don't go to work.
Stay, stay, stay.
Oh, I wish.
But I've got to earn a living so
that we can have a lovely life together.
-[both chuckle]
-[Poppy] Meow.
-[Belinda] Hello.
-[Doctor] Hi. Meow.
-Meow. [chuckles]
-Meow.
-Did you see a cat?
-Uh-huh.
-Is that you wanting a cat?
-Yeah.
-[both] Yeah.
-[chuckles] Oh.
-[Poppy] Meow.
-[both] Meow.
…and the weather's going to be nice
all across England
and the whole of Great Britain.
It's nice in France and Africa,
and Venezuela and Missouri
and New Zealand.
That's my promise.
Really nice weather all over the world.
Happy morning, everyone.
[both] Happy morning, Conrad.
[♪ theme song playing]
Now, it's time for today's story.
Doctor Who and the Deadly Wish.
Once upon a time…
The Time Lords were really clever people
from the planet Gallifrey,
but one of the Time Lords ran away.
What's Uncle Connie saying, Poppy?
[sighs] I've got so much to do.
There's the laundry and shopping
and amma's coming round
'cause we've got to make plans.
Do you know why, Poppy?
-[Doctor] Hmm.
-Oh, come here, jam face.
-[chuckles]
-Oh!
[both chuckle]
Do you know what day tomorrow is, Poppy?
It's May Day.
It's May the 24th.
May the 24th, the big day.
-Mm-hmm.
-[chuckles]
We're gonna celebrate
with balloons and songs.
Mummy will cook a big pot of biryani.
-Is that nice?
-No.
-[Doctor] Hmm.
-[glass shattering]
-I've got it. I've got it.
-Oh.
-You head off, darling.
-Okay.
Maybe you shouldn't doubt things
so much, Poppy, huh?
-You need to be careful, okay?
-Okay.
Okay.
-[chuckles]
-Thank you, darling.
Hi.
Hello.
Yeah, um…
Sorry about this.
-Do I know you?
-I don't think so.
-Who are you?
-I've got to ask…
Are you the Doctor?
-Do you need a doctor? Is everything okay?
-No, no, um…
Are you called the Doctor?
My name is John Smith.
Okay. [chuckles]
Okay, but it's not.
I don't know why, it's just not.
-What's going on?
-[Doctor] Uh, it's…
It's nothing, darling.
It's, um, it's just someone.
Listen, is this some sort of a game
because I don't really appreciate it
-on my doorstep.
-And you're John Smith's wife.
I certainly am.
Who are you?
-That's your daughter.
-Of course it is.
-That's Poppy.
-But she's not…
I-I-I'm sorry,
but you don't have a daughter.
Oh, my God.
I beg your pardon.
-That is the most outrageous thing to say.
-Yeah.
-Why don't you watch Uncle Conrad?
-No, please. I'm so sorry.
My name's Ruby, I swear.
I'm just trying to help.
No, please. I didn't mean to just…
Did you… Did you say…
Ruby?
[Belinda] Yes, hello.
I have someone expressing doubt.
The address is 11 Calico Avenue.
I'd be grateful if you could come at once.
-[Mel grunts]
-[Ruby gasps]
-But…
-[Doctor] Uh, no, no, no, no, no.
Don't speak to her, Melanie.
You're called Mel?
I'm sorry, do I know you?
N-No.
[Mel grunts]
What was all that about, Mr Smith?
Oh, never mind.
Best forgotten, hey?
[chuckles] One more day till May the 24th.
-[chuckles]
-Any plans?
Oh, you know, I'm single,
no parents, no children.
So I will sit in silent contemplation
and be jolly glad.
-[chuckles]
-[creature groaning]
[roars]
Aren't they beautiful?
I ask you, how can anyone doubt
this glorious world that we live in?
[chuckles]
The people who lived on
the Earth were called humans.
Doctor Who had lots
and lots of human friends.
They loved him and travelled with him.
But sometimes they'd leave him
so they could go and fall in love,
and marry and have babies.
And then the Doctor was all alone,
but he travelled on
with bravery in his heart,
-looking for his next best friend.
-Anything, mate? Anything?
[♪ cheerful music playing]
[Doctor] Happy morning.
Happy morning.
Cutting it fine.
Another two minutes
and you'd have been late.
I did work late last night.
Time carries no favours.
-Happy morning.
Now, milk, no sugar, Mr Smith.
I've got digestives, Bourbons
and nice vanilla wafers.
Just give us a shout if you need anything.
I don't think anyone will be shouting,
thank you very much.
It might be a public holiday
on May the 24th, but that's tomorrow.
But then a sad day came along…
All the Time Lords were killed,
and Doctor Who was the only one left.
Psst.
[Conrad] He ran back home,
but he was too late…
I've heard she likes Chinese food.
Deborah in accounts
said Kate swears by it. Loves it.
But what am I going to say?
"Can we go out to dinner?
Just you and me."
If you two got together,
she wouldn't have to work.
It's undignified. You'd be saving her.
But she's way out of my league.
Oh, she's not. You're a beautiful man.
[chuckles]
-What's that supposed to mean?
-Uh…
No. [chuckling] No.
-No, no, no. I'm just saying…
-You're a man.
How can you find another man beautiful?
[stammering]
[glass shattering]
Oh! Sorry, that was, uh…
that was the slip.
Yeah, sorry. Sorry. That was the slip.
-I've got it. Don't worry.
-Okay.
[sighs] "Many a slip,
'twixt cup and lip", as they say.
9:00 a.m. We have begun.
Get to work.
[phone ringing]
Happy morning. Unified National
Insurance Team, how can I help?
And Doctor Who wished
it was like the old days
when he had a faithful companion…
companion… companion at his side.
But sadly, those days were gone.
-[knocking]
-[parent] Knock, knock.
-It's only us.
-Oh! [chuckles]
Mwah. Mwah.
-Make way. Make way.
-Hello, Amma.
You look well, Auntie.
I was just saying to Devika,
May the 24th is a lovely day,
-except for your father singing.
-[adults laughing]
-Hello, Poppy-loo.
-[giggles]
And it's May the 24th tomorrow.
Won't that be fun?
-No!
-[adults laughing]
She is getting cheeky.
Don't worry. Plenty of time
to drum that out of her.
You know her path in life.
It's all very clear.
Good little girl, then good little wife,
then good little mother.
-[giggles]
-And as Conrad says,
that's what we're here for.
And Conrad is never wrong.
[parent] Mind you, Belinda.
I thought you were destined to be trouble.
Twenty-four hours labour. Do you remember?
Oh, I thought she'd never arrive.
-[adults laughing]
-How long were you with Poppy?
-How long was I what?
-In labour.
Um…
I must have been there.
Was I?
[chuckles]
I can't remember. [chuckles]
[aunt] The birth of your only child.
Every mother remembers.
Yes, I know.
I-It must have been…
What was it, Amma?
Uh…
I-It's funny, but I can't remember.
[♪ tense music playing]
[chuckles]
What was it like, Pops?
Do you remember?
The day of your birth.
When was it?
[♪ tense music continues]
[glass shattering]
[parent] Oh.
Ooh. That was quite a slip.
Don't worry. It's only natural.
Easily done, darling, easily fixed.
You see? That's what happens
when you doubt something.
Here we go.
Out the way, sweetheart.
There we go.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[panting]
[panting continues]
[screaming]
-[screaming]
-[♪ suspenseful music ends]
It turned out Doctor Who
wasn't the only one left.
A Time Lady had survived.
There she is!
It's her.
It is really her! There she is.
You're supposed to be working.
-Come on, it's her.
-[gasps]
[Doctor] Wow. [chuckles]
[chattering]
It is an honour to get a sighting.
-It must be for May the 24th.
-[Ibrahim] Oh, there she goes.
[laughs]
Come on. Come, come, come on.
-[all clamouring, laughing]
-Come on!
[gasps] She's so beautiful.
I wonder who she is.
-Oh, my gosh.
-What is wrong with you today?
-Do you wonder who she is?
-No.
No, no, I, she just…
She just is.
She just is. She…
She is who she is and that…
and that is all.
[chuckles]
[♪ fast-paced music playing]
[The Rani] Mortadella from Italy.
It's dead, pink fat,
but humans seem to like it.
Let's keep the boy happy.
Is that a salad or a sandwich?
How are we doing?
Better than ever.
Very strong doubts.
We're even getting nines
this time of the day.
-Nine, three, three, nine, four.
-Listen.
Nine, nine, nine, nine, nine, nine, nine.
Six, nine, nine, nine, six, five,
five, five, five, nine, nine.
Nine, six, six, seven, seven, seven,
seven, seven, seven, seven.
Six, six, six, six, six, six, six…
Nine, nine, nine, nine, eight, nine.
Excellent.
Seek and ye shall find.
-[Seeker continues counting]
-Sandwich, obviously.
Oh, right.
Do this, do that.
Yes, ma'am. No, ma'am.
Can I cut your toenails, ma'am?
Snip, bloody snip.
Oh, let's pause there.
Now have a look at some pictures of India.
Hello there.
Hi. It's been ages.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
You know the mistress,
she has a lot of demands.
[chuckles]
But she thought you'd like this.
Nice, thanks.
But…
Is it okay out there? Is it working?
I think so, Conrad.
Very much so.
It's such a lot of hard work.
All the thinking.
Sometimes I forget about the weather
and-and-and South Africa gets flooded.
Oh, darling, you're worn out.
I am a bit.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
Oh.
You work so hard.
And you're doing a very, very good job.
Would I lie?
Oh, yes, I would.
But not this time, darling.
That's why we found you and saved you.
And that's why the mistress chose you.
The boy who wants the world to be better.
A wish from the heart.
[chuckles] Yeah.
How's the little one?
Oh, uh, you know, same as ever.
Smiling.
[baby coos]
[coos]
-Look at him.
-[coos]
[Conrad] He's so tiny.
But he sustains this entire world.
-And he never cries.
-No.
No, all he does is chuckle.
[chuckles]
He's amazing.
Isn't he?
He's terrifying.
He's absolutely terrifying.
And we have a temporal fix.
Counting down.
Vindicator now powered up
to 99% and rising.
When you've got time…
You said make him a sandwich.
Is the trap ready?
Just waiting to be primed, ma'am.
Good, good, good.
Careful, ma'am.
Gets a bit slippy with ice.
Ooh. And ever so cold.
I'm not a child.
Well, you're my child
in a manner of speaking.
It could be said
that you sprang from my loins.
That's the most disgusting thing
I've ever heard.
How's the Doctor?
Getting there.
Doubts at 30%.
But it's sunset at 20:58,
and that's when his thinking intensifies.
[The Rani] It's a shame
these little people have to die.
I was getting rather fond of them.
But tonight we will find him.
The One Who is Lost.
And then the great work begins.
[Conrad] Many years ago
when Gallifrey was young,
the Doctor and the Time Lady
had been terrible enemies.
They had fought over all sorts
of irrelevant things.
But the Time Lady knew
they could be great friends.
If only Doctor Who knew
how clever she was.
So one day
-she stepped out of the shadows.
-It's weird, innit?
-Like they're there but not there.
-She said, "Doctor Who, remember me?"
-How is that even possible?
-[Conrad] And he did.
He said her name out loud.
And he said,
"We shouldn't be enemies anymore."
-Uh, sorry.
-[Conrad] We're the only ones left.
I don't suppose you could spare us
a couple of quid, could you?
-[Conrad] All the Time Lords are dead…
-No, no.
I shouldn't be talking to you.
This isn't right.
[Conrad speaks indistinctly]
Sorry, but is your name Shirley?
Ruby.
[chuckles]
[chattering]
This is how we live.
The disabled, the dispossessed,
the ones who don't fit in.
I swear I've never seen this place before.
Yes, you have. You walk past it every day,
and you ignore us.
But how do I know you,
'cause I swear we've never met.
Can you please just tell me
what the hell is going on?
[Shirley] We get ignored.
We're poor and forgotten and irrelevant,
and that is the way the world is.
Except… sometimes all of us
in the camp get these glimpses.
It's like a glimpse
in the corner of my eye,
like I can remember something.
Then… it's gone.
-A glimpse of a better world.
-[chuckles]
[Shirley] Yeah,
but you're different from us lot.
Pardon me if I don't frisk you,
but you seem very non-disabled to me.
Oh. [chuckles]
Well, I could be taller, but yeah.
[all laughing]
Yeah, but despite that,
you're the same as us.
You keep having doubts
about the world, but why?
Um…
Well, there's this man called the Doctor,
and he's connected somehow.
'Cause it feels like
I've lived through this before.
I've seen 2025 and it was different.
And I tried telling my mum
and my gran, and they said…
You can't say things like that.
A foster child can't listen to doubts!
There is something wrong with you,
my girl.
Somebody put guzum upon you.
[Carla] It's my daughter.
She's been expressing doubts.
I think you need to come
and take her away.
My own mother.
[glass shattering]
[sighs] Get her another one, Pete.
Val says you were lucky.
She says we're all lucky.
We live outside the world,
so we can see it better.
-We can see when things don't make sense…
-Thank you.
…but here we are.
We haven't got a penny,
but I've got this wheelchair.
State of the art.
And God knows, with my spina bifida
I need medicine, and I've got nothing.
But I'm okay.
Val says we're suspended.
For me, I think these things
are like fossils or relics,
like they're bleeding through
from a life that's been lost.
Brian, tell 'em your theory.
It all comes down to Conrad Clark.
Yeah, well… [chuckles]
I keep having thoughts about him too.
[chuckles]
Ruby Sunday.
I don't trust him for a second.
Oh, my God, you too.
You can get arrested
for saying things like that.
Yeah, well, I don't know why or how.
But Conrad Clark is a monster.
[all cheering]
That's exactly what I say.
Everything that's wrong
revolves around Conrad.
And that man's hiding something.
But what? Can you tell from,
like, the sound of his voice?
Yes, because being blind
gives you magical powers.
-[all laughing]
-All right. [chuckles]
Give me a break. [chuckles]
No, it's obvious.
It's perception bias.
He's not disabled,
so he literally can't see us.
And if he can't see us,
well then we don't get seen.
Yeah, he's like king
and ruler and emperor and god.
I mean, how did Conrad
become god of the earth?
[sighs]
So what do you think, Ruby?
About what?
We don't just sit here
all day complaining.
We've got plans.
[sighs]
We're gonna bring down God.
You with us?
Oh, I'm in. [chuckles]
I am in. [chuckles]
[sighs]
But the Time Lady had an idea.
She said, it's not over… not over,
because I know a secret hidden away.
And the secret came from the depths
of Time Lord history.
A secret so old and so terrible,
everyone had forgotten,
but the secret was beginning to wake.
And the Doctor said, "Tell me the secret."
But the mysterious Time Lady
was clever and wise,
and she knew that Doctor Who was weak.
Doctor?
Doctor, can you hear me?
I haven't got much time. They're coming.
And this hell dimension
is sliding into the pit.
I don't know if I'm gonna survive.
Thank you for that, you know.
But I have to warn you,
I can only send you one warning
and this is gonna sound strange,
but listen to me.
Tables don't do that.
Remember, tables don't do that.
I gotta go.
I miss you.
Well,
more than that,
I love you.
I warn you, Doctor,
this secret will change reality forever.
[glass shattering]
[glass shattering continues]
John,
what are you doing?
Come on, look.
Look, look, look, look. Look.
-It's been a very long day.
-No.
-Why don't you come to bed?
-No. Wait.
Wait, wait.
Do you see?
-[chuckles]
-So?
-That's a slip. That's what happens.
-No.
-Things slip.
-No, no.
[panting]
But how?
-How do they slip?
-It's just the way of the world, John.
They always have, and they always will.
Now, stop it.
[gasps]
'Cause he said…
he said, tables don't do that.
And I thought he's right.
He's right. That is not
what tables are supposed to do.
Who said?
There was a man on the TV.
And I really liked him.
Hello?
I'm sorry.
It's my husband.
He's having doubts.
[sirens wailing]
[tyres squealing]
[police radio chatter]
-He's in there.
-[Doctor] No, I wasn't…
I wasn't doubting anything. I just asked.
I had a question.
I had a good question. That's all.
-I am sorry.
-[Belinda] I had to think of Poppy.
-I got this thought.
-I couldn't have doubts in the house.
-Not with her upstairs.
-I couldn't stop it.
I am sorry, Bel.
I couldn't stop it.
[grunts]
[♪ tense music playing]
[police, on radio]
We have the unit secure.
I'm really very sorry, Mrs Smith,
but I have a job to do.
[gasps] Amma?
What are you doing here?
There's a child asleep upstairs,
and she's going to need someone with her
in the morning.
-Take her.
-What are you doing?
Get off me! Leave me alone.
-[gasps] Amma!
-I'm sorry, Belinda!
I'm so sorry.
[Mrs Flood]
You recognised your husband's doubt
because you've been
expressing doubt yourself.
That's what it does, Mrs Smith.
It contaminates, it breeds, it festers,
and it's my job to cut it out.
My job and my very great pleasure.
[grunting, panting]
[sirens wailing]
[♪ tense music playing]
-Hurry up.
-[Shirley] All right. All right.
[tyres squealing]
We're not exactly
the best bunch of spies, are we?
-Oy, ya ableist.
-Well, come on.
If we're caught outside after the curfew,
then we'll be locked up
for doubting the system.
Stop worrying, you.
This is the perfect vantage point. Look.
And I've got this.
Well, what does it do?
It's one of the relics
from the other world.
And…
-[device beeping]
-…it's got power.
-[friend] Like magic.
-But it's not.
[chuckles]
-Why does it feel so familiar?
-I know.
Like I've seen it before.
But whatever it is,
we think this can help us
with Conrad Clark.
-Do you see the way the picture links up?
-[Ruby] Hmm.
I think that means that Conrad
is broadcasting from up there.
And if this thing can trace the signal,
what if we can block it?
What if we can cut him off?
Then he'd have to find us.
The plan is for Conrad
to leave the Bone Palace,
-and then once he's outside…
-That's all I need.
If I can just meet Conrad,
if I can look him in the eye,
then I'll remember.
I just feel like I'll remember.
And if I can remember everything,
then I can remember the Doctor
and the world that was.
[device whirring]
[droneguard]
You will step over the threshold.
-I don't know what you mean.
-What are these things?
[droneguard]
The male will step over first.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay.
[sighing]
-[droneguard] Now, the female.
-Okay.
[chuckles]
It's fine.
-It's fine. It's good.
-I'm sorry I reported you.
It's my fault.
I have my doubts, okay?
But I never doubt you, Belinda.
Whatever this place is,
we'll find out together.
[gasps]
[Belinda breathes shakily]
What the hell?
Doctor.
Oh, yes, Doctor.
Remember?
Oh, come on, we go way back.
-Open up that memory.
-[gasps]
What about this?
It's called the Seal of Rassilon.
Rassilon was the President Eternal
of the Time Lords.
Anything? No? Nothing?
And these things, clone-type-classiforms.
Basic Seeker-function animals.
No?
Is any of this making sense?
Don't you ever wonder deep down
in both your hearts,
where your TARDIS is?
T-A-R-D-I-S.
Who are you?
[Belinda] I want to ask.
Please, I have a child at home.
Her name is Poppy.
And I promise we won't mention
any of this, ever,
if you just let us go home
and look after her.
No, you haven't.
-What?
-Got a child.
I beg your pardon?
You haven't got a child.
Don't you dare say that.
-That girl, she said--
-Yes.
Yes, yes, yes, that's it. You remember.
What was her name?
-Ruby.
-[gasps]
Oh, he's getting there. That's it.
May the 24th, it's on its way.
Nine minutes, close down,
lock all externals.
What's it doing?
It-It's telling us the time,
but I don't understand
why that's so important.
What's going on up there?
Music!
[♪ dance music playing]
We danced once upon a time, you and I.
At the siege of Persephone,
with the city burning around us.
People said we were lovers.
Can you remember if that's true?
Far away in time and space.
Were we?
[♪ dance music continues]
Yes, I had a different face.
So did you a long time ago,
because the tragedy is
we were never enemies.
Every villain you ever fought
wanted death.
I only wanted life.
Remember?
My name is the Rani.
[♪ music stops]
[breathes shakily] No.
No.
-You remember.
-No.
-I am the Rani.
No, no, no, no.
[panting]
And I am the Rani.
-We bi-generated.
-[panting]
[both] We are both the Rani.
-[Doctor panting]
-What the hell are you saying?
The two of you?
It sounds like one of Conrad's stories.
-I love saying this bit.
-[chuckles]
Your husband is an alien and so am I.
We are the last Time Lord
and the last Time Lady
from the planet Gallifrey
in the constellation of Kasterborous.
-No, no, no, no, no.
-But this planet is a lie.
This whole world is a wish.
What are you even talking about?
-[panting]
-Oh, darling, darling.
I know this is hard.
-Come. Come.
-Leave him alone!
But he made so much of this happen.
He stirred the gods, Belinda.
He woke the most ancient of powers.
Come and see.
I can't let you in.
I don't trust you for a single second.
But look.
What?
[panting]
Conrad?
Doctor.
Why does everyone keep calling me that?
The last time we met,
you told me I was nothing.
So what do you think of me now?
[The Rani] It's the child, Doctor.
You woke the Pantheon.
And the most powerful god of all was born,
Desidirium, the God of Wishes.
And he's mine.
All the world below
is a world I have wished.
[The Rani] We needed one more thing.
Come on.
No God of Wishes
could have infinite power,
or we'd be drowning
in a universe of breast milk.
So, I needed to boost his powers
which led to the Vindicator.
Hidden in plain sight, do you remember?
-No. No.
-Gotta say, great bit of tech.
It criss-crossed the universe,
creating a web of power
to bring you back here.
Look at that.
Voystet-bladen energy
to the power of five,
-roughly the equivalent of…
-A billion supernovas.
There.
He's remembering.
So the Vindicator created a web
of titanic power ready for me to use.
Power great enough
to amplify the wishes of a god,
allowing Conrad to create an entire world.
You cannot wish
a whole world into existence.
Exactly.
It's full of mistakes
and it cannot sustain itself
because you have doubts.
Doubts… Doubts are not allowed.
[Belinda] All right, yes, we have doubts.
So what if we do?
Everybody has doubts.
Oh, she's got it.
She's very good.
Because the truth is…
[Mrs Flood]
The doubts are not the problem.
The doubts are the whole point.
Doubt is such a beautiful thing.
If you question hard enough,
then doubt can crack open the world.
-[rumbling]
-On cue!
[gasps]
It shook.
The whole palace shook.
What is happening?
That's why I needed you
trapped inside the wish.
Because this isn't
just exposition, Doctor.
I need to tell you everything
so that your doubt becomes all-consuming.
If ordinary doubt cracks open the world,
then a Time Lord's doubt rips open
the structure of reality itself.
Come and see.
-Quickly. Out we go!
-[panting]
So much fun.
Look at the city.
[gasps]
Farewell to London.
That is not real. It can't be.
That is not… That is not real.
The palace exists
as a fixed point. It's safe.
But you wished this world into existence,
and then you kill it.
Why are you doing this?
Because once reality is broken
on a scale as vast as this,
-I can see underneath.
-See what?
Deep within the Underverse, he is hidden.
The One Who is Lost.
Who?
Oh!
There she blows!
[♪ fast-paced music playing]
[inhales sharply] Tell me. Tell me.
Tell me who you are looking for.
Omega.
The first Time Lord.
The creator of the Time Lords.
The greatest
and most terrifying Time Lord of all.
[in ominous voice] Long live Omega.
Omega shall be free!
[groaning, panting]
[sighs]
I remember.
The Doctor is me.
And the Rani…
[panting]
You can't do this!
I remember! All right?
I am the Doctor!
Oh, my God. Belinda.
Get rid of the wife.
Take her across the threshold.
[Belinda] What are you doing?
Where's John? Where is he?
[laughs] There is no John.
You married a ghost.
Nice of you to join us, Doctor,
but I remember you too.
And I know that you'll try everything
to stop me, so I can't take that risk.
[Doctor gasps]
[screaming] Rani!
[panting]
[all scream]
But don't you understand?
I have a daughter!
Poppy is real!
Don't you know what that means?
[grunting]
-[screaming]
-[♪ fast-paced music ends]
[♪ closing theme song playing]