(THUNDER CRASHES AND ROLLS)
Confined again.
I cannot bear it.
The very world itself
seems sick.
A most ungenial summer.
I've never known air as dank
and frigid.
Oh!
Dank and frigid?
Who does that remind me of,
I wonder.
Oh!
Sleep well, sweet boy.
Perhaps Lord Byron or
Dr Polidori would read to us?
What would Miss Clairmont
wish to hear?
Something to awaken
thrilling horror.
Yes, Mrs Shelley.
To make us dread to
look around.
- (THUNDER RUMBLES)
- To curdle the blood
and quicken the beatings
of the heart.
I have just the thing.
Oh...
(EXHALES)
Tales Of The Dead.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
"At midnight, we took a torch
to the chapel "
(THUNDER CRASHES)
"With pallid countenance
and trembling limbs,
"we descended to the vault.
"Hildegarde's leaden coffin
loomed before us.
"The Count was seized
with the sensations of terror. "
(HANDLE RATTLES)
"He opened the coffin
with a stifled cry of dread,
"and inside we saw..."
- (BANGING ON DOOR)
- (WOMEN SHRIEK)
I shall send whoever calls
away, my lord.
No, Fletcher.
What if it is she?
(WHISPERS) Hildegarde,
the death-bride.
If something infernal
is on my doorstep,
I should be the one
to go and greet it.
- Infernal?
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
Surely not?
Who is brave enough
to come and see?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I'll wager it's Shelley,
amusing himself with a trick.
Shelley is not one for tricks.
(CRASH)
There is nothing to be
afraid of.
(ALL SHRIEK)
Good evening! Not quite
the welcome I was hoping for,
but I'll admit
we've looked better.
It's a pleasure to make
your acquaintances. I'm...
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Nothing?
Weird.
Might need a blow-dry.
Got a bit caught
in the downpour.
Yes, because it is a truth
universally acknowledged...
Wrong writer!
...that one's driver will park
one's carriage
imprudently too far from
whence one is going.
Can we please just come in?
Before we drown to death.
Please.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Ha-ha!
DOCTOR: One hour, tops.
GRAHAM: Plus drying time.
DOCTOR: OK, so there was
a spot of rain
and gale-force winds
and a super-long walk.
But I got us here, didn't I?
And Mary Wollstonecraft Godwin,
soon to be Shelley,
screamed in your face.
Quality historical experience,
that. Gold!
(WHISPERS) On the night
that inspired Frankenstein.
If...you'd be so kind...
Blimey!
Excuse me, Yaz. I was
very clear about the rules.
Nobody mention Frankenstein,
and don't interfere.
And nobody snog Byron.
In, out, soak up the atmos.
Witness some of the most
enlightened minds
of a generation
at the pinnacle,
the absolute zenith
of their creativity...
(ALL SHRIEK)
(SHRIEKING STOPS)
What would you all
care to drink?
CLAIRE: We shall teach them
the dance.
(LIVELY PIANO MUSIC)
(SIGHS) I detest all gossip,
you understand.
Utterly abhor it.
Mary goes by Mrs Shelley...
...except she and Percy
are not married.
It really is quite a scandal.
Lord Byron is separated
from his wife.
The rumours are so disastrous
he cannot return to England.
Now he keeps company
with Mary's stepsister,
Miss Clairmont.
We have an exceptionally strong
attachment.
She scrambled 500 miles
from England
to come and see me here.
Couldn't exactly turn her away.
(GASPS) Please excuse me,
fair lady.
I must poppeth
to the little boys' room.
So...that was marvellous.
(PANTS) Is anyone up for,
I don't know,
I'm spitballing here, how about
writing the most gruesome,
spine-chilling ghost story
of all time?
(SPEAKS SOFTLY IN FRENCH)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(KEY TURNS IN LOCK)
(WIND WHISTLES)
(SHRIEKS)
DOCTOR: ...you know?
A bit of blood and guts?
Throw in a corpse
for good measure.
Float anyone's boat? Mary?
Or perhaps another quadrille?
- I shall choose the music.
- LORD BYRON: Hear, hear!
Excuse me, Doctor.
You broke a rule.
Next, you'll be snogging Byron.
I was trying to get them
back on track.
Something's wrong here.
This night, June 1816,
Byron challenges Mary Polidori
and Percy Shelley
to come up with a ghost story.
Spot the difference!
You and I shall be partners
for the next dance.
Not much writing going on?
And there's no Shelley.
Bingo! They're a man down.
Why?
(FOOTSTEPS)
- Sorry, love.
- (GASPS)
Oh...
Crikey. A bit lost.
Looking for the lavatory?
C'est diabolique, monsieur!
C'est terrible.
Never mind. I can hold it.
Big house like this - there's
got to be a lav somewhere.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
I'm going round in circles
here.
(GASPS)
It is impolite not to announce
oneself, Miss Khan.
Breaking and entering's worse.
I'm not at fault if Lord Byron
selfishly keeps it locked.
What are you after?
Letters.
If he's written about me, I can
ascertain his true sentiments.
Or...
...you could try asking him.
I have.
His answers only increase
the enigma.
I know someone like that.
Mary reproaches me...
...and says I should find
a more reliable prospect.
Not that she can talk.
Perhaps she's right.
His eye does seem to wander.
This enigmatic person
of yours...
Would you trade them for
reliable and dull?
My person's a bit different.
Did you see that?
What?
Nothing.
Trick of the light.
(SONIC BUZZES)
She walks in beauty,
like the night.
Of cloudless climes
and starry skies.
(SONIC BUZZES)
I'm intensely flattered
you're familiar with my work,
Mrs Doctor.
Just Doctor is fine.
I'm quite into Shelley's stuff
too. He about?
Indisposed, I'm afraid.
He won't be joining us.
May I be candid?
Go for it.
I sent my man out to fetch
your carriage,
but it seems to have
disappeared.
(# Chopsticks)
(NOTES JAR)
Such a jaunty air!
Is it popular in the colonies?
Er...yeah.
My nan taught me but I always
get the keys wrong.
But she always said
there's no reason not to try.
I should practise more.
But I confess,
I prefer to write...
Ah.
...even though my efforts
are weak.
I could never hope to match
the achievements of my parents.
My nan would say stick with it.
MARY: Hmm.
- What's his problem?
- Oh...
Pay Dr Polidori no heed.
He's bad-tempered because
he does not sleep.
He walks at night.
A terrible affliction.
Imagine...never being able to
truly rest.
I'm fully aware
of what you want!
Please reveal all.
My third canto.
Of Childe Harold's Pilgrimage,
my work in progress.
Nah, it goes on a bit,
that one. No offence.
Nice mention of Ada, though.
I'm a big fan of hers.
You know of my daughter?
Will do. Gorgeous brain.
Why are you here?
For a quick visit, supposedly,
but I'm getting this really
weird vibe off your house.
Vibe?
Yeah.
I don't want to worry you,
but I'm sensing
that it's sort of...
...unrelentingly evil.
Ryan, it's like a maze
up there,
and they're a few years shy
- of a toilet.
- Sir?
Oh, blimey!
You've gotta stop doing that.
Splendid.
Very convenient.
Ryan, not a khazi
for love nor money,
and a Frenchwoman who's got
a right hump about something.
Mrs Shelley seems fatigued.
Only of waiting to dance.
You're the one
who looks like death.
- Do you insult my visage, sir?
- You might want to
stop shooting daggers and maybe
take a nap, all right?
I beg your pardon?
He means, perhaps you should
take a rest.
I'm a physician.
I'm in rude health.
Whatever you say, mate.
(CHUCKLES)
Then I say choose, sir!
Sorry.
He does this rather a lot.
- Choose your weapon!
- What?
Isn't it obvious?
He's challenging you to a duel.
Oh... Look, hey, look,
I'm not here to fight anyone,
- so everyone just calm down.
- Fletcher!
- You will be my second.
- (FLETCHER GROANS)
- Will Mr O'Brien be yours?
- No!
- Cheers, mate.
- No, what I mean... No,
because there's going to be no
duel. I absolutely forbid it.
- Ooh! Ooh!
- What's up? What's up?
I shall return with my pistol.
He's getting a gun.
Whatever is that?
No...
I think it's a...
...hand!
It's definitely a hand!
Get it off him.
- Doc!
- It's so strong!
- (GASPS)
- And ferocious!
(MARY GASPS)
Great shot.
Hmm.
14th. No...
15th century. Touch more umami.
- She licked it!
- She is
the most baffling creature
I've ever been acquainted with.
Human. Protein. Collagen and...
...nothing abnormal.
What kind of implement is that?
One that zaps people's
heads off who threaten
- people with guns.
- I don't think they're
- really from the colonies.
- No.
She is from somewhere
much, much stranger.
The north.
How did it come to life, then?
Was it haunted, or something?
Unlikely.
Well, you did say the house
was evil.
Well, that's a development.
I've been getting a vibe.
If there is evil here,
I know who brought it in.
(SIGHS) Very well. I may have
a skeleton...in my chamber.
Right. You keep an eye on
Trigger Happy.
Me and you need to take a squiz
at your skeleton.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- It's a collection.
- Of what?
- Dead stuff?
- Relics of war.
(SONIC BUZZES)
From my travels.
Reminders that we tread
on the dust of empires.
Crops now grow
where blood was split.
An innocent fascination,
I assure you.
Waterloo!
Oh! I love a good plume!
What do you think?
A 15th-century soldier...
...from the Battle of Morat.
His final remains.
One hand gone.
Both hands gone.
Great. There's another
on the loose.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Anything else strange happen
since you've been here?
When the weather turned,
Shelley began having visions.
He's prone to them.
What did he see?
An apparition of a figure...
...floating above the lake.
When you said he was
indisposed, what did you mean?
Uh, well,
when he didn't join us,
my mind naturally wandered
to the idea of
some torrid assignation
in town.
Shelley often retires
to our chalet...
...to write.
Maison Chapuis. On the shore.
You should probably pop down
and have a chat.
(SNORING)
(CLOCK TICKS)
You're like ninjas, you lot.
(CHUCKLES)
Fair play to you, though, love.
Food!
There's never any food.
Cheers. You're a better. Yeah.
- Baby-sitting duty. Yeah.
- (SNORING)
He'll be no trouble now,
though. Dead to the world.
This apparition -
did Shelley describe it
in any more detail?
Dark. Charred by fire.
Suspended over the water
like a death god
rising from Hades.
Right...
Nothing too sinister, then.
You can ask him more questions
when we get to the chalet.
Did we just go down to the top?
What reanimates bones
and leaves no trace?
Why just the hands?
Why only parts?
However, my collection's
not demonic?
Correct.
But I'll probably come back
for this, though.
Strictly for, er,
safety purposes.
Not because it really suits me,
or anything.
This vibe you mentioned -
is it still there?
Yeah. I can't...
It's like it won't let me
think.
I need to get
out of this house.
Easier said than done,
apparently.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- Oh... How many times now?
- RYAN: Seven?
Mrs Doctor said the house
was evil. She must be right.
It's turning against us.
A house can't do that.
Even an evil one.
Oh, don't worry. We're great at
sorting things out like this.
There's always
an explanation...
Oh, it touched me!
Ghost! Ghost.
It definitely touched me.
Ryan, that was my elbow.
I knew that.
I totally knew that.
(BABY CRIES)
Please tell me
there's a real baby in here.
My son - William.
I must get to him!
(BOTH GASP)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
You're going nowhere, pal.
You're staying right there.
I'm on guard.
Oh...
Hey! Poli?
Poli? Hello?
Poli?
Poli? Can you hear me, son?
Can you hear me?
(GROANS)
The same chamber.
Over and over.
- How is it possible?
- It's not.
- It's...
- Like a dream.
Elise!
Can you hear me?
Do you have William?
YAZ: He'll be OK.
He probably just cried himself
out and fell asleep.
Doc! Poli! Doc! Doc!
(GRAHAM GASPS)
There's something
seriously wrong with this gaff.
Is anyone else trapped?
Yeah. And I think I'm seeing
dead people.
(WIND WHISTLES)
- Perfect...
- RYAN: We're the same!
I totally saw a ghost.
- We're stuck on the stairs!
- Please!
How do we move upwards?
I need to check my son is well.
Working on it!
Head's a bit fuzzy.
Normal service will resume
shortly.
- And ghosts don't exist.
- Of course not!
You two just need a spray tan
and a kip, eh?
Graham, what sort of
dead people, exactly?
Oh... How can I hear
your voice, Doc?
(MUFFLED) I'm using
the fireplace chimney.
Doc?
Graham?
They've gone now.
And...
...so's Polidori.
- I've lost him.
- You had one job!
Yeah, made more challenging
by his ability to walk
through walls!
Through?
He just turned sort of zombie
- and went into one.
- What do you speak of?
What is a zombie?
Mrs Doctor?
Kind of a dead person walking,
but it won't be that.
- Mrs Doctor?
- How do you know?
Because Polidori isn't dead,
for a kick-off.
- Mrs Doctor!
- Really, just Doctor is fine.
Polidori!
(GASPS) He emerged
from the wall like a phantom.
Be gone, demon!
Pulse - check.
Breathing - check.
May I just say, you are
quite lovely in a crisis.
No, you may not!
The lights are on.
He's gone on a mini-break.
Possessed?
Or asleep?
He walks in his sleep.
One does not sleepwalk
through walls.
Not just through - up.
He was downstairs a second ago.
What you said before...
- About being lovely?
- Back a bit!
Er... Demon?
It's like dreaming...
...only we aren't...and he is.
So he can't see the illusion.
It's more than that.
We're surrounded. Immersed.
It's sort of like
a perception filter.
Close your eyes.
Clear your mind.
We're only experiencing
what it wants us to.
I can feel it.
She's right.
Our minds are being deceived.
Here is the door,
hidden from our eyes.
Elise?
I'm coming for William.
MARY: How are we here now?
This is impossible.
This should be William's room.
This place keeps on changing,
like a puzzle.
I don't get it.
Why hide a house
inside a house?
William! My darling!
(SCREAMS)
I suspect I must have missed
something.
Yes, but you've shown us
how to get out of this room.
POLIDORI:
This cannot be the hallway.
We've not descended the stairs.
BYRON: It is. But there
should be a door here.
Please can we get out of here?
In theory, yes.
We just have to tell ourselves
that we can walk
through the door
we know is right there...
- (THUD)
- (GASPS)
Ohh!
My bones have never caused
such mischief before, I swear.
The things we know - we can
move inside but not out.
Dead things don't act dead.
People vanish. Elise?
My poor William.
RYAN: There's no sign
of Fletcher either.
Hey, maybe Shelley didn't turn
up because he couldn't get in.
I've never believed in such
things, but could this be Hell?
Could we be deceased?
Nice blue-sky thinking, but no.
This place keeps on folding in
on itself as well.
Exactly.
I think we're caught in
a security system. It's...
It's turned the house into
a sort of giant panic room.
In 18167
The Year Without a Summer.
They blamed it on volcanic ash
covering the sunlight.
Weather went haywire.
What if something came here
that wasn't supposed to
and caused a major disturbance?
Like what?
That?
That could be a solid option,
Mary, yes.
MARY: What is it?
I don't know.
RYAN: It's sort of
just floating around.
Like a death god
rising from Hades.
Shelley's vision.
But we're all having it.
No. It's pushing through.
That is what Shelley saw.
It's not a vision.
It never was.
It's a traveller...
...moving through time.
And he's trying to get in.
Are you the guardian?
Thatis a lone Cyberman.
(DOCTOR GASPS)
Jack's warning - beware of
the lone Cyberman. Don't let it
- have what it wants.
- At all costs!
Yes, thank you!
Barricade the door!
May I ask, what is a Cyberman?
Someone altered.
Organs, flesh surgically
replaced with mechanical parts
without consent.
He drives them insane
so they alter the brain too,
- switch off all emotion.
- Are you the guardian?
Never seen one like him before.
He's different.
(BANG ON DOOR)
- Unfinished.
- Are you the guardian?
- (BANG ON DOOR)
- Whatever he came for
is hidden here.
It explains the security.
- What's hidden?
- I've no idea,
but I need to beat him to it.
Quick.
(BLASTER FIRES THEN FADES)
FLETCHER: Lord Byron?
Doctor, what are you doing?
Where are you going?
You're not leaving us?
I have to find out
what he's looking for.
Alone.
You need backup.
All of us against one.
One Cyberman,
but then thousands.
Humans like all of you changed
into empty, soulless shells.
No feeling, no control,
no way back.
I will not lose anyone else
to that!
Do not follow me.
Lord Byron?
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Is that you?
I fear I've lost my faculties
entirely.
(GASPS)
Are you the guardian?
No, sir.
I am the valet.
(GROANS)
(BABY CRIES)
(BABY CRIES SOFTLY)
(PRAYS SOFTLY IN FRENCH)
(BABY CRIES)
(CRYING INTENSIFIES)
(GASPS)
(PRAYING CONTINUES)
(ELISE SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING STOPS ABRUPTLY)
(BABY CRIES SOFTLY)
(CRYING STOPS)
Don't be afraid, little one.
You will be like us.
MARY: What if it finds William?
We need to find the child.
- And a way out.
- We are not safe here.
He could pass through a wall
at any moment.
The Doctor told us to wait.
Technically, she only told us
not to follow her.
Let's split up.
Tell me what you're after.
I might be able to help.
Well, it was never going to be
under there...
...unless you don't actually
know what it looks like.
Funny...
This dark age is surprising.
You're not as primitive
as I expected.
You're not as cyborg-y
You have met my kind before?
- You could say that.
- You appear courageous,
but your vital signs betray
a heightened state of anxiety.
Or as I like to call it,
Tuesday. Interesting look.
What happened? They get bored
halfway through, or something?
I am complete enough
to serve my purpose.
(BLASTER FIRES THEN FADES)
Oh.
Bit embarrassing.
Time hop took a lot of juice.
Now you're fresh out.
You irritate me.
How very human.
Still feel things, then?
No inhibitor yet.
I do not need to be stabilised!
OK. Here's the thing. There's a
chance I might be the guardian,
only I don't know what it is
I'm supposed to be guarding.
This isn't my time either.
Maybe we're supposed to work
together.
- Together?
- Anything's possible.
The house still shifts.
- Whose room is this?
- No-one's.
I thought it was empty.
YAZ: But the writing on the
walls and all of these papers?
The writing... It's Shelley's.
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
The cellar.
We'll give it a miss, eh?
Could the coal hatch be
a means of escape?
We should try everywhere.
Is it too late to choose
another group?
(WIND WHISTLES)
Ooh! You ever considered
breath mints?
Recharging? Not good.
Figuring out how to
manipulate the elements
and creating
an extremely sophisticated
and probably unlimited
external power source.
That's better!
POLIDORI:
The coal hatch has gone.
There's no way out.
Claire, you OK?
Miss Clairmont?
(SHAKILY) There's something
down here with us.
I can read the energy field
now.
You are not the guardian.
The Cyberium has selected
another as host too.
What's a Cyberium?
I'll find it and remove it.
What are we talking here?
A life form?
A weapon of some kind?
Both...
What's happening to you?
There's not one atom
of yon earth...
...but once was living man.
The sword that stabs
his peace...
CYBERMAN AND MARY:
...He cherisheth
The snakes that gnaw his heart
And he raises up the tyrant
Whose delight...
CYBERMAN: ...is in woe.
(GASPS)
Shelley's words.
How does it know them?
Something crept in front of me.
I heard its vile breath.
Listen...
(WIND WHISTLES)
I'm sorry,
but I tried to hide it.
I have to keep him out.
Who are you?
I'm the guardian.
I am...
SHELLEY AND CYBERMAN:
...Percy Bysshe Shelley.
He is whom I seek.
But he is fortified against me!
OK. Good to know.
So I vote we split up
and continue the search.
You go this way, and I'll go...
- YAZ: Doctor, you're here!
- Come on, then.
Oh... William!
Dear Fletcher, no.
It cannot be.
Mr O'Brien needs you
in the cellar at once.
We found Shelley.
All of you,
find somewhere to hide.
- But I...
- Do you want to listen,
or do you want to end up
like them?
None of this is
supposed to happen.
They weren't supposed to die,
neither are you,
so, please, let's not unravel
anything else.
Hide, and stay there.
History is vulnerable tonight.
I mean it.
Now go on.
You're going to take William
for me.
(WILLIAM GURGLES)
Guard him well.
Stay safe.
I need to see Percy.
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- Shelley in a cellar,
hidden away, cloaked -
too big to register.
That's why my readings
have been off.
It's something called
a Cyberium.
I'm trying to protect it.
- (DOCTOR GASPS)
- SHELLEY: Be gone, invader!
(EXHALES)
(ROARS)
- (ROAR ECHOES)
- Who moved him?
Is it you? Changing the house?
Some, but not all.
It has its own room.
- Mary!
- I cannot hide.
Not while he suffers.
Show me.
What happened to you?
I was out walking alone.
There was a glimmer
in the lake.
Exquisite.
Alive.
Like quicksilver. I fished it
out to study it more closely.
But then it took root
within me.
(CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
I returned...
Hello!
I was changed.
(GROANS)
No-one could see me.
It hid itself in me, and hid me
within the villa.
DOCTOR: And when it thought
it might be discovered,
it manipulated
all of our perceptions.
SHELLEY: Since the quicksilver
has taken hold of me,
I see symbols.
Symbols and numbers.
They will not leave my head,
no matter how much
I transcribe them.
YAZ: The symbols were
all over his room.
All over the walls.
The house was like
shifting sands.
I sought solitude here,
in the dark.
- What happened to him?
- I'm going with...
- ...alien parasite.
- Cyber technology.
The knowledge of the whole
cyber race and Al
from the future,
containing the knowledge and
future history of all Cybermen.
SHELLEY: They scorched
and split the sky.
Built the army of all armies.
Left behind only pain, rage,
fear and death.
MARY: How has he seen all this?
The Cyberium is burning through
his mind.
It'll destroy him
if it stays in him much longer.
An epic battle. The Cyberium
at the heart of it,
controlling data, strategy,
decision-making.
Clever!
Very clever. Someone took it
from the Cybermen,
sent it back through time here
in an attempt to change
the future. (GASPS)
In an attempt to protect it
from that.
I can't keep him away
much longer.
Then don't.
) - Doc!
Stop fighting
- It's OK.
- Jack's warning!
Jack isn't here now,
stuck in a house with that.
Exactly. You didn't want us
near it a minute ago.
I've just been inside
his brain.
There's a supercomputer
fused to a cerebral cortex.
He's the only one who knows
how to get that out!
Don't let the Cyberman have
what it wants.
I know, because armies will
rise and billions will die.
Shelley's going to die
if that stuff stays inside him.
Shelley's only one life
against all those others.
What are you saying?
How can you condemn him
to death like that?
But is he, Ryan?
His thoughts, his words
inspire and influence thousands
for centuries. If he dies now,
who knows what damage that will
have on future history?
Words matter!
One death, one ripple, and
history will change in a blink.
The future will not be
the world you know.
The world you came from,
the world you were created in
won't exist,
so neither will you.
It's not just his life
at stake. It's yours.
You want to sacrifice yourself
for this?
You want me to sacrifice you?
You want to call it? Do it now.
All of you.
Yeah. Cos sometimes
this team structure isn't flat.
It's mountainous,
with me at the summit
in the stratosphere. Alone.
Left to choose.
Save the poet,
save the universe.
Watch people burn now
or tomorrow.
Sometimes, even I can't win.
Please...
Help me.
(GASPS)
Release what you hold.
- How?
- Release it!
GRAHAM: He doesn't know
what that means!
You've got to tell him
what he's got to do!
I am addressing the Cyberium.
It must execute the host
to be extracted.
It's not obeying you.
Hmm.
Then I shall execute the host.
What is your name, sir?
Mary, this is not a good time
to talk.
Or names. Are you several men?
A composite of parts.
I am better than men!
Yet I still see a soul
in there.
(CHUCKLES)
What do you think you see,
child?
I see the man
who spared my son.
Were you a father? Before?
I was.
You didn't want to be this way.
They hurt you,
this modern Prometheus.
You loved once.
(WHIRRING)
And were loved in return.
You do not wish to kill.
My name was Ashad.
I did spare your son...
(WHIRRING)
...because he's a useless runt,
sickly and weak.
And I did have children.
I slit their throats when
they joined the resistance.
- (SHRIEKS)
- In death we are transformed,
improved, updated,
as you will learn!
Transformed in death.
I'm sorry, Percy Shelley.
So very sorry.
MARY: Mrs Doctor, what are you
doing to him?
Doctor...
YAZ: The Cyberium!
It's leaving his body!
GRAHAM: What just happened?
- YAZ: How are we back here?
- He's reset the house.
Shelley needs help!
I think I've freed him
from the Cyberium!
At what cost?
ASHAD: No!
And it chooses me.
Interesting.
Time Lord magnetism.
Looks like
I'm the true guardian.
(GASPS)
Surrender it
or I will execute you.
I'd be very careful
with those execution threats.
I can feel it already,
fusing to me.
It feels very at home.
Recognising great
host material.
Not to big myself up,
but I don't think it'll vacate
me without a fight.
(WHIRRING)
- (STORM INTENSIFIES)
- (ASHAD ROARS)
- What are you doing?
- Transmitting.
My ship will lock on
to my signal.
It will tear this reality,
and this planet will remain
only in shreds!
This world doesn't end in 1816.
It can't.
It will.
He's bluffing.
Don't listen to him.
But I can't be sure.
I can't risk this planet!
I can't win!
We are inevitable.
Yes.
You are.
What are you doing?
Giving it what it wants.
(BIRDSONG)
(ALL GASP)
What did you do to Shelley?
Old Time Lord trick.
Not a nice one.
Pushed his mind
to his future death,
tricked the Cyberium
into letting go,
hoped his body would survive
the trauma. I'm sorry.
I hope you can forgive me.
You saved Shelley, but what
does that mean for the future?
It means I've put it
in the gravest danger.
Please tell me
- that was part of the plan.
- Yes.
A last-minute,
imperfect, all-I've-got plan.
Saving Shelley was step one.
What's step two?
Fix the mess
I created in step one.
Go to the future, find him
and stop him from rebuilding
the Cyber Army.
Shelley, can you give Yaz
those symbols and numbers?
We're going to need them.
POLIDORI: Well, that was
quite the evening.
Indeed.
Perhaps Miss Clairmont
would care to retire?
A lie-down could prove
restorative.
You pursued Mrs Doctor without
a care for my presence...
...belittled my thoughts
and opinions...
...and then proceeded to use
my person as a human shield.
And...?
And the spell is broken,
my lord.
You have returned me to life,
although I feel as though
I have none of it left to live.
Sorry about the sneak peek.
Every moment will be precious.
How can we repay you?
Just don't lose hope.
Yeah. Keep doing
that writing thing.
If you like.
So, if all the weirdness was
the Cyberium, you know,
the bones and Shelley
floating about and all that,
why would it reanimate
a couple of stiffs
just to bring me a sarnie?
You know, the maid
and the creepy little kid?
Er...no.
We thought you saw Shelley,
like we did.
Oh, come on! Beady eyes?
Made the room go all arctic?
- Where do them two fit in?
- I'm not sure they did.
No, come on, Doc.
This is where you jump in
with a rational explanation.
I mean, ghosts don't exist,
right?
- Unless they do.
- What?!
Inside, you three.
We need to talk.
Listen...
You don't need to come with me.
Cyber war zones and people
don't mix.
I'll drop you back in 2020.
Or we can use
Shelley's numbers.
Co-ordinates, right?
Yeah. Wherever you think's
a good place to start.
With step two.
BYRON: The world was void
The populous and the powerful
was a lump
Seasonless, her bless, treeless
Manless, lifeless
A lump of death
A chaos of hard clay
Ships sailor less lay rotting
on the sea
And their masts fell down
piecemeal
As they dropped
They slept on the abyss
without a surge
The waves were dead
The tides were in their grave
The moon, their mistress
Had expired before
The winds withered
in the stagnant air
And the clouds perished
Darkness had no need of aid
from them
She was the universe.
DOCTOR: Any ideas
what we're walking into -
this planet, this time period,
in the very far future,
immediate aftermath
of the Cyber Wars?