-(NEIGHING)
-Whoa!
-Stand and deliver.
-Do as he says.
I've heard of this brigand.
He is known as the Knightmare.
Faster than Sam Swift the Quick.
Deadlier than Deadly Dupont...
Dabbling lowpads, the pair of them!
With terrible pseudonyms to boot.
Cash bags, jewels, the lot.
I will not be robbed
by some lone ranting cavalier.
Who says I am alone?
(SCREAMING)
-Right.
-(SCANNER BEEPING)
Warm...
Warmer.
We are cursed. The Knightmare
is in league with the devil.
Aye, Satan's sidekick, me.
Where's the rest?
What else would you take from me, sir?
You know what I want.
Hand over the amulet.
-DOCTOR: Hello.
-(MAN YELLS)
Oh, sorry. Chill it.
Don't mind me, don't mind me.
I'm only going to be a minute.
Don't worry. Oh, very warm.
-HIGHWAYMAN: What are you doing?
-Oh, just ignore me,
I'm just passing through,
like fish in the night...
This is a robbery!
Not fish in the night.
-No, it's something else.
-This is my robbery.
No, ships in the night, yeah,
something like that.
Step aside
or I shall blow your brains out.
Sorry, were you talking to me there?
Try again, I promise
I'll listen this time.
You have interrupted my robbery, sir,
and you will step away,
if you wish to take another breath.
You're going to get us all killed
if you don't shut your mouth.
Sorry, sorry, I really was planning
to listen that time.
-But, basically, uh, I didn't.
-(SCANNER BEEPING)
Usually someone hits me at this point,
but she's taking
the year sevens for tae Kwon do.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
Yes! Got You!
Ha-ha!
Oh, hang on. If I didn't know better,
I'd say this was a robbery.
I am robbing these people,
you are getting out of my way.
I just need one tiny little thing
from out of this box.
-This is my robbery.
-Well, can't we share it?
-Isn't that what robbery's all about?
-COACHMAN: Hyaa!
-Hyaa!
-Oh, no, no!
No, no, no, no, no!
You bungled my heist.
No, you bungled mine, Zorro!
Whey-faced fool!
Yeah, well, why don't you
show your face?
At least I show my face,
what's wrong with yours?
(GIRL'S VOICE) Nothing, Doctor.
-You?
-Yes.
It is me.
What took you so long, old man?
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
-"Old man?”
-Seemed apt.
Life expectancy is 35 these days.
Well, for everyone else.
-But didn't you know it was me?
-Of course.
You don't forget the man
who saved your life.
-It's good to see you.
-Yes, I didn't get that impression
when you were threatening to kill me.
(MAN'S VOICE) The Knightmare
has a reputation to maintain.
That's a very good voice.
How do you do that?
Practise.
Last time I saw you,
you were founding a leper colony.
I was so proud of you.
Proud of me? You weren't even there.
Yes, I was.
You didn't see me, but I saw you.
And you just left me there?
Well, you seemed fine.
In a leper colony?
No matter.
You're here now. We should celebrate.
Oh, no, this isn't a visit.
I've got a job to do.
I'm here looking for an alien object,
which has no business
being here on earth in 1651.
It was just... It just so happened,
you know, that my tracking device,
it led me to the carriage that you were,
you know, robbing.
There wasn't, I didn't, it was...
You mean...
You haven't come for me?
No, it was just a coincidence.
Oh, Ashildr, I'm sorry.
Who's Ashildr?
You are. That's your name.
Ashildr.
Daughter of Einarr.
Chuckles. I used to call him Chuckles.
Do you remember that?
Yes.
I think I remember the village.
You loved that village.
If you say so.
Anyone in that village
would have died for you.
Well, they're all dead now
and here I am.
So, I guess it all worked out.
-Ashildr...
-That's not my name.
I don't even remember that name.
(STAMMERING) Well,
what do you call yourself?
-Me.
-Yes, you. There's nobody else here.
No.
I call myself "Me".
All the other names I chose died
with whoever knew me.
Me is who I am now.
No one's mother, daughter, wife.
My own companion.
Singular. Unattached.
Alone.
Anyway, I should get started.
Jump on, I'll give you a ride.
You can help me.
With what?
Packing.
Come on.
It's a big place for someone
who lives on their own.
I have a servant.
And all matters of visitors drop in.
(CREATURE SNARLING)
(SNARLING CONTINUES)
Your device,
what is it?
My curioscanner.
Oh, it sort of, it scans for,
it scans for curios.
I just realised how it got its name.
It's been tracking exoplanetary energy
for the last couple of weeks.
I've been following it
across the galaxy.
And do you know what you're looking for?
I've got a pretty good idea. Yes. Why?
I wasn't just robbing Lucie Fanshawe
for her loot.
She's bragged about having
the rarest gem in the land.
An ancient amulet from foreign parts.
Could it be we are
looking for the same prize?
Clearly, you don't need money.
So, why do you rob?
For the adventure, Doctor.
Isn't that what life's all about?
I've had 800 years of adventure.
Enough to fill a library
if you write it down.
A medieval queen? How exciting.
You'd think.
It was paperwork and backgammon mainly,
as I recall.
Ended up faking my own death.
Did a bunk before the evisceration.
Now this was much more my thing.
The battle of Agincourt.
My first stint as a man.
No one will ever know that a mere woman
helped end the Hundred Years' War.
DOCTOR: You're immortal
not indestructible.
You can be hurt.
Killed even.
Ten thousand hours is all it takes
to master any skill.
Over 100,000 hours
and you're the best there's ever been.
I don't need to be indestructible.
I'm superb.
You should have seen me.
I could shoot six arrows a minute,
got so close to the enemy,
I penetrated arm our.
How many people have you killed?
You'll have to check my diaries.
You can't remember.
For what it's worth,
I've saved many lives, too.
I cured an entire village
of scarlet fever once.
Almost got drowned
as a witch for my troubles.
Fortunately,
I'm really good at holding my breath.
Ungrateful peasants.
The Black Death.
1348.
-I meant to warn you.
-I got sick.
But I got better.
Of course.
Your immune system is learning, too.
There's another bout coming.
And a big fire
that tears through London.
Excellent.
-Maybe I start it.
-No, that was the Terileptils.
Surgeon, scientist,
inventor, composer...
It's a fantastic CV.
You should try my journals.
I read them myself now and then.
Drink pomace wine.
Have a little me time.
You don't seem the nostalgic type.
It's not nostalgia,
it's curiosity.
I can't remember most of it.
That's the trouble
with an infinite life
and a normal-sized memory.
It can't have been easy.
Outliving the people you love.
According to my journals, hell.
Sorry.
You'll have to remind me,
what's sorrow like?
It all just runs out, Doctor.
I'm just what's left.
In fact, I've done all I can here.
I look up to the sky and wonder
what it's like out there.
Please, take me with you.
All these people here,
they're like smoke,
they blow away in a moment.
-You don't know what it's like.
-I do know what it's like.
Then, however you fly,
whatever ship you sail in,
take me with you.
How do you know I had a ship?
Because I'm incredibly clever,
it doesn't matter.
Take me with you.
We'll talk about it.
This thing you're looking for,
I'll help you find it, it'll be quicker.
-I don't need your help.
-Yes, you do.
I know where Lucie Fanshawe lives.
And I'm an excellent housebreaker.
We'll leave in an hour.
(DOOR CREAKING SHUT)
ME: Today is the day I should have died.
Instead, I was reborn.
By my hero, a man called the Doctor.
My love is dying.
It broke my heart
when the questions started
and I knew I had to leave him.
I return to find an old man
who smiles and thinks I am a dream.
I am flesh and blood, my love,
but all you see is a ghost.
Tears.
ME: The plague.
-Mass graves.
-(WOMAN CRYING)
Sightless children...
DOCTOR: “...clutching toys
as they sleep,
"never to wake up.
"My children.
"My screams.
"I could not save you,
"little ones.
"Such pain.
"And yet, still still
"I am not brave enough to die.
"To let go of this
"wretched life.
"I will endure,
"but no more babies.
-"I cannot, will not suffer...
-(SOBBING)
"...such heartbreak again.
"From now on,
it's me against the world."
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Quiet, my friend.
We have a visitor.
I didn't get it.
-But I will.
-(GROWLING)
If your promise stands,
I'll have it by dawn.
My visitor can help me.
Don't worry, he doesn't know about you.
Only about the artefact.
He has no idea what we intend
to do with it.
(BLOWS)
I read your journals.
Why are there pages missing?
When things get really bad,
I tear the memories out.
What can be worse
than losing your children?
I keep that entry to remind me
not to have any more.
I've left you alone too long.
I had no idea how much you had suffered.
But I remember the person
you used to be.
She's still in there.
-I can help you find her.
-Spare me your pity. I'm fine.
I think this is just another mask
that you wear,
to protect you from the pain.
I think the alternative frightens you.
That this is who I've become.
This is no way to live your life.
Desensitised to the world.
So you intend to fix me?
Make me feel again?
Then run away?
I don't need your help, Doctor.
You need mine.
Just this once, you can't run off
like you usually do.
How do you know?
How do you know what I usually do?
We met once in a Viking village.
I didn't give you my life story.
It's true, though, isn't it?
You're the man who runs away.
Oh, who told you that?
Maybe I just worked it out.
Come on.
(SNARLING)
ME: Housebreaks can be tricky.
DOCTOR: Not for me.
Sonic technology.
Should be able to deactivate any alarms.
What's an alarm?
The most wanted in the land.
Now is not the time to be showing off.
Now seems like a very good time to me.
You'll need a mask, sidekick.
-Watch and learn.
-Brought my own, thanks.
ME: 'Tis black as night.
I have a tinderbox somewhere.
(BUZZING)
Show-off.
Know where you're going, do you?
The servants' stairs.
Follow me.
Why are you still alone?
What happened
to the second immortality charge
-I gave you?
-Shh!
No one's good enough.
-Humans need...
-Hush!
(DOCTOR WHISPERING)
Humans need shared experiences...
I'm regretting sharing this one.
It isn't right for you
to be on your own.
-Goodnight, ma'am.
-(DOOR SHUTS)
I'll wager there's a dressing room.
Come on.
(DOOR CREAKING)
-(SCANNER BEEPING)
-(ME WHISPERING) Doctor!
Doctor, turn that thing off!
(BEEPING FASTER)
(PULSATING)
The Eyes of Hades.
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
-(BOTH GASPING)
-(BOTH PANTING)
(BOTH SIGHING)
(LOUD SNORING)
(WHISPERING) Let's just go around,
see if we can't get out the back.
Okay.
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
Lucie?
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENING AND SHUTTING)
(SILVERWARE CLATTERING)
MR FANSHAWE: There is an intruder
on the premises!
Bring me my blunderbuss!
-What are you doing?
-It's kill or be killed.
(WHISPERING) No! You can't.
We should hide.
Guard the doors!
Alert the militia!
Your feet, you oaf.
Oh, I said you'd be a liability.
Just let me shoot them
and be done with it.
(STRAINING) You're the liability.
Never have this trouble with Clara.
Oh, is she still with you is she?
(GRUNTS)
Oh, you remember Clara, do you?
Of course.
I take particular note
of anyone's weaknesses.
MR FANSHAWE: Search every nook
and cranny!
I warrant they will hang for this!
-So what's wrong with Clara, then?
-There's nothing wrong with her.
Why haven't you made her immortal?
Well, look how you turned out.
She'll die on you, you know.
She'll blow away like smoke.
Save your breath.
How old are you, Doctor?
Older than you.
How many have you lost?
How many Claras?
(PANTING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
Robbery, burglary, that's capital.
Meat and drink to the hangman, Ashildr.
I'm not Ashildr.
I'm Me.
And I fear no hangman in Christendom.
Ah-ha!
Sam Swift the Quick!
I wouldn't be so bold, if I were you.
Don't you know who I am?
The Knightmare,
which is why I'm not alone.
'Tis hardly a fair fight.
And it was fair when you stole my patch?
Is that a fake nose, Sam?
Should call you Sam Sniffed.
What's wrong with it,
it's perfectly normal, isn't it?
For an anteater, maybe.
Ooh!
Well, never knew
you were so puny, Knightmare.
Or should I say, Slightmare.
No, not the puns.
Line in the sand, no puns.
It's what's in my brain
that counts, Bingo Boy.
Well, no brain
outwits a bullet, Dandiprat.
This is banter! I'm against banter!
I'm on record on the subject of banter.
Lay down your arms,
hand over the loot or I'll shoot.
(SIGHING) We'd better had.
He'll probably aim to miss
and hit one of us.
We could give you cash instead.
Who's this? Your sidekick?
You got your dad as a sidekick?
I'm not his dad, I'm the Doctor.
Is that the best name
you could come up with?
What, says "Sam Swift the Quick"?
Trying a bit too hard, isn't it?
Or are you a little bit slow?
You what?
I rest my case.
No one outwits the Knightmare.
Whoa!
If you value the life of your sidekick,
back off.
Put the weapon down...
Who's slow now, Doctor?
Whoa!
-Good question.
-Please.
Knightmare, I don't want to die.
Let's have honour amongst us.
Also, can you confirm
that I'm not your dad?
What do you say, Dad?
I should kill him?
He'll be dead in a minute,
what difference does it make?
Kill him and you make an enemy of me.
Run.
I know their lives are short.
I understand.
But those lives do matter.
Shut up.
You're not my dad.
I have a theory about the amulet.
(MAN COUGHING)
Morning, sir. Forgive me,
but might I enquire into who you are?
The Doctor.
Clayton, sir.
-Would you care for a cocktail, my lady?
-Oh, yes, please.
(CLAYTON COUGHING)
Half-blind and deaf as a post.
He's no use any more really but...
You keep him on.
See? You do have a heart.
You don't fool me.
-How do I look?
-Pink.
Are you coming down with something?
Look, why would an alien artefact
resemble the Eyes of Hades,
King of the Underworld?
An ancient Greek talisman
which wards off evil
and protects those in death
on their journey to an afterlife.
You tell me.
Could it be that the mythology
originated on another planet?
You can't wait to get going
and find out, I'll wager.
No. I think I want to stick around,
keep an eye on you for a while.
Get me back on track.
Well, why not?
Hey, we're a good team.
Then take me with you.
You don't want to be stuck
with an old fool like me,
you have this whole wonderful planet
to play on...
It takes a day to get to Kent.
In the future, you'll fly.
I want to fly right now.
(RAGGED BREATHING) I have waited longer
than I should have ever lived.
I have lost more
than I can even remember.
(SOBBING)
Please, Doctor,
just get me out of this.
I want more than this.
I deserve more than this.
Why not?
Because it wouldn't be good.
Ashildr, please.
Ashildr...
I am not Ashildr any more.
(FAINT GROWLING)
Do you have a cat?
Sounds like a very big cat.
-(LOUD GROWLING)
-Hence, the very big cat flap.
Leandro, meet the Doctor.
You thought I was helping you.
In fact, it was the other way around.
Leandro, we have it.
My friend here
was as useful as I'd hoped.
If somebody needed my help,
why did nobody just ask?
I am forced to assume that you have
plans that I wouldn't approve.
-Oh, Ashildr.
-Stop calling me that.
-Kill me.
-Why?
If you intend any harm to this planet
or its people,
then killing me is by far
your best move.
You invite your own death?
No, I just want you to attack first.
Then my conscience is clear.
-Of what?
-You.
(LEANDRO LAUGHING)
You are not of this world
or part of my plans.
I have no quarrel with you.
Then tell me why you are here
and what you intend to do.
Otherwise, get on
with trying to kill me,
but I advise you,
be very quick and very sure.
I am from Delta Leonis.
My tribe was overthrown,
my world destroyed,
my wife killed as we escaped.
Using the amulet?
That was your means of travel.
I lost it when I crashed to earth.
I found him in my grounds.
He's been sleeping there
while I searched for it.
The underworld.
Gateway to an afterlife.
-Another reality.
-We need it to open a portal.
-Travel the galaxy.
-Oh!
Oh, so what's the plan, Ashildr?
Fancy yourself as his new queen?
Hunting, running errands
while he sleeps.
Oh, dear God.
You're just like every other man.
I'm not looking for a husband, you oaf.
I'm looking
for a horse to get me out of town.
-You said no.
-What? Do you think you can trust him?
He knows what it is to be alone.
So do 1.
Then how could you do what you did?
-I'm looking for the headline here.
-ME: The what?
Well, you know, you want to escape?
Well, go on, escape as much as you like!
Why would I not approve?
-The amulet...
-What about it?
A death is required.
It is the only way the amulet works.
Of course.
Every single death is a tiny fracture
in reality.
And the amulet
can lever the fracture open.
Primitive, but effective.
It's just exploiting
an abundant resource.
-There's so much dying here.
-So who dies,
SO you can run away?
Clayton?
CLAYTON: (COUGHING) Coming, my lady.
No, you can't, he loves you.
To the end, it would seem.
Would you rather take his place?
(ROARING)
Not the Doctor, we agreed.
(GROWLING)
Ashildr, daughter of Einarr,
what happened to you?
You did, Doctor.
You happened.
I know you've suffered.
Your children dying.
They would have died anyway.
Human life is fleeting.
People are mayflies, breeding and dying,
repeating the same mistakes.
It's boring.
And I am stuck here.
Abandoned.
By the one man who should know
what eternity feels like.
Who should understand.
I do, now. But...
You still won't take me with you.
You gad about,
while I trudge through the centuries,
day by day.
Hour by hour.
Do you ever think or care
what happens after you've flown away?
I live in the world you leave behind.
Because you abandoned me to it.
Why should I be responsible for you?
-You made me immortal!
-I saved your life.
I didn't know your heart would rust
because I kept it beating.
I didn't think that your conscience
would need renewing,
or that the well of human kindness
would run dry.
I just wanted
to save a terrified young woman's life.
You didn't save my life, Doctor.
You trapped me inside it.
And now I found someone
who will set me free.
Someone who understands.
Look, I don't know what Lenny the Lion
is up to,
but I know his type.
Very first argument,
guaranteed he'll bite your head off.
Or I'll bite his off.
Perhaps I'll enjoy that.
You're playing with fire.
Open that portal, you have no idea
what horrors might come through.
That's as good a reason as any to do it.
You're not like this. I know you're not.
This is exactly what I'm like.
This is what you made of me.
He'll kill you.
He'll have to be fast.
And if he does...
Perhaps it's about time.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN: Lady Me?
Oh, Lady Me,
thank goodness you are safe.
Sam Swift has been captured,
and he swore the Knightmare
was heading in this direction.
I've not seen him.
Sam Swift will hang in Tyburn at noon.
In half an hour?
A guilty man, destined to die,
no harm in that.
I've not seen the Knightmare.
But this is his sidekick, the Doctor.
He was robbing me.
I only just managed to overpower him.
-You will hang for this.
-No.
Listen, I was trying to help her.
Silence or we'll...
Shoot.
He needn't hang. But keep him
under lock and key for all our sakes.
(DOOR CREAKING OPEN)
Was that the door?
Oh, dear. Always the quiet ones.
Goodbye, Clayton.
You see? I do have a heart.
In which case, don't do it.
Do I look like some feckless thief?
I'm on your side,
I'm an undercover constable
from Scotland Yard.
Do you have Scotland Yard yet?
Been on the cider, have we? (LAUGHS)
The Dunbar victory medal.
I was decorated for valour in battle.
Tell it to the Newgate jailer.
All I want is to bring
the Knightmare to justice.
But you were robbing Lady Me.
I came to warn her.
I fear her life is in danger.
Look, it's the Knightmare.
Cloaked and in disguise, bound
for Tyburn. You have to let me go.
Or take me there.
You wish to hang, too?
Will you take me there if I say yes?
Indeed. There's a bounty
on your head for £20.
Twenty pounds? Is that all?
'Tis a small fortune to us.
Well, in that case, I know where
Lady Me keeps all of her money.
Almost £30.
Now, why didn't you
say that in the first place?
(BREATHING STRENUOUSLY)
(CROWD BOOING AND JEERING)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Hang him!
MAN: All right, calm down, steady on.
Such a good turnout. I'm honoured.
(LAUGHS) Oh, yeah.
Hey, he's new at this,
someone had to show him the ropes.
(CROWD LAUGHS)
Don't worry, mate,
you'll get the hang of it.
When I'm gone, they'll all say
that Sam Swift, he was well hung.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Well, I think a few of you
know that already.
(LAUGHS) Oh, yeah, I'm sure
I recognise a few of you lovely ladies.
You, and you.
I mean, I'd introduce you all,
but I can't remember your names.
(CROWD BOOING)
(GRUNTS)
It's a good job you're here,
or they'd kill me.
(BELL TOLLS)
-(NEIGHING)
-(GRUNTS)
-(BELL TOLLING)
-(MAN YELLING)
Mary, Meg, help me out here, miss.
That's Mrs Baxter to you.
That's a funny name for a fellow.
(CROWD LAUGHS)
It's time.
SWIFT: I've got plenty more,
jokes that is, as well as women.
Hang him now!
CROWD: Hang him! Hang him!
(URGING HORSE ALONG)
MAN: Make us laugh, Sam.
Aye, for while you laugh, I live.
It was raining on the way over here.
The hangman says to me,
"It's all right for you,
I've got to walk back through this."
(CROWD LAUGHS)
What are you paying for, my beauty?
To make it quick.
A fitting end for you, Sam Swift.
Who should be the last
to kiss these lips?
WOMEN IN CROWD: Me! Me!
They must mean you, Lady Me.
You remind me of someone.
Now I want to live more than ever.
DOCTOR: Sorry, yes, yes,
sorry about the horse, excuse me.
Sorry, excuse me, excuse me! Sorry.
Time to hang!
All right, all right.
As God is my highwayman,
he steals the most precious gift of all.
Life.
Magical, filled with adventures.
But at least I can say
that I lived mine to the full.
WOMAN: I love you, Sam Swift!
Is that the Doctor? Doctor, Doctor!
I'm a robber!
Have you taken anything for it?
(CROWD LAUGHS)
Doctor, Doctor!
-Quick, I'm running out of patients.
-(CROWD LAUGHS)
Have you ever seen a sidekick so old?
I'm no one's sidekick!
-He's so old, he farts dust!
-(CROWD LAUGHS)
His nose is so big that...
They'll have to widen the noose.
Or bury him in a pyramid.
You know what they say? Big nose...
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
-Big handkerchief?
-(CROWD LAUGHS)
No, Doctor, don't leave me hanging.
I have a pardon here for Sam Swift,
from Cromwell himself.
Sam Swift is pardoned.
(CROWD BOOS)
MAN: We didn't come
all this way not to see someone hang!
What about the Doctor?
CROWD: Hang the Doctor! Hang the Doctor!
(CROWD YELLING)
Shh.
You want to see someone die?
How's this?
No, Ashildr, no!
No!
DOCTOR: Purple, colour of death.
His life force is opening a portal.
ME: To my new life.
Or to hell.
(ROARING)
A lion man!
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Look!
Goodbye, Doctor.
You are going nowhere.
Doors work both ways.
They let people out,
and they let the enemy in.
ME: What's that? What's happening?
What are those things?
Spaceships, or they will be.
They're coming through the rift
actualising in this plane of reality.
You said you were
the last of the Leonians.
-We were meant to escape!
-You shall, in death.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
No!
Doctor, what have I done?
What have I done to these people?
Stop this! They are defenceless.
Ashildr!
-He doesn't care.
-But I do.
Oh, God, I do. I actually do, I care.
It's awful, isn't it? It's infuriating.
You think you don't care,
but then you fall off the wagon.
Never mind about me,
what are we gonna do about them?
We have to help them, they need you.
They need us!
-Welcome back.
-Well, do something then!
Okay, okay, um, Eyes of Hades,
afterlife, death opens up a gateway...
We need to close it.
-Yeah, I know, but how?
-Sam Swift, he's the conduit.
The amulet, it's still in him.
It's his death that's opening the rift.
So, what do we do?
-Reverse it.
-You cannot reverse death.
Oh, yes, we can.
DOCTOR: Run!
No, my lady,
they will destroy me for this.
The light of immortality.
(ROARING)
Spare me, my brothers!
SAM: Alive.
I'm alive!
-(LAUGHS)
-(CROWD CHEERS)
Last thing I remember
is you turning up, Doctor.
Good thing, too. Between you and me,
I was running out of material.
I could tell, gave a whole
new meaning to dying on stage.
Gallows humour can be tricky.
But at least
there's never a second house.
We've nearly finished these,
I'll get some more in.
By the way,
I've not forgotten that kiss.
-Is he immortal now?
-Do you want him to be?
I don't think I want anyone to be.
Well, probably not.
Probably the power
would have been drained
by the whole opening
and reversing the portal thingy.
There'll be enough power
to bring him back,
but not enough power
to keep him here. Probably.
-Did you just make all of that up?
-Yeah.
It's hard to keep track
of all this stuff.
Keep an eye on him though,
he might be around for a while. Or not.
Who can say?
You're still not going
to take me with you, are you?
People like us, we go on too long.
We forget what matters.
The last thing we need is each other.
We need the mayflies.
See, the mayflies,
they know more than we do.
They know how beautiful and precious
life is because it's fleeting.
Look how Sam Swift made every
last moment count, right to the gallows.
Look how glad he is to be alive.
I looked into your eyes
and I saw my worst fears.
Weariness, emptiness.
That's why you can't travel with me.
Our perspectives are too vast,
too far away.
You're not first, you know.
I did travel with another immortal once.
Captain Jack Harkness.
Who?
(SCOFFS)
He'll get 'round to you, eventually.
Who told you about me?
The man who comes for the battle
and runs away from the fallout.
Take your pick.
You've had an impact on this world.
You've made waves.
Sometimes tidal waves.
-I'm flattered.
-Well, you should be.
You're an extraordinary woman, Ashildr,
but I think I'm gonna
have to keep an eye on you.
-No.
-No?
Someone has to look out
for the people you abandon.
Who better than me? I'll be the patron
saint of the Doctor's leftovers.
While you're busy protecting this world,
I'll get busy protecting it from you.
So, are we enemies now?
Of course not.
Enemies are never a problem.
It's your friends
you have to watch out for.
And, my friend,
I'll be watching out for you.
Ashildr,
I think I'm very glad I saved you.
Oh, I think everyone will be.
(GUITAR STRUMS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey! Hello?
Oh, hello! Hi!
-Did you miss me?
-Be more specific. Who are you?
Ha-ha. I've got a present for you.
-Why, am I ill? Are you ill?
-No. No.
Are you never gonna travel
with me again because I said a thing?
It's not a good present.
Oh, well, that's a relief.
Okay, Evie Hubbard.
Year seven.
You helped her out with her homework?
Imaginary interview
with Winston Churchill?
-You basically cheated.
-That was her fault.
Because she should
have stressed "imaginary".
Anyway, she got an A and so,
(CHUCKLES)
she has sent you a selfie.
Yes, you're right,
that is not a good present.
-Come on.
-Do they make sherbet lemons any more?
And I'd like a Ferrari,
what about a Ferrari?
I knew you'd be thrilled.
Okay, come on, let me see,
let me see, let me see.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
What's wrong?
Nothing. Nothing at all.
-Doctor?
-Tell her, next time, I'll take cash.
So...
-Where are you gonna take me?
-Wherever you want.
Hmm. Somewhere...
Somewhere magical.
Somewhere new.
Ah, there is nowhere new under the sun.
Above it, on the other hand,
I've missed you, Clara Oswald.
Well, don't worry, daft old man,
I'm not going anywhere.
OSGOOD: Twenty million Zygons have been
allowed to take human form,
and are now living amongst us.
WOMAN: Any living thing in this world,
including my family and friends,
could turn into a Zygon and kill me.
It's not paranoia when it's real.
They've kidnapped Osgood
and they've stolen the location
of every Zygon on earth.
-Doctor, the ceasefire's broken down.
-Run away!
We have a Zygon revolution on our hands.
ZYGON: We've won the first battle.
There will be truce.
ZYGON: And now
we are going to begin the war.
WOMAN: Or there will be consequences.
-CLARA: I think you might be right?
-About what?
The end of the world.