(WHOOSHING)
I wonder what's wrong with her.
She's sort of queasy.
-Indigestion. Like she didn't want to land.
-If you think there's gonna be trouble,
we could always get back inside
and go somewhere else.
I think we've landed inside a cupboard.
Here we go.
Open door 15.
Some sort of base.
Moon base, sea base, space base.
They build these things out of kits.
Glad we're indoors.
Sounds like a storm out there.
Open door 16.
Human design,
you've got a thing about kits.
This place was put together like a flat-pack
wardrobe, only bigger and easier.
-Open door 17.
-Oh, it's a sanctuary base!
-Close door 17.
-Deep-space exploration.
We've gone way out. And listen to that.
(HUMMING)
Underneath. Someone's drilling.
"Welcome to hell.”
-Oh, it's not that bad.
-No, over there.
Hold on.
What does that say?
That's weird. It won't translate.
But I thought the Tardis
translated everything, writing as well.
-I should see English.
-Exactly.
Now if that's not working, then it means...
this writing is old.
Very old.
Impossibly old.
We should find out who's in charge.
We've gone beyond the reach of
the Tardis' knowledge. Not a good move.
-And if someone's looking for...
-Open door 189.
Right, hello. Sorry.
I was just saying, nice place.
We must feed.
-You gotta what?
-We must feed.
-Yeah, I think they mean us.
We must feed.
We must feed. We must feed.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
We must feed...
you, if you are hungry.
-Sorry?
-We apologise.
Electromagnetics have interfered
with speech systems.
Would you like some refreshment?
-Open door 18.
-Um...
What the hell?
How did...
Captain, you're not gonna believe this.
We've got people.
Out of nowhere.
I mean, real people. I mean...
Two living people just standing here
right in front of me.
(ON RADIO)
Don't be stupid, that's impossible.
-I suggest telling them that.
-But you're a sort of space base.
You must have visitors now and then.
It can't be that impossible.
You telling me
you don't know where you are?
No idea. More fun that way.
(ON PA) Stand by, everyone. Buckle down.
We have incoming, and it's a big one.
Quake 0.5 on its way.
(ALARMS BLARING)
Through here. Now.
Quickly, come on! Move!
Move it! Come on!
Keep moving! Come on! Keep moving!
Oh, my God, you meant it.
-People! Look at that, real people.
-That's us. Hurray!
Yeah, definitely real.
My name's Rose, Rose Tyler,
and this is the Doctor.
Come on, the oxygen must be offline.
We're hallucinating, they can't be...
-No, they're real.
-Come on, we're in the middle of an alert.
Danny, strap up, the quake's coming in.
Impact in 30 seconds.
Sorry, you two, whoever you are,
just hold on. Tight.
-Hold on to what?
-Anything, I don't care, just hold on.
Ood, are we fixed?
Your kindness in this emergency
is much appreciated.
-What's this planet called anyway?
-Don't be stupid. It hasn't got a name.
How could it have a name?
You really don't know, do you?
And impact!
Oh, well. That wasn't so bad...
Okay, that's it. Everyone all right?
Speak to me! Ida?
-Yeah.
-Danny?
-I'm fine.
-Toby?
-Fine.
-Scooti?
-No damage.
-Jefferson?
Check!
We're fine, thanks, fine.
Yeah, don't worry about us.
Surface caved in.
I deflected it onto Storage 5 through 8.
We've lost them completely.
Toby, go and check the rocket link.
That's not my department.
Just do as I say, yeah?
IDA: Oxygen holding.
Internal gravity at 56.6.
We should be okay.
Never mind the earthquake, that's...
That's one hell of a storm.
What is that, a hurricane?
You need an atmosphere for a hurricane.
There's no air out there.
It's a complete vacuum.
Then what's shaking the roof?
You're not joking. You really don't know.
Well, introductions.
FYI, as they said in the olden days.
I'm Ida Scott, Science Officer.
Zachary Cross Flane, Acting Captain, sir.
You've met Mr Jefferson,
he's Head of Security.
Danny Bartock, Ethics Committee.
Not as boring as it sounds.
And that man who just left,
that was Toby Zed,
Archaeology, and this...
is Scooti Manista, Trainee Maintenance.
And this...
This is home.
Brace yourselves.
The sight of it sends some people mad.
That's a black hole.
But that's impossible.
I did warn you.
We're standing under a black hole.
-In orbit.
-We can't be.
IDA: You can see for yourself.
We're in orbit.
But we can't be.
This lump of rock is suspended
in perpetual geostationary orbit
around that black hole, without falling in.
Discuss.
And that's bad, yeah?
Bad doesn't cover it.
A black hole's a dead star.
It collapses in on itself, in and in and in,
until the matter's so dense and tight,
it starts to pull everything else in, too.
Nothing in the universe can escape it.
Light, gravity, time,
everything just gets
pulled inside and crushed.
So they can't be in orbit?
-We should be pulled right in.
-We should be dead.
And yet, here we are.
Beyond the laws of physics.
Welcome onboard.
But if there's no atmosphere out there,
what's that?
IDA: Stars breaking up. Gas clouds.
We have whole solar systems
being ripped apart above our heads,
before falling into that thing.
So, a bit worse than a storm, then.
-Just a bit.
-Just a bit, yeah.
VOICE: (WHISPERING) Toby.
Who's that?
Danny?
-Close door 1.
-The rocket link's fine.
That's the black hole,
officially designated K37 Gem 5.
In the scriptures of the Veltino,
this planet is called Krop Tor, the bitter pill.
And the black hole
is supposed to be a mighty demon
who was tricked into devouring the planet
only to spit it out because it was poison.
-The bitter pill. I like that.
-We are so far out.
Lost in the drifts of the universe.
How did you even get here?
We flew in. You see...
this planet's generating a gravity field.
We don't know how, we've no idea,
but it's kept in constant balance
against the black hole.
And the field extends out there as a funnel,
a distinct gravity funnel
reaching out into clear space.
That was our way in.
You flew down that thing?
Like a roller coaster.
By rights,
the ship should've been torn apart.
We lost the captain,
which is what put me in charge.
And you're doing a good job.
Yeah, well. Needs must.
But if that gravity funnel closes,
there's no way out.
Oh, we have fun speculating about that.
Oh, yeah. That's the word, "fun".
But that field would take
phenomenal amounts of power, I mean...
Not just big, but off the scale. Can I...?
Sure, help yourself.
Your refreshment.
Oh, yeah, thanks. Thank you.
I'm sorry, what was your name?
We have no titles. We are as one.
Erm, what are they called?
Oh, come on. Where have you been living?
Everyone's got one.
Well, not me. So, what are they?
-They're the Ood.
-The Ood?
The Ood.
Well, that's Ood.
Very Ood. But handy.
They work the mine shaft,
all the drilling and stuff.
Supervision and maintenance.
They're born for it. Basic slave race.
You've got slaves?
Don't start. She's like one of that lot,
Friends of the Ood.
Well, maybe I am, yeah.
Since when do humans need slaves?
But the Ood offer themselves.
If you don't give them orders,
they just pine away and die.
Seriously? You like being ordered about?
It is all we crave.
-Why is that, then?
-We have nothing else in life.
Yeah, well, I used to think like that.
-Long time ago.
-DOCTOR: There we go. Do you see?
To generate that gravity field
and the funnel,
you'd need a power source
with an inverted self-extrapolating reflex
of six to the power of six every six seconds.
-That's all the sixes.
-And it's impossible.
It took us two years to work that out.
-I'm very good.
-But that's why we're here.
This power source is ten miles below,
through solid rock.
Point 0.
We're drilling down to try and find it.
It's giving off readings
of over 90 Statts on the Blazen Scale.
It could revolutionise modern science.
We could use it to fuel the empire.
Or start a war.
It's buried beneath us.
In the darkness, waiting.
What's your job? Chief dramatist?
Well, whatever it is down there,
it's not a natural phenomenon.
This planet once supported life,
aeons ago, before the human race
had even learnt to walk.
I saw that lettering written on the wall,
did you do that?
I copied it from fragments
we found unearthed by the drilling,
but I can't translate it.
No, neither can I.
And that's saying something.
And there was some form of civilisation.
They buried something.
Now, it's reaching out.
Calling us in.
And you came.
How could we not?
So, when it comes right down to it,
why did you come here?
Why did you do that? Why? I'll tell you why.
Because it was there. Brilliant!
-Excuse me. Zack, wasn't it?
-That's me.
Just stand there 'cause I'm gonna hug you,
is that all right?
Suppose so.
Here we go. Coming in.
Human beings. You are amazing.
-DOCTOR: Thank you.
-Not at all.
But apart from that,
you're completely mad.
You should pack your bags,
get back on that ship and fly for your lives.
You can talk. How the hell did you get here?
Oh, I've got this... This ship...
It's hard to explain, it just sort of appears.
We can show you,
we parked down the corridor from...
-What's it called? Habitation Area 37
-3.
Do you mean Storage 67
It was a bit of a cupboard, yeah.
Storage 67 But you said...
You said...
You said Storage 5 to 8.
What is it? What's wrong?
Open door 189.
Close door 18.
-Doors, come on!
-Open door 17.
Open door 15.
-Open door 16.
-It can't be, it can't be!
What's wrong? What is it?
Doctor, the Tardis is in there.
What's happened?
The Tardis is gone.
Door 16 out of commission.
The earthquake. This section collapsed.
But it's got to be out there somewhere.
Look down.
The ground gave way. My Tardis must have
fallen down into the heart of the planet.
You've got robot drills
heading the same way.
We can't divert the drilling.
But I need my ship!
It's all I've got. Literally, the only thing.
Doctor, we've only got the resources
to dig one central shaft
down to the power source and that's it.
No diversions, no distractions,
no exceptions.
Your machine is lost.
Alll can do is offer you a lift,
if we ever get to leave this place.
And that is the end of it.
I'll put you on the duty roster.
We need someone in the laundry.
Open door 1.
Close door 1.
-I've trapped you here.
-No, don't worry about me.
(RUMBLING)
Okay, we're on a planet
that shouldn't exist,
underneath a black hole
and no way out.
Yeah, I've changed my mind.
Start worrying about me.
COMPUTER: Entering night shift.
Your chosen track for transition
ls Ravel's Bolero.
(BOLERO PLAYING ON PA)
All finished. Heading back inside.
Server Gamma 10.
Server Gamma 11.
Server Gamma 12.
(PA CUTS OUT ABRUPTLY)
VOICE: (WHISPERING) Toby.
-I can see you.
-Danny, is that you?
It's not funny, all right?
Dan?
I'm trying to work, Daniel.
(STUTTERING) If that's you, Dan,
can you just stop it?
(BUZZING)
ZACK: (ON PA) Danny,
check the temperature in Ood Habitation.
It seems to be rising.
Help yourself, just don't have the green.
Or the blue.
Um, a bit of that, thanks.
Would you like sauce with that?
I'll have a go, yeah.
I did that job once. I was a dinner lady.
Not that I'm calling you a lady.
Although, I don't know, you might be.
Do you actually get paid, though?
Do they give you money?
The Beast and his armies shall rise
from the Pit to make war against God.
I'm sorry?
Apologies.
I said I hope you enjoy your meal.
Yeah.
COMPUTER: Drill head now at point 16.
Drill head speed increasing.
Keep pressure at 60.
(GROWLING)
Close door 3.
(MOCKING) Close door 3.
He is awake.
What did you say?
Close door 3.
VOICE: (WHISPERING) Toby.
Don't turn around.
Dan?
-That's not Dan.
-Don't look at me.
(STUTTERING) Who are you?
I have so many names.
If I could...
If you look at me, you will die.
But who are you?
I'm behind you, Toby.
I'm right behind you.
Don't look. Don't look at me.
One look and you will die.
I'm reaching out, Toby.
I'm so close.
Don't turn around.
Oh, I can touch you.
No.
Zack, we got a problem?
ZACK: No more than usual.
Got the Scarlet System burning up.
Might be worth a look.
You might want to see this.
Moment in history.
There, on the edge.
That red cloud.
That used to be the Scarlet System.
Home to the Pallushi.
A mighty civilisation
spanning a billion years
disappearing forever.
Their planets and suns consumed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have witnessed its passing.
No, could you leave it open?
Just for a bit. I won't go mad, I promise.
How would you know?
Scooti, check the lockdown.
Jefferson, sign off the airlock seals for me.
Open door 18.
I've seen films and things, yeah?
They say black holes are like
gateways to another universe.
Close door 18.
Not that one. It just eats.
A long way from home.
Go that way,
turn right, keep going for, erm...
about 500 years and you'll reach the Earth.
No signal.
That's first time we've gone out of range.
Mind you, even if I could...
What would I tell her?
Can you build another Tardis?
They were grown, not built.
And with my home planet gone,
we're kind of stuck.
Well, it could be worse.
This lot said they'd give us a lift.
And then what?
I don't know.
Find a planet. Get a job.
You live your life
same as the rest of the universe.
I'd have to settle down.
Get a house or something.
A proper house with...
doors and things. Carpets.
Me, living in a house!
Now, that... That... That is terrifying.
You'd have to get a mortgage.
-No.
-Oh, yes.
I'm dying. That's it, I am dying.
It is all over.
What about me? I'd have to get one, too.
I don't know, could be the same one.
We could both...
I don't know, share.
Or not. Whatever.
I don't know. All sorts of...
-Anyway...
-We'll see.
I promised Jackie
I would always take you back home.
Everyone leaves home in the end.
Not to end up stuck here.
Yeah, but stuck with you, that's not so bad.
-Yeah?
-Yes.
(MOBILE RINGING)
VOICE: He is awake.
-DOCTOR: Evening.
-Only us.
The mysterious couple.
How are you, then? Settling in?
Yeah, sorry, straight to business.
The Ood, how do they communicate?
I mean, with each other?
Oh, just empaths.
There's a low-level telepathic field
connecting them.
Not that that does them much good.
They're basically a herd race, like cattle.
This telepathic field,
can it pick up messages?
'Cause I was having dinner
and one of the Oods said something...
Well, odd.
Hmm. An odd Ood.
And then I got something else on my...
communicator thing.
Well, be fair.
We've got whole star systems
burning up around us,
there's all sorts of stray transmissions.
Probably nothing.
Look, if there was something wrong,
it would show.
We monitor the telepathic field.
It's the only way to look after them.
They're so stupid.
They don't even tell us when they're ill.
-Monitor the field, that's this thing.
-Yeah.
But like I said, it's low-level telepathy.
They only register Basic 5.
Well, that's not Basic 5. 10.
20.
-They've gone up to Basic 30.
-But they can't.
Doctor, the Ood.
What does Basic 30 mean?
Well, it means that they're shouting,
screaming inside their heads.
Or something is shouting at them.
But where is it coming from?
What is it saying?
What did it say to you?
Something about the Beast and the Pit.
What about your communicator?
What did that say?
He is awake.
THE OOD: And you will worship him.
-What the hell?
-He is awake.
THE OOD: And you will worship him.
Worship who?
Who's talking to you? Who is it?
Toby, I've got your expenditure.
Open door 41.
Close door 41.
Close door 40.
Computer, did you open and close door 417
Confirmed.
But that's the airlock.
Why would you open the airlock?
It's the night shift,
we're not allowed outside.
-Has someone gone out?
-Confirmed.
-But who was it?
-Cannot confirm.
Okay. Right, hold on, I know.
Tell me whose spacesuit
has been logged out.
-No spacesuit has been logged out.
-But...
You're not making any sense.
You can't go outside without...
Zack, I think we've got a breakdown
on door 41.
It's saying somebody's gone outside
onto the planet's surface.
(STATIC)
Zack?
-Computer, trace fault.
-There is no fault.
-Tell me who went through that door?
-He is awake.
-What?
-He ls awake.
-What's that supposed to mean?
-He bathes in the black sun.
Toby.
There's no air, there's no...
No, stop it! You can't be!
Open door 40! Open door 40!
Open door 40!
(SCREAMING)
Emergency hull breach.
Which section?
Everyone, evacuate 11 to 13.
We've got a breach.
The Base is open. Repeat, the Base is open.
Open door 189.
Close door 18.
I can't contain the oxygen field.
We're gonna lose it.
Come on! Keep moving!
And you, too, sunshine!
-Everyone all right?
-Breach sealed.
-What happened? What was it?
-Hull breach.
We were open to the elements.
Another couple of minutes
and we'd have been inspecting
that black hole at close quarters.
That wasn't a quake. What caused it?
We've lost sections 11 to 13.
Everyone all right?
We've got everyone here except Scooti.
Scooti, report.
Scooti Manista, this is an order, report.
ZACK: She"s all right.
I've picked up her bio chip.
She's in Habitation 3.
Better go and check
if she's not responding.
She might be unconscious.
ZACK: But how about that eh? We survived.
Habitation 3. Come on.
I don't often say this,
but I think we could all do with a drink.
Come on.
What happened?
(STUTTERING) I don't know.
I was working and then I can't remember.
All that noise. The room was falling apart.
There was no air.
Come on, up you get.
Come and have some Protein One.
-You've gone native.
-0i, don't knock it, it's nice.
Protein One with just a dash of Three.
There's no sign of her,
but the bio chip says she's in this area.
IDA: Scooti, please respond.
If you can hear this, please respond.
-Habitation 6...
-Nowhere here.
Zack, we've got a problem.
Scooti's still missing.
ZACK: But it says Habitation 3.
Well, that's where I am
and I'm telling you, she's not here.
I've found her.
Oh, my God.
Sorry. I'm so sorry.
Captain...
report Officer Scootori Manista, PKD...
deceased.
43K 2.1.
She was 20.
20 years old.
For how should man die better
Than facing fearful odds
For the ashes of his father
And the temples of his gods?
(RUMBLING STOPS)
It's stopped.
What was that?
-What was it?
-The drill.
We've stopped drilling. We've made it.
Point 0.
ZACK: All non-essential Oods
to be confined.
Capsule established.
All systems functioning.
The mine shaft is go.
Bring systems online now.
Reporting as a volunteer
for the expeditionary force.
Doctor, this is breaking
every single protocol.
-We don't even know who you are.
-Yeah, but you trust me, don't you?
And you can't let Ida
go down there on her own.
Go on, look me in the eye.
Yes, you do. I can see it. Trust.
I should be going down.
The captain doesn't lead the mission.
He stays here, in charge.
Not much good here, am I?
Positions!
We're going down in two!
Everyone, positions!
Mr Jefferson, I want maximum systems...
Oxygen, nitro balance, gravity.
It's ages since I wore one of these.
I want that spacesuit back in one piece.
You got that?
Yes, sir.
It's funny 'cause people back home
think that space travel is gonna be all...
whizzing about and teleports, anti-gravity.
But it's not, is it? It's tough.
I'll see you later.
Not if I see you first.
You will remain here.
No command can override this.
Have you got that?
My instructions only.
Capsule active.
Counting down, in ten, nine,
eight, seven, six, five,
four, three, two,
one, release.
You've gone beyond the oxygen field.
You're on your own.
Don't forget to breathe. Breathing is good.
-Rose, stay off the comm.
-No chance.
(ALARM BLARING)
Doctor? Doctor, are you all right?
Ida, report to me.
Doctor?
DOCTOR: It's all right. We've made it.
Heading out of the capsule now.
ROSE: What's it like down there?
It's hard to tell.
Some sort of cave. Cavern. It's massive.
Well, this should help. Gravity globe.
That's...
Oh, my God. That's beautiful.
Rose...
you can tell Toby...
we've found his civilisation.
Oi, Toby, sounds like
you've got plenty of work.
Good, good.
Good.
Concentrate now, people.
Keep on the mission.
Ida, what about the power source?
We're close.
Energy signature indicates north-northwest.
Are you getting pictures up there?
ZACK: There's too much interference.
We're in your hands.
Well, we've come this far.
There's no turning back.
DOCTOR: Oh, did you have to?
No turning back? That's almost as bad as,
"Nothing can possibly go wrong"
or "This is gonna be the best Christmas
Walford's ever had."”
Have you finished?
Yeah. Finished.
Captain, sir, there's something happening
with the Ood.
What are they doing?
They're staring at me.
I've told them to stop, but they won't.
Danny, you're a big boy,
I think you can take being stared at.
But the telepathic field, sir,
it's at Basic 100.
I've checked. There isn't any fault.
-It's definitely 100.
-ZACK: But that's impossible.
-What's Basic 100 mean?
-They should be dead.
Basic 100 is brain death.
But they're safe?
They're not actually moving?
No, sir.
Keep watching them. And you, Jefferson,
keep a guard on the Ood.
Officer at arms.
You can't fire a gun in here.
What if you hit a wall?
Firing Stock 15,
only impacts upon organics.
-Keep watch. Guard them.
-Yes, sir.
-DOCTOR: Is everything all right up there?
-Yeah, yeah.
-It's fine.
-Great.
DOCTOR: We've found something.
It looks like metal, like some sort of seal.
I've got a nasty feeling
the word might be "trap door”.
Not a good word, trap door.
Never met a trap door I liked.
IDA: The edge is covered
with those symbols.
-ZACK: Do you think it opens?
-That's what trap doors tend to do.
Trap door doesn't do it justice.
It's massive, Zack.
-About 30 feet in diameter.
-ZACK: Any way of opening it?
Don't know.
I can't see any sort of mechanism.
DOCTOR: I suppose that's the writing.
It would tell us what to do.
The letters that defy translation.
Toby, did you get anywhere
with decoding it?
Toby, they need to know. That lettering,
does it make any sort of sense?
I know what it says.
Then tell them.
-When did you work that out?
-It doesn't matter, just tell them!
(DISTORTED VOICE)
These are the words of the Beast.
And he has woken.
He is the heart that beats in the darkness.
He is the blood that will never cease.
And now he will rise.
Officer, you will stand down. Stand down!
What is it? What's he done?
What's happening? Rose, what's going on?
Jefferson, report.
Report!
Officer, you have compromised security.
You will stand down
and be confined. Immediately!
Mr Jefferson, tell me, sir...
did your wife ever forgive you?
I don't know what you mean.
Let me tell you a secret.
She never did.
Officer, you will stand down
and be confined.
Or what?
Or under the strictures of Condition Red,
I am authorised to shoot you.
But how many can you kill?
THE OOD: We are the legion of the Beast.
Rose, what is it? Rose?
-I'm going back up.
-ZACK: Report! Report!
Jefferson, report!
Someone report!
The legion shall be many
and the legion shall be few.
It's the Ood.
Sir, we have contamination of the livestock.
Doctor, I don't know what it is.
It's like they're possessed.
They won't listen to us.
THE OOD: He has woven himself
in the fabric of your life
since the dawn of time.
Some may call him Abbadon.
Some may call him Krop Tor.
Some may call him Satan or Lucifer.
Captain, it's the Ood. They're out of control.
...the King of Despair, the Deathless Prince.
The Bringer of Night.
And these are the words
that shall set him free.
Back up to the door!
-I am become manifest.
-Move quickly!
-I shall walk in the light.
-To the door!
And my legions will swarm across worlds.
Doctor, it's opening!
We're moving!
The whole thing's moving,
the planet's moving.
I am the sin and the temptation
and the desire.
I am the pain and the loss
and the death of hope.
JEFFERSON: Get that door open!
The gravity field, it's going!
We're losing orbit!
We're gonna fall into the black hole!
I have been imprisoned for eternity.
But no more.
COMPUTER: Door sealed. Door sealed.
BEAST: The Pit is open
and I am free!
(BEAST LAUGHING)
DANNY: It's the Ood. They've gone mad.
Doctor, can you hear me?
Doctor, Ida, are you there?
ZACK: Danny, turn right.
That thing is playing on very basic fears.
-The cable's snapped.
-Get out!
You will die and I will live.