MAN: Close your eyes
and tell me what you see.
The library.
Open your eyes again.
-Where are you now?
-My living room, Dr Moon.
-When you close your eyes?
-I go to the library.
Go to the library now.
-DR MOON: Are you back there?
-Yes.
The same part?
GIRL: No, it's always different.
The library goes on forever.
-How do you move around?
-By wishing.
(DOOR RATTLING)
-What's wrong?
-Something's here.
Someone's got in.
No one's supposed to get in.
She's never mentioned anyone else.
She's always been alone.
Someone's in my library.
No, no, please! That's not allowed!
It's not allowed!
Listen to me.
The library is in your mind.
I know it's in my mind.
But something's got inside.
Oh, hello!
Sorry to burst in on you like this.
Okay if we stop here for a bit?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Books!
People never really stop loving books.
51st century.
By now you've got holovids,
direct-to-brain downloads, fiction-mist.
But you need the smell.
The smell of books, Donna. Deep breath.
The library.
So big it doesn't need a name,
just a great, big "the".
-It's like a city.
-It's a world, literally, a world.
The whole core of the planet
is the index computer,
biggest hard drive ever.
And up here, every book ever written.
Whole continents of
Jeffrey Archer, Bridget Jones,
Monty Python's Big Red Book.
Brand-new editions, especially printed.
We're near the equator, so...
This must be biographies!
I love biographies.
Yeah, very you.
Always a death at the end.
You need a good death.
Without death there'd only be comedies.
Dying gives us size.
Whay! Spoilers.
-What?
-These books are from your future.
You don't wanna read ahead,
spoil all the surprises.
It's like peeking at the end.
Isn't travelling with you
one big spoiler?
I try to keep you away
from major plot developments.
Which, to be honest,
I seem to be very bad at
'cause, you know what, this is
the biggest library in the universe.
So where is everyone?
-It's silent.
-The library?
The planet.
The whole planet.
Maybe it's a Sunday.
No, I never land on Sundays.
Sundays are boring.
Oh, maybe everyone's really,
really quiet.
Yeah, maybe.
But they'd still show up on the system.
-Doctor, why are we here? Really, why?
-Oh, you know, just passing.
No, seriously.
It was all, "Let's hit the beach,"
then suddenly we're in a library. Why?
-Now that's interesting.
-What?
Scanning for life forms. If I do a scan
looking for your basic humanoids,
you know, your book-readers,
few limbs and a face,
apart from us, I get nothing.
Zippo, nada. See, nobody home.
But if I widen the parameters
to any kind of life...
A million million. Gives up after that.
A million million.
DONNA: But there's nothing here.
There's no one.
And not a sound.
A million million life forms
and silence in the library.
But there's no one here.
There's just books.
I mean, it's not the books, is it?
I mean, it can't be the books, can it?
I mean, books can't be alive.
ELECTRONIC VOICE: Welcome!
-That came from here?
-Yeah.
I am Courtesy Node 710/Aqua.
Please enjoy the library
and respect the personal access codes
of all your fellow readers,
regardless of species or hygiene taboo.
-That face, it looks real.
-Yeah, don't worry about it.
A statue with a real face, though?
-It's a hologram or something, innit?
-No, but really, it's fine.
Additional. There follows
a brief message from the head librarian
for your urgent attention.
It has been edited for tone and content
by a Felman Lux
Automated Decency Filter.
Message follows.
Run. For God's sake, run.
Nowhere is safe.
The library has sealed itself.
We can't...Oh, they're here.
Arg. Slarg. Snick.
Message ends.
Please switch off your mobile comm-units
for the comfort of other readers.
So that's why we're here.
Any other messages, same date stamp?
One additional message.
This message carries
a Felman Lux Coherency Warning of...
Yeah, yeah. Fine, fine, fine!
Just play it.
Message follows.
Count the shadows.
For God's sake remember,
if you want to live, count the shadows.
Message ends.
-Donna.
-Yeah.
Stay out of the shadows.
Why, what's in the shadows?
So, we weren't just
in the neighbourhood.
Yeah, I kind of, sort of, lied a bit.
I got a message on the psychic paper.
What do you think? Cry for help?
Cry for help with a kiss?
We've all done that.
-Who's it from?
-No idea.
-So why did we come here? Why did you...
-Donna.
(BEEPING)
-What' s happening?
-Run! |
Come on!
-What, is it locked?
-Jammed! The wood's warped.
Sonic it! Use the thingy!
I can't, it's wood.
-What, it doesn't do wood?
-Hang on, hang on.
I can vibrate the molecules, fry
the bindings, I can shatter line the...
Oh, get out of the way!
Oh, hello!
Sorry to burst in on you like this.
Okay if we stop here for a bit?
What is it?
A security camera.
Switched itself off.
They were in my library.
How can they be in my library?
Who were they?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-What's that? What's that noise?
-What noise?
-Nice door skills, Donna.
-Yeah, well, you know, boyfriends.
Sometimes you need
the element of surprise.
What was that? What was after us?
I mean,
did we just run away from a power cut?
Possibly.
Are we safe here?
Of course we're safe.
There's a little shop.
Gotcha!
(SOBBING) No, stop it! No! No!
Ooh, I'm sorry. I really am.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
It's alive.
You said it was a security camera.
It is. It's an alive one.
DR MOON: Can you hear me?
Are you all right?
-Others are coming.
-Who's coming? Who are the others?
The library is breached.
Others are coming.
What others?
DONNA: "Others"? What's it mean, others?
Excuse me. What does it mean, others?
That's barely more than a speak
your weight machine. It can't help you.
So why's it got a face?
This flesh aspect was donated
by Mark Chambers
on the occasion of his death.
It's a real face.
It has been actualised
individually for you
from the many facial aspects
saved to our extensive flesh banks.
Please enjoy.
It chose me a dead face
it thought I'd like?
That statue's got
a real dead person's face on it!
It's the 51st century. That's basically
like donating a park bench.
It's donating a face!
-No! Wait! No!
-Hands!
Shadow, look.
What about it?
DOCTOR: Count the shadows.
One, there. I've counted it, one shadow.
Yeah.
But what's casting it?
Oh! I'm thick! Look at me!
I'm old and thick!
Head's too full of stuff!
I need a bigger head!
DONNA: Power must be going.
This place runs on fission cells.
They'll out-burn the sun.
-Then why is it dark?
-It's not dark.
That shadow, it's gone.
-We need to get back to the Tardis.
-Why?
Because that shadow hasn't gone,
it's moved.
Reminder. The library has been breached.
Others are coming.
-Hello, sweetie.
-Get out.
Doctor...
All of you, turn around,
get back in your rocket and fly away.
Tell your grandchildren
you came to the library and lived.
They won't believe you.
Pop your helmets, everyone,
we got breathers.
How do you know they're not androids?
'Cause I've dated androids.
They're rubbish.
Who is this?
You said we were the only expedition.
I paid for exclusives.
I lied. I'm always lying.
Bound to be others.
Miss Evangelista,
I want to see the contracts.
You came through the north door?
How was that? Much damage?
Please just leave.
I'm asking you seriously and properly.
Just...Hang on. Did you say expedition?
My expedition. I funded it.
Oh, you're not, are you?
Tell me you're not archaeologists.
Got a problem with archaeologists?
I'm a time traveller.
I point and laugh at archaeologists.
Ah. Professor River Song.
-Archaeologist.
-River Song. Lovely name.
As you're leaving,
and you're leaving now,
you need to set up a quarantine beacon,
code-wall the planet.
The whole planet!
Nobody comes here, not ever again!
Not one living thing,
not here, not ever!
-Stop right there! What's your name?
-Anita.
Anita, stay out of the shadows.
Not a foot, not a finger in the shadows
till you're safely back in your ship.
Goes for all of you, stay in the light!
Find a nice bright spot and just stand.
If you understand me,
look very, very scared.
No, a bit more scared than that.
-Okay, do for now. You, who are you?
-Dave.
-Okay, Dave...
-Oh, well, Other Dave.
Because that's Proper Dave, the pilot.
He was the first Dave. So when...
Other Dave, the way you came,
does it look the same as before?
-Yeah. Oh! It's a bit darker.
-How much darker?
Like, I could see where we came through
just a moment ago. I can't now.
Seal up this door.
We'll find another way out.
-Would you...
-We're not looking for a way out.
Miss Evangelista.
I'm Mr Lux's personal everything.
You need to sign these contracts
agreeing that your individual
experience inside the library
are the intellectual property
of the Felman Lux Corporation.
-Right. Give it here.
-Yeah, lovely. Thanks.
My family built this library.
I have rights.
You have a mouth that won't stop.
You think there's danger here?
Something came to this library
and killed everything in it.
Killed a whole world. Danger? Could be.
That was 100 years ago.
The library's been silent for 100 years.
Whatever came here is long dead.
Bet your life?
Always.
-LUX: What are you doing?
-He said seal the door.
-Torch.
-You're taking orders from him?
Spooky, isn't it?
Almost every species in the universe
has an irrational fear of the dark.
But they're wrong,
'cause it's not irrational.
It's Vashta Nerada.
DONNA: What's Vashta Nerada?
It's what's in the dark.
It's what's always in the dark.
Lights! That's what we need! Lights!
You got lights?
-What for?
-Form a circle,
safe area, big as you can.
Lights pointing out.
-Why?
-Do as he says.
-You're not listening to this man?
-Apparently I am.
Anita, un-pack the lights.
Other Dave, make sure the door's secure
then help Anita.
Mr Lux, put your helmet back on
and block the visor.
Proper Dave, find an active terminal,
access the library database.
See what you can find out about
what happened here 100 years ago.
Pretty boy, you're with me.
Step into my office.
Professor Song,
why am I the only one wearing my helmet?
I don't fancy you.
Probably I can help you.
Pretty boy, with me I said.
-Oh, I , I'm pretty boy?
-Yes! ”
Ooh, that came out a bit quick.
Pretty?
(EXCLAIMS)
Don't let your shadows cross.
Seriously, don't even let them touch.
-Any of them could be infected.
-How could a shadow be infected?
-Excuse me. Can I help?
-No, we're fine.
-I could just, you know, hold things.
-No, really, we're okay.
Okay.
Couldn't she help?
Trust me. I just spent four days
on a ship with that woman. She's a...
Couldn't tell the difference
between the escape pod and the bathroom.
We had to go back for her.
Twice.
(CHATTERING)
(DOCTOR CLEARS THROAT)
Thanks.
-For what?
-The usual, for coming when I call.
Oh, that was you?
You're doing a very good job
acting like you don't know me.
-I'm assuming there's a reason.
-A fairly good one, actually.
Okay, shall we do diaries, then?
Where are we this time?
Ah, going by your face,
I'd say it's early days for you.
Yeah, so, crash of the Byzantium,
have we done that yet?
Obviously ringing no bells.
All right, Oh...Picnic at Asgard.
Have we done Asgard yet?
Obviously not.
Blimey. Very early days, then.
Oh! Life of a time traveller,
never knew it could be such hard work.
Um...
Look at you.
-You're young.
-I'm really not, you know.
Oh, but you are.
Your eyes.
You're younger than I've ever seen you.
You've seen me before, then?
Doctor...
please tell me you know who I am.
Who are you?
(ALARM BUZZING)
PROPER DAVE: Sorry, that was me.
Trying to get through
into the security protocols,
I seem to have set something off.
What is that? Is that an alarm?
-Doctor...Doctor that sounds like...
-Yeah, it is. It's a phone.
(RINGING)
-Dad.
-In a minute.
I'm trying to call up the data core
but it's not responding,
just that noise.
-But it's a phone.
-Let me try something.
Dad, the phone.
Aren't you going to answer it?
It's not ringing, sweetie.
Okay, it don't like that.
Let's try something else.
DOCTOR ON TV: Okay, here it comes.
-Hello.
Are you in my television?
Well no, I'm...I'm sort of in space.
Um, I was trying to
call up the data core
of a Triple-Grid Security Processor.
Would you like to speak to my dad?
Your dad or your mum,
that would be lovely.
I know you. You were in my library.
Your library?
The library's never been
on television before.
What have you done?
Ah, well, um, I just...
What happened? Who was that?
Keep working on those lights.
I need those lights.
You heard him, people.
Let there be light.
Sorry, you're not allowed
to see inside the book.
-It's against the rules.
-What rules?
Your rules.
(CHATTERING ON TELEVISION)
What's that?
-I didn't do that. Did you do that?
-Not me.
What's CAL?
You all right?
-What's that? What's happening?
-I don't know.
Oh, thanks for, you know,
offering to help with the lights.
They don't want me.
They think I'm stupid 'cause I'm pretty.
Of course they don't.
Nobody thinks that.
No, they're right, though.
I'm a moron really.
My dad said I had the IQ of plankton
and I was pleased.
(LAUGHING) See, that's funny.
No, I really was pleased.
-Is that funny?
-No. No.
What's causing that?
Is it the little girl?
Who is the little girl?
What's she gotta do with this place?
ON TV: No way. No swapsies.
This eeny-weeny bit of metal is...
How does the data core work?
What's the principle? What's CAL?
Ask Mr Lux.
CAL, what is it?
Sorry, you didn't sign
your personal experience contracts.
Mr Lux, right now
you're in more danger than
you've ever been in your whole life.
-And you're protecting a patent?
-I'm protecting my family's pride.
Well, funny thing, Mr Lux.
I don't wanna see
everyone in this room dead
because some idiot thinks his pride
is more important.
Then why don't you sign his contract?
I didn't either.
I'm getting worse than you.
Okay. Okay, let's start at
the beginning. What happened here?
On the actual day, 100 years ago,
what physically happened?
MAN ON TV: See? How about this huge...
SONG: There was a message
from the library, just one.
"The lights are going out.”
Then the computer sealed the planet,
and there was nothing for 100 years.
It's taken three generations
of my family
just to decode the seals
and get back in.
-Um, excuse me?
-LUX: Not just now.
There was one other thing
in the last message.
-That's confidential.
-I trust this man.
With my life, with everything.
-You've only just met him.
-No. He's only just met me.
-Um, this might be important, actually.
-In a moment.
This is a data extract
that came with the message.
"4,022 saved. No survivors."
4,022, that's the exact number of people
who were in the library
when the planet was sealed.
How can 4,022 people have been saved
if there were no survivors?
That's what we're here to find out.
And so far,
what we haven't found are any bodies.
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
(EVANGELISTA SCREAMS)
Everybody, careful. Stay in the light.
You keep saying that,
I don't see the point.
-Who screamed?
-Miss Evangelista.
Where is she?
Miss Evangelista,
please state your current...
(ECHOING)
Please state your current...
...position.
It's her.
That's Miss Evangelista.
We heard her scream a few seconds ago.
What could do that to a person
in a few seconds?
-Took a lot less than a few seconds.
-What did?
-EVANGELISTA: Hello?
-Uh, I'm sorry, everyone.
This isn't going to be pleasant.
-She's ghosting.
-She's what?
Hello, excuse me?
I'm sorry, hello, excuse me?
That's...That's her.
That's Miss Evangelista.
I don't wanna sound horrible,
but couldn't we just, you know...
This is her last moment, no, we can't.
A little respect, thank you.
Sorry, where am I? Excuse me?
-But that's Miss Evangelista.
-It's a data ghost.
She'll be gone in a moment.
(ECHOING) Miss Evangelista, you're fine.
Just relax.
We'll be with you presently.
What's a data ghost?
There's a neural relay
in the communicator,
lets you send thought-mails.
That's it there. Those green lights.
Sometimes it can hold an impression
of a living consciousness
for a short time after death.
Like an after image.
Her grandfather lasted a day.
Kept talking about his shoelaces.
She's in there.
I can't see. I can't... Where am I?
She's just brainwaves now.
Pattern won't hold for long.
She's conscious.
-She's thinking.
-I can't see. I can't...
-I don't know what I'm thinking.
-She's a footprint on the beach.
-And the tide's coming in.
-Where is that woman?
The nice woman, is she there?
What woman?
She means...
I think she means me.
Is she there? The nice woman?
Yes, she's here. Hang on.
Go ahead, she can hear you.
Hello, are you there?
Help her.
-She's dead.
-Yeah, help her.
Hello, is that the nice woman?
Yeah. Hello. Yeah, I'm...I'm here.
You okay?
What I said before, about being stupid,
don't tell the others,
they'll only laugh.
Of course I won't.
Course I won't tell them.
Don't tell the others,
they'll only laugh.
I won't tell them. I said I won't.
Don't tell the others,
they'll only laugh.
I'm not going to tell them.
Don't tell the others,
they'll only laugh.
She's looping now.
The pattern's degrading.
I can't think...
(SIGNAL FLUTTERING) I don't know...I...
. __7__.
Ice cream. Ice cream.
Ice cream. Ice cream. Ice cream...
-Does anybody mind if I...
-Ice cream...
Ice cream. Ice cream. Ice cream...
That was... That was horrible.
That was the most horrible thing
I've ever seen.
Well, it's just a freak of technology.
Whatever did this to her,
whatever killed her,
-I'd like a word with that.
-I'll introduce you.
-I'm gonna need a packed lunch.
-Hang on.
-What's in that book?
-Spoilers.
Who are you?
-Professor River Song. University of...
-To me.
-Who are you to me?
-Again.
Spoilers.
Chicken and a bit of salad,
knock yourself out.
Right, you lot.
Let's all meet the Vashta Nerada.
Darling, Dr Moon is going now,
but he'd like a word with you alone.
-Is that all right?
-Yes, of course, Dr Moon.
Thank you.
Now, listen.
This is important.
There's the real world,
and there's the world of nightmares.
That's right, isn't it?
You understand that?
Yes, I know, Dr Moon.
What I want you to remember is this,
and I know it's hard.
The real world is a lie,
and your nightmares are real.
The library is real.
There are people trapped in there.
People who need to be saved.
The shadows are moving again.
Those people are depending on you.
Only you can save them. Only you.
You travel with him, don't you?
The Doctor, you travel with him.
What of it?
-Proper Dave, could you move over a bit?
-Why?
Over there by the water cooler. Thanks.
DONNA: You know him, don't you?
SONG: Oh, God, do I know that man!
We go way back, that man and me.
-Just not this far back.
-I'm sorry, what?
He hasn't met me yet.
I sent him a message, but it went wrong.
It arrived too early.
This is the Doctor in the days
before he knew me.
And he looks at me...
He looks right through me
and it shouldn't kill me but it does.
What're you talking about?
Are you just talking rubbish?
Do you know him, or don't you?
-DOCTOR: Donna! Quiet, I'm working.
-Sorry.
-Donna, you're Donna? Donna Noble.
-Yeah. Why?
I do know the Doctor. But in the future.
His personal future.
So, why don't you know me?
Where am I in the future?
DOCTOR: Okay, got a live one.
That's not darkness down those tunnels.
This is not a shadow.
It's a swarm. A man-eating swarm.
The piranhas of the air,
the Vashta Nerada.
Literally, the shadows
that melt the flesh.
Most planets have them,
but usually in small clusters.
I've never seen an infestation
on this scale, or this aggressive.
What do you mean, most planets?
Not Earth?
Mmm. Earth, and a billion other worlds.
Where there's meat,
there's Vashta Nerada.
You can see them sometimes, if you look.
The dust in sunbeams.
If they were on Earth, we'd know.
Nah. Normally they live on road-kill.
But sometimes people go missing.
Not everyone comes back out of the dark.
-Every shadow?
-No, but any shadow.
So, what do we do?
Daleks, aim for the eye-stalk.
Sontarans, back of the neck.
Vashta Nerada...
run. Just run.
Run? Run where?
This is an index point, there must be
an exit teleport somewhere.
Don't look at me,
I haven't memorised the schematics.
Doctor, the little shop. They always
make you go through the little shop
on the way out
so they can sell you stuff.
You're right. Brilliant!
That's why I like the little shop.
-Okay, let's move it.
-Actually, Proper Dave...
Could you stay
where you are for a moment?
Why?
I'm sorry. I'm so, so sorry.
But you've got two shadows.
It's how they hunt. They latch onto
a food source and keep it fresh.
-What do I do?
-You stay absolutely still.
Like there's a wasp in the room.
Like there's a million wasps.
-We're not leaving you, Dave.
-Of course we're not leaving you.
Where's your helmet?
Don't point, just tell me.
On the floor, by my bag.
Don't cross his shadow!
Thanks. Now, the rest of you,
helmets back on and sealed up.
We'll need everything we've got.
DONNA: Doctor, we haven't got
any helmets.
-Yeah, but we're safe anyway.
-How are we safe?
We're not.
That was a clever lie to shut you up.
Professor, anything I can do
with the suit?
What good are the damn suits?
Miss Evangelista was wearing a suit,
there was nothing left.
We can increase the mesh density.
Dial it up 400%.
-Make it a tougher meal.
-DOCTOR: Okay.
-800%. Pass it on.
-Gotcha.
-What's that?
-It's a screwdriver.
-It's sonic.
-Yeah, I know. Snap.
With me, come on.
What are we doing? We're shopping?
Is it a good time to shop?
No talking, just moving. Try it.
Right, stand out in the middle.
It's a teleport. Stand in the middle.
Can't send the others,
Tardis won't recognise them.
-What're you doing?
-You don't have a suit, you're not safe.
You don't have a suit,
so you're in as much danger as I am.
-I'm not leaving...
-Donna, let me explain!
Ah, that's how you do it.
SONG: Doctor.
(SCREAMING)
Where did it go?
It's just gone, I looked around,
one shadow, see?
Does that mean we can leave?
I don't want to hang around here.
I don't know why we're still here.
We can leave him, can't we?
-I mean, no offence.
-Shut up, Mr Lux.
Did you feel anything like
an energy transfer? Anything at all?
No, no, but look. It's gone.
Stop there. Stop. Stop. Stop there.
Stop moving.
They're never just gone
and they never give up.
Mmm-mmm. This one's benign.
Hey, who turned out the lights?
-No one, they're fine.
-No, seriously, turn them back on.
They are on.
I can't see a ruddy thing.
-Dave, turn around.
-What's going on?
Why can't I see? Is the power gone?
-Are we safe here?
-Dave, I want you to stay still.
Absolutely still.
Dave, Dave, Dave, can you hear me?
Talk to me, Dave.
-I'm fine. I'm okay, I'm fine.
-I want you to stay still.
-Absolutely still.
-I'm fine.
I'm okay, I'm fine.
I can't... Why can't I? I...
I can't..Why can'tl? I...
-He's gone. He's ghosting.
-I can't...Why can't I? I...
Then why is he still standing?
Hey, who turned out the lights?
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
-Doctor, don't.
-Dave, can you hear me?
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
Who turned out the lights?
-Excuse me!
Back from it, get back, right back!
-Doesn't move that fast, does it?
-It's a swarm in a suit.
But it's learning.
-What do we do? Where do we go?
-See that wall behind you?
Duck.
Squareness gun!
Everybody out. Go, go, go. Move it.
Move, move.
Move it. Move, move.
-You said not every shadow.
-But any shadow.
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
-SONG: Run.
Sweetie, dinner's ready.
Donna Noble has been saved.
Sweetie?
(DISTANT BUZZING)
Trying to boost the power.
Light doesn't stop them,
but it slows them down.
So, what's the plan? We have a plan?
Your screwdriver.
-Looks exactly like mine.
-Yeah.
-You gave it to me.
-I don't give my screwdriver to anyone.
-I'm not anyone.
-Who are you?
-What's the plan?
- Iteleported Donna back to the Tardis.
If we don't get back there
in under five hours,
Emergency Programme One will activate.
Take her home, yeah.
We need to get a shift on.
She's not there.
I should've received a signal.
The console signals me
if there's a teleport breach.
Maybe the coordinates have slipped.
The equipment here's ancient.
Donna Noble. There's a Donna Noble
somewhere in this library,
do you have the software
to locate her position?
Donna Noble has left the library.
Donna Noble has been saved.
-Donna...
-Donna Noble has left the library.
Donna Noble has been saved.
How can it be Donna?
How's that possible?
Donna Noble has left the library.
Donna Noble has been saved.
-Oh, Donna...
-Donna Noble has...
Hey, who turned out the lights?
-Doctor.
-Donna Noble has been saved.
Hey, who turned out the lights?
Donna Noble has left the library.
-Doctor, we've got to go now!
-Donna Noble has been saved.
Hey, who turned out the lights?
Donna Noble has left the library.
-Donna Noble has been saved.
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
Donna Noble has left the library.
-Donna Noble has been saved.
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
Donna Noble has left the library.
-Donna Noble has been saved.
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
Donna Noble has left the library.
Doctor, what're we gonna do?
-Hey, who turned out the lights?
-Donna Noble has left the library.
Donna Noble has been saved.
I trust that man
to the end of the universe.
-And actually, we've been.
-Who are you?
And then you forgot.
You just killed someone I like,
that is not a safe place to stand.
This planet is gonna crack like an egg.
Daddy! No, Daddy!
-I hate you sometimes.
-I know.
Don't play games with me.
We need to stop this.
We've gotta save CAL.
What is it? What is CAL?
-Spoilers.
No, don't tell! You mustn't tell!