ROSE: Peter Alan Tyler, my dad.
The most wonderful man in the world.
Born 15th September, 1954.
Come here, Rose. Come here.
Who's that? It's your daddy.
You weren't old enough
to remember when he died.
1987, 7th November.
Do you remember
what I told you?
The day that Stuart Hoskins
and Sarah Clark got married.
He was always
having adventures.
He would have loved
to have seen you now.
That's what Mum always says.
So I was thinking,
could we go and see my dad
when he was still alive?
Where's this come
from all of a sudden?
All right, if we can't, if it goes
against the laws of time or something,
then never mind,
just leave it.
No, I can do anything.
I'm just more worried about you.
I want to see him.
Your wish is my command.
But be careful what you wish for.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME MUSIC)
I, Peter Alan Tyler,
take you,
Jacqueline Andrea Suzette Prentice.
I, Peter Alan Tyler,
take you, Jacqueline...
Susanne, Suzette...
Anita?
Just carry on.
It's good enough for Lady Di.
I thought he'd be taller.
To be my lawful wedded wife.
To love and behold till death us do part.
MUM: He died so close to home.
I wasn't there. Nobody was.
It was a hit-and-run driver.
Never found out who.
He was dead
when the ambulance got there.
I only wish there'd been
someone there for him.
ROSE: I want to be that someone.
So he doesn't die alone.
-November 7th?
-1987.
(WHOOSHING)
It's so weird.
The day my father died.
I thought it'd be all sort of grim and stormy.
It's just an ordinary day.
The past is another country.
1987 is just the Isle of Wight.
-You sure about this?
-Yeah.
This is it. Jordan Road.
He was late.
He'd been to get a wedding present,
a vase.
Mum always said,
"That stupid vase."
He got out of his car...
and crossed the road.
Oh, God, this is it.
Go to him. Quick.
It's too late now.
By the time the ambulance got there,
he was dead.
He can't die on his own.
Can I try again?
Right, that's the first you and me.
It's a very bad idea, two sets of us
being here at the same time.
Just be careful
they don't see us.
Wait till she runs off and he follows
then go to your dad.
Oh, God, this is it.
I can't do this.
You don't have to do anything
you don't want to.
But this is the last
time we can be here.
Rose, no!
I did it. I saved your life.
Blimey, did you see the speed of it?
Did you get his number?
I really did it.
Oh, my God, look at you, you're alive.
That car was gonna kill you.
Give me some credit, I did see it coming.
I wasn't gonna walk under it, was I?
I'm Rose.
That's a coincidence.
That's my daughter's name.
That's a great name.
Good choice. Well done.
Right. I better shift.
I've got a wedding to go to.
-Is that Sarah Clark's wedding?
-Yeah. Are you going?
Yeah.
Do you and your
boyfriend need a lift?
(SCREECHING)
Right, there we go,
sorry about the mess.
If you want a cup of tea,
kitchen's down there, milk's in the fridge.
It would be, wouldn't it?
Where else would you put the milk?
Mind you, there's always
the windowsill outside.
I always thought if someone invented
a windowsill with special compartments,
one for milk, one for yoghurt,
make a lot of money out of that.
Sell it to students and things.
I should write that down.
Anyway, never mind that.
Excuse me, I got to go and change.
All the stuff Mum kept.
His stuff.
She kept it all packed away
in boxes in the cupboard.
She used to show me
when she'd had a bit to drink.
Here it is, on display.
Where it should be.
Third prize at the bowling.
First two got to go to Didcot.
Health drinks.
Tonics Mum used to call them.
He made his money
selling this Vitex stuff.
He had all sorts of jobs,
he was so clever.
Solar power.
Mum said he was going to do this.
Now he can.
Okay, I'll tell him
you're not my boyfriend.
When we met I said,
"Travel with me in space.”
You said, "No."
Then I said, "Time machine."
It wasn't some big plan.
I just saw it happening,
and I thought, "I can stop it."
I did it again.
I picked another stupid ape.
I should have known. It's not about
showing you the universe. It never is.
It's about the universe
doing something for you.
So it's okay when you go to other times
and you save people's lives
but not when it's
me saving my dad?
I know what I'm doing,
you don't.
Two sets of us being there
made that a vulnerable point.
But he's alive.
My entire planet died,
my whole family.
Do you think it never occurred to me
to go back and save them?
But it's not like
I've changed history.
Not much. I mean,
he's never gonna be a world leader,
he's not gonna start World War III.
Rose, there's a man alive in the world
who wasn't alive before.
An ordinary man.
That's the most important thing in creation.
The whole world's different
because he's alive.
-Would you rather him dead?
-I'm not saying that...
No, I get it. For once, you're not
the most important man in my life.
Let's see how you get on without me.
Give me the key.
The Tardis key.
If I'm so insignificant, give it me back.
All right then, I will.
You've got what you wanted
so that's goodbye, then.
You don't scare me.
I know how sad you are.
You'll be back in a minute.
Or you'll hang around
outside the Tardis waiting for me.
And I'll make you
wait a long time.
Boyfriend trouble?
(SCREECHING)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Excuse me, do you mind?
What are you tidying up for?
Sorry, force of habit.
Don't worry about him.
Couples have rows all the time.
We're not a couple.
Why does everyone think we're a couple?
-I think he left me.
-What? A pretty girl like you?
-If I was going out with you...
-Stop right there.
I'm just saying...
I know what you're saying
and we're not going there.
At no point are we going
anywhere near there.
You aren't even aware
that there exists...
I don't want to think about there and,
believe me, neither do you.
There, for you, is like...
like the Bermuda Triangle.
-Blimey, you know how to flatter a bloke.
-Right. Are we off?
-That wouldn't be a mixed signal at all?
-Absolutely not.
I'll take you back to the loony bin
where you belong.
Except I'm sure
I've met you somewhere before.
(CHURCH ORGAN MUSIC)
-It's weird.
-What?
There's so many people missing.
Uncle Steven, Auntie Lynn,
all the Baxters.
Where are they?
You don't think
something's gone wrong?
Maybe it's a godsend,
gives you time to think.
You don't have to go through with it,
not these days.
-Live in sin for a bit.
-Dad.
In 10 years' time, you'll turn round and say,
"If only I could turn the clock back."
Is it me or did it just get cold?
(BIRD CAWING)
Rose.
I met this bloke at the horses
and he's cutting me in on copyright.
But I thought you were
a proper businessman.
I wish. I do a bit of this, bit of that.
I scrape by.
Right. I must've heard wrong.
So, really,
you're a bit of a Del Boy.
Shoot me down in flames.
You're not related to my wife
by any chance, are you?
Oh, my God.
She's gonna be at the wedding.
Jackie? Do you know her?
Sort of.
What's she told you about me, then?
She said she'd picked
the most fantastic man in the world.
Must be a different Jackie, then.
She'd never say that.
(RAP MUSIC)
This stuff goes
right over my head.
-That's not out yet.
-Good job and all.
-I'm just gonna check my messages.
-How do you mean? Messages?
-Is that a phone?
-Yeah.
MAN: Watson, come here.
I need you.
Watson, come here. I need you.
Half the guests haven't turned up.
You're better off not being here,
it's a disaster in the making.
No, in this case,
"knocked her up” is a phrase I'd use.
Watson, come here. I need you.
Hello? Who's this?
Watson, come here. I...
Dad, get inside.
We can't see the bride before the wedding.
-That's bad luck.
-Bad luck when you met her.
I tell you, this day is cursed.
Now that's what I call a meringue.
Stuart's dad said go round the block
"cause there's people missing.
How do you mean, missing?
There's no Dave, no Sunita, no Bee...
There's no one from The Lamb and Flag.
My train's detached again.
I knew I should have used Velcro.
I'm here, stop your bellyaching.
Take Rose a sec, will you?
Ain't she pretty?
She's a little madam,
that's what she is.
I need more hands.
Where's her useless article
of a dad got to?
Dad!
It's that car.
Same one as before.
It was right in front of us,
where's he gone?
You called me "Dad"?
What did you say that for?
Oh, wonderful! Here he is,
the accident waiting to happen.
You'd be late for your own funeral
and it nearly was.
-No damage done.
-And who's this?
What are you looking at
with your mouth open?
-Your hair.
-What?
I've never seen it like...
I mean...
it's lovely, your hair's lovely.
And that baby you're holding.
That would be your baby.
-Another one of yours, is she?
-She saved my life.
That's a new one.
What was it last time?
I didn't even know her.
She was a cloakroom attendant.
I was helping her
look for my ticket.
There were three duffle coats all the same.
Somehow the rack collapsed.
We were under all this stuff.
Were you playing around?
What's it got to do with you
what he gets up to?
-What does he get up to?
-You'd know.
Because I'm that stupid. I play around
and I bring her to meet the missus.
-You silly...
-But you are that stupid.
Can we keep this stuff for back home,
just for now?
What, with the rest of the rubbish?
You bring home cut-price detergents,
tonic water,
Betamax tapes and none of it works.
I'm drowning in your rubbish.
What did he tell you?
Did he say he's this big businessman?
'Cause he's not. He's a failure.
Born failure, that one.
Rose needs a proper father...
Jackie, I'm making a living.
It keeps us fed, doesn't it?
Stop it.
You're not like this.
You love each other.
Pete, you never used to
like them mental.
-Or I don't know, maybe you did.
-Jackie, wait, listen...
If you're not careful, there'll be a wedding
and a divorce on the same day.
(BABY CRYING)
Wait here.
Give us a couple of minutes with the missus.
Tell you what, straighten the car up.
Stick it round the corner.
Don't cause any more trouble.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Hey, Jack.
I'm not listening.
It's the duffle coats all over again.
Jackie, sometimes a duffle coat
is just a duffle coat.
Things will get better soon.
I promise.
I've had enough of
all your daft schemes.
I never know where
the next meal's coming from.
I'll get it right, love. One day soon,
I promise you I'll get it right.
Come on.
Monsters! Going to eat us!
What sort of monsters, sweetheart?
Is it aliens?
Rose!
Get in the church!
(SCREECHES)
Oh, my God. What are they?
Inside!
-Sarah!
-Stay in there!
(REAPER SCREECHING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
In.
(REAPERS SCREECHING)
They can't get in.
Old windows and doors. Okay.
The older something is,
the stronger it is.
What else?
Go and check the other doors.
Move!
What's happening?
What are they? What are they?
There's been an accident in time.
A wound in time.
They're like bacteria,
taking advantage.
What do you mean? Time?
What are you jabbering on about time?
I might've known you'd argue.
-Jackie, I'm sick of you complaining.
-How do you know my name?
I've never met you in my life.
You never will
unless I sort this out.
If you don't mind,
I've waited a long time to say this,
Jackie Tyler, do as I say.
Go and check the doors.
Yes, sir.
I should've done that ages ago.
-My dad was out there.
-You can mourn him later.
Now we've got to concentrate
on keeping ourselves alive.
-My dad had...
-There is nothing I can do for him.
No, but he had this phone thing.
I can't get it to work.
I keep getting this voice.
Watson, come here. I need you.
That's the very first phone call.
Alexander Graham Bell.
I don't think the telephone's
gonna be much use.
Someone must have
called the police.
The police can't help you now,
no one can.
Nothing in this universe
can harm those things.
Time's been damaged
and they've come to sterilise the wound.
By consuming everything inside.
Is this because...
Is this my fault?
No!
There's smoke coming up from the city.
But no sirens.
I don't think it's just us.
I think these things are all over the place.
Maybe the whole world.
Was that a car?
It's not important.
Don't worry about it.
This mate of yours.
What did he mean, this is your fault?
Don't know. Just everything.
I gave you my car keys.
You don't give your keys
to a complete stranger.
It's like I trusted you.
The moment I met you,
I just did.
A wound in time.
You called me Dad.
I can see it.
In my eyes.
Jackie's attitude.
You sound like her
when you shout.
You are.
You are. You're my Rose.
You're my Rose, grown up.
Dad! My dad. My daddy.
Excuse me.
-Mister...?
-Doctor.
-You seem to know what's going on.
-I give that impression, yeah.
-I just wanted to ask...
-Can you save us?
Who are you two, then?
-Stuart Hoskins.
-Sarah Clark.
And one extra? Boy or girl?
I don't know.
I don't want to know, really.
How did all this get started?
Outside the Beatbox Club,
2:00 in the morning.
Street corner, I'd lost my purse,
didn't have money for a taxi.
- I took her home.
-Then what?
Asked her for a date?
-Wrote his number on my hand.
-Never got rid of her since.
My dad said...
I don't know what this is all about
and I know we're not important...
Who said you're not important?
I've travelled to all sorts of places,
done things you couldn't even imagine.
But you two.
Street corner, 2:00 in the morning,
getting a taxi home.
I've never had a life like that.
Yes.
I'll try and save you.
I'm a dad.
I mean, I'm already a dad
but Rose grows up and she's you.
That's wonderful.
I mean, I suppose I thought
that you'd be a bit useless
what with my useless genes
and all but...
Well, I mean, how did you get here?
-Do you really want to know?
-Yeah.
A time machine.
-Time machine?
-Cross my heart.
Do you all have time machines
where you come from?
No, just the Doctor.
Did you know these
things were coming?
No.
God, I don't know,
my head's spinning.
What's the future like?
It's not so different.
What am I like?
Have I gone grey?
Have I gone bald?
Don't tell me I've gone bald.
So, if this mate of yours isn't your boyfriend,
and I have to say I'm glad
'cause being your dad and all,
I think he's a bit old for you.
-Have you got a bloke?
-No. I did have.
MUM: Mickey.
Do you know him?
I just didn't recognise him in a suit.
You have to let go of me, sweetheart.
I'm always saying that.
He just grabs hold of what's passing
and holds on for dear life.
God help his poor girlfriend
if he ever gets one.
-Me and Rose were just talking.
-Oh, yeah? Talking?
While the world comes to an end,
what do you do?
Cling to the youngest blonde.
Come on, Mick.
-You can't tell her.
-Why?
I mean,
I really don't want you to tell her.
-You don't want people to know?
-Where I come from,
Jackie doesn't know how
to work the timer on the video recorder.
I showed her that last week.
Point taken.
Rose, you're not going to bring about
the end of the world, are you?
Are you?
Jackie gave her to me to look after.
How times change.
I'd better be careful.
I think I just imprinted myself on Mickey
like a mother chicken.
No. Don't touch the baby.
You're both the same person,
that's a paradox.
We don't want a paradox happening,
not with these things outside.
Anything new, any disturbance in time,
makes them stronger.
A paradox might let them in.
I can't do anything right, can I?
Since you asked, no.
So, don't touch the baby.
-I'm not stupid.
-You could have fooled me.
All right...
I'm sorry.
I wasn't really gonna leave you
on your own.
I know.
Between you and me,
I haven't got a plan. No idea.
No way out.
You'll think of something.
The entire Earth's been sterilised.
This, and other places like it,
are all that's left of the human race.
We might hold out for a while,
but nothing can stop those creatures.
They'll get through in the end.
The walls aren't that old.
And there's nothing I can do to stop them.
There used to be laws stopping
this kind of thing from happening.
My people would have stopped this.
But they're all gone.
And now I'm going the same way.
If I'd realised...
Just...
tell me you're sorry.
I am.
I'm sorry.
Have you got something hot?
It's the Tardis key.
It's telling me
it's still connected to the Tardis.
The inside of my ship
was thrown out of the wound
but we can use
this to bring it back.
And once I've got my ship back,
then I can mend everything.
Now, I just need a bit of power.
Has anybody got a battery?
This one big enough?
Fantastic.
Good old Dad. There you go.
Just need to do
a bit of charging up.
And then we can
bring everyone back.
(REAPERS SCREECHING)
(POUNDING ON THE DOORS)
You, erm, you never said why
you came here in the first place.
If I had a time machine, I wouldn't have
thought 1987 was anything special.
Not round here, anyway.
-We just ended up here.
-Lucky for me, eh?
-If you hadn't been there to save me...
-That was just a coincidence.
That was just really good luck.
It's amazing.
So, in the future,
are me and her indoors still together?
Yeah.
-You still living with us?
-Yep.
Am I a good dad?
You...
You told me a bedtime story
every night when I was small.
You were always there,
you never missed one.
And, erm...
you took us for picnics
in the country every Saturday.
You never let us down.
You were there for us all the time.
Someone I could really rely on.
That's not me.
Right, no one touches that key,
have you got that? Don't touch it.
Anyone touches that key,
it'll be, well, zap!
Just leave it be and everything will be fine.
We'll get out. All of us.
Stuart, Sarah, you're gonna get married,
just like I said.
-When time gets sorted out...
-Everybody here forgets what happened.
And don't worry, the thing
that you changed will stay changed.
You mean I'll still be alive.
Though I'm meant to be dead.
That's why I haven't done anything
with my life.
Why it didn't mean anything.
-Doesn't work like that.
-Rubbish.
I was so useless
I couldn't even die properly.
Now it's my fault
all this has happened.
-This is my fault.
-No, love.
I'm your dad.
It's my job for it to be my fault.
Her dad?
How are you her dad?
How old were you? 127
-Oh, that's disgusting.
-Jacks, listen.
-This is Rose.
-Rose?
How sick is that?
Did you give my daughter
a second-hand name?
How many are there?
Do you call them all Rose?
Oh, for God's sake, look.
It's the same Rose.
Rose, no!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Everyone, behind me!
I'm the oldest thing in here.
Doctor!
It's cold.
The key's cold.
Oh, my God, he's dead.
This is all my fault.
Both of you, all of you.
The whole world.
This is it. There's nothing we can do.
It's the end.
The Doctor really cared about you.
He didn't want you to go through it again.
Not if there was another way.
Now there isn't.
What are you talking about?
The car that should
have killed me, love.
It's here.
The Doctor worked it out way back but he...
tried to protect me.
Still.
He's not in charge anymore.
I am.
-But you can't.
-Who am I, love?
My daddy.
Jackie, look at her.
She's ours.
Of course.
I'm meant to be dead, Jackie.
You're gonna get rid of me at last.
Don't say that.
For once in your life, trust me.
It's got to be done.
You've got to survive
'cause you've got to bring up our daughter.
I never read you those bedtime stories,
I never took you on those picnics.
I was never there for you.
You would've been.
But I can do this for you.
I can be a proper dad to you now.
But it's not fair.
I've had all these extra hours.
No one else in the world
has ever had that.
And on top of that,
I get to see you.
And you're beautiful.
How lucky am I, eh?
So, come on.
Do as your dad says.
You gonna be there for me, love?
Thanks for saving me.
(REAPERS SCREECHING)
Goodbye, love.
Go to him. Quick.
MUM: The driver was just a kid.
He stopped,
he waited for the police.
It wasn't his fault.
For some reason,
Pete just ran out.
People say there was this girl.
And she sat with Pete
while he was dying.
She held his hand.
Then she was gone.
Never found out who she was.
ROSE: Peter Alan Tyler, my dad.
The most wonderful man in the world.
Died 7th November, 1987.
And why are we chasing it?
It's mauve and dangerous, and about
30 seconds from the centre of London.
Rose!
Please let me in, Mummy.
You mustn't let him touch you.
-Are you a doctor?
-I have my moments.
They've all got the same injuries.
Right down to the scar
on the back of the hand.
Physical injuries as plague.
-Hello.
Shall we have
a drink on the balcony?
(ROSE EXCLAIMS)
-I like to think of myself as a criminal.
-I bet you do.
(ROSE SCREAMING)