A few months ago,
the Veritas was translated again.
Everyone who worked on the translation
and everyone who subsequently read it
is now dead.
Your tutor's a what?
An alien.
What do you mean, an alien?
A space one.
A space alien.
Will you read the Veritas?
So, you're blind,
and you don't want your enemies to know.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(LAUGHS) So your tutor ran
a computer simulation?
Well, more like he got trapped
inside one.
-Can that happen?
-Yeah, he's a alien.
-(CHUCKLES)
-A space one.
(LAUGHS) Yeah, a space one.
Well, let's just call it
a sort of dream.
(PANTING)
(GROWLS)
(LAUGHS) Are you just completely mad?
-Is it working?
-A little bit.
-Not so mad then.
-(LAUGHS)
What are you doing?
I'm doing what everybody does
when the world is in danger.
I'm calling the Doctor.
Pressing send.
(GLASSES CHIME)
So this computer simulation
dream thing...
Yeah?
Which, to be clear,
I don't believe a word of.
-Fair enough.
-You said I was in it.
Yeah.
Well, how did it go? The dream version?
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
-The Pope?
-In person.
-The Pope
-in your flat here.
-Yeah.
-Your tutor has strange dreams.
-I bet he does, you know.
Maybe he's just trying
to keep you on the straight and narrow.
Maybe, yeah.
How do you feel on the subject?
-(DOOR SLAMS OPEN)
-BILL: Whoa!
-(GASPS)
-Stay where you are!
(RAPID BREATHING)
-SOLDIER: Clear!
-Please remain still and calm.
-Sit down.
-Mmm-hmm.
Keep your hands in sight on the table.
-Miss Potts?
-Yeah?
Who is this?
This is my friend Penny.
Who the hell are you?
Room is secure, Your Excellency!
-This is Miss Potts, sir.
-Hi.
Miss Potts, this is
the Secretary-General of the UN.
I have flown here today
to speak to the President.
I'm told you might be able to help.
I don't know the President.
How would I know the President? I mean,
I wouldn't have even voted for him.
He's orange.
I mean, "the" President.
The Doctor.
The Doctor's not a president.
What's he president of?
Well...
In times of crisis,
Earth.
Is it okay if I get a move on?
BILL: President of the world?
In times of unusual danger,
that status is made official.
Turmezistan, near the border.
This is a disputed area.
A potential hot spot.
The Chinese have troops here.
The Russians here.
The Americans here.
-And in the centre...
-(BEEPING)
A pyramid.
Sir? I have Colonel Brabbit on the line.
Colonel Brabbit, you're on
with the Secretary-General.
Colonel, what have you to report?
Nothing, sir. Nothing at all.
It seems dormant.
The Russians and the Chinese are
reporting the same.
Reporting what? What's dormant?
The pyramid.
We're keeping it under observation.
Why? What's it been doing?
-You haven't told her?
-SECRETARY-GENERAL: I haven't, no.
COLONEL BRABBIT:
It's a 5,000-year-old pyramid.
There's one problem with that.
One little problem.
Wasn't there yesterday.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUITAR PLAYING)
The end of your life
has already begun.
There's a last place
you will ever go.
A last store you will ever walk through.
A last sight you will ever see.
And every step you ever take
ls moving you closer.
-The end of the world...
-(CAR BEEPS)
DOCTOR: Is a billion,
billion tiny moments.
-Don't shut the door!
-(CRACKING)
-(WOMAN SIGHS)
-DOCTOR: And somewhere,
-unnoticed...
-Sorry.
...In silence or in darkness...
-(SIGHS) Damn it.
-...it has already begun.
BILL: (THROUGH DOOR) Are you talking
to yourself in there?
I'm meditating.
Been in there for hours.
I've been trying to talk to you.
-(BANGS ON DOOR)
-Have you double locked this thing?
I'm busy thinking.
-(WHIRRING)
-Excellent. Who needs eyesight?
Those monk creatures I told you about.
If they've model led
every event in human history,
if they've simulated
entire events streamed
from day one till now,
think what they'd know.
Think what they could do with that.
BILL: (THROUGH DOOR) The UN called.
They want you
in Turmezistan immediately.
Tell them no!
Oh.
NARDOLE: They wouldn't
take no for an answer.
How did they get it out of my office?
The windows aren't big enough.
Oh, er, they are now.
Are you gonna ask what's going on?
Last I heard, you were on a date
with Penny. What happened?
Uh, the, uh,
United Nations Secretary-General.
-Awesome.
-Nah, that wasn't a metaphor.
Good, because I really
wasn't following it.
SECRETARY-GENERAL: Mr President.
I'm very pleased to see you.
I think we have something of interest.
(WHIRRING)
Why don't you tell me in your own words?
SECRETARY-GENERAL:
It's a matter of a pyramid.
Hello.
Hi.
Oh! You're an angel.
(SCOFFS) You look...
Don't take this the wrong way.
You look awful.
How could anyone possibly
take that the wrong way?
(CHUCKLES) Big night last night?
(SIGHS)
There was drinking.
There were breakages.
Textbook.
We're going to stage two today.
Well, it'd be rude not to.
You okay mixing it?
I broke my reading glasses.
(MIST SPRAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Tell me what you see.
It's a 5,000-year-old pyramid.
-(WHIRRING)
-DOCTOR: What do you know?
It wasn't there yesterday.
Therefore?
It's not really a pyramid.
It's something disquised
as a pyramid that
just appeared out of thin air.
And that's all way beyond
human technology
so it's gotta be alien.
It's an alien spaceship.
DOCTOR: There you go.
And what's it doing?
It could've chosen anywhere
on this planet. It chose to sit
on the strategic intersection of
the three most powerful armies on Earth.
So what it's doing, Colonel,
-is sending us a message.
-What message?
Bring it.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Mr President...
-Sir? What are you doing?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Bringing it.
Nardole. (BEEPS)
(BEEPS) On it, sir.
What's he doing?
We don't know what the thing
is capable of.
(WHIRRING)
Nothing yet.
All looks fine.
What are you doing?
Oh, updating him.
(STONE SCRAPING)
There's something happening, sir.
It's opening up, sir.
There's a door.
Nardole?
Something's coming out, sir.
Going by the description you gave me
from the simulation, sir,
I think that's
one of the monk creatures.
Hello?
We know you.
Then you'll know
that there is a line in the sand.
And I'm the man on the other side of it.
You wanna keep me that way.
We will take this planet and its people.
You will be prevented.
You will be fought.
We will be invited.
We will take this world.
We will rule its people.
But only when we're asked.
-We will talk again.
-When?
At the end of the Earth.
(STONE SCRAPING)
(WHIRRING)
(MOBILES RINGING)
-COLONEL BRABBIT: 11:57...
-P.M.
Yeah, mine too.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
It's everyone's.
11:57 p.m.
(WHIRRING)
NARDOLE: Did you get that, sir?
Everyone's phones gone to 11:57.
Yup. Same here.
What's...
-(BEEPS)
-What does that mean, 11:577
Also known as,
three minutes to midnight.
The Doomsday Clock.
-The what?
-Symbolic clock face.
Representing a countdown
to possible global catastrophes
started by some atomic scientists
in 1947.
The closer they set
the clock to midnight,
the closer we are to global disaster.
Currently it's set
at three minutes to midnight.
So now, every clock in the world
is the Doomsday Clock.
-Thanks to the Monks, yes.
-Is this a threat?
I wish it was. Did I tell you?
See, I think this is a warning.
Somewhere, somehow,
the end has begun.
(SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
Fully automated.
Lunch?
Well, it'd be rude not to.
(MOBILE RINGING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(TARDIS STOPS)
-Hello. Privet.
-Ah?
Sorry about that. Needed the call
to zero in on your coordinates.
Now, this is the Secretary-General
of the UN.
I am the President of the world.
And this is Xiaglian.
She's in charge of the Chinese Army.
Say hi to each other.
Now, we've been having a bit of a chat.
Thing is, World War Three.
What do you think?
Basically, we're against it.
DOCTOR: Listen to me.
Those creatures in that pyramid,
they have studied your species,
your civilisation.
Your entire history.
They've run a computer simulation
of this world
since you lot first slopped
out of the ocean looking for a fight,
and they have chosen this exact moment
and this exact place to arrive.
Why?
BILL: Because a war is
about to break out.
Possibly.
But whatever it is,
they're right here, right now,
because they believe humanity
will be at its weakest.
Then we'll demonstrate strength.
We will attack the pyramid.
Force is never the answer.
Isn't that right, Doctor?
Contact your masters.
Coordinate your attacks.
Doctor?
I doubt you'll even scratch that thing.
But if you demonstrate
strength and unity,
they might choose to step away.
Bill, take that look off your face.
There's no look on my face.
They did not come here in peace.
We have to do what we can.
Yeah, I get it.
(MOBILES RINGING)
It's two minutes to now.
The Doomsday Clock is moving.
What do we do?
Coordinate your attacks.
What's wrong with him?
What's wrong with the Doctor?
Did Nardole send you to speak with me?
Mighta done.
Mighta said there was something
you want to tell me.
Funny thing, fear, isn't it?
Once it rules you,
you're even afraid
to admit what's scaring you.
For the record, I for one,
fully understand my weakness.
(LOUD BOOM)
Oh, God, what's that?
PILOT: Approaching target.
Permission to strike.
BILL: So, why's the pyramid active now?
DOCTOR: Possibly they know
they're about to be bombed.
PILOT: Target distance 10 miles.
Set position five degrees.
(BUZZING)
(GROWLS)
PILOT: Code 72. Mayday. Mayday!
It's the Monks.
They've hijacked the plane.
How did they do that?
Oh, they're fine. The crew are alive.
Who are those guys?
I think they're ours.
-Yours?
-We targeted the pyramid with a missile.
(MISSILE LAUNCHING)
(CRASHING)
RUSSIAN OFFICER: From a submarine.
So demonstrating strength
isn't going to help.
MONKS: We are ready to talk.
Why don't you just take
the afternoon off if you feel that bad?
I can't just take the afternoon off.
How 'bout a kip on the floor
under your desk.
Now that's an idea I can get behind.
(SIGHS)
(MIST HISSING)
(WHIRRING)
I mean, this is a trap. Right?
Possibly.
Probably.
And we're just walking into it?
Well, every trap you walk into
Is a chance to learn about your enemies.
Impossible to set a trap
without making a self-portrait
of your own weaknesses.
Great.
Unless it kills us.
Well, you could say that about anything.
(PYRAMID OPENING SHUTS)
(EXHALES)
The human race is about to end.
The chain of events
is already in motion.
Life on Earth will cease
by humanity's own hand.
Observe.
DOCTOR: Ah.
The simulation machine
looks a bit different from the outside.
MONK: We are modelling the future.
Each thread is a chain of days
leading to your end.
We can detect
when a catastrophe is about to occur.
-And?
-MONK: Stop it from occurring.
COLONEL BRABBIT: You don't look
much like guardian angels.
MONK: We have chosen
this form to look like you.
COLONEL BRABBIT: You look like corpses.
You are corpses to us.
Your world is ending.
You can do nothing.
But we can save you.
Save us, then.
To save you, we must be asked.
Then what?
We will protect you.
-How long for?
-Forever.
Do you understand now?
Do you see?
Asking them for help has conditions.
Invite them in
and it will be
the last free action you take.
If you do not ask for help
then see the days to come.
(MONK SNARLS)
These are the threads that lead
to one year in your future.
Take them as proof.
(GASPS)
(ALL GROANING)
What was that?
Planet Earth. Not a single living thing.
Dead as the moon.
You seem pretty damn calm about it.
Do I? Oh, I'm sorry.
It's not my first dead planet.
Ask for help. It will be given.
-Why do you need to be asked?
-Power must consent.
"Power must consent.”
What does that mean?
Those who hold power in this world
must consent to our dominion.
Why?
(MOBILES RINGING)
One minute to midnight.
You could take this planet in a...
In a heartbeat.
Why do you need consent?
We must be wanted.
We must be loved.
-To rule through fear is inefficient.
-Of course.
Fear is temporary. Love
is slavery.
If consent is what you need,
I consent now.
No. No.
Don't do this, please.
Don't even consider this...
What I saw is real.
I felt it.
If you can help us,
-I consent.
-Please.
Listen to me.
(WHIRRING)
Do you have power?
I have power.
Does power consent?
Please, stop. Just stop this!
MONK: If your consent is impure,
it will kill you.
DOCTOR: Impure?
What does that mean, impure?
You act out of fear.
Fear is not consent.
(CRIES OUT)
(GASPS)
Planet Earth does not consent
to your help,
your presence, or your conquest.
Thank you for playing
the big pyramid game.
Bye-bye.
See you again next week. Hopefully not.
Without our help,
planet Earth is doomed.
DOCTOR: Yes.
Well, it's been doomed before.
Guess what happened? Me.
(GROWLING)
-What are you doing?
-I just need a minute.
I was about to throw up in my suit.
I did that once.
Urgh.
(PLANTS CRACKLING)
Oh, my God.
Okay. Whatever that is,
that is not meant to happen.
We need to sort this.
-(PANEL BEEPING)
-(ROOM DECOMPRESSING)
(DOOR SHUTTING)
(TANK DECOMPRESSING)
(PANEL BEEPING)
COLONEL BRABBIT:
Why do they need consent?
BILL: Maybe they're like vampires.
Can't come in unless they're invited.
They're not vampires.
The future we saw, is it the war?
Do we bring the future?
That would seem to be
the most obvious conclusion.
No! I say no. Friend?
I will not fight you.
We are just soldiers in the field.
Are we too afraid to disobey?
I'm not.
Neither am I.
This is amazing.
What do you think, Mr President?
Did we just... Give peace a chance?
The clock.
COLONEL BRABBIT: Sorry?
Look at the clock.
Still one minute to midnight.
It made no difference.
How could this make no difference?
Because it's not you
who's going to end the world.
You were never the problem.
Then who is the problem?
Something is happening somewhere else.
Somewhere in the world.
In silence or in darkness.
The world is ending, right now.
And we have to find out where.
It's gone crazy.
It's much too strong.
It's not just breaking
the root system down,
it's killing the whole thing.
We have to seal off the lab.
The greenhouse. Everything.
This can't be allowed
to get into the atmosphere.
This is impossible. We can't search
a whole planet in a few minutes.
Narrow it down. They landed the pyramid
in the middle of a military crisis.
What was the point of that?
Okay, what was the point?
What was the effect?
They told us the world was ending
in a potential war zone.
What did we assume was going to happen?
World War Three.
But it didn't.
The trick with misdirection,
don't look where the arrow is pointing.
Look where it's pointing away from.
So, what's already on our radar that
we should be worried about, right now?
Forgot about war.
What else could end the world?
-Bacteria.
-I like the sound of that.
New strain of flu? Plague?
People can be immune.
And whatever it is,
it will kill all life on Earth.
Not just humans.
Plague discriminates.
So this isn't a plan. It's a mistake.
Somebody, somewhere, is doing something
that's about to blow up
in everybody's face.
(SCREEN CRACKLING)
What are you doing?
A distraction tells
that whatever's coming
is already on a watch list.
I just put all the top secret
intelligence documents in the world
online, in searchable format!
-What?
-Sit down and Google!
It's never done anything
like that before.
Check the mix.
Anything?
(CHOKING)
Douglas?
Douglas!
(PANTING)
(PANEL BEEPING)
-Doctor, listen.
-What?
Isn't it worth at least
just considering doing the deal?
-What deal?
-All we have to do is consent.
That's what the Secretary-General
thought, and they burned him.
He was afraid.
I'm not being afraid, I'm being smart.
Yeah. Being smart is
not giving away your planet.
So, an accident leading
to irrevocable consequences.
I like bacteria.
They can spread. Once they're out,
you can't put them away again.
What could they do?
What do you depend on?
Air, water, food, beer.
Air, water, and food.
Let's say something's going to change,
something is going to be released.
Something
new, something fast, I'm feeling...
I'm feeling biochemical.
-Check biochemical trials.
-Yes, sir.
Doctor.
That world was dead a year from now.
We should at least go in there and talk.
Well, there are about a hundred thousand
biochemical trials going on right now.
Specifically related to GM bacteria.
Uh, 6,0007?
How many have reached stage two?
You cannot accept their offer.
Why not?
Because whatever the price is,
it's too high.
We'll work it out.
428.
It's too many.
And we don't even know if you're right.
Well, I probably am.
"Probably” isn't good enough.
Well, "probably” is all you have got!
It's your planet,
I can't just give it away.
You know what, sir? Finally
you've said something I agree with.
It's our planet.
Our choice.
You can't make a deal with them.
You don't know what you're agreeing to.
I don't know.
AILLT know is,
I plan on living to fight another day.
Right now, what we don't have
is a whole lot of other days.
-Agreed.
-Also agreed.
Doctor.
Is it just possible that they're right?
Being right is easy. We need to win.
All these soldiers in the room,
and you're the only one still fighting.
Would you make the deal?
Even not knowing what's going to happen?
Those guys have model led every event
in human history, to find our weak spot.
Are you gonna do the same
in a couple of minutes?
-Would you make the deal?
-No.
Not if I had a choice.
But we don't. Do we?
It's your world.
Not any more.
Okay.
Back to the pyramid.
And negotiate our surrender.
Doctor.
What are you gonna do?
Well, for a start,
I'm going to tell you the truth.
I've been keeping a secret from you.
BILL: Doctor?
We can blind them. That's how we do it.
We blind them.
Blind who? The Monks?
Bill, go to the pyramid.
Keep an eye on them all.
-Nardole, with me, to the TARDIS!
-Yes, sir.
Have you got a plan?
You'll be hearing from me.
WOMAN: (OVER TANNOY)
Biohazard. Lab in lockdown.
(ALARM BEEPING)
WOMAN: (OVER TANNOY)
Biohazard. Lab in lockdown.
Oh, Douglas, what have you done?
Okay, there's a list of labs
on the unit watch list.
If they're being watched, that means
that they've got CCTV cameras
with feeds to Unit 8Q.
-Can you hack them?
-Course I can, I'm not just sexy.
But there's 428 of them,
we can't watch them all.
-Are you following me?
-Yeah, I think I get it.
Yes, well, we're not
going to watch them,
we're going to switch them off,
-can you do that?
-What good would switching them off do?
If I'm right, the Monks are
only watching one of those labs.
How would they do that?
Well, I suppose they'd just...
Hack the cameras!
So switch 'em off.
(MACHINE POWERING OFF)
Okay, so... We've blinded them.
But whatever's happening
is still happening.
-Yup.
-And the Monks are powerful.
They can just turn the cameras back on.
Yes, they can.
But they're only watching one lab.
So all we need to know is
which lab just got its cameras back?
-(MACHINE DINGS)
-Oh, you genius.
Boom.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Oh, my God.
No, I'm the Doctor.
But it's an easy mistake to make.
The eyebrows.
How did you do that? What is that thing?
Uh, it's Nardole. He's not my fault.
Back to the TARDIS, this place is toxic.
I'm not human?
Well, you're human enough.
I got your lungs cheap.
Urgh, now he tells me.
Park her close, monitor me.
Oh, tidy up your room?
Urgh.
You have a problem, I believe.
Who the hell are you?
Don't be alarmed, we don't have time.
Just jump straight
to all the explaining.
(COUGHING)
(MOBILE RINGING)
It's the Doctor.
DOCTOR: (OVER PHONE)
Okay, found it. Lab in Yorkshire.
Long story short,
misplaced decimal point
resulting in a bacteria
that turns any living thing it touches
into gunk.
So why is it going to end the world?
Has it been dispersed already?
Uh, no. It's still in the lab.
I think I can contain it.
We give him two minutes,
and we're heading in. Agreed?
Agreed.
We have an air filtration system
to take toxins out of the air.
It runs a cycle every 30 minutes.
It's gonna pump the bacteria
into the atmosphere.
-So switch it off.
-I can't.
Oh. Right, okay. When's the next cycle?
Twenty minutes.
What?
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
Anything?
The venting system is automatic.
This is going to be trickier
than I thought.
(ALL PHONES RINGING)
We're going in.
Think, think, think...
Stupid Doctor, stupid, stupid, stupid...
Handsome Doctor!
Adorable, hugely intelligent,
but still approachable Doctor!
What's another way to destroy bacteria?
-Sterilisation.
-And how do you sterilise something?
Put it in boiling water.
-Or?
-Put it in a flame.
She's got it!
By George, she's got it!
I'm not going to lie to you.
This means that your insurance premiums
are going to go through the roof.
In fact, pretty much everything is
going to go through the roof,
because I'm going to blow up the lab.
Just need some kind of a trigger first.
But, what are you going to
blow it up with?
The bacteria is making ethanol.
The greenhouse
and the lab are full of it!
Seriously, what are you doing
when this is all over?
COLONEL BRABBIT: We're ready to talk.
(LOUD BOOM)
Do you have power?
Well, right now we're representing
the three biggest armies on the planet,
so I guess we do.
Does power consent?
We consent.
If your consent is impure,
it will kill you.
I surrender. We surrender.
What more do you want?
To rule, there must be love.
Your consent must be pure.
You act out of strategy,
strategy is not consent.
(ALL GROANING)
Do you consent?
I don't have any power. I'm nobody.
You represent the greatest power
on the planet.
You represent the Doctor.
Is your consent pure?
-Is this going to work?
-Trust me.
I pop it in there, machine goes ping,
lab goes boom, world is saved.
You develop
a pretty intense crush on me.
Okay, go through to the machine room.
You're going to have to let me back in
when I'm done.
-How long before the vents kick in?
-Four minutes.
Doctor, are you still there?
There's no way of stopping
the lab venting.
So I'm going to sterilise the building
by blowing it up.
Everything in here will be destroyed.
-Including you?
-Not if I pull my socks up.
Honest answer. You gonna do it?
'Course I'm going to do it.
"Cause... Because
they're still offering a deal, and...
And I'm the only one left.
Tell them you're flattered, but don't.
What does "consent" mean?
You must ask for our help, and want it.
And know you will then be ours.
Only then can the link be formed.
What link?
Do you consent?
(ROOM DECOMPRESSING)
Can you hear me?
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
-I don't even know your name.
-Erica.
Did you always want
to be a scientist, Erica?
Since I was about eight.
Before that I wanted to be a bus driver.
(CHUCKLING) Because I liked
how they waved at other bus drivers.
(BEEPING)
Okay, I've given us two minutes.
Right. You need to get out of there.
(TIMER BEEPING)
Hello, I'm the Doctor.
Saving the world with my eyes shut.
(ALARM RINGING)
Doctor, the clock's going back.
Have you done it?
Yes, I have! I am totally
the President of Earth.
And, from now on, two planes.
One for me, and one for my
glamorous assistant, Erica.
Say hello to the folks at home, Erica.
And let me through the door.
Bill, get the hell out of that pyramid.
I can't open it.
It's under emergency protocol.
You need to use the combination lock.
Set it to three, six, one, four.
Uh...
You're going to have to guide me.
Well, I can't see it from here.
You can see it, right?
How long have I got?
One minute 40. Three, six, one, four.
Come on!
Doctor, what's happening? Are you okay?
Bill, sorry, uh, slight hitch.
-Working on it.
-What's the problem?
Three, six, one, four.
I need to open the door,
but I can't, uh, see the numbers.
ERICA: One minute 20.
I don't understand the problem.
Combination lock. All the sonic could
do was calculate the number.
But I still have to enter it.
Nardole. Nardole!
Nardole, I need you to do
a visual on the lab.
There's a camera in here.
Nardole?
Nardole, can you hear me?
I don't understand the problem.
Just open the door.
-I can't.
-Why can't you?
Because I'm blind.
I'm sorry, I'm blind.
(STUTTERING) What do you mean blind,
what are you talking about?
I lied.
I've been blind since Chasm Forge.
I didn't get my sight back,
I've been lying to you.
There's a combination lock,
with numbers, and...
I can't see them.
(CRYING)
You are the stupidest idiot ever.
I'm not gonna let you die.
No, you have to. There's no choice.
No one else can help me now.
The Monks. The Monks can help you.
No. Bill, no. Don't do that.
I'm sorry.
I have made a mistake.
I have to face that.
But do not ask the Monks for help.
(MACHINES BEEPING)
Bill!
Doctor. This planet needs you.
So I'm making an executive decision.
I'm keeping you alive.
Bill. Listen to me. Please.
I don't know what consenting
allows them to do to you.
DOCTOR: You don't know
what you're agreeing to.
Can you give him his sight back?
His sight can be restored.
Then... Then I'm asking you for help.
I give you my consent.
Is your consent pure?
Just give him his sight back.
You can have the world,
just make him see again.
I consent.
You act out of love.
Love is consent.
We must be loved.
Bill, do not make this deal.
I forbid it.
(BEEPING)
Bill, can you hear me? What's happening?
Bill?
(DOOR BEEPS)
Bill. What have you done?
Tell you what, old man.
You'd better get my planet back.
MONKS: Enjoy your sight, Doctor.
Now see our world.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
BILL: 7 woke up,
and the Monks were here.
They've always been here.
All that we believe now is a lie.
I want to speak to her.
All we have to do is find
whoever opened the door to the Monks
and just kill them.
I'm sorry your plus one doesn't get
a happy ending.
All anyone's seen of the Doctor
in the last six months
are those broadcasts he does.
I have joined the Monks.
(GUNSHOT)