AMY: Life with the Doctor was like this.
(SCREAMS)
Real life was like this.
-(PHONE BEEPS)
-WOMAN: It's Lens Opticians.
Just a reminder your reading glasses
are ready for collection.
-AMY: Milk. Two months out of date.
-Bye!
Yogurt. (SHRIEKS) Don't ask.
We've run out of washing tablets.
We have two lives.
Real life and Doctor life.
Doesn't feel like real life
gets much of a look in.
What do we do?
Choose.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-Not today, though.
-No, not today.
AMY: Every time we flew away
with the Doctor
we'd just become part of his life.
But he never stood still long enough
to become part of ours.
Except once.
The year of the slow invasion.
The time the Doctor came to stay.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(DOORBELL CHIMING REPEATEDLY)
Dad, it's half past 6:00 in the morning.
BRIAN: What are you doing lying around?
Haven't you seen them?
RORY: What are they?
BRIAN: Nobody knows.
But they're everywhere.
Well, where did they come from?
Wait.
Doctor!
Invasion of the very small cubes.
That's new.
World leaders are appealing for calm.
The global appearance of millions
of small cubes...
Despite official warnings, people have
been taking the cubes from the streets
into offices and homes.
-What are they?
-Where did they come from?
And why are they here?
Well, they're certainly
not random space debris.
They're too perfectly formed for that.
Are they extraterrestrial in origin?
Well you'll have to ask
a better man than me.
All absolutely identical.
Not a single molecule's difference
between them.
No blemishes, imperfections,
individualities.
What if they're bombs?
Billions of tiny bombs?
Or transport capsules, maybe,
with a mini-robot inside?
Or deadly hard drives?
Or alien eggs?
Or messages needing decoding?
Or they're all parts of a bigger whole.
Jigsaw puzzles
that need fitting together.
Very thorough, Brian.
Very, very thorough. Well done.
Stay here, watch these.
Yell if anything happens.
Doctor, is this an alien invasion?
Because that's what it feels like.
There couldn't be life forms
in every cube, could there?
I don't know.
And I really don't like not knowing.
Right! I need to use
your kitchen as a lab.
Cook up some cubes, see what happens.
Right. I'm due at work.
What? You've got a job?
Of course I've got a...
What do you think we do
when we're not with you?
I imagine mostly kissing.
I write travel articles for magazines
and Rory heals the sick.
My shift starts in an hour.
You don't know where my scrubs are?
In the lounge, where you left them.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER, INDISTINCT)
MAN: Target unconfirmed. May be hostile.
Approaching source now.
Area will be secured in 60 seconds.
Ultimate force available.
Ah, the Ponds.
With their house and their jobs
and their everyday lives.
The journalist and the nurse.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-Long way from Leadworth.
We think it's been ten years.
Not for you or Earth, but for us.
Ten years older, ten years of you.
On and off.
Look at you now.
All grown up.
(LOUD CRASH)
(POLICE CHATTER ON RADIO)
-Trap One, kitchen secured.
-Trap Three, back garden secured.
There are soldiers all over my house
and I'm in my pants.
My whole life
I've dreamed of saying that.
And I miss it by being someone else.
All these muscles and they still
don't know how to knock.
Sorry about the raucous entrance.
Spike in artron energy reading
at this address.
In the light of the last 24 hours,
we had to check it out
and the dogs do love a run-out.
Hello. Kate Stewart,
Head of Scientific Research at UNIT.
And with dress sense like that...
(BEEPING)
...you must be the Doctor.
I hoped it'd be you.
Tell me, since when did science
run the military, Kate?
Since me. UNIT's been adapting.
Well, I dragged them along.
Kicking and screaming, which...
which made it sound like
more fun than it actually was.
What do we know about these cubes?
Far less than we need to.
We've been freighting them in
from around the world for testing.
So far we've subjected them
to temperatures of
plus and minus 200 Celsius,
simulated a water depth of five miles,
dropped one out of a helicopter
at 10,000 feet
and rolled our best tank over it.
Always intact.
That's impressive.
I don't want them to be impressive.
I want them vulnerable,
with a nice Achilles heel.
We don't know how they got here,
what they're made of
or why they're here.
And all around the world people are
picking them up and taking them home.
Like iPads have dropped out of the sky.
Taking them to work, taking pictures,
making films, posting them on Flickr
and YouTube.
Within three hours, the cubes had
1,000 separate Twitter accounts.
-Twitter.
-I've recommended we treat this
as a hostile incursion,
gather them all up and lock them
in a secure facility,
but that would take massive
international agreement and cooperation.
We need evidence.
The cubes arrived in plain sight,
in vast quantities, as the sun rose.
So, what does that tell us?
Maybe they wanted to be seen, noticed.
Or more than that,
they want to be observed.
So we observe them, stay with them.
Round the clock, watch the cubes,
day and night.
Record absolutely everything about them.
Team cube, in it together.
Four days, nothing.
Nothing.
Not a single change in any cube
anywhere in the world.
Four days and I am still in your lounge!
You were the one who wanted
to observe them.
Yes, I thought they'd do something,
didn't I?
Not just sit there
while everyone eats endless cereal!
You said we had to be patient.
Yes, you! You, not me.
I hate being patient.
Patience is for wimps.
I can't live like this. Don't make me.
-I need to be busy.
-Fine!
-Be busy. We'll watch the cubes.
-Yes.
(LAWNMOWER HUMMING)
Ninety-eight, 99, 100. Amy!
Four million, nine hundred
and ninety-nine. Five million.
That's better. Nothing like
a bit of activity to pass the time.
How long was I gone?
Uh, about an hour.
I can't do it.
Where are you going?
Brian! You're still here.
-You told me to watch the cubes.
-Four days ago.
Doesn't time fly
when you're alone with your thoughts?
You can't just leave, Doctor.
Yes, of course I can.
Quick jaunt, restore sanity.
Ooh! Hey, come if you like.
They can't just go off like that.
Can't they? Can't you?
That's how it goes, isn't it?
I've got my job.
Oh, yes, Rory, the universe is awaiting
but you have a little job to go to.
It's not little. It's important to me.
Look, what you do isn't all there is.
I never said it was.
All right. Fine.
I'll be back soon.
Monitor the cubes, call me.
I'll have the Tardis set
to every Earth newsfeed.
(DOOR CLOSES)
At the end of a week of cubic
questions and theories but no answers,
could this be the greatest stealth
marketing campaign in business history?
And if it is,
will those behind it ever come forward
and explain exactly what it's for?
I'm so pleased for you two.
It's about time you made
an honest woman of her.
-Amy, about bridesmaids.
-Mmm.
You've missed quite a few things
the last year or two.
I'm so totally there, whatever you need.
Everyone here loves you.
The nurses, the doctors.
You're a lifesaver, mate, literally.
Well, thanks.
There are months
where we don't see you.
And we can't do without you.
I want you to go full-time.
Full-time? Blimey. Uh...
I said yes.
-I committed.
-And I committed to being a bridesmaid.
Months in advance.
Like I know I'm going to be here.
So, the Doctor's God knows where,
the cubes aren't doing anything at all.
Did real life just get started?
-I like it.
-So do I.
Brian's log. Day 67.
You can't call it that. Brian's log?
Cube was quiet all night, once again.
Cube was quiet all day.
As per previously,
no movement, no change in measurements.
End of entry.
You stay up and watch it all the time?
I film it while I'm asleep.
When I wake up, I watch the footage
on fast-forward.
I email the result to UNIT.
My middle name is Diligence.
Wow! I can't wait to see day 68.
Don't mock my log.
I'm doing what the Doctor asked.
(MERRY XMAS EVERYBODY
BY SLADE PLAYING ON PA)
Uh, Mr Ryan, please.
Again?
I'm fine, I've been done.
-What seems to be the matter?
-I'm just waiting for a prescription.
-Where does it hurt?
-I said I'm fine.
Can you tell your colleague here
that I...
Stop!
(MAN SCREAMING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey! Doctor, it's me. Hello.
So, the UN classified the cubes as
provisionally safe, whatever that means.
And Banksy and Damien Hirst
put out a statement
saying the cubes are
nothing to do with them.
And the cubes, well,
they're just here, still.
What's it been, nine months?
People are just taking them for granted.
Maybe we'll never know why they came.
But anyway, I got to Laura's wedding.
It was great. She's here tonight,
being as it's our wedding anniversary.
We thought you might have dropped by.
I left you messages.
I know! Happy anniversary!
Come with me and bring your husband.
(CLAPS TWICE)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Twenty-sixth of June, 1890.
The recently opened Savoy Hotel.
Dinner, bed and breakfast for two.
Bonjour, bonjour. Merci, Auguste.
You'll be back before the party is over,
they won't even notice you went.
No complications, I promise.
Oh.
(LAUGHING)
Bit of a shock.
Zygon ship under the Savoy,
half the staff impostors.
Still, it's all fixed now, eh?
MAN: Check the corridors!
I thought we were going home.
You can't miss a good wedding.
Under the bed, under the bed.
(MAN SHOUTING, HALL DOORS OPENING)
Shh!
-It wasn't my fault.
-It was totally your fault.
Somebody was talking
and I just said yes.
RORY: To wedding vows!
You just married Henry VIII
on our anniversary.
(SNEEZES)
Sorry.
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHOOPS)
How long were they away?
I don't know what
you're talking about, Brian.
Because they're wearing
totally different clothes from earlier.
Seven weeks.
I got side-tracked.
A lot.
What happened to the other people
who travel with you?
Uh...
Some left me.
Some got left behind.
And some,
not many, but...
some died.
Not them. Not them, Brian.
Never them.
Can I...stay here
with you and Rory for a bit?
Keep an eye on the cubes.
However long that takes?
I thought it would drive you mad.
No. No, no.
I mean, I'll be better at it this time.
I._..
Miss you.
Brian's log. Day 361.
8:50 p.m., no movement.
And I am cream-crackered.
I sent you out to sell as many cubes
as you could in 24 hours.
And look at you, you've made a right
hash of it, haven't you?
Well Craig, you're fired.
If I had a restaurant,
this'd be all I'd serve.
Yeah, right. You running a restaurant.
I've run restaurants.
Who do you think invented
the Yorkshire pudding?
(CHUCKLING)
You didn't.
Pudding yet savoury.
Sound familiar?
(CUBE BUZZES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(GASPS)
Do it again.
Good job, mister.
Civilisations saved. Surfaces wiped.
What more could any woman ask for?
I mean it.
-Where's the Doctor?
-On the Wii again.
-Oh.
-I'm going for a bath.
(GRUNTING)
Oh, that's second set, Doctor! (LAUGHS)
Oh, if Fred Perry could see me now, eh?
He'd probably ask for his shorts back.
(WARBLING)
Ah!
Third set decider, come on, then.
Out of the way, dear, I'm trying to...
Whatever you are,
this planet, these people,
are precious to me,
and I will defend them
to my last breath.
Is that all you can do? Hover?
I had a metal dog could do that.
Ooh! Ooh, that's clever. What's that?
Whoa!
-Ooh, you really have woken up.
-RORY: Doctor!
Hi, uh, the cube in there,
it just opened.
The cube upstairs just spiked me
and took my pulse.
(LAUGHS) Really? Mine fired laser bolts
and now it's surfing the net!
You're never going to believe this.
-My cube just moved.
-(MOBILE RINGING)
-It rattled.
-(DOCTOR CHUCKLING)
-Hello?
-Rory, mate.
I'm desperate for help.
People are saying
they're being attacked by the cubes.
It's going to be a long night.
RORY: Okay, I'm on my way.
I have to get to work,
they need all the help they can get.
Let me come, help out.
Take-your-dad-to-work night, brilliant.
Okay, you going to be all right here?
-Keep away from the cubes.
-Right.
What are you grinning about?
We're wanted at the Tower of London.
Every cube across the whole world
activated at the same moment.
Now we're in business.
You sent me a message
to my psychic paper.
You know what? I'm almost impressed.
Secret base beneath the Tower?
Hope we're not here
because we know too much.
Yes, I've got officers trained
in beheading. Also, ravens of death.
I like her.
(ANNOUNCEMENT ABOUT CUBES
ON PA, INDISTINCT)
There are 50 being monitored
and more coming in all the time.
I don't know how useful it is.
Every cube is behaving individually,
there's no meaningful pattern.
Some respond to proximity.
Some create mood swings.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
AMY: What's this one?
KATE: Try the door.
(CHICKEN DANCE PLAYING)
On a loop.
-This is the latest.
-DOCTOR: Oh, dear.
Systems breach at the Pentagon, China,
every African nation, the Middle East.
KATE: I've got governments
screaming for explanations
and no idea what to tell them.
I'm lost, Doctor.
We all are.
Don't despair, Kate. Your dad never did.
Kate Stewart, heading up UNIT,
changing the way they work.
How could you not be?
Why did you drop Lethbridge?
I didn't want any favours.
Though he guided me, even to the end.
"Science leads," he always told me.
Said he'd learnt that
from an old friend.
We don't let him down.
We don't let this planet down.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
They've stopped.
The cubes, across the world,
they just shut down.
Active for 47 minutes
and then they just die?
-Not dead, dormant maybe.
-Then why shut down?
I don't know.
I don't know, I need to think.
I need some air.
Who has an underground base?
Terrible ventilation.
The moment they arrived,
I should have made sure
they were collected and burned.
That is what I should have done.
How? Nobody would have listened.
You're thinking of stopping, aren't you?
You and Rory.
No. I mean, we haven't made a decision.
But you're considering it.
Maybe. I don't know, we don't know.
Well, our lives have changed so much.
Well, there was a time, there were years
when I couldn't live without you.
Um...
When just the whole everyday thing
would drive me crazy.
But since you dropped us back here,
since you gave us this house,
you know, we've built a life.
I don't know if I can have both.
-Why?
-Because they pull at each other.
Because they pull at me
and because the travelling is starting
to feel like running away.
-That's not what it is.
-Oh, come on.
Look at you - four days in the lounge
and you go crazy.
I'm not running away.
But this is one corner
of one country and one continent
on one planet
that's a corner of a galaxy
that's a corner of a universe
that is forever growing and shrinking
and creating and destroying
and never remaining the same
for a single millisecond
and there is so much,
so much to see, Amy.
Because it goes so fast.
I'm not running away from things,
I am running to them,
before they flare and fade forever.
It's all right.
Our lives won't run the same.
They can't.
One day, soon, maybe,
you'll stop.
I've known for a while.
Then why do you keep coming back for us?
Because you were the first.
The first face this face saw.
And you were seared onto my hearts,
Amelia Pond.
You always will be.
I'm running to you and Rory,
before you...
fade from me.
Don't be nice to me.
-I don't want you to be nice to me.
-Yeah, you do, Pond.
And you always get what you want.
-They got what they wanted.
-What? Who did?
The cubes, that's why they stopped.
Come on.
Kate!
Before they shut down,
they scanned everything,
from your medical limits to your
military response patterns.
They made a complete assessment
of planet Earth and its inhabitants.
That's what the surge of activity was.
Problem with the power?
Not possible, we've got backups.
Hmm.
Doctor? Look!
DOCTOR: What?
KATE: Why do they all say seven?
Seven. Seven, what's important about
seven? Seven wonders of the world.
Seven streams of the river Ota.
Seven sides of a cube.
-A cube has six sides.
-Not if you count the inside.
It has to be a countdown.
-Not in minutes.
-Why would it be minutes, Kate?
We have to get humanity
away from those cubes.
God knows what they'll do
if they hit zero.
Get the information out any way you can.
News channels, websites,
radio, text messages.
People have to know
that the cubes are dangerous.
Okay, but why is this starting now?
I mean, the cubes arrived months ago.
-Why wait this long?
-Because they're clever.
Allow people
enough time to collect them,
take them into their homes,
their lives.
Humans, the great early adopters.
And then wham!
Profile every inch of Earth's existence.
Discover how best to attack us.
Get that information
out any way you can, go.
Right. Every cube was activated.
There must be signals,
energy fluctuations on a colossal scale.
There must be some trace.
There can't not be.
We need to think of all the variables.
All the possibilities.
Okay, go, go, go, go!
NEWSREADER:
This is a national security alert.
The Government advises
that members of the public
dispose of all cubes.
If there are cubes inside your house,
remove them immediately.
Get them out of the building.
Just away from here, as far as you can.
And get back here before it hits zero.
Dad, could you go
and get me box of tape for dressings?
It's just the cupboard
around the corner.
Yes, boss.
Sorry. Excuse me.
I'm looking for the supplies cupboard.
I said I'm looking
for the supplies cupboard.
-Look, have you seen my dad?
-No, sorry.
Hey. Dad. Hey!
Hey!
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
AMY: Doctor, please,
you don't have to do this.
She's right.
You don't have to be in there.
-We can do this remotely.
-Remotely isn't my style.
See you after.
Geronimo.
What's happening?
Well, what's in there?
There is nothing in here.
AMY: Um, well, that's good.
You know, it's not bombs,
it's not aliens.
Why? Why is there nothing inside?
Why? It doesn't make any sense.
Glasses, is it the same?
-Is it the same all around the world?
-KATE: They're empty.
We're safe, right?
No, no, no, we are very far from safe.
All along, every action
has been deliberate.
Why draw attention to the cubes
if they don't contain anything?
Doctor, look.
GLASSES: They're CCTV feeds
from across the world
that are showing the same.
People are dying.
What? They can't be dying.
How? How are they dying?
KATE: I want information
on how people are being affected.
Uh, the cubes brought
people close together.
They opened and then... (SCREAMS)
Doctor, what's the matter?
-(RAPID BEEPING)
-I don't know!
Hospitals are logging a global surge
in heart failures,
-cardiac arrests.
-That's it. Ah!
Ah! Ah! Only one heart.
-Other one's not working.
-AMY: Okay.
I'm going to get you to the hospital.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Turn around, turn around, turn around.
Tell me, show me.
Ten seconds after the cubes opened,
show me the patterns
in their electrical currents.
-(COMPUTER BEEPING)
-See?
-No!
-Yes, the power cut.
They suck the power and then...
(SCREAMS)
They're signal boxes.
People leaning ni, wham,
pure electrical surge out of the cube
targeted at the nearest human heart.
The heart, an organ powered
by electrical current.
Short-circuited. How to destroy
a human? Go for the heart.
Ow! Crikey Moses!
Doctor, the scan that you set running.
The transmitter locations,
it's found them.
Oh, look at them all,
pulsing, bold as brass.
Seven of them all across the world.
Ow! Seven stations, seven minutes.
Why is that important?
Ah! Ow, ow!
How do you people manage one heart?
It is pitiful!
The wormhole bridging two dimensions.
Seven of them etched onto this planet,
but-but-but where's the closest one?
Glasses, zoom in.
That's the hospital where Rory works.
Dad. Dad!
Just get away from him.
-How many deaths have been recorded?
-We don't know.
We think it could
be a third of the population.
Kate, I have to find the wormhole.
But the attacks could still happen.
Tell the world.
Tell them how to deal with this.
The world needs
your leadership right now.
-I'll do my best.
-Of course you will. Good luck.
Kate... (GROANS)
Okay, how long are you
going to last with only one heart?
Not much longer.
I need to locate the wormhole portal.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
Hello, hello.
Ah, hello.
You are giving off
some very strange signals.
Oh, my God!
Outlier droid monitoring everything.
If I shut her down, I can...
(ELECTRONIC WARBLING)
It's all right. It's all right.
Ah! I can't, Amy.
I can't do it. I need both hearts.
(GROANING)
All right.
-Desperate measures.
-What?
No! No, no, no. That won't work.
I'm a time lord. Ah, hey! (SCREAMS)
-No. No...
-All right, clear!
(GROANS)
Ooh!
Welcome back, leftie!
Whoa-ho! Two hearts. Whoo!
Back in the game.
Never do that to me again.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Oh, portal to another
dimension in a goods Lift?
The energy signals converge here.
Does seem a bit cramped, though.
Through the looking glass, Amelia.
AMY: Where are we?
DOCTOR: We're in orbit.
-One dimension to the left.
-Rory!
Saborian smelling salts.
Outlawed in seven galaxies.
Whoa-ho!
Whoa! What kind of
a weapon do you call that?
-Get them out of here. You two, now!
-What are you gonna do?
Absolutely no idea.
Get him through the portal.
Whoa!
So many of them
crawling the planet,
seeping into every corner.
It's not possible.
I thought the Shakri were a myth.
A myth to keep the
young of Gallifrey in their place.
The Shakri exist in all of time,
and none.
We travel alone and together.
The seven.
The Shakri craft connected to Earth
through seven portals in seven minutes.
Ah, but why?
Serving the word of the Tally.
Why the cubes? Why Earth?
Not Earth, humanity.
The Shakri will halt the human plague
before the spread.
Erase humanity
before it colonises space.
We thought the cubes were an invasion,
the start of war.
The human contagion only
must be eliminated.
Who are you calling a contagion?
DOCTOR: Oi, didn't I tell you two to go?
-You should have learnt by now.
-Yeah, and what is this Tally, anyway?
Some people call it Judgment Day
or the Reckoning.
-Don't you know?
-I've never wanted to find out.
Before the closure there is the Tally.
The Shakri serves the Tally.
DOCTOR: The pest controllers
of the universe.
That's how the tales went, isn't it?
Wow! That's some seriously
weird bedtime story.
You can talk.
Wolf in your grandmother's nightdress?
So, here you are,
depositing slug pellets
all over the Earth,
made attractive
so humans will collect them,
hoping to find something
beautiful inside.
Because that's what they are.
Not pests or plague, creatures of hope.
Forever building and reaching.
Making mistakes, of course.
Every life form does.
But... But they learn.
And they strive for greater
and they achieve it.
You want a tally?
Put their achievements
against their failings
through the whole of time.
I will back humanity
against the Shakri every time.
(CHUCKLES) The Tally must be met.
The second wave will be released.
AMY: What does that mean?
It's going to release more cubes
to kill more people.
Tell the Secretary-General
it's not just hospitals and equipment,
it's people.
Our best hope now is each other.
The human plague, raiding and fighting.
And when cornered,
the rage to destroy.
You are too late, Doctor.
The Tally shall be met.
-He's gone.
-He was never really here.
It's just the ship's
automated interface,
like a talking propaganda poster.
I can stop the second wave.
I can disconnect all the Shakri craft
from their portals,
leave them drifting in the dark space.
Ah, but all those people
who were near the cubes,
so many of them will have died.
-I restarted one of your hearts.
-You'd need mass defibrillation.
Of course. Ah. Beautiful. But...
Pond, Ponds! We are going to go
one better than that.
The Shakri used the cubes
to turn people's hearts off.
Bingo! We're going to use them
to turn them back on again.
-Will that work?
-Ah, creatures of hope.
Has to.
Thirty seconds.
Don't let me down, cubes.
You're working for me now.
Oh, dear! All those cubes.
There's going to be
a terrible wave of energy
ricocheting around here any second.
Run!
I'm going to miss this.
(SCREAMING)
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
NEWSREADER: Emergency hospitals
and field units
are working at full capacity
around the world,
as millions of survivors
of cardiac arrest
are nursed back to health
after an unprecedented
night across the globe.
KATE: You, uh...
You really are
as remarkable as Dad said.
-Thank you.
-My!
A kiss from a Lethbridge-Stewart.
That is new. (LAUGHS)
Oh! I'm late for dinner.
Ah!
(LAUGHING)
Hmm. Forgive me.
I'd better get going. Things to do.
Worlds to save, swings to...
swing on.
Look, I know you both have lives here.
Beautiful, messy lives. That is what
makes you so fabulously human.
You don't want to give them up.
I understand.
Actually, it's you
they can't give up, Doctor.
And I don't think they should.
Go with him.
Go save every world you can find.
Who else has that chance?
Life will still be here.
-You could come, Brian.
-Somebody's got to water the plants.
Just bring them back safe.
AMY: So that was
the year of the slow invasion,
when the Earth got cubed
and the Doctor came to stay.
It was also when we realised something
the Shakri never understood,
what cubed actually means.
The power of three.
GRAYLE: You don't believe
that statues can move.
(CHUCKLES) And you're right,
they can't.
When you're looking.
DOCTOR: New York is policed by Angels.
Every time you try to escape,
you get zapped back in time.
The city that never sleeps.
The Angels will come
and I think they're coming for you.
Displacing someone back in time
creates time energy.
And that is what the Angels feed on.
What the hell are you doing?
-Any ideas?
-Run!