And I know that you'll try everything
to stop me, so I can't take that risk.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[screaming] Rani!
[♪ theme song playing]
[screams]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Welcome to the Time Hotel.
If you'd like to come with me, sir?
Magic door?
He had an actual magic door? The little--
Too late.
[gasps]
[gasps, sighing]
Happy morning.
One more day to go.
It's May the 24th tomorrow.
[alarm clock rings]
Mmm.
[alarm stops]
John?
[pants]
-What? But…
-[chuckles]
Anita!
Hello, Doctor.
Oh! [chuckles] Oh, my God.
Oh… [stammers] But the world…
The world was…
The world was destroyed.
No. No, no, look.
-Look.
-[keypad beeps]
-[Anita] It's May the 23rd again.
-[roaring]
May the 24th never arrives. It resets.
It gets to midnight
and then it all clicks back
to 7:00 a.m. on May the 23rd.
It's done it hundreds of times.
[Doctor] But we're…
We're in mid-air.
I've got the house key.
I can open a door anywhere.
This is crazy.
Anita, it's…
It's so good to see you.
[♪ whimsical music playing]
And, honey, somebody else
was pleased to see you too.
[both laugh]
[both sigh]
-[Anita chuckles]
-[Doctor sighs]
-Ricardo.
-Head of HR.
He worries too much, but he's lovely.
And this is a baby boy,
due in three months…
If we ever get there
because this place is in trouble.
[building crashes, strains]
[alarm sounds]
The Hotel's in spasm,
'cause we're in 4202
and the world keeps ending in 2025.
As far as I can see,
-that woman in the sky--
-The Rani.
-She's a Time Lord too, yeah?
-Yes.
I tried looking for your TARDIS…
-…but I can't find it.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Anita, you are…
You are talking Time Lords and TARDISes.
When I left you, you were just… [chuckles]
Ordinary.
I didn't say that.
This job at the Time Hotel
taught me so much…
[Doctor chuckles]
And…
on my days off, I'd go looking for you.
-[crowd cheering]
-[wind blowing]
[♪ heroic music playing]
[Dalek] You are the Doctor!
You are an enemy of the Daleks!
Now you are in our power.
You will be exterminated.
[♪ chamber music playing]
Oh.
I ran straight from that to Ricardo,
so all's well that ends well.
But what about this Rani?
Why's she doing all this?
Why does Friday the 23rd
keep resetting itself?
She needs the same day to
keep repeating itself
so that it gets thinner and thinner
and thinner until it snaps.
Once it's broken, she can see
underneath the skin of reality.
What for?
To find Omega.
[♪ ominous music playing]
The most fearsome Time Lord in existence.
Can you take me to her?
That palace of hers is No Entry.
She's surrounded by a Threshold.
We can't get in.
It says that portal
was the Time Hotel, December 2024.
You were supposed to
follow him everywhere.
All right, I had Christmas off,
and so did you.
We're the same person.
That strutting little pompadour.
He'll try to stop us.
We can't wait for another midnight.
Nine, nine, nine, nine,
seven, seven, seven,
six, seven, seven, seven,
seven, seven, nine.
We don't have to.
The Seekers have fixed the location.
There. Hidden beneath reality,
deep in the Underverse.
Omega.
Creator of the Time Lords.
Our Lord and Master.
No one is Lord and Master of me.
Now, how to bring him home?
[display beeps]
[portal opens]
[Anita] Here you are, Doctor.
Poppy's room.
[portal closes]
[♪ unsettling music playing]
[footsteps approach]
Belinda woke up without you.
Every time the world resets,
it gets a bit bumpy.
Things fall through the gaps.
Everyone sort of compensates,
like they make the reality work.
It's a world built on a wish,
willed into existence by
the Rani's pet human, Conrad Clark.
Oh, the Doctor loved
playing jokes and games.
And he had a favourite planet
called Earth.
A quiet little…
And I have a daughter.
But she isn't real.
How dare you?
I have been in
the halls of the Goblin King.
I have stood in the Palaces of the Daleks.
I have entered the caves of Satan himself.
But what has happened here
in this tiny little bedroom
in the middle of suburbia
is bigger than anything.
[Belinda] Hello?
Is someone there?
-It's me.
-Oh.
You're home. I thought you were…
I don't know what I thought.
I'm coming down.
I'll make us some tea.
[♪ uplifting music playing]
[sighs]
Nice surprise. Daddy's here.
-[portal opens]
-[♪ gentle music playing]
[portal closes]
But I'm…
I'm Belinda Chandra.
And you're Poppy.
She's real.
-Oh, my God. You're the Doctor.
-[chuckles]
But you're real.
Here she is.
-We've had a baby.
-In a single day.
[both laugh]
And who's that?
[stammers] This… This is Anita.
I just work in hospitality, really.
Is she safe, Doctor?
Please tell me our daughter is safe.
She is in danger,
but we will fight, Bel, to save her.
Fight like never before.
[phones ringing]
What on earth?
Well, don't look.
All of you, keep working.
I said keep working.
[♪ heroic music playing]
Mr Smith,
what on earth do you think you're wearing?
The future.
Just a second, guys,
because these are doorways into real time,
allowing you to see the truth.
-[grunts]
-[gasps]
Mr Smith, whatever this is,
I demand that you stop.
Mr Smith is gone.
I am the Doctor.
I'm wearing a suit.
I'm wearing tweed.
I'm wearing nylon.
[workers shouting]
Danger. Sub-atomic disruption.
Reality levels now converging.
[chuckles]
Doctor, what's happening?
Welcome back, Kate.
-[explosion sounds]
-[metal creaks]
-What is it now?
-I don't know.
I've never done this before.
Hold on tight.
I think reality is reasserting itself.
Rosie.
-Oh. [laughs]
-[laughs]
Rosie.
Conrad… Conrad couldn't imagine you
for even a second
so you didn't exist.
But now you are back, thanks to Anita.
[laughs]
I'm in the hotel industry.
Neet, Neet, I need you to stay there.
Keep that door open.
Keep the real time flowing, honey.
Why is Conrad Clark on television?
Never mind him.
What the bloody hell is that thing?
Bone Beasts.
Creatures from the Underverse.
Because when two realities collide,
it creates friction
and the friction creates
these excitated atoms,
and that summons the Bone Beasts.
They're like antibodies.
They sort of graze, feeding off the atoms.
Cleaning up the world.
Now,
one more thing.
[♪ gentle music playing]
Hello, everyone.
I'm Belinda.
And this is our daughter, Poppy.
Well, now you're going too far.
[trains rumble]
[Shirley] Morning, Winnie love.
Another day in paradise?
-Happy May the 23rd.
-Same to you.
Only one day to go.
We had all UNIT personnel biochipped
so we know where they are.
We only have a ten-mile radius,
but maybe we can use the chip
to signal them and wake them up.
[computer beeping]
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[chip beeps]
But…
What the hell is going on?
[chip beeps]
You can't say things like that.
You've got to behave, Ruby.
You can't go slandering Conrad.
Winnie, I'm sorry about this,
but I promise things will change.
I don't understand.
It's just a normal day.
Where are you going?
Me?
I'm gonna save the world.
-[wheelchair blasts off]
-[gasps]
Whoo-hoo! [laughs]
You're running up and down
like a mad sumaddy.
What you really doing?
What I do best.
Bye!
[Conrad] Okay. Let's repeat chapter one.
[♪ unsettling music playing]
-Is it working?
-We need to move a little faster.
Sweet little Desidirium.
If only you were older,
you could imagine such complicated things.
Instead, I've got you.
I'll do anything for you, mistress.
Don't say that.
You really are ridiculously handsome.
I could tilt you on your side
and serve olives in those dimples.
-[chuckles]
-Hmm?
But still, the Doctor,
he's out there somewhere
and you hold all of the wish
in your head, Conrad.
Can you see him?
Can you find him, Connie?
For me?
[tannoy] Gold alert. Gold alert.
So, you see those plans up there?
Cross-match them into null-space.
I need you to build me that
in record time. Can you do that?
Consider it done, sir. [chuckles]
Doctor!
[laughs]
-Oh, hello.
-Hi.
-You're blonder.
-Yes.
-How is Carla?
-She's fine.
How is--
-[exclaims]
-Oh, no.
No, no, no. Do not go hugging me, you.
I feel like I haven't washed for days.
[chuckles, sighs]
A daughter?
Do you mean an actual daughter?
That's amazing.
-Yeah, it surprised me too.
-[engine sounds]
[horn toots]
I have been a housewife.
[laughs]
Come here!
[all chuckle]
Gold protocols. Doctor on the bridge.
-Update all of us please.
-[Ruby, Mel sigh]
Basically,
we are facing the Unholy Trinity.
God of Wishes, crazy Time Lady,
Conrad Clark.
Mel, I am sorry. It is the Rani.
-She's still alive?
-Mmm.
I fought the Rani when I travelled
with the Doctor all those years ago.
This should be the best day of my life.
Another Time Lord. It means
I'm not alone… [chuckles] …except…
She's ruthless.
Worse than ruthless,
she's indifferent to any pain
or morality or humanity.
The whole universe is
just an experiment to her.
Now, the Trinity have wished
this world into existence. Conrad's world.
But he couldn't imagine everything,
so he used us.
We half-remembered ourselves,
living Conrad's version
of an ordinary life.
All crushed and stifled and appalling.
But if things are half remembered,
then we met a girl named Poppy.
-Exactly like her, Doctor.
-What does that mean?
It just makes it even more amazing, Bel.
Little scraps of memories, yours and mine,
have come to life in a child of our own.
[alarm blares]
Caution. Teleport incoming.
[♪ menacing music playing]
You really are an idiot, Doctor.
You had a whole world to hide in
and you ran half a mile away.
The Rani.
-[chuckles]
-Hmm.
And Melanie.
We meet again.
I thought you'd be dead.
I thought there's no way that painted doll
of a princess could ever survive.
I never thought about you once.
Oh, you thought of me every night.
Rani, the Time Lords were slaughtered.
How did you survive?
I saw it coming, the genetic explosion.
I had a split second, flipped my DNA,
made a biological sidestep,
survived the carnage.
How did you get to Earth?
I have the only TARDIS in existence.
[both chuckle]
[Doctor] Time Ring.
-Poor baby.
-It led me to you.
Although, that wasn't difficult.
Find a stupid, blonde Earth girl
and there you are.
Excuse me?
It was so tedious putting up with you
and your 57 mothers.
I've never met you in my life.
-All right, Rubes darling?
-Uh, Mrs Flood?
-That's my neighbour.
They're both the Rani.
We bi-generated.
Obviously, I bow to the mistress,
but it took a lot of planning
spying on those two.
"Cor blimey, look at that police box."
And pinning it all down to May the 24th.
But I was brilliant.
The plan is Omega?
Splitting open the world
to reach him in the Underverse beneath.
Oh.
Every civilisation has a thousand legends
about the world hidden below.
The Upside Down or Narnia or Hell.
That is the Underverse.
To which Omega was banished.
My father fought Omega back in the 1970s.
Said he was a Titan,
called him the Mad God.
Omega was the first.
The one who discovered time travel.
Some call him
the Original Sin of the Time Lords.
Cast out from Gallifrey.
Legend says that they bound him
and banished him because he is insane.
The point is, he's alive.
Exiled to the Underverse
means he survived.
You can't know that.
Alive or dead,
he will work as a gene bank.
With his body,
I can resurrect the Time Lords
and construct a new Gallifrey.
[chuckles]
Your Gallifrey?
Well, the Gallifrey of old
never did appreciate me.
But this one,
this will be a power in the sky.
But if you need the DNA of a Time Lord,
then what about you?
The two of you?
I think she's asking us to mate.
You don't understand.
That's why I keep telling you
that Poppy is so special.
Because she is impossible.
The child of a Time Lord.
And?
There's no such thing.
We're sterile.
We are infertile.
The species is barren.
We're a biological dead end.
There can never be
another Gallifreyan child.
Sometimes I think
that's what bi-generation is.
A life force trying anything it can
to survive.
What happened?
That genetic explosion it… [sighs]
It didn't kill us but it roasted us
and sterilised us.
Extinction is taking a bit longer,
that's all.
So, Poppy came out of the wish?
Like an accident?
The most beautiful accident
because that is what life does.
It just happens.
A mad woman and a maniac
came up with a ridiculous plan
and out of it… [chuckles] …came her.
Doesn't Poppy solve everything?
I mean, she's Time Lord DNA.
Well, yes, except…
-The mother.
-What about me?
-Human.
-And?
The child is contaminated.
-[groans]
-[Shirley laughs] Oh, come on.
Oh, I think I've lost the crowd.
-You are disgusting.
-And you are cattle.
We're talking about Time Lords here.
The highest universal race,
the greatest and purest
classification of life.
He walks around like he's one of you,
but you're like insects to him,
playthings, a fetish.
And deep down in your hearts, you know it.
Now shut up, step aside.
Let me build a new Gallifrey,
and I will leave your world untouched.
Then… Then the wish ends.
-What would happen to Poppy?
-She would cease to exist.
-No.
-She would vanish.
Like a whisper.
Doctor, I am genuinely sorry,
but she's not real.
She's made of hopes and dreams and wishes.
That is every child.
But if we don't end the wish,
this stays as Conrad's world.
We can't do that. That's not happening.
Absolutely not.
Don't you tell me what we can and can't do
'cause I don't care what UNIT thinks,
or Time Lords or gods or anyone.
I remember her being my daughter,
and if I remember it, then it's true.
Not one of you is taking her
out of existence.
Have you got that?
Not one of you.
Quite the dilemma.
I just came to make an offer.
Stand with me, Doctor,
and set a new race of Time Lords
up on high,
or stay down here with the beasts below.
I swear I will stop you.
[grunts]
The battle is on, Doctor.
Good luck.
How close are we?
Target fixed.
The Chronon Beam
will pull Omega out of the Underverse.
Trouble is, the UNIT tower is
a tinderbox of weapons,
but if we fake an excitation of its atoms,
the Bone Beasts will see the Tower
as an enemy.
[alarm blares]
She is provoking the Bone Beasts.
We are at war.
[roars]
[♪ adventurous music playing]
-[tannoy] Hostiles detected.
-[alarm blares]
Sector 7, grid 5, sector 14, grid 1,
sector 19, grid 5, sector 27, grid 4.
-All weapons coordinated and primed.
-Attention all staff.
This tower is going into battle mode.
Combat teams, attend your stations now!
-[Vlinx] The Vlinx is designated…
-[Doctor] Mel. Melanie!
-…Prime Battle Coordinator.
-Power up the Indigo Device.
Rose, I want you to bio-sync Ruby
-for the flight.
-I'm on it.
-Did you say flight?
-[Doctor] Yes, I did.
-[tannoy] Gold alert. Gold alert.
-Anita, Anita, keep that door open.
I need you to keep real time flowing.
Hey. Hi. Bel, trust me.
We're going down to floor minus 10, yeah?
-Come on.
-Activating weapons platform.
[tannoy] Warning. Null-space activation.
Warning. Null-space activation.
Is it ready?
If I have to hold it together
with my bare hands.
-Yes, it's ready.
-What is that thing?
[Doctor] I call it a Zero Room.
We're half a mile underground.
We're shielded from all signals.
And the room inside that thing,
it is beyond time and space.
It will exist outside of reality.
We put Poppy in and if the wish
comes to an end, we open it up.
And Poppy will still exist?
-I hope.
-You hope?
I will do everything
I can to make it work.
I owe the Doctor my life, Miss Chandra.
I won't let him down.
[Belinda] Do you mean Poppy
goes in there alone?
'Cause I'm telling you, she does not.
I'm going with her.
And I can't help you in the fight.
My battle is in there, saving my daughter.
Bel,
if the Rani wins and we are destroyed,
you will be locked in there
for all eternity.
You wouldn't starve or age or suffocate.
You'd just…
You'd just be. Forever.
-With Poppy.
Let's do it.
[grunts]
Open the Parallax Cannons.
-Fire!
-[tannoy] Maximum parallax!
Caution. Zero coordinates mapped on to
Real Time Dynamics.
Repeat. Zero coordinates mapped on to
Warning.
Floor minus 10 is now an instability zone.
-[Bone Beasts roar]
-[explosions sound]
-What if it doesn't work?
-I think we won't remember.
She will fade away like gossamer.
It'll be like Poppy never existed.
-That will never happen.
-Never.
Because it makes sense now.
I was meant to meet you, Belinda.
It was all for this,
so that Poppy can live.
[kisses]
Close it.
-Double galvanic beams.
-Fire!
[tannoy] Squad 1, maintain position.
-They're getting closer.
-Squad 2, maintain position.
-More power.
-Squad 3, terminated.
[gasps, shouts]
[tannoy] Squad 4, defend the east flank.
-Ow. What's that for?
-It's like a bio sync-up thing.
It makes the software respond to you.
[shouts]
The Indigo Device is a transmat,
like a matter transporter.
You'll be fine as long as
you don't press the yellow button.
Oh, my God. It really works.
Press the blue button.
That'll get you to Conrad
so you can stop him
and bring his wish to an end.
Well, how do I do that?
What do I do? Can I punch him?
Yes, you can.
[all grunt, shout]
[UNIT soldier 1] Medic! Medic!
Parallax Cannons, east 21.6.
Fire!
Well, hang on.
What about Anita and her magic doors?
I'm just a hotelier, really.
Well, can't you get us into the palace?
Anita needs to keep that door open
or you lot will slip back into the wish.
Now, the Bone Palace is protected.
It has a Threshold.
If you tried to transmat in there,
-you'd be pureed, baby girl.
-Nice.
I need to get in there,
lower the Threshold
so I can stop the Rani.
-But how can you do that?
-Oh, I… I tricked her.
Hmm?
[the sonic beeps]
Copied her coding.
[the sonic whirs]
Bone Beast three, out of range.
We're turning, west 44.5.
All personnel, hold on tight.
-[tannoy] Warning, revolve protocols.
-[grunts]
-Warning, revolve protocols.
-Galvanic beams at maximum.
-Fire!
[shouting]
Get to cover!
Shirley,
monitor the Threshold on frequency five.
As soon as it falls,
Ruby, activate the Indigo Device.
Fly well, Doctor.
If we die here today, I love you lot.
Just shut up and go!
[laughs]
[♪ heroic music playing]
Protect the retrofold cables.
Keep the red-links connected.
[no audible sound]
[♪ music resumes]
[grunts]
Threshold down!
Come on!
-[gasps]
-Like I wasn't ready for you.
[groans]
-Ouch!
-You were too late, Doctor.
The portal has locked on to its target.
And you're really very obvious.
I know you haven't arrived with a weapon.
Only a speech, some dazzling words,
maybe a pun
and then some lachrymose
little tug-the-heartstrings
mimosa-scented platitudes
about the power of love.
But aren't you tempted, Doctor,
to start again?
The Time Lords reborn?
The Time Lords of Omega
were tyrants and murderers.
Then rebuild them with us.
You're not amongst the humans now.
Stop pretending.
You're a Lord of Time and Space.
Now act like it.
[Mrs Flood] Don't you want to see him?
The Almighty One.
Don't you?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Yes.
Omega locked and approaching.
Here he comes. Back to reality.
What is that? What is that?
Is that a doorway or…
The tomb of Omega
or his prison, his asylum?
I suggest we find out.
[the Rani's sonic whirs]
[♪ tense music playing]
[Ruby pants]
I want to say thank you.
[scoffs, chuckles]
-Sure.
-I mean it.
Because Conrad's World,
it could've been so much worse.
A fantasy world, I'd expect guns
and whisky and girls, but yours is nice.
-It's actually nice.
-I did what he said.
-Who?
-The Doctor.
He told me people just want to be
safe and fed and warm.
So that's what I did.
And you tried to give everyone a family.
All that time we spent together,
you never mentioned your dad.
You never ever mentioned your father.
And I… I wonder why.
You don't know me at all.
[the Rani's sonic whirs]
[double heartbeat sounds]
[Seekers mutter]
A heartbeat.
A double heartbeat.
Omega lives.
Omega. Omega. Omega…
I summon you, creator of the Time Lords.
Come back to this world.
Omega. Omega. Omega. Omega.
But some of it was true.
You and me.
Because I was there, Conrad.
In the dark, when I made you smile.
That was real.
[Seekers] Omega. Omega. Omega. Omega.
Omega. Omega. Omega. Omega.
Drone Guards, stand by.
[the Rani] Yes.
[growls]
What?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[roars]
Rani, get back.
But what is it?
The Underverse is a world of legends,
so Omega has become his own legend.
He is the Mad God,
the Titan,
the Original Sin.
I will become the God of Time
with Time Lords to feast upon.
Well, I think you'll find…
[the Rani screams]
[screams]
[Beast of Omega] So sweet.
[roars]
[high-pitch ringing]
[screaming]
[Beast of Omega growls]
Omega.
Omega!
Remember me?
My little Doctor.
It's been a very long time.
May I introduce to you the Rani.
[Beast of Omega] This little thing?
So much for the two Ranis.
It's a goodnight from me.
Oh, thanks.
-Omega.
-[growls]
The very first Time Lord.
May I ask, what is your intent?
I am free to feast upon this world.
None shall stop me.
Then there's nothing I can do.
I stand here without hope or help.
Just thinking if only…
[chuckles]
If only I had a weapon…
hiding in plain sight.
Wait a minute.
[♪ heroic music playing]
The power of one billion supernovas.
[grunts]
[shouting]
[Beast of Omega howls]
[Indigo Device beeps]
[Ruby] Conrad…
I wish you to be happy.
[blows]
-[shouting]
-[Beast of Omega howling]
Back into Hell!
[♪ music ends]
[sighs]
[kisses]
End the wish.
[blows]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Hold your fire. Hold your fire.
Don't you ever wonder deep down
in both your hearts,
where your TARDIS is?
[chuckles] We were in the TARDIS.
[pants]
[TARDIS warbles]
[laughs]
[Ruby gasps]
[Doctor] Back to floor minus 10.
[breathing heavily]
-[TARDIS groans]
-[shushes]
It's okay.
[♪ wistful music playing]
Can't we wish for Poppy?
But then she might vanish…
when I do this.
Because I must.
No more wishes.
-Ooh.
-[Desidirium cries]
-You okay?
-I'm okay.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
I don't know.
[all cheering]
Poppy.
[Doctor laughing]
Oh, baby!
[Doctor] Poppy!
Oh, my God.
Hey. Boop.
[♪ gentle music playing]
Well, we know he's human by birth.
We just don't know where
in time and space he's from.
Do we? We don't know.
Hey, he's a foundling just like me.
Like me.
So, I thought,
-who is the best mother in the world?
-Me.
But I am too busy playing poker.
Cherry.
[Carla] But we can't just…
I mean, there's paperwork and all sorts.
-Paperwork is sorted.
-[Ruby] Ah.
Joseph.
Joseph was my late husband's name.
-Aw, Joe Sunday.
-Aw. Joe Sunday.
-Little Joe Sunday.
-Yeah.
And what about you, Doctor?
-Ruby says you're a father now.
-Uh-huh.
I pity the child.
But what will you do?
You can't run around
like a nutcase anymore.
Things will have to change.
[chuckles]
I know.
Poppy! Where's my girl?
She's too big for this already.
Aren't you, Poppy?
She'll climb out.
This place is a deathtrap.
I know, I know, I know.
We need rails.
Safety rails going all the way around.
It's gonna look amazing.
So what are you guys gonna do,
the three of you?
-Like, settle down?
-Oh, absolutely not.
My daughter's not gonna
have a boring life.
-We can go anywhere…
-[blowing raspberries]
…and everywhere and show her everything.
Are you too hot in this, Pops?
It's always cold in here,
but for the first time it's too warm.
Mmm. That's the TARDIS accommodating.
There's one thing
I still don't understand.
How come my memory was different?
Why did I remember things
that no one else could?
I have no idea,
but we have seen many a strange thing
together, Ruby-Roo.
Hey, it's a skill!
It's a skill.
[all laugh]
We'll need all sorts of things,
like a room for toys.
I can do that. I can do that.
I can turn the TARDIS into anything.
[console beeps]
We can put a room off there or anywhere.
-[chuckles, sighs]
-I wonder where we take her first.
She could see Neptune. No!
-She could see Kerala!
-Kerala.
-I have never been.
-[chuckles]
All of the universe and I have never been.
We can go and see my Uncle Roo.
Oh, he's wonderful.
In the year 60,000,
there is a planet called New New Delhi.
-Oh, we are going there.
-We're going there.
[♪ wistful music playing]
Isn't it funny?
I used to say take me home.
Mm-hmm. And now you wanna stay. I knew it.
I knew. I knew I would get you in the end.
I wanna see planets and galaxies.
-Oh.
-I wanna see the Big Bang.
Mate, we will have the best of times.
[chuckles]
Where's she gone?
-Who?
-Poppy.
Who's Poppy?
But…
[console beeps]
One more thing I've gotta sort out.
Oh. Okay. Let's see.
Because the robots…
The robots from Missbelindachandra One.
-Oh.
-[Doctor, Belinda laugh]
Ruby, I had a whole planet named after me.
It was so mad.
They picked up the Star Register
in the future
after the Rani destroyed the Earth.
Now, the planet is not destroyed,
so I've gotta chuck this thing
back out into space,
then the robots can find it.
[laughs]
[grunts]
History is intact. Thank you very much.
-Doctor, where's she gone?
-Who?
-Poppy.
-Who's Poppy?
Your daughter.
What do you mean?
You have a daughter.
The two of you. Together.
I think I'd remember that.
Imagine.
But what… what do you think the cot is?
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
There… There was…
There was a little girl named Poppy.
A long time ago.
That space baby lives far away
in a different world.
Ruby, I think your memory
got a little bit scrambled.
[chuckles]
Belinda, where shall we go?
There's a great big universe
waiting for us.
Take me to the stars.
Good. Good. Good, good, good. [laughs]
Let me just make sure everything
is back in place.
-[TARDIS warbles]
-[door opens]
Oh, look out. Here he is. Trouble.
And you're just in time, Doctor.
Here it comes.
[bell tolls]
-[laughs]
-[UNIT soldiers cheering]
[cheers]
-At last!
-It is now officially May the 24th.
The day we thought would never arrive.
Congratulations.
Welcome.
Happy May the 24th.
-Happy 24th.
And I better go.
That signals the end of my time here,
I think.
Anita, you are so amazing. I…
Thank you.
You're very welcome to stay, Anita.
You could work for UNIT.
You'd be very useful with a key like that.
Oh, I'm so sorry, but this key is
far too powerful for the 21st century.
And they only gave me one day.
I'm not allowed to stay.
There's far too much to do.
-Oh, they say hello, by the way.
-Who does?
The Boss.
[portal closes]
Okay. Parking that.
So, the entire world is back to normal?
Yes. Yes!
And we… [laughs] …are off to Neptune.
See you later. [laughs]
-Come on, Rubes, we'll pop you home.
-No, no. Just wait. It's important.
Is the world exactly as it was?
Well, funny you should say.
There are tiny little changes.
Like, Conrad's World was sort of glitchy.
Now we've got the same.
We're getting reports that
the border between Norway and Sweden
has moved seven miles east.
And the colour teal is a bit more blue.
And Ernest Borgnine is still alive.
So there are mistakes.
It was bound to happen, Ruby.
Reality shifted on a massive scale.
-Ernest Borgnine got lucky.
-[chuckles]
And there's one more big change.
[Kate] Mel found this.
Reporting from Empress House.
And I found him.
He posted this online.
Stop filming me.
Nice.
Chief cook and bottle washer.
Nice little place in Lewisham.
I looked inside. It's harmless.
And no one remembers him
from the old days.
That Conrad's been forgotten.
Even by himself.
I think Ruby did a very kind thing.
The gods are full of tricks.
One wish survived.
And it turns out to be him, not Poppy.
Ruby. Ruby, I told you
there is no one called Poppy.
[♪ ominous music playing]
Kate, do you remember
a child called Poppy in this room?
No.
-Do you?
-No.
The Vlinx, do you have any record
of a child called Poppy,
in this building, on May the 23rd?
Negative.
Shirley, do you remember her?
No.
Susan, you saved Poppy's life.
You built a Zero Room to save her.
Surely you've got to remember that.
There is a Zero Room on floor minus 10.
I built it like an escape pod.
For all of us.
Poppy went in there.
We all watched her come out.
-We saw it. We did.
-[Doctor] Ruby, I'm sorry,
but you are remembering this wrong.
[Belinda] And not to be rude,
but it's kind of offensive to say
I've got a daughter I don't remember.
Poppy's your daughter?
Well, exactly.
She doesn't exist.
So what we're saying is,
my memory is one of the glitches.
-It must be.
-I'm glitching?
-Yes.
-Poppy's a glitch?
Yes.
Except the glitches were real
before they changed.
Because I was right in the Wish World,
wasn't I?
And I'm right now.
Conrad wasn't some nice, happy chef,
-was he, Kate?
-No.
And that's not teal, is it?
No, it's too blue.
Don't you see? There's another world.
A slightly different reality.
And it might just be a tiny little change,
but she's a child.
She's a little girl
and she's so beautiful.
Her name is Poppy,
and she's lost somewhere out there.
Ruby, I'm not wrong on this.
Doctor, one life has disappeared.
And you know this can happen.
You know this better than anyone
because it has happened before.
It happened to me, remember?
I'm looking for your daughter, Ruby.
-Who's Ruby?
-[Ruby] That Christmas…
-I was that life. I ceased to exist.
-[crying]
And you did everything you could
to bring me back
because you couldn't bear a world
with one person missing.
You did that for me too.
I was trapped in that time explosion.
[shouting]
I was a baby.
And you were there.
You said you went through my entire life.
That car when you were seven.
-That was you.
-Yeah, but…
You saved me.
I'm barely a year old.
Born out of the TARDIS, remember?
You set me free and saved my life.
You save all of us.
Sometimes I think we're all your children.
[♪ majestic music playing]
We're missing one person.
Your daughter.
I have a daughter?
Yes. [chuckles]
If Poppy's real, that means she was mine.
I will find her.
Bel, I swear on my life
I will do anything to find her.
But, Doctor, we can help.
We've got the Time Window.
We've got temporal dams.
We've got retrodynamic artron cascades.
Time has shifted by one degree.
By the tiniest little degree.
There is no technology in the universe
that can change that.
There is only one thing
that is strong enough…
to change reality one tiny degree.
Which is what?
The last of the Time Lords.
[♪ heroic music playing]
[TARDIS warbles]
[grunts]
Okay.
[blows]
[sighs] Poppy.
Her name is Poppy.
Okay. Her name is Poppy.
[sighs]
Aw, man, I like this face.
[TARDIS console whirs]
What are you showing me that for?
Man.
Oh, man.
Let's be honest.
I was the best.
Okay, let's say best male.
But don't tell the others.
[♪ electronic music playing]
What? How?
-How are you here?
-I know.
I shouldn't be here at all.
Cause and effect is getting
a little bit out of order.
I'm surprised it's not the other guy.
He is always turning up.
You've redecorated.
I don't like it.
Does it really need to be bigger
in a room defined by its bigness?
But why are you here?
I've been popped out,
like popped out of my timeline
because there's a great big time schism
on its way, caused by you.
Time needs to be shifted, Doctor.
So I am going to punch a ton of
regeneration energy
into the vortex to jolt it. One degree.
-Giving your life?
-A life for a life.
Because I saved the world
at the expense of one person.
And that is no world at all.
There won't be any worlds.
If you rupture the Time Vortex,
you could damage the whole of creation.
Is that why you're here?
To stop me?
Nah, it was never gonna work.
[sighs]
Blimey, you're gorgeous.
Your face is absolutely beautiful.
Well, it will be our last one
if I get this wrong.
Don't get it wrong then.
Good idea. [chuckles]
This is gonna eat my soul.
-No chance of bi-generation?
-No chance of what?
Oh. Never mind. Forget I said anything.
Just… this is gonna hurt.
Try shifting your third strand
of phenotype markers
one micro-spasm to the left.
Just might help.
Oh, that is clever.
But, hold on…
I'm older than you.
Why didn't I know that?
You know, it's all a bit
-timey wimey.
-Time-wimey.
-Is that still a thing?
-Going strong.
[gasps]
-[chuckles]
-We never change.
All these faces
and we never really change.
[sighs]
-Oh, man.
-You scared?
Terrified.
Don't go in fear.
Go with that lovely smile.
[chuckles]
I just wish we…
we had longer.
May we always wish that.
[TARDIS warbles]
We're stretching the timeline too far.
I've got to go.
Back to my old life.
Bye then.
Good luck.
I love you, Doctor.
I never say things like that.
That's why you got me.
I should say that to Yaz.
[Doctor] You never do.
But she knows.
-Goodbye, Doctor.
[♪ heroic music playing]
[breathing heavily]
-[regeneration energy swells]
-[grunts]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[shouts]
[grunts]
[shouting]
[panting]
[♪ gentle music playing]
-[regeneration energy swells]
-[gasps]
No.
Not yet.
[grunting, pants]
Here he is.
-Bad penny.
-[gasps]
Go on then, mystery man.
Where have you been?
Oh, I would love to be called Bad Penny.
[laughs]
But… what…
What happened?
You were there, and then you were gone.
[chuckles] But come on. She's waiting.
-Uh… [stammers] …who is?
-Poppy.
Poppy.
[gasps] Oh.
Poppy, Poppy, Poppy, Poppy, Poppy!
-[laughs]
-Oh.
-Isn't she beautiful? [chuckles]
-The best. How could I forget?
Remind me, what happened…
What happened again?
I was with you and then…
Well, we stopped the Rani.
And then all of UNIT got busy
all of a sudden.
Then I turned around and you'd gone.
And I had to get back home.
'Cause that was the point.
All this time I had to be here,
in this house, at 7:30 a.m.
on the 24th of May, remember?
I kept telling you every time we landed.
-[grunts]
-[TARDIS warbles]
Doctor, I told you. Get me home!
24th of May 2025.
I need to get back for Poppy.
Never mind Miami.
Poppy's waiting for me.
My daughter.
Will I ever see her again?
Never mind happy New Year.
I've got to be home
for Poppy on May the 24th.
If I'm not back by 7:30, I'm in trouble.
I can't wait for you to meet Poppy.
She's so cheeky.
So you were…
You were always coming home for Poppy.
-Exactly.
-[chuckles]
I got taken away
by the Robots on the 23rd.
And for my timeline to get back to normal,
I had to be here, for Poppy,
on the 24th of May at 7:30 a.m.
But why 7:30?
Right. Better be off.
Oh.
Bit early for gentlemen callers, Belinda.
But he's a nice one.
-This is my mum, Lakshmi.
-[Doctor chuckles]
Oh.
-Hello. I have heard so much about you.
-Oh. [chuckles]
And this, um, is one of the doctors
from the hospital.
At last.
I keep telling her to bring home a doctor.
-Amma.
-No, no, no, not for you.
-For me, Doctor.
-Oh.
You see, I have this pain down
my left side every time I turn corners.
-Right.
-It's really…
-[car horn honks]
-Oh… [laughs] …that's for me.
I got to go.
I've got a concert in Manchester.
-Oh, good luck.
-Lovely meeting you.
And you as well.
-Bye, sweetheart.
-Bye.
Bye, Poppy love. [kisses]
Bye-bye.
[Doctor laughs]
So you… You had to come
home because your mother…
I'm on nights.
So Mum and Dad had Poppy.
I had to be back for 7:30…
-Because Manchester.
-[door closes]
You really have forgotten, haven't you?
[chuckles]
I'm glad you managed to find us
so you can finally meet.
Poppy, this is Uncle Doctor.
I'm her uncle?
[Poppy babbles]
Well, I thought it sounded nice.
[chuckles]
Who's her father?
-I've told you.
-Remind me.
Her father's Ritchie.
-Ritchie Akingbola.
-Oh.
I've known him since I was 21.
We got together, and well, Poppy was born.
[chuckles]
We're not together anymore.
We both wanted different things,
but he's a lovely man.
He sees her all the time.
He's a good soul. You'd like him.
[chuckles]
I hope Ritchie Akingbola knows
how lucky he is
to be the father of a girl who is…
[the sonic whirs]
[the sonic beeps]
[chuckles]
…one hundred per cent human
since the day she was born.
What else would she be?
Nothing. Nothing. [laughs]
Poppy the human. Always and forever.
-[door opens, closes]
-All is well with the universe.
I thought I had those grips.
You know, the ones for my hands.
Have you seen them?
I saw Dad trying them out.
I think they're under the stairs.
Hold on.
Hello, Pops. [chuckles]
Can I tell you a secret?
I can't have children.
But if I could,
I wish that she was exactly like you.
Boop.
Except I brought all the wishes to an end.
Clever old me.
[chuckles, inhales sharply]
There we go.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, just, you know, thinking.
The gods play tricks.
[chuckles]
But I beat them.
I always win.
[both chuckle]
Thank you. For everything.
You've driven me absolutely mad.
[chuckles]
But I've got to say,
you're the most amazing man in the world.
[both chuckle]
That sounds like a goodbye.
[Belinda] Hmm.
I wish we could come with you.
I'd love to show Poppy the stars.
But you know what happens next.
She'll be shot at by lasers
or hunted by cartoons
or blown up by mad Time Ladies.
I can't do that to her.
It's been an honour, Miss Belinda Chandra.
An honour, a nightmare and a triumph.
Maybe when she's grown up,
you could come back?
Take me to Neptune?
I'd like that.
I'd love that.
But will you?
Will I ever see you again
or do you never go back?
I hope you'll see me again.
But not like this.
[chuckles] What does that mean?
[laughs]
I've got to go.
Just…
[breathes heavily]
Why does it feel like
there's something I've forgotten?
That's our lives, Belinda.
We travel in and out of
the slipstreams of time.
Beautiful things can
be forgotten and gone.
But they still happened somewhere.
I think one thing remains.
I love you.
And I love you, Pops.
That will never change.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[TARDIS warbles]
[♪ poignant music playing]
[chuckles]
Don't wanna do this alone.
I'm never alone with you.
[chuckles]
Joy to the world!
And that is exactly the word.
This has been an absolute joy.
Oh, hello.
[♪ closing theme song playing]