(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: I'm sure
it's somewhere around here.
-(CHILDREN LAUGH)
-GRAHAM: Come on, Doc, admit it.
I don't know what you mean.
Well, look at it! This ain't
the coronation of Elizabeth I, is it?
-Mmm.
-It's like a street party.
Ye olde hipster pop-up happenin'.
The TARDIS is being a bit stubborn
at exact readings.
-So where are we?
-Apple bobbing!
I love apple bobbing.
-Is this Halloween?
-No, it's Sunday.
Yeah, but what's the party for?
We do this every Sunday.
Oh, happy Sunday.
Northern accent,
we must be close to home.
(HAND BELL RINGING)
Mistress Savage demands your presence.
The ceremony will begin.
Anybody else missing the party vibe
all of a sudden?
Go on.
YASMIN: Where are they all going?
Whatever this is,
I need you all to remember,
the most important thing
about dips into the past,
do not interfere
with the fundamental fabric of history.
Even if something's not right?
DOCTOR: Yep, and judging
by the vibe here,
something is definitely not right.
(GIRL SOBBING)
Are you okay?
Can you tell us what's going on here?
Guys, that's Pendle Hill.
We're in Lancashire.
People of Bilehurst Cragg,
we are forced to meet here once again.
Satan stalks this land.
We must continue to root him out
and do whatever it takes
to save the soul of our village.
Let us put the accused to the test.
-Granny!
-Hush, Willa.
-It's a witch trial.
-BECKA: Old Mother Twiston.
Must be early 17th century.
You stand accused of witchcraft
and shall be tried by my ducking stool,
hewn from the mightiest tree
on Pendle Hill.
If you drown, you are innocent.
If you survive, you are a witch
and shall be hanged.
(VILLAGERS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
This is way too dark for me.
We've got to do something, Doctor.
Uh-uh. The Doc said don't interfere.
You said don't interfere, right?
MOTHER TWISTON: Don't cry, Willa.
(WHIMPERS)
I will still be with you.
In the water.
In the fire.
In the air.
In the earth.
-Duck the witch.
-(VILLAGERS SHOUTING)
-Duck the witch!
-MAN: Duck the witch!
YASMIN: Doctor!
WOMAN: Not that way.
MAN 2: Witch!
MAN 3: Come on!
-MAN 4: Duck the witch!
- (CLAMOURING)
Granny!
-MAN 5: That's it!
-Meet me on the other side.
So much for not interfering.
YASMIN: Open the bridge. Come on!
BECKA: Who dares interfere
with this trial?
Thirty-five witches we have tried,
and still Satan surrounds us.
We shall not be stopped.
(PANTING)
YASMIN: Doctor, we're here.
BECKA: You will be punished
for your interference.
The trials are sacred.
They are the will of God!
Is she alive?
I'm sorry.
-(SOBBING)
-BECKA: Now we have
no way of knowing
if Mother Twiston was a witch or not.
Guards, whip these wanderers
off this bank
and then seize Willa Twiston.
We can take no chances.
Leave her alone.
I'd bet my life neither of these women
are witches.
But you, Mistress Savage,
are without question, a murderer!
Who are you to address me this way?
I'll tell you who I am.
Huh?
Oh, sorry, one sec.
Witchfinder General?
That's right, Witchfinder General,
with my crack team,
taking over this village.
Right, gang?
Yeah, 'cause you
are in Special Measures.
DOCTOR: Now do you recognise
our authority?
I do beg your pardon,
Mistress Witchfinder.
Please come to my home.
We must talk in private.
If you swear not to hurt that girl
or anyone else.
If that is your wish,
you have the command.
DOCTOR: Everybody go home.
-This trial is over.
-(SOBS GENTLY)
I have to bury her.
(BIRD SQUAWKS)
BECKA: Please forgive me, Mistress.
If I'd have known who you were,
I'd have bowed
to your authority immediately.
So tell me, who exactly are you?
And what gives you authority here?
I am Becka Savage,
landowner of Bilehurst Cragg.
It belonged to my late husband.
Passed to me when he died.
I have tried to be a benevolent leader,
but it's very difficult in these times,
especially for a woman.
If you're the landowner,
why are you walking?
Where are the horses?
Horses are banned in Bilehurst.
They are creatures of Satan.
I had them all shot.
Hey, Doc.
I've done the old
Pendle Witches Walking Trail,
nobody ever mentioned Bilehurst Cragg.
Never heard of it,
and she's killed 35 people.
-Thirty-six, now.
-Yeah.
Maybe she wipes this whole place
off the map?
We're going to find out what happened.
And how we can make her stop.
And that hall looks like
the best place to start.
YASMIN: Not the only place.
I'm gonna find that girl
who's just lost her gran.
We'll deal with Her Ladyship,
if you go do some family liaison.
I'll meet you in a bit.
Hopefully by then I'll be a bit dry.
BECKA: I hope the fire has warmed you.
-Some wine?
-No.
So, your witch trials have become
a weekly event
with a village celebration.
Any moment where a witch is uncovered
and Satan driven out
has to be cause for a celebration.
We will not stop
until that work is done.
You keep saying "Satan", but how
is Satan manifesting himself here?
Blighting the crops. Bewitching animals.
Plaguing people with fits,
sickness, and visions.
If all that's Satan,
where do the witches come in to it?
They're in league with him.
Kill the witches, defeat Satan.
As King James has written
in his new Bible,
"Thou shalt not suffer a witch to live."
In the Old Testament.
There's a twist in the sequel, "Love
thy neighbour”, which is why we've come.
To help you fix your problems
without killing anyone.
That's what King James would want.
(GASPS)
BECKA: What is the meaning of this?
Madam, I have come to your rescue.
King James. (GASPS)
-(GASPS)
-Your Majesty.
KING JAMES: You may
prostrate yourselves before me,
God's chosen ruler
and Satan's greatest foe,
come to vanquish the scourge
of witchcraft across the land.
Forgive the mask, I have enemies
everywhere and have to travel incognito.
Also, I rather like the drama.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
-(DOOR OPENS)
-A peculiar rag-bag of folks.
And those garments... Are you actors?
We are
witchfinders, Sire,
as we explained to Mistress Savage.
Witchfinder's assistant?
So you must be the Witchfinder General?
-(GROANS)
-No, she said she was.
(SCOFFING) A woman could never
be the general!
(CHUCKLES HALF-HEARTEDLY)
Silly me, must have got all confused.
-Mmm.
-DOCTOR: Mustn't I, boss?
Er, yeah, that's me, Sire.
Er, Northwest Division,
promoted from Essex.
And these are your underlings?
It's a very flat team structure.
We all have our area of expertise.
Even the wee lassie?
Even me. Very handy under cover.
Set a woman to catch a woman.
A cunning ruse using your innate
aptitude for nosiness and gossip.
(GROANS)
And what is your field of expertise,
my Nubian prince?
Er...
Torture?
-Me?
-KING JAMES: Yeah.
Er...
Paperwork, mostly, Your Majesty.
Paper? How fascinating!
We should talk.
But first, madam, word has reached
me of your battle against Satan,
your crusade against witchcraft.
But what I saw today convinced me
you need assistance.
That's what we've just been saying.
Hold your tongue, lassie.
Stick to snooping and leave the strategy
to your king.
This is no time for the weak.
Satan preys on the innocent,
even while they sleep.
Together, we must purify your land,
starting with the grandchild
of the witch you tried today.
A fine plan, is it not?
-(GASPING)
-A genius plan, Your Majesty.
-Oh.
-Together we shall save the souls
of my people from Satan,
even if it means killing them all.
(GASPS)
(WILLA SNIFFLES)
WILLA: I will still be with you.
In the water.
In the fire.
In the earth.
In the air.
Willa!
(GASPING)
Get away from her!
(YASMIN GRUNTS)
-Are you all right?
-What was that?
I don't know.
But I want to help.
You can't. Nobody can.
Wait, Willa!
Becka wasn't kidding.
These are hard times for women.
If we're not being drowned,
we're being patronised to death.
(GASPS)
-(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
-Becka's bedroom. In here, quick.
We are gonna
help them though, right, Doc?
I mean, otherwise this place
won't exist by the morning.
Not now those two have hit it off,
I don't know which one's more barking.
A dozen hankies. That's a lot.
Maybe she cries herself to sleep.
Maybe. Don't worry, Graham,
I'm staying here and sorting it,
even if I am just a woman.
Well, to be fair to King James,
you are snooping.
I'm investigating!
-Hey, missed a bit.
-(SNIFFS)
Whoa.
This Becka's seriously paranoid, man.
-(ALL GASP)
-Here you are!
I've been creeping around this place
looking for you.
I found that girl Willa at her granny's
grave, doing some kind of ritual,
and the next thing I know,
this big, kind of, mud tendril thing
attacked her!
-"Mud tendril"?
-Coming up out of the ground.
I had to smash it to pieces.
Got it all over me.
Just the one mud tendril? How big?
Oh, and when you say "ritual”,
do you mean like a spell?
-Like she conjured it up?
-She was scared of it.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Whatever it was, it wasn't friendly.
-(BLEEPING)
-Just seems to be like
good old-fashioned Lancashire mud.
Here's the plan. You and me need
to check out that mud and talk to Willa.
You two, stick with Becka
and King James,
keep them here.
Make sure they don't kill anyone else.
-King James?
-It's a long story.
I'll explain on the way.
Remember, no more witch hunts.
KING JAMES: This is Alfonso,
my personal guardian.
He guards my witch-finding tools
with his life.
Time is against us
if we are to get to the village
and hunt down the witches
from their hiding.
No!
(CHUCKLES) No, we're fine.
I bet you have all the best kit,
Your Majesty.
I have a great many artefacts.
Torture implements, charms,
and a wide selection of body parts.
Oh.
Here.
Belonged to my first
Witchfinder General.
-Oh.
-KING JAMES: Scottie,
who saved my life in Berwick,
then later betrayed me,
so I had him shot.
I'm sure you will serve me better.
You may wear the hat.
(CHUCKLES)
You can trust me, Sire.
I can trust no one.
That is why I need all these.
Mmm.
To ward off evil spirits.
I'll be keeping an eye on you.
(CHUCKLING EXCITEDLY)
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY) What's this?
Careful, it's my pricker.
Essential for inspections.
A true witch will not bleed
if her mark is pricked.
Madam, do you have one of these?
-No, Sire.
-Hmm.
You may use this. It's my spare.
GRAHAM: (WHISPERING) Ryan, do something.
Oh, erm, there's still some
really, really fascinating
body parts in here
that you could tell us about.
(MOUTHING)
-Yes, perhaps later. (CHUCKLES)
-Mmm.
Oh, but also, before we depart,
we should make a list
of all the villagers.
-Mmm.
-And names of suspects,
background info.
It's all in the preparation.
Well, there is no need.
I know everything about this place
and my people.
And I know everything about Satan.
Together, we will find where he's hiding
and cut him out.
By nightfall,
every last witch in this village
shall be destroyed.
YASMIN: Willa.
My name's Yaz. This is the Doctor.
Where are you going?
As far away from here as I can.
Don't blame you.
But before you do,
can we talk to you first?
We're not witchfinders,
we just want to find out
exactly what's going on here
and maybe we can fix things.
Can you help us, Willa?
Because we want to help you.
(GASPS)
Wow! Are these all yours?
They were my grandmother's.
She made medicines to help people.
She wasn't a witch.
Everyone knows that.
So why did Becka Savage target her?
Maybe she was ashamed
of the woman who brought her up.
Wait, you and Becka are family?
Cousins.
We were all close,
until Becka married up.
(INHALES SHARPLY) Left us all behind.
Still, thought it'd be safe
when the witch-hunt started.
And then it just got worse and worse,
everyone turned on each other.
Granny said it was only a matter of time
before they turned on us.
I didn't believe her.
GRAHAM: Oi, oi, hold up.
What's the rush?
I want this over
so we can return to the way things were
before Satan infested this land.
Excuse me, when you say "Satan”,
what exactly do you mean?
Satan is all around us, all of the time.
We must be strong
or else he will take us.
Of that, I have no doubt.
Really, no doubt?
What if you're wrong?
Because you're killing
all these people, friends, neighbours.
If people are good,
they have nothing to fear.
Are you a good person, Mistress Savage?
My conscience is clean.
WILLA: Here.
Granny's special tea.
It soothes the soul.
Unless you think I'm a witch.
Are you not having any?
I feel too sick.
Do you mind if I check you over?
Don't worry, I am a doctor.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-What's that?
Er, specialist equipment.
That movement in the mud,
it was Satan, wasn't it?
-Doubt it.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Not a big believer in Satan.
My granny used to say
there was enough wonder in nature
-without making things up.
-(BLEEPING)
I like your granny.
Completely normal.
No magic, and no signs of any sickness.
You're wrong.
I think I know what it is
that's making you sick.
I had it at my school where I'm from.
When Izzy Flint
turned the whole class against me.
Every day I'd wake up feeling this...
Dread.
Fear.
-How did you get rid of it?
-YASMIN: I didn't.
I just took it. Had the year from hell.
When I say "hell", I don't literally
mean hell. I mean it was really awful.
And I told myself when I got bigger,
I'd stand up to the Izzy Flints
of this world.
I can't stand up to Becka.
She'll have me tried for a witch.
(SOFTLY) What am I meant to do?
Seems to me like you have two choices.
Run as far away from here as possible,
or stick with us.
We'll stand up to Becka Savage
and we'll make this place safe again.
How would we do that?
Ah! "We", that's good, Willa!
See? Feels better already.
Now, first things first,
I need to get a sample of that mud.
Oh, can I use this?
Oh, yeah.
Want to come with us?
Not really.
Look at him, Alfonso's loyalty
is rare and pure,
it's only a matter of time
before I inevitably get let down.
Why do you find it so hard
to trust people?
Mmm.
It's a long, sad story.
A tragedy. (LAUGHS)
I've got time. Tell me.
My father died when I was a baby.
I feel you.
I lost me mum and me nan.
My father was murdered by my mother,
who was then imprisoned and beheaded.
Okay, that's worse. Yeah.
I was raised by regents.
One was assassinated, one died in battle
and another died
in suspicious circumstances.
There have been numerous attempts
to kidnap me, kill me, or blow me up.
It's a miracle I'm still alive.
(LAUGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT) You're not kidding.
No, I'm not.
It is a miracle that I have prevailed
whilst all around me, others fall.
You should definitely get yourself
back to London, Sire.
Keep yourself safe.
God will keep me safe
as long as I do his work.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES) Ooh!
That felt good.
(JAMES CHUCKLES)
Thank you.
And now we can have some fun.
Eh, Ryan?
Just mud.
No sign of any tendency to tendril.
Shouldn't be disappointed,
but I am a bit.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
What was that ritual you were doing
before the tendril arrived?
A prayer
to help my grandmother rest in peace.
I brought her body here,
I dug that grave and placed her in it.
But I didn't get to finish the prayer.
-You can finish it now if you like.
-Yes.
DOCTOR: Right, little sample.
What aren't you telling me?
Whoa! I am no longer disappointed.
See? The mud is alive!
But now I'm not sure it's mud at all.
YASMIN: It looks pretty angry in there.
-WILLA: Yaz?
-Obviously doesn't like
being trapped, do you? What are you?
Give us a clue.
What's happening?
I think this is some kind
of alien matter.
But I'm not sure if it's sentient.
Doctor,
-park that, please.
-Why?
Granny!
-That is not your granny, Willa.
-Yes, it is.
No, that's the not-mud.
(PANTING) Some sort of alien matter
filling her body
and reanimating it.
So, it is pretty sentient.
I'm so sorry for this, Willa.
Hi, not-Willa's-granny.
I presume you're just using the body
to give whatever you are, form.
Better than tendrils, right?
But really not right.
Not cool.
Is that why it went after Willa?
Of course.
Not to kill her, but to fill her.
Ooh, check out my rhymes.
Poetry under pressure.
Oh.
-(GURGLING)
-What are you doing?
You want this?
-One of you, is it? Or part of you?
-(GRUNTS)
Oh, no, no, no! Not until you tell me
what's going on here.
(GROANS IN DISGUST)
I don't like the look of your hands.
It's all bubbling away inside you,
isn't it?
-(GURGLING)
-Oh, no! You're not filling me!
If you're that desperate for it, here.
Have it.
(SLURPING AND MOANING)
Delightful.
Down the hatch.
I've got so many questions
right now, like,
did you drink that or absorb it?
Are you all one big muddy mass,
or separate entities
only taking the one body?
Doctor?
DOCTOR: Oh.
Always good to get fast answers.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
What was that?
I cannot imagine.
Erm, best let us deal with that, Sire.
You should stay here
where it's safe, Sire.
Nowhere is safe
until Satan has been vanquished.
GRAHAM: Oh, did it come
from that way, Sire?
I thought it came from the other way.
-DOCTOR: No! Stay back, please!
-Come on.
I've given you the blob,
what more do you need?
It's so annoying when they're silent.
KING JAMES: Witchcraft!
So much for keeping
that lot at the house.
KING JAMES: Stay where you are!
-Hi, Sire! I know it looks bad.
-Uh...
But don't worry, I'm all over it.
Willa Twiston was the witch all along!
-I knew it!
-I'm not. This isn't me, Becka! I swear!
She's right.
It's not her and it's not witchcraft.
-I'm working it out.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
KING JAMES: This is beyond you!
-Alfonso, shoot them!
-Of course, Your Majesty.
No, Alfonso, don't.
In the air and in the earth!
-(YELPS)
-(ALL GASP)
KING JAMES: Alfonso.
Now you've made them angry.
They're getting stronger.
Everybody out of here.
-(WHIMPERS)
-YASMIN: Get away from them now!
BECKA: We must protect you, Sire.
Back through the forest.
DOCTOR: Keep running.
This clearing, through here.
(JAMES WHIMPERS)
I don't think they're following.
(PANTING) If they're not following,
what are they doing?
Want us to go and look?
We escaped from Satan and you wish
to go directly back into battle?
We need to know what they're up to.
Make sure no one else is in danger.
I'll go too and keep an eye
on my underlings.
-Very well.
-DOCTOR: I'll stay with Willa.
Be careful!
What were those aberrations?
-It is the work of Satan!
-It wasn't Satan.
Or witches, or Willa's granny.
Those creatures were being controlled
by something in the mud.
Something not of this Earth.
Something beyond your understanding.
Something from hell?
More like from the heavens.
It chose to kill Alfonso
when he was a threat.
But in other circumstances, it fills
the bodies and uses them as vessels.
I don't know why.
Maybe only when they're dead.
No. It attacked me, too.
DOCTOR: And why today?
Because this is my problem.
I can buy that this is the biggest ever
witch-hunt in England,
or I can buy it's an alien mud invasion.
But both on the same day?
I can't buy that!
Why does the lassie speak of commerce?
-DOCTOR: Oh, wait.
-I don't know.
Unless they're connected.
Your witch-hunt's
been going on a while now.
So there's no way that mud
has just rocked up today.
What do you know, Becka?
What's going on here in Bilehurst Cragg?
A woman who keeps an axe by her bed.
What have you seen?
I have seen you with your wand,
raising your kin from the dead.
-Yes.
-What? No.
-Hold on a sec.
-You're no witchfinder's assistant.
-You are Satan's acolyte!
-DOCTOR: I am not.
That's why it's happening today,
because you are here.
As you say, to take over this village.
You know that's not what I meant.
-We do not have time for this.
-(BLADE CLICKS)
Mistress Savage is correct.
It is your fault that Alfonso is dead.
-I tried to save him.
-Save them
from being shot?
You said this evil fell from heavens.
Oh yes, it fell,
like your lord, Lucifer!
Honestly, if I was still a bloke,
I could get on with the job and not
have to waste time defending myself.
Oh, you bewitch us
with your alluring form
and your incessant jabber,
but I knew you were unnatural
from the very start.
And now I see you
for what you really are.
She was trying to save us, Sire.
Thank you, Willa.
BECKA: Are you sure
you're not mistaken, Willa?
Or are you in league
with the witches as I first suspected?
She said she wanted to help me.
Who do you trust to save you?
Your king? Your family?
Whatever I have done,
I did to save all of our souls.
What's really going on, Becka?
Hold your tongue or I will cut it out.
Well?
Tell the truth, lassie.
I did think it was strange when
they said her name was "the Doctor".
Like Dr D, a necromancer.
That seals it.
Arrest the witch!
I...I am not a witch!
GRAHAM: Which way
do you reckon they went?
Hey, guys, over here.
There you go.
Holly berries.
No holly tree.
YASMIN: There's more this way.
They can't be that far ahead.
Come on.
KING JAMES: Comfortable, witch?
I do hope not.
Come for a visit?
I shall take my opportunity
to converse with an agent of Satan.
If I was Satan's agent, do you seriously
think a bit of rope would stop me?
I say a bit, quite a lot.
Tightly bound.
It's pretty painful.
You know how to tie a knot
in this part of the world.
I am an expert on witchcraft, Doctor.
But I wish to learn more.
Before you die, I want answers.
Your wand, how does it work?
Why do you want to know?
I wish to know all the secrets
of existence.
DOCTOR: Don't we all?
But true knowledge has to be earned.
I tell you what,
I'll trade you my wand for answers
to as many questions you want to ask.
(SCOFFS)
I'm not a fool, Doctor.
-I am King James, Satan's greatest foe.
-DOCTOR: Yeah, yeah. I know.
It must be comforting,
playing that role.
Hiding behind a title.
Just as you hide behind
"Doctor”, perhaps.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
You should take up witch finding
for a living.
Yeah.
Shame I missed the training session
on what to do when you found them.
RYAN: I guess we have to follow them
very quietly.
Okay.
Who are you, really?
Behind the mask?
The drama?
What does it say on your garter?
"Honi soit gqui mal y pense.”
"Evil be to him that evil thinks."
You wear it like a hero,
even though you're killing
and scapegoating,
and stirring up hate.
And you wonder why the darkness
comes back at you.
There's no darkness in me.
I quest for goodness and knowledge,
beauty and art, all of God's virtues.
Your own mother was scapegoated.
How do you square that
with your witch-hunts?
What do you know of my mother?
You could have seen her before she died,
but you didn't want to, why?
She left me
when I was not even one year old.
What kind of mother does that?
Why would I wish to see her?
Nobody will ever know
why she left you, James.
But you can't go hurting people
just because you're scared
to face up to the darkness inside you.
You have to be better than that.
Who are you?
How do you know these things?
I know because
we are all the same.
We want certainty, security.
To believe that people are evil
or heroic.
But that's not how people are.
You want to know
the secrets of existence?
Start with the mysteries of the heart.
I can show you everything
if you stop being afraid
of what you don't understand.
If you trust me.
I am not a witch.
But if you want to defeat evil,
you have to let me go. Now.
Please, Sire.
(DOCTOR BREATHING HEAVILY)
I do not know what you are,
and there is only one way to be certain.
Guards, summon the villagers!
RYAN: All the way through the forest
and back where we started.
GRAHAM: Keep your voice down.
YASMIN: What would they come here for?
(LIQUID BUBBLING)
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
That's Becka's bedroom.
They're looking for her.
Revenge, that's why the undead
always come back.
Must be why Becka has the axe.
(AXE CLANKING)
GRAHAM: Speaking of which.
In here.
RYAN: Where are they going now?
-(HAND BELL RINGING)
-DOCTOR: I see you've
brought a gathering.
Thanks very much.
Mind if I take off my coat?
Lots in my pockets.
Might stop me floating.
Of course, as a woman, you don't get
to have pockets for a while yet.
A girl called Izzy Flint
bullied my friend Yaz
so no one would pick on Izzy.
That's what you're doing.
Pointing the finger at other people
so no one points it at you.
But what I don't know is, why?
What are you hiding, Becka?
Sit down.
Or would you prefer a hanging?
(CHAINS RATTLING)
Do you know why the ducking stool
was invented, Doctor?
To silence foolish women
who talk too much.
Yeah, I did know that, which is daft,
because talking's brilliant.
Like, if you'd talk to me now,
I can help.
You've ducked 36 people already.
And whatever it is has only got worse,
hasn't it?
(CRACKLES)
What was that?
It reacted to your touch, why?
I warned you to keep quiet.
-Rather I ask Willa?
-Silence!
Or I shall duck her, too.
Last request.
I definitely get a last request.
(CHAINS CLINK)
Lend us your hanky.
I don't have one.
There's loads in your room.
And an empty medicine bottle.
What were you taking
the medicine for, Becka?
Know this, Doctor,
once I have dealt with you,
I shall go after all of your friends.
RYAN: Quiet a sec.
(HAND BELL RINGING IN DISTANCE)
Listen.
That was coming from the river.
Someone must be getting ducked.
The Doctor wouldn't let that happen.
-Oh.
-Unless...
-Yeah.
-BECKA: Satan has made
our crops fail, bewitched our animals,
and brought the sickness.
His agent sits before you.
The most evil witch in Christendom.
And she would call herself "the Doctor".
(VILLAGERS JEERING)
We bring her to justice
in front of our great Majesty,
King James.
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-Give the word, Sire,
and we shall duck the witch
and save our souls from Satan
once and for all.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-Duck the witch.
-MAN: Duck her!
(VILLAGERS CLAMOURING)
I was right.
-Doctor!
-BECKA: Guards, duck her now.
-Bring her back up now.
-RYAN: What have you done?
You will see the result.
I'm the Witchfinder General,
I'm giving you an order.
I obey only my king.
Sire, please order her to be raised.
She's not a witch, she's your only hope
of getting out of here alive.
BECKA: They're witches, Sire.
All of them. It's Satan testing us.
YASMIN: Get her out of there.
It has been long enough.
No, it hasn't. We must be certain.
Bring her up, now.
Now!
RYAN: Please, Your Majesty.
Raise the stool. The trial is over.
RYAN: Where has she gone?
What's happened to her?
No.
No!
YASMIN: Where is she?
-Looking for me?
-YASMIN: Doctor!
She truly is a powerful witch.
No, Sire, I am no witch.
I'm just good at holding my breath
and getting out of chains
thanks to a very wet weekend
with Houdini.
Hi, team.
Gang. Fam!
-No.
-WILLA: I'm so sorry, Doctor.
I was scared.
See?
That's all it takes, Becka.
Start there.
Tell me the truth.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
She survived, she is a witch!
No, I'm not.
-And despite all appearances...
-WILLA: Doctor!
...neither are they.
You might want to come and stand
with me now, Becka,
'cause they look like
they've come for you.
(VILLAGERS SCREAMING)
(MUTTERING)
RYAN: We have to help out.
Yes. Yes, we must confront those agents
of Satan even in the face
of witchery and...
Oh, mate, seriously? Not witches.
Bodies, possessed by alien mud.
Come on!
I will be with you.
In the water.
In the fire.
In the air.
Stop, just stop.
They're obeying you.
Why are they obeying you?
What happened, Becka?
I thought they'd come to kill you.
Which is a fair assumption
given they're carrying an axe.
But they haven't, have they?
Of course, they've come to join you.
(COUGHING AND GASPING)
It's in you, just as it's in them.
And none of you can hide it any more.
In the earth.
What happened?
I cut down her favourite tree.
(SNARLS)
What? I don't understand.
BECKA: It was spoiling
my view of the hill.
(GRUNTING)
But something lay beneath it.
I awoke hell
Satan himself attacked me,
poisoned me.
That night, I felt it growing inside me.
The mark of Satan.
I fought it.
I took medicine, I prayed.
But it grew. I did God's work
in the hope that he would save me.
You killed people
to try and save yourself.
All these witches? All this evil?
You knew they weren't witches.
The only thing you feared was yourself.
Did your granny know
what you needed the medicine for?
Not to start with,
but then I had to tell her.
I needed her help. I begged for it.
For her to lance this evil out of me!
(SOBBING)
But she was too weak.
So you killed her by ducking?
I had to, she knew!
-(MUD FLOWING)
-(GROANING)
I can't fight it any more, Doctor.
You cannot fight it
because you are the witch.
I have let Satan in.
I have failed you, Sire.
Yes, I am the witch!
Everyone, behind me.
-It's Becka they want.
-RYAN: But why?
WILLA: What's happening to her?
I tried to hold Satan back.
I'm so scared.
Please forgive me!
(GASPS)
(DEMONIC SCREAMING)
What is happening?
She's possessed by Satan.
Not by Satan.
Then by what?
Something not of this Earth.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
Morax.
Who are you?
Hand me your king.
-What?
-Haven't you got your own king?
-Or is he hiding?
-He does not hide.
He waits.
We have all waited for too long,
trapped in the hill.
-Pendle Hill.
-MORAX: Our prison.
The mighty Morax army,
captured and imprisoned
on this pitiful planet
for war crimes.
Pendle Hill is a prison
for an alien army!
Oh, well, it's obvious
when you put it like that.
Imprisoned no more. The lock was broken.
What lock? How was it broken?
Now, the Morax army shall rise again
and take form.
Your king shall be filled with our king,
and we shall be free to fill all of you.
To fill this whole planet with rage
and force, and hate,
and Morax!
YASMIN: Come on, Witchfinder.
Up you get.
Go on, what happened?
YASMIN: Same thing happened
to all of us.
Oh, ow.
Zapped by Becka Savage,
queen of the Morax.
-(GROANING)
-She's taken the king,
-knocked the rest of us out.
-(GROANS) Okay.
DOCTOR: Quite a blast, that.
Haven't had a hangover like this
since the Milk Wars of Keston Five.
What are you doing with this thing?
Tell them what "Bilehurst" means.
Sacred tree on a hill.
The tree Becka chopped down
because it was obscuring her view,
the tree this ducking stool
is made from,
the tree that isn't a tree...
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-...is ancient alien technology.
Beautiful and broken.
A very old, very advanced,
biomech security system.
A lock to keep the Morax army
imprisoned here.
It responded to Becka's touch because
of the Morax infection inside her.
So, Pendle Hill was a prison?
From what Becka said,
I'm guessing the Morax
are royals with soldiers,
pretty brutal ones at that.
Presumably exiled for war crimes,
scrambled down into their primal form...
And they stay in prison
until Becka Savage goes at that tree.
Well, it can't be much of a lock
if she can break it.
It's old. Eroded over billions
of years, presumably.
But she must have broke it enough
for part of the queen's form
to escape and infect her.
According to my calculations,
this ancient alien wood
is like Semtex to Morax.
That's why it made such a good lock.
Right, help me break it up.
Break it up? Why, what for?
(WOOD CRACKING)
Anti-Morax weapons.
The smoke is toxic to Morax.
Should be enough to fend them off
so you can rescue King James
and I can get to the tree.
Then what?
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-I fix the lock,
putting all the Morax energy
back in the slammer.
GRAHAM: One more thing, Doc.
Moraxfinder General back in command.
It's a very flat team structure.
Ready for battle?
Yes, we are.
You don't have to, Willa.
It's time to stop being scared.
Little bit of scared isn't a bad thing.
Morax is way more dangerous
than Becka ever was.
Only I know the path up the hill.
So you need me to lead the way.
She's right, Doc.
There are more powerful people here
than kings and queens.
There's us.
Together.
Lead on, Willa Twiston.
Onwards, to save the king.
MORAX: Kneel before Morax, feeble human.
Tell me what you are,
you Satanic creature.
-We will rule this world.
-KING JAMES: "We"?
Your body filled with my Morax king.
Come to me, my love.
(GASPS)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
KING JAMES: Satan rises.
(JAMES GROANS)
(JAMES SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
I may fear you, but I have my faith.
(ROARS)
May the Lord save me!
DOCTOR: Or, alternatively,
Witchfinders United at your service.
Yeah, mate, you better back off.
Let him go, Morax.
You can't have King James
or this planet.
RYAN: Get away from the king.
(GRUNTING)
The torches are working.
He won't come near the flames.
RYAN: I've got you, Sire.
KING JAMES: My protector!
Willa, watch out for your granny.
-(SNARLS)
-You're not my granny.
Let her rest!
And you, Morax, back into your cell.
Now, please.
Those flames don't scare me, Doctor.
Nothing scares me now!
WILLA: I know you're in there, Becka.
I know you're scared.
Nothing of that pathetic woman remains.
No fear, only power.
We will fill your king and kill you all!
Afraid not, Morax. I'm here.
(MORAX SCREAMS)
-DOCTOR: Everybody back!
- (EXCLAIMING)
DOCTOR: I've reactivated the prison.
Back you go, King of the Morax!
(ROARING)
DOCTOR: Jail re-energised.
MORAX: No!
What have you done?
Feel that security system
kicking back in,
sucking every Morax cell back.
Back down into Pendle Hill.
Back out of the bodies they hijacked.
Have peace.
MORAX: No!
I will not go!
Yes, you will.
-Burn the witch!
-DOCTOR: No, Sire, stay away!
(SCREAMING)
(ALL PANTING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
What, woman?
She was a witch. She confessed.
-So you got what you came for.
-I have vanquished Satan.
No more witch-hunts.
She still does not speak to me, Ryan.
Can you get through to her?
Afraid not, Sire. This is on you.
What apparition is this?
Just another inexplicable
wonder of existence
you're not going to be able
to tell anyone about.
Doctor, I understand
you are displeased with me.
And I owe my life to you.
Not one word of any of this
shall ever be spoken.
And even the name "Bilehurst"
shall be erased
from all records.
As long as all the villagers
make it out alive.
What will you do, Willa?
Find a new home?
Take Granny's potions and be a healer.
Be a doctor.
I reckon you'll be good at that.
One final command,
as your king.
Come back to London with me, Ryan.
Be my protector.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY) I mean,
it's a kind offer, Sire,
but, er, you know,
I've got stuff to do.
But I'll keep me eye on you.
So you behave yourself. (CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
Or else...
-(TARDIS DOOR OPENS)
-...we will strike down upon thee
with great vengeance and furious anger.
Ezekiel.
Tarantino.
Wh... What are you all doing?
A brilliant man once said,
"Any sufficiently advanced technology
is indistinguishable from magic.”
We're just about to prove him right.
(TARDIS DOOR CLOSES)
(WHOOSHING)
Where did they go?
(LAUGHS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: A cottage in Norway in winter,
with a chimney but no smoke.
MAN'S VOICE: Such tragedy
makes me
hungry.