Well, there we go, universal roaming.
Never have to worry
about a signal again.
No way. This is too mad.
You're telling me I can phone anyone
anywhere in space and time on my mobile?
As long as you know the area code.
Frequent flyers' privilege.
Go on, try it.
(ALARM BLARING)
Distress signal. Clocking off.
Might be a bit of...
turbulence. Sorry.
Come on, Martha, let's take a look.
COMPUTER:
Automated distress signal transmitted.
Now, that is hot.
COMPUTER:
Automated distress signal transmitted.
It's like a sauna in here.
Venting systems working at full pelt,
trying to cool down
wherever it is we are.
Well, if you can't stand the heat...
-That's better.
-SCANNELL: Oi, you two!
-Get out of there!
-Seal that door now!
Who are you?
What are you doing on my ship?
-Are you police?
-Why would we be police?
We got your distress signal.
If this is a ship,
why can't I hear any engines?
It went dead four minutes ago.
So maybe we should stop chatting
and get to Engineering, Captain.
(ALARM BLARING)
COMPUTER: Secure closure active.
-What?
-The ship's gone mad.
Who activated secure closure?
I nearly got locked into area 27.
-Who are you?
-He's the Doctor and I'm Martha. Hello.
COMPUTER: Impact projection,
42 minutes, 27 seconds.
We'll get out of this, I promise.
-Doctor.
-Forty two minutes until what?
Doctor!
Look!
KATH: Forty two minutes
until we crash into the sun.
-How many crew members on board?
-Seven, including us.
We transfer cargo across the galaxy.
Everything's automated.
-We just keep the ship...
-Call the others. I'll get you out!
-What's he doing?
-Doctor, don't!
-But my ship's in there!
-In the vent chamber?
-It's our lifeboat.
-It's lava.
Temperature's going mad in there.
Up 3,000 degrees in 10 seconds
-and still rising.
-Channelling the air.
The closer we get to the sun,
the hotter that room's gonna get.
-We're stuck here.
-So we fix the engines.
We steer the ship away from the sun.
Simple. Engineering down here, is it?
-Yes.
-COMPUTER: Impact in 40:26.
Blimey. Do you always
leave things in such a mess?
-Oh, my God.
-The hell happened?
Oh, it's wrecked.
Pretty efficiently, too.
Someone knew what they were doing.
Where's Korwin?
Has anyone heard from him or Ashton?
No.
MARTHA: Do you mean
someone did this on purpose?
Korwin, Ashton, where are you?
Korwin, can you answer?
Where the hell is he?
He should be up here.
Oh, we're in the Toragy system. Lovely.
You're a long way from home,
Martha, half a universe away.
Yeah, feels it.
And you're still using energy scoops for
fusion. Hasn't that been outlawed yet?
We're due to upgrade next docking.
Scan all engine reports.
(BEEPING)
-No response.
-What?
They're burnt out.
The controls are wrecked.
I can't get them back online.
Oh, come on, auxiliary engines.
Every craft's got auxiliaries.
KATH: We don't have access from here.
The auxiliary controls
are in the front of the ship.
There are 29 password-sealed doors
between us and them.
-You'll never get there on time.
-Can't you override the doors?
No, sealed closure means what it says.
They're all deadlock sealed.
So a sonic screwdriver's no use.
Nothing's any use. We've got no engines,
no time and no chance.
Oh, listen to you!
Defeated before you even started.
Where's your Dunkirk spirit?
Who's got the door passwords?
They're randomly generated.
Reckon I'd know most of them.
Sorry. Riley Vashtee.
Then what are you waiting for,
Riley Vashtee? Get on it.
Well, it's a two-person job.
One to take this for the questions.
The other to carry this.
The oldest and cheapest security system
around, eh, Captain?
Reliable and simple.
Just like you, eh, Riley?
-Try to be helpful, get abuse. Nice.
-I'll help you. Make myself useful.
It's remotely controlled
by the computer panel.
-That's why it needs two.
-Oi, be careful.
You, too.
(OVER PA) McDonnell, it's Ashton.
-Where are you? Is Korwin with you?
-Get up to the med centre now.
COMPUTER: Impact in 34:31.
-I've got to stop it!
-Korwin, it's Abi.
Open your eyes.
I need to take a look at you.
Korwin! What's happened? Is he okay?
Help! Help me! It's burning me!
-How long's he been like this?
-Ashton just brought him in.
-What are you doing to him?
-Don't get too close.
-Don't be stupid. He's my husband.
-And he's just sabotaged our ship.
-What?
-He went mad.
He put the ship under secure closure.
Then he sent a heat pulse
to melt the control.
-No way! He wouldn't do that.
-I saw it happen, Captain.
Korwin?
Korwin, open your eyes for me a second.
-I can't.
-Yeah, of course you can. Go on.
Don't make me look at you. Please.
All right, all right,
all right, just relax. Sedative.
What's wrong with him?
Rising body temperature,
unusual energy readings.
Stasis chamber.
I do love a good stasis chamber.
Keep him sedated in there.
Regulate the body temperature.
And just for fun, run a bio-scan,
a tissue profile and a metabolic detail.
Just doing them now.
Oh, you're good.
Anyone else presenting these symptoms?
-Not so far.
-Well, that's something.
Will someone tell me
what is the matter with him?
Some sort of infection.
We'll know more after the test results.
Now, allons-y! Back downstairs, eh?
See about those engines. Go.
Hey! Go.
Call us if there's news. Any questions?
-Yeah. Who are you?
-I'm the Doctor.
COMPUTER: Heat shield failing at 25%.
Impact in 32:50.
-Hurry up, will you?
-All right. Fix the clamp on.
What are you typing?
These doors' trip code is the answer
to a random question set by the crew.
Nine tours back,
we got drunk, thought them up.
Reckoning was, if we're hijacked, we're
the only ones who know all the answers.
-So you type in the right answer...
-This sends a remote pulse to the clamp.
But we only get one chance per door.
Get it wrong, the whole system freezes.
-Better not get it wrong, then.
-Okay.
"Date of SS Pentallian's first flight?"
That's all right. Go!
-Yes!
-Twenty eight more to go!
(MARTHA LAUGHING)
Abi, how's Korwin doing?
Any results from the bio-scan?
He's under heavy sedation.
I'm just trying
to make sense of this data.
Give me a couple of minutes
and I'll let you know.
-Martha, Riley, how are you doing?
-Area 29, at the door to 28.
-Yeah, you've got to move faster.
-We're doing our best.
"Find the next number in the sequence:
313, 331, 367."
-What?
-You said the crew knew all the answers.
The crew's changed
since we set the questions.
-You're joking.
-379.
-MARTHA: What?
-It's a sequence of happy primes. 379.
-Happy what?
-Just enter it.
Are you sure? We only get one chance.
Any number that reduces to one
when you take the sum of the square
of its digits and continue iterating
until it yields one is a happy number.
Any number that doesn't, isn't.
A happy prime is a number
that's both happy and prime.
Now type it in!
I don't know. Talk about dumbing down.
Don't they teach
recreational mathematics any more?
(BEEPING)
-We're through!
-DOCTOR: Keep moving fast as you can.
And, Martha, be careful. There may be
something else onboard the ship.
Any time you want to unnerve me,
feel free.
Will do, thanks.
COMPUTER: Impact inn 30-50.
I can't believe our lives depend
on some stupid pub quiz.
-Is that the next one?
-Oh, this is a nightmare.
"Classical music, who had the most
pre-download number ones,
"Elvis Presley or The Bee-atles?"
How are we supposed to know that?
We need a backup in case they don't
reach the auxiliary engine in time.
Come on, think.
Resources. What have we got?
-MARTHA: Doctor?
-What is it now?
Who had the most number ones,
Elvis or The Beatles?
-That's pre-download.
-Elvis.
No, The Beatles! No, wait...
Oh, what was that remix?
-I don't know. I am a bit busy.
-Fine. I'll ask someone else.
Now, where was I?
Here Comes the Sun. No, resources.
So, the power's still working.
The generator's going.
If we can harness that... Ah!
Use the generator to jump start the ship.
Exactly. At the very least,
it will buy some more time.
-That is brilliant.
-I know. See?
-Tiny glimmer of hope.
-If it works.
Oh, believe me,
you're gonna make it work.
That told him.
COMPUTER: Impact in 29:46.
(MOBILE RINGING)
-Hello?
-Mum, it's me. It's Martha. Wow!
Where are you? Don't you check
your messages? I've been calling you.
Actually, a bit busy.
I need you to do something for me.
No, listen to me.
We have to talk about the Doctor.
Mum, please, not now! I need you
to look something up on the Internet.
-Do it yourself. You've got a computer.
-Oh, just do it, will you?
-Please.
-When did you get so rude?
I'll tell you when.
Ever since you met that man.
I need to know who has more
number ones, The Beatles or Elvis.
Hang on. The mouse is unplugged.
(GROANING)
-Okay, hang on. What is this, pub quiz?
-Yeah, pub quiz.
-Using your mobile is cheating.
-Have you found it?
There's over 400,000 results.
Give me a minute.
COMPUTER: Impact in 28-50.
Doctor, these readings
are starting to scare me.
-What do you mean?
-Look, Korwin's body is changing.
His whole biological make-up...
It's impossible.
(BEEPING)
This is med centre. Urgent assistance
requested. Urgent assistance!
Stay here! Keep working!
Urgent assistance!
Abi, they're on their way.
What's happening to you?
(IN ALIEN VOICE) Burn with me.
(OVER PA) Burn with me.
Captain?
I told you to stay in Engineering.
I only take orders
from one person round here.
Oh, is he always this cheery?
-Elvis.
-What?
Really? Elvis!
Burn with me.
Korwin, you're sick.
Burn with me!
-Mum, you're a star.
-Now, we need to have a serious...
-What was that?
-I've got to go.
Doctor, what were those screams?
Concentrate on those doors.
You gotta keep moving forward!
COMPUTER: Impact in 27-06.
Korwin's gone.
Oh, my God.
Tell me that's not Lerner.
Endothermic vaporisation.
I've never seen one this ferocious.
"Burn with me."
-That's what we heard Korwin say.
-What?
Do you think... No way.
Scannell, tell him.
Korwin is not a killer.
-He can't vaporise people. He's human.
-These bio-scan results.
Internal temperature, 100 degrees.
Body oxygen replaced by hydrogen.
Your husband hasn't been infected.
-He's been overwhelmed.
-The test results are wrong.
What is it, though?
A parasite? A mutagenic virus?
Something that needs a host body,
but how did it get inside him?
Stop talking
like he's some kind of experiment.
Where's this ship been?
Have you made planet fall recently?
Docked with any other vessels?
Any sort of external contact at all?
What is this, an interrogation?
We've got to stop him
before he kills again.
We're just a cargo ship.
Doctor, if you give her a minute...
I'm fine. I need to warn the crew.
Everybody listen to me.
Something has infected Korwin.
We think
he killed Abi Lerner.
None of you must go anywhere near him.
Is that clear?
ASHTON: Understood, Captain.
Erina, get back here
with that equipment.
Whatever you say, boss.
"Go there. Come back. Fetch this.
Carry these. Make drinks. Sweep up."”
Please, kill me now.
Burn with me.
COMPUTER: Impact inn 24-517.
Is the infection permanent?
Can you cure him?
-I don't know.
-Don't lie to me, Doctor.
Eleven years we've been married.
We chose this ship together.
He keeps me honest.
So I don't want false hope.
The parasite's too aggressive.
Your husband's gone.
There's no way back. Sorry.
Thank you.
Are you certain
nothing happened to provoke this?
Nobody's working on anything secret?
'Cause it's vital that you tell me.
I know every inch of this ship.
I know every detail of my crew's lives.
There is nothing.
Then why is this thing
so interested in you?
I wish I knew.
MARTHA: Doctor, we've moved to area 17.
Keep going. You've got to get
to area 1 and reboot those engines.
(DOOR OPENING)
You got those tools, Erina?
'Cause I'm...
(EXCLAIMING)
Korwin, it's me. We're mates.
They are getting too far.
We must share the light.
COMPUTER: Heat shields failing at 20%.
Come on!
Everything on this ship is so cheap.
(DOOR OPENING)
Who's there?
MARTHA: Is that Korwin?
RILEY: No, wait a minute.
Oh, Ashton, what are you doing?
(IN ALIEN VOICE) Burn with me.
-Well, if you want to help...
-Burn with me.
Burn with me.
No! Come on!
-What is happening on this ship?
-Never mind that. Where are we?
COMPUTER:
Airlock field. Jettison escape pod.
Does it mean us? Doctor!
COMPUTER: Pod jettison initiated.
Doctor, we're stuck in an escape pod
of the area-17 airlock.
One of the crew's trying to jettison us.
You've got to help us!
Tell me you can stop it.
-Why is this happening?
-Stay here.
I mean it this time.
Don't start those engines!
He's picking us off one by one.
COMPUTER: Jettison held.
Thank you.
COMPUTER: Jettison reactivated.
Come on.
Sierpinski sequence. This'll get him.
COMPUTER:
Jettison held. Escape pod stabilised.
You're pretty good.
Ashton!
Someone's hacked at the systems.
I can't re-root the generators.
There's no way
I'm gonna be able to jump start the ship.
SCANNELL: Who the hell did that?
Korwin?
What are you?
Why are you killing my crew?
What did you do to him?
What have you done to my husband?
You recognise me. Korwin, you know me.
It's Kath, your wife.
-My wife?
-That's right.
You're still in there. I'm your wife.
It's your fault.
That's enough!
What do you want?
Why this ship? Tell me.
(SCREAMING)
COMPUTER: Jettison activated.
He's crushed the circuit.
I can't stop it. I can't stop it!
What do you mean, it's my fault?
It's your fault. Now burn with me.
(KORWIN SHRIEKING)
-What are you doing?
-Freezing him. Ice vents.
You'll kill him!
Come on, let's see you.
I want to know what you really are.
COMPUTER: Airlock sealed.
McDonnell, Ashton's heading
in your direction.
He's been infected, just like Korwin.
Korwin's dead, Doctor.
Everything's locked.
COMPUTER:
Airlock decompression completed.
Jettisoning pod.
(BEEPING)
-Doctor!
-I'll save you.
Martha, it's too late.
-Doctor!
-I'll save you.
I can't hear you.
(INAUDIBLE)
Sorry.
COMPUTER: Impact in 17:05.
What did he mean, your fault?
What are you doing?
Don't touch him. He's infected.
-We don't know how it spreads.
-You murdered him.
-He was about to kill you.
-He recognised me.
You heard the Doctor.
It isn't Korwin any more.
The Doctor doesn't know.
None of us know.
So what are you gonna do?
Stay there until we burn?
'Cause without you, none of us
stand a chance of getting out of here.
DOCTOR: Scannell
I need a spacesuit in area 17 now!
-What for?
-Just get down here!
Well, go on. Do what he says.
-Ashton's still out there.
-I'll deal with him.
The wonderful world of space travel.
The prettier it looks,
the more likely it is to kill you.
-He'll come for us.
-No, it's too late.
Our heat shields will pack in any minute
and then we go into free fall.
We'll fall into the sun way before
he has a chance to do anything.
You don't know the Doctor.
I believe in him.
Then you're lucky. I've never found
anyone worth believing in.
No girlfriend? Boyfriend?
The job doesn't lend itself
to stable relationships.
-Family, then?
-My dad's dead.
I haven't seen my mum in six years.
She didn't want me
to sign on for cargo tours.
Things were said,
and since then, all silent.
She wanted to hold on to me.
I know that. God, she's so stubborn.
Yeah, well, that's families.
What about you?
Full works. Mum, dad, dad's girlfriend,
brother, sister.
There's no silence there.
So much noise.
God, they'll never know.
I'll just have disappeared,
and they'll always be waiting.
Call them.
Ashton!
(GROANING)
-I can't let you do this.
-You're wasting your breath, Scannell.
-You're not gonna stop me.
-You want to open an airlock in flight
on a ship spinning into the sun.
No one can survive that.
-Oh, just you watch.
-You open that airlock, it's suicide.
This close to the sun,
the shields will barely protect you.
If I can boost the magnetic lock
on the ship's exterior,
it should re-magnetise the pod.
Now, while I'm out there, you've got
to get the rest of those doors open.
We need those auxiliary engines.
Doctor, will you listen.
They're too far away. It's too late.
I'm not gonna lose her.
COMPUTER: Decompression initiated.
Impact in 12:55.
(MOBILE RINGING)
-Hello?
-It's me again. Sorry about earlier.
-Is everything all right?
-Yeah. Of course.
-Martha?
-Mum...
-You know I love you, don't you?
-Of course, I do.
-What's brought this on?
-I never say it.
I never get the time
or never think of it, and then...
I really love you.
Tell Dad, Leo and Tish
that I love them, too.
-Martha, what's wrong?
-Nothing, promise.
-Where are you?
-Just out.
-With anyone nice?
-Some mates.
-What mates?
-Mum, can we not just talk?
Of course.
What do you want to talk about?
I don't know. Anything.
What you had for breakfast,
what you watched on telly last night,
how much you're gonna kill Dad
next time you see him, just anything.
Is the Doctor with you? Is he there now?
-Mum, just leave it.
-It's a simple enough question.
I better go.
-No, Martha, wait.
-See ya, Mum.
COMPUTER: Impact in 11:15.
Heat shields
failing at 10%.
(GRUNTING)
Come on!
Go on, my son.
SCANNELL ON RADIO:
Doctor, how are you doing?
I can't... I can't reach.
I don't know how much longer I can last.
SCANNELL: Come on, don't give up now.
-We're being pulled back!
-I told you! The Doctor!
It's alive.
Doctor, close the airlock now!
That pod's gonna smash into him.
Stay here.
COMPUTER: Impact inn 8-5 7.
Airlock recompression completed.
Doctor! Doctor! Are you okay?
(IN ALIEN VOICE) Stay away from me.
What's happened?
It's your fault, Captain McDonnell.
Riley, get down to area 10
and help Scannell with the doors.
Go!
You mined that sun,
stripped its surface for cheap fuel.
-You should have scanned for life!
-I don't understand.
Doctor, what are you talking about?
That's sun's alive, a living organism.
They scooped out its heart, used it
for fuel and now it's screaming!
What do you mean? How can
a sun be alive? Why is he saying that?
Because it's living in me.
-Oh, my God.
-Humans!
You grab whatever's nearest
and bleed it dry!
You should've scanned!
-It takes too long. We'd be caught.
-Fusion scoops are illegal.
Martha, you've got
to freeze me, quickly.
-What?
-Stasis chamber.
Look, you've got to take me
to below -200. Freeze it out of me.
It'll use me to kill you if you don't.
The closer we get to the sun,
the stronger it is...
-Med centre. Quickly! Quickly!
-Help me!
COMPUTER: Impact in 7-30.
-What's your favourite colour?
-You what?
-It's the question.
-Purple.
-Or did I say orange?
-Come on!
-Martha, where are you?
-It's all right. I'm here.
Just setting everything up.
Stasis chamber, minus 200, yeah?
But you don't know how
this equipment works. You'll kill him.
Nobody can survive those temperatures.
He's not human.
If he says he can survive, then he can.
-Let me help you, then.
-You've done enough damage.
Ten seconds.
That's all I'll be able to take.
-Martha!
-Yeah?
It's burning me up. I can't control it.
If you don't get rid of it,
I could kill you. I could kill you all.
-I'm scared. I'm so scared.
-Just stay calm.
You saved me. Now I return the favour.
Just believe in me.
It's burning. Kill me.
Then it won't happen.
That's enough. I've got you.
There's this process...this thing
that happens if I'm about to die...
Shh! Quiet now,
'cause that is not going to happen.
-You ready?
-No.
COMPUTER: Heat shields failing at 5%.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
No! Martha, you can't stop it! Not yet!
-What happened?
-The power's been cut in Engineering.
-But who's down there?
-Leave it to me.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
COMPUTER: Impact in 4:47.
Are we gonna do it in time?
Come on, you're defrosting.
Martha, listen, I could go
at any moment. You've got to go.
-No way.
-Get to the front. Vent the engines.
Sun particles in the fuel.
Get rid of them.
-I am not leaving you.
-You've got to!
Give back what they took.
-Doctor.
-Please, go!
I'll be back for you.
COMPUTER: Impact inn 4-08.
(GASPING)
You were right. It was my fault.
COMPUTER: Impact in 3:43.
I didn't know. I really didn't know.
Korwin, please stop.
Everyone must burn.
Riley, Scannell, I'm sorry.
McDonnell! McDonnell!
I love you.
COMPUTER: Exterior airlock opened.
It's the last door.
We've got to keep going.
COMPUTER: Impact in 2:17.
Primary engine critical.
Repeat, primary engine critical.
Survival estimate projection, 0%.
Martha!
Doctor! What are you doing?
I can't fight it.
(OVER PA) Keep back, Martha!
Burn with me.
(OVER PA) Burn with me, Martha.
COMPUTER: Impact in 1:21.
Got it!
COMPUTER:
Life support systems reaching critical.
Repeat, life support systems
reaching critical.
Impact inn 7-06.
(ALARM BLARING)
Collision alert. Collision alert.
It's not working. Why is it not working?
COMPUTER: Collision alert.
Fifty eight seconds to fatal impact.
-Vent the engines. Dump the fuel.
-What?
Sun particles in the fuel.
Get rid of them. Do it. Now!
Come on, Doctor, hold on.
COMPUTER: Fuel dump in progress.
Fuel dump in progress.
Ah, the engines are firing!
COMPUTER: Impact averted.
Impact averted. Impact averted.
We're clear.
We've got just enough reserves.
Doctor!
-This is never your ship.
-Compact, eh?
And another good word, robust.
Barely a scorch mark on her.
We can't just leave you
drifting with no fuel.
We've sent out an official mayday.
The authorities
will pick us up soon enough.
-Though how we explain what happened...
-Just tell them.
That sun needs care and protection,
just like any other living thing.
So you're off, then.
-No chance I'll see you again?
-Not really.
It was nice, not dying with you.
I reckon you'll find
someone worth believing in.
I think I already did.
Well done. Very hot.
So, didn't really need you
in the end, did we?
Sorry.
How are you doing?
Now, what do you say?
Ice-skating on the mineral lakes
of Kur-ha. Fancy it?
Whatever you like.
By the way, you'll be needing this.
-Really?
-Frequent flyers' privilege.
-Thank you.
-Don't mention it.
Oh, no! Mum!
(MOBILE RINGING)
Hello?
-It's me again.
-Three calls in one day.
I'm sorry about earlier.
Over-emotional mad day.
What are you doing tonight?
Why don't you come round?
I'll make something nice
and we can catch up.
Yeah, tonight. Do my best.
Just remind me, what day is it again?
-Election day.
-Right. Of course.
I'll be round for tea, roughly.
-And what about...
-Anyway, I've got to go.
See you later. Love you.
-That's all?
-For now.
-Have you voted?
-Of course.
Just don't expect me
to tell you who for.
Thanks for all you're doing, Mrs Jones.
Mr Saxon will be very grateful.
Martha, this watch is...
If anything goes wrong,
it's all down to you, Martha.
It's Monday, November 10, 1913.
-We make quite a team.
-Don't we just.
You've quite an eye for a pretty girl.
Look in the sky.
Help me!
"Completely human”. Hmm.