Emergency transmission
from the Toraji Transport Network.
This is an urgent request
for immediate assistance!
This is an all-frequency appeal
for help.
We're under attack!
We've been hijacked!
ALARM SOUNDS
PANICKED SHOUTS
All passengers down here!
Marshals, to your posts.
Who is it? Who's attacking us?
Be careful.
It's all right, they're dead.
Go through. Head down the train.
There are more marshals.
Secure passenger safety.
What's happening to them?
That energy... They're regenerating!
All frequencies -
urgent appeal for help!
Is there anyone out there?
DOCTOR: Yes, there is.
TARDIS THRUMMING
We're unable to
materialise inside your craft.
The Cybermen have
a blocking field in action.
We're taking a different approach.
Get out of there now!
Ready?
Ready. Ready.
Leader, we have detected
a rescue attempt.
Scans detect a TARDIS.
The Doctor.
DAN: Could you not have got
a less wobbly ladder?
Why? It's perfect!
Er...
Well, ALMOST perfect.
Tiny jump.
Cool, right?
Oh!
Ah!
Doctor!
I've got you.
Come on, Dan.
What am I doing?
I've got a date to get to.
DAN YELLS
Yeah! What a landing!
9.9. Get in!
Our boots are connected to
the electromagnetic roof.
We're literally surfing
on a space train.
Shut up, Dan!
All right, Sheffield, just cos my
jump was better than yours!
Dan, turn around!
We need to wake the long-haul
passengers. There's no time.
We can't just leave them.
You know what'll happen to them.
We have to protect the cargo.
Keep moving!
EXPLOSION
Go with the passengers.
I'll hold them off.
Where is the cargo?
There's no cargo on board
this train.
You lie.
Identify the location
of the cargo carriage or be deleted.
I'm not afraid of the Cybermen.
We are more than Cybermen.
We have evolved.
We are your Cyber Masters.
OK, two important points.
Number one - find something to
hold on to.
Number two - don't get shot! What?!
I'm going to deactivate
the train's electromagnets.
But aren't they keeping us
stuck to the roof?!
Yeah, but not just us.
Watch out!
The train needs bringing
under control.
We need to get the train to a halt.
The controls are over there,
as I showed you.
Don't lose my sonic.
We need to find and keep
the passengers safe
and find out what those
Cyber Masters want with this train.
LASER FIRE
Leader, the cargo has been secured.
Open it.
It's all right. It's all right.
We're here to help.
I'm the Doctor. This is Yaz.
I can sort that wound out.
Pass that medpack off the wall.
All right, Dan, son,
just like she showed you.
Dan? Whoops, sorry!
Wrong setting.
Sorting it, hopefully.
ANNOUNCEMENT: This is your space
train driver Dan
reassuring you
everything is under control
and we will be slowing
to a gentle stop momentarily.
I'll deal with the Cybermen.
They're not ordinary Cybermen.
I know.
Get away from that pod.
Doctor, you shall
not disrupt our mission.
Oh, I think I shall.
Feel that slowing down?
This train's under my control
and reinforcements
will be here any moment.
So whatever you came for, whatever
that cargo is, you've failed.
EXPLOSION
It's all right.
Don't be scared.
I'm the Doctor.
I'm going to protect you.
The Doctor lies.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Father Grigori, I have
a message from the Tsarina.
Your presence is urgently
required at the Winter Palace.
The Tsarevich has been taken ill.
Excuse me.
Can I help?
What's happened to this painting?
It was taken down
for restoration work.
Was there something wrong with it?
No.
From time to time,
all the paintings need a little TLC.
But this one was only restored
two months ago.
It required
a little additional work.
Did it?
15 of the world's most well-known
paintings all been taken down
pretty much simultaneously
and with no explanation.
Where are you, anyway?
Sorry, Ace. Say again?
I said, where are you, Tegan?
What day is it, Thursday?
Romania.
Somewhere near the Carpathians
or maybe in them.
I'm losing track.
What are you doing there?
There's a volcanic chain where those
three seismologists were last seen
investigating a nearby earthquake.
And did you find them?
Disappeared off the face
of the Earth, just like the others.
A dozen seismologists
and 15 paintings.
There's something else.
When I arrived at this cabin,
there was a package waiting for me.
When I opened it up, there was
a Russian doll toy box inside.
But there was also a card
from the Doctor.
Ace, I haven't heard from the Doctor
for nearly four decades.
Yeah, all right, show-off!
Just cos it's only
three decades for me.
So what was the doll?
A Cyberman! Of all the things.
Why would the Doctor send me that?
That's not a fond memory.
It's not even a Russian doll
and why send it to me now?
I think we should go in.
TARDIS THRUMS
Back in time for your date.
You're welcome.
Should we pick you up again
in 24 hours?
Yaz, you and I can try
and pick up the trail
of where the Cyber Masters went
with that child.
You don't have to come back for me.
OK. What?
I was one hand away from flying
off into space and suffocating.
I don't want to push me luck
any further.
I mean, all this...
All this is amazing
and I've had the most
incredible time.
But it's not my life.
And my life's
far from perfect, but...
..I need to get back to it.
I need to attack it.
And I can now...
..cos I've been with you.
I get it.
Life's important.
Home's important.
Yeah.
My house.
Looks like I'll be kipping
on my mum and dad's sofa tonight.
See you again, Doctor.
DOOR SHUTS
Have I upset her?
Not one for goodbyes.
Whereas me,
I'm glad to see the back of you.
I'll call you.
I'll ghost you.
TRANSMISSION: Doctor!
No!
Breaching transmission firewalls.
Get out of my TARDIS!
I mean you no harm.
You'd be the first Dalek
to ever mean that.
I have information critical to the
future of both humans and Daleks.
It is imperative that you and I
meet immediately.
I don't think so.
I offer you the key
to the destruction of the Daleks!
A Dalek invades my TARDIS with
a message offering to destroy
its own species?
I no longer believe
in the Dalek mission.
Well, that's a new one.
The Dalek machine was
created to ensure
the survival of the Kaled race.
Yet Kaled identity
has eroded over time.
The Dalek mission has
changed to become
the perpetuation of the Dalek race.
Analysis concludes
we have lost the right to survive.
Your Creator would
both be impressed and horrified.
So you come to me as what, a spy?
A Dalek incursion on Earth
is imminent.
I offer you the chance to destroy
every Dalek before that attack.
Why would I ever trust you?
To save the lives of
billions of humans.
I will communicate location
and time. You must attend.
No-no-no, you don't order me!
I am detected.
Transmission must end.
YAZ: Who are you yelling at?
ALARM SOUNDS
The TARDIS has locked on to
the cargo trail.
Now, where is that child?
That data doesn't make sense.
It's just outside Earth
in the year 1916.
Why doesn't that make sense?
Because I'm seeing one planet
too many in your solar system.
And that extra planet is right
in the shadow of Earth.
Tsarina, Rasputin approaches.
It is good to see you,
Father Grigori.
How is my son?
Such a tiny injury and such
a terrible effect.
His haemophilia is a cruel illness.
I cannot help but think
that he has worsened
ever since the arrival
of the second moon in the sky.
An entire new moon.
These special times must
not challenge our faith.
They should strengthen it.
I'm afraid for my son.
I believe in the morning
he'll be much improved.
But can you be sure?
Are my eyes not full of certainty?
Yes...
..they are.
My dear Tsar, this endless war!
Have you made your decision to
send more troops or withdraw?
It is so difficult.
What would your advice be?
My main concern is that you and your
family take some time away.
A holiday.
Very soon.
Don't you think?
Long holiday?
Yes.
Yes, I, erm...
..I think so.
Don't I?
I will take care of your beautiful
Winter Palace
and you will remain assured of
your one certainty.
Which is?
That you are the Master...
..and I will obey you.
TARDIS THRUMS
Organic life converted
into metal on a planetary scale.
Cybertechnology.
Are they capable of this?
There's Cybermen everywhere we go
right now, Yaz.
Those ones on the train,
the Cyber Masters,
they were created by the Master
on Gallifrey.
Doctor.
Stay here.
Nope.
It's not yours, is it?
Yours from another time?
In the future?
I feel like I'm being taunted.
DOCTOR GASPS
The core of this TARDIS
has been lashed into the centre
of the planet's metal structure.
But why?
The screen's showing another energy
source on the surface.
Come on.
Ah, there's a rudimentary cloaking
shield in operation.
Soon fix that.
The Cybermen have tethered
that child into this planet.
It was registering
as an energy source.
How is that child an energy source?
Wait, there's more layers
to the shield.
Oh, not just cloaking.
It's a consciousness shield!
A creature trying to evade capture,
hiding behind a visual projection
shield, and this one shows us
what we instinctively want to
protect, as a defence.
So what is it?
Oh, a Qurunx!
One of the great mysteries
of the universe.
I've never seen one before, Yaz.
Sentient energy enough to power
planets and civilisations.
They're so rare.
A metal planet with a Qurunx
at the heart of it
on the edge of Earth in the second
decade of the 20th century.
Why?
Desist!
Ah, decided to show your face,
have you?
Is this planet your doing?
This structure is
the zenith of Cyberconversion.
An entire planet transported here.
You think I'm going to allow that?
You will not be able to stop it.
Oh, yeah?
Why is that?
Your Master awaits, Doctor.
Doctor, what does it mean by that?
LASER FIRE
TARDIS THRUMS
Yes, what?
TRANSMISSION: Doctor, UNIT needs
your help!
Bit busy, Kate. Can it wait?
Absolutely not. Oh!
Nice new building.
Thank you.
Now, a dozen of the world's leading
seismologists have gone missing
in the past two weeks.
Plus 15 of the world's most
valuable paintings
have disappeared from view.
That's what you called us here for?
Have you any idea what's going on
in outer space in 1916 right now?
Strangely enough, no.
Oh, also new freelancers.
Don't be cross.
Are you ready for this? No!
Me neither.
I believe you three
know each other of old.
Oh, wow!
You said a woman.
You never said young.
Tegan.
Ace?
That is a good look on you,
Professor.
What are you doing here?
I brought them in.
I'm rebuilding our intelligence
networks with people who understand
the problems Earth faces
from personal experience.
It seemed pretty clear
where to start.
So...how have you been?
Like you care!
Tegan, we discussed this.
38 years!
I'm Yaz. The only one here who
doesn't really know what's going on.
We used to be you, decades back.
I see.
Wow...
So what was so urgent, Kate?
This is why I brought you in.
Let's start with the paintings.
Mona Lisa, The Scream, The Hay Wain,
Girl With A Pearl Earring,
The Last Supper -
all of them and more
taken out of public view
because all of them we've discovered
have been defaced.
The face of Rasputin
inserted into every painting.
Oh, no.
That's not Rasputin.
That's the Master.
What? What?
Greetings, seismology fans!
If you're craving answers
to life's little mysteries,
my keynote address at the
International Seismology
Memorial Conference is now
starting at a conference hall
vaguely near you.
Come feel the Earth move.
Here's the pin. See you in a bit.
So that's the Master now?
1916, Rasputin,
and the only person who would leave
a TARDIS that looked like mine.
Hotel.
3.2 kilometres from Mount Vesuvius.
We've got a UNIT base near Naples.
I'll get you local support.
Sorry, dealing with multiple
somethings.
It's good to see you both.
Ow!
You gave me an electric shock.
Sorry. My bad. I promise.
I'm coming back. Ow!
Oh, you are really staticky.
We'll be back. Come on, Yaz.
I think I handled that quite well.
TARDIS THRUMS
If we correlate the
latest tremor detection data
with the aforementioned ground
deformation measurements,
cross-referencing the increase
in volcanic gas emissions
and rising magma levels, we know...
Doctor, look!
..ladies and gentlemen, that it
would only take the slightest
tectonic pressure...
Do you like my seismologist
collection?
I think I've got the whole set now.
All right,
I followed your breadcrumb trail.
Some people think you're Rasputin,
you've got a TARDIS on a metal
planet with a stolen Qurunx,
guarded by your Cyber Masters
in 1916.
Now, do I win a prize if I guess
how this all fits together
or are you just going to tell me
why you're grandstanding?
Be patient. We'll get there.
How did you even escape
from Gallifrey?
Magnificent attention to detail.
I'm a seismologist now.
You killed all these people.
For what?
To give you simple, fair warning.
Leave Earth now, Doctor,
or it will be the death of you,
because really, honestly, truly,
this is the day you die.
No...not just die.
This is the day
you are erased from existence...
..forever!
I know, a bit of a
conversation stopper.
Awkward, right, Yaz?
Do you see what I've done?
I was so clever because I can give
her this warning,
but we both know she won't leave.
She can't, not now
I've said that to her,
and yet she knows she should,
because she also knows
I don't make empty threats.
I can absolutely, categorically,
pinky-promisey confirm
this is no empty threat.
DOOR SLAMS
SOLDIERS: Go! Go! Go! Go!
Oh, oh!
You brought soldiers!
Are these for me?
Oh, you shouldn't have.
Is this rendition?
I've always wanted to be
renditioned. Or is it rendered?
Ooh, gentle, gentle, gentle, boys!
Am I going to UNIT?
I hope I'm going to UNIT.
Give her a gun.
What?
Cover him. We're going to take
him in the TARDIS.
Take the gun.
Yaz, she must be worried.
Thought she didn't like guns.
Fine.
Do you even know how to use that,
love?
Don't you worry,
I've had weapons training.
Now move!
Great chat. Good meeting.
Thank you all.
Clear up the tiny bodies
and inform the loved ones for me,
would you?
You're not going to shoot me.
Not in her TARDIS.
Think of the mess!
Just in case you're wondering,
all this
I'm-messing-with-your-mind chat,
I've heard worse on a Friday
night in Sheffield.
HE LAUGHS
Can I let you in on a little secret?
It's OK, it's OK.
I ingested the Cyberium -
the battle AI of the Cybermen.
I'm so many steps ahead.
I can see it all...
..right through to all our ends.
I'm sorry, Yaz, this is going to
be very, very painful.
In your dreams, mate.
Yeah.
UNIT will keep you under
armed guard, while I get rid of
all the mess you've been scattering
around the place.
Whatever you want.
I'm in her head.
I said I'm in your head, dear.
ALARM SOUNDS
Aren't those Dalek symbols?
What are they, coordinates?
Why are you getting
messages from Daleks?
Why is she getting messages
from Daleks?
I'm sure there's a good reason.
Let's hope so.
Status report - Inston-Vee Vinder
now exiting the wormhole.
I've survived, and I'm detecting a
life signal from the missing Qurunx,
but the wormhole is playing
havoc with the ship.
In summary, wormhole navigation
was a really bad idea!
LOUD CRASH
OK...
Let's start with the good news.
The ship did accurately predict
the wormhole
and managed to surf it
with me inside.
Good news part two.
It did lead me to
the missing Qurunx,
so I guess we could say
mission partially successful?
Except...
..apparently it's connected to some
control system on a planet
that shouldn't even be here,
according to the charts.
Oh, and I have a ship problem
in that it's broken.
Thanks, wormhole.
Wait...
Put him in the bunker.
Constant monitoring,
full security detail.
Ooh, the bunker!
That sounds nice! I love a bunker!
Anybody want to join me?
Bunk-up in the bunker?
Your dad was an idiot.
Oh, Tegan Jovanka!
How's your Auntie Vanessa? Do you
keep her in a little doll's house?
I'm going to enjoy watching you
locked up in a tiny cell.
That's right, you tell me.
And Ace!
Or should I say Dorothy?
Didn't the Doctor ditch you?
No? Little fallout
with your Machiavellian maestro?
Last time I saw you,
you were half cat.
A man's allowed to experiment.
Take him away.
Yes, yes, take me away!
You'll all feel safer then
with me in the building.
You're not staying, Doctor?
You're not going to leave them
alone, are you...
..while you go Dalek hunting?
Whoo!
Ace, Tegan, I need you to stay here
and monitor the Master.
We won't be long.
ACE: Professor,
where are you going?
She really doesn't want us
back in there.
Wow.
Love what you've done
with the place.
Darling, I don't seem to have
the room-service menu.
Only, I have allergies.
I'm human-intolerant.
LOCK CLANGS
No?
Just trying to lighten the tone
before you all die.
YAZ: Doctor!
Stop for a second.
I can't keep doing this with you -
running from one place
to the next, never explaining.
Sorry, no time.
Make time.
Daleks...
On the same day as the Master
and Cybermen.
I know. They're either separate
problems, or all part of
one bigger scheme.
He doesn't have that power.
He couldn't corral Daleks
and Cybermen...
Could he?
It's all happening so fast.
Ooh!
Very sorry.
I am really staticky today.
SONIC WHIRS
You're going to meet a Dalek.
Has it never occurred to you
that it could be a trap?
Of course it has.
But there's about to be
a Dalek attack on Earth.
And the one that tipped me off
said it has information
which could help us
stop the Daleks,
but not just now -
all Daleks, for ever.
It's a calculated risk.
And it's one I have to take.
TARDIS THRUMS
I'll take down there.
Meet you back here.
Be careful.
I'm supposed to be
the one saying that to you.
I am surprised, Doctor.
I was not sure you would come.
Well, I did.
Now give me the information
you promised.
All data is
contained within my casing.
You must be fast.
This will extract
all the information.
You're really going to let me
do this?
I am.
Data transfer in progress.
I have betrayed my species.
You must ensure
they are destroyed.
DALEK: Testing complete.
All systems are in place
and operating
at maximum efficiency.
We are ready. No...
They're already here.
Seismology.
Volcanoes.
Daleks.
And the Master.
No...
This is not good news.
I'll get surveillance up
on the Master's cell.
We can take turns watching.
Whatever he's up to,
he can't do much
from a UNIT prison cell.
I really thought
I'd seen the last of him.
CLATTER
Ace?
The toy...
MASTER: Oh!
Didn't it want to stay
inside your bag?
Oh, Tegan.
Do you really think
the Doctor cared enough
to send you
even one meagre toy?
How's he doing that?
The Doctor
didn't send you that,
I did...
..knowing what
you would do with it.
You'd keep it so close to you
because you have nothing else.
Do you know the great thing
about tissue compression?
It also works in reverse.
That ain't just any Cyberman.
It's a Russian doll.
Oh! And say hello
to my friend Ashad.
I killed him once,
but he's forgiven me now.
Tegan!
MASTER LAUGHS
Gold bullets, tin-heads!
Did you think UNIT
wouldn't be ready?
Why isn't it working?
We long ago
developed resistance to gold.
BOTH: Run!
Oh, run!
MASTER LAUGHS
Run! Oh, look at them.
KATE ON TANNOY: All units,
full combat protocols.
UNIT is under attack.
I repeat, UNIT is under attack
from Cybermen.
HE GRUNTS
I am so glad I cloned you.
Every detail...
..paying off.
Such a good plan.
Data transfer almost complete.
We are detected!
DALEK COMMANDER:
Stay where you are, Doctor.
You have no escape.
Was this your plan?
To lure me in
and then betray me?
I did not betray you.
The traitor speaks the truth.
We allowed the traitor
to contact you.
Force opening of traitor.
DOCTOR YELLS
SNARLING
DALEK COMMANDER:
Exterminate the traitor.
DALEKS: Exterminate!
Enter the casing, Doctor.
No!
Obey! Obey!
Or be exterminated!
DOCTOR YELLS
DALEK COMMANDER:
Mission successful.
The Doctor is a prisoner
of the Daleks.
Activate spatiotemporal shift!
I can do this. I can do this.
TARDIS THRUMS
The Doctor's in danger.
There must be a Dalek teleport
trace that we can follow,
that you can lock on to.
And why am I talking to you?
MASTER: Hello, Doctor.
Welcome to the end
of your existence.
Say hello to my friends.
I believe
we're all acquainted...
..right? Do you like the garb?
I love the garb.
Got to dress for the occasion.
I was just thinking...
We could call this...
..the Master's Dalek Plan.
Or the, er...
..Cyber-Dalek Master Plan,
or the Cyber-Master's Dalek Plan?
I can't quite get it.
But in the end
I suppose we'll just call it
the day I killed the Doctor...
..with a little help
from my friends.
SCOFFING: Your friends?
You hate each other.
And the one thing stronger
than their hatred for each other...
..is their hatred for you.
Just took a little handsome genius
to point it out to them.
"What unites us...
"..is stronger
than what divides us."
I mean, that's very you, that,
isn't it?
You love a team, don't you?
Letting every Tom, Dick
and Harriet into your TARDIS...
Well, you have your fam.
Now...
..I have mine.
So everything else was a diversion?
No.
No. No!
Not a diversion.
Very important!
Three-phase plan.
You'll see.
Except you won't.
MASTER LAUGHS
But rest assured,
without you to defend it,
Earth will fall very, very fast.
I did warn you, Doctor.
I'm going old-school, Doctor.
A tribute to our elders.
Do you remember the ultimate
sanction for breaking our laws?
WHISPERS: Forced regeneration.
They even did it to you once,
didn't they?
Well, maybe more than once.
Who knows?
Not you.
You don't have the technology.
I do.
I do!
MASTER GIGGLES
When I ransacked Gallifrey,
I took everything.
But where would he get the power?
If only I had a planet built
for this purpose.
No, wait, wait. I do!
MASTER LAUGHS MANIACALLY
You did get that, right?
A conversion planet.
Except it doesn't only convert
organic to Cyber.
I brought it here to help
another conversion altogether.
MUSIC: Rasputin by Boney M
# There lived a certain man
in Russia long ago
# He was big and strong
In his eyes a flaming glow
# Most people looked at him
with terror and with fear... #
VINDER: OK, Doctor.
This is my last
roll of the dice. I've been
carrying this around with me
since you gave it to me.
# ..like a preacher
Full of ecstasy and fire
# But he also... #
You need my help?
I could certainly do with yours.
But I'm not holding out much hope.
# Ra-Ra-Rasputin
Lover of the Russian queen
# There was a cat
that really was gone
# Ra-Ra-Rasputin
Russia's greatest love machine
# It was a shame
how he carried on... #
Let's get you out of there.
This is Inston-Vee Vinder
saying,
if you need my help... Vinder!
..I could certainly do with yours.
MASTER: Hello, TARDIS.
Receiving this loud and clear?
Say goodbye, Yaz.
TARDIS, lock on to his signal.
Forced regeneration, Doctor.
To force you...
..to regenerate...
..into me. Oh, no!
You wouldn't.
MASTER YELLS
Yaz!
MASTER ROARS
RAGGED BREATHING
MASTER GROANS
WHISPERS: It worked.
MASTER GROANS WITH TRIUMPH
I...
..am...
..the Doctor.
TARDIS THRUMS
Oh, hello...
..Yasmin Khan.
Where's the Doctor?
MASTER LAUGHS
MY Doctor.
Gone.
Really gone.
Forever gone.
Don't...don't worry.
You'll get used to me.
Everyone will.
I still need a companion
to ask and...
..bask in my brilliance.
Come on, Yaz.
Let's go on an adventure!
Don't make me ask twice.
I'd hate to have
to bring you down to size.
TEGAN: We only just got here!
They're all over
the lower floors!
I have to lock down the building.
I can't risk them
getting into the world.
You both need to leave. How?
You have these panels
in every room.
Automated landing parachutes.
If you can't go down,
you've got to go up.
Off the roof?
You're kidding. I stashed
some of my stuff in here earlier.
Hope you don't mind.
Very '80s.
Thanks. Come on, Tegan.
I'll hold the lockdown
till you're clear.
You carry that bat with you
all the time?
Beyonce copied all my moves.
Come on, Yaz!
Let's save a civilisation!
Let's correct history!
Rescue a sick animal!
These yours?
Oh, bless.
Ow!
What was that?!
Some sort of dirty protest?
Unless you want to be consigned
down a black hole for eternity,
you'd better behave!
I am the Doctor,
and you will obey me.
MASTER BURPS
MASTER GRUNTS
Change back.
Can't be done.
I know you're worried about
what I'm going to do.
It's simple.
The Earth will become
a foundry for Daleks
and Cyber production,
hence the work in the volcano,
while I tarnish the name
of the Doctor.
I'm going to make the Doctor
a byword
for fear, pain and destruction,
so when people hear that name
in future,
they quake in fear. If you think
I am going to let you...!
I am the Doctor now!
I am the Doctor!
MASTER GROANS
You should have shot me
when you had the chance.
I need clothes.
Try to escape,
or touch anything,
and I'll kill you.
Out here!
What are you doing?
We can do this.
I brought them in - the Cybermen.
It's my mistake.
You go, find the Doctor.
I need to help Kate.
Tegan!
MASTER: Oh, lovely.
Gold star and a sticker.
That's how you stop two sides
warring, Yaz.
Destroy them both.
Oh, hello.
I have a message
for all your remaining news viewers.
I am the Doctor.
And I caused this.
See?
No-one to stop me now.
No!
TARDIS THRUMS
I'll wait.
You'll be back.
And I have...all the time.
MUSIC: Skye Boat Song
Well!
You're obviously one
of the more determined of us.
I'm sorry?
You refuse to pass through.
Quite the strength
of character,
this incarnation, mm?
The question is, what are
we going to do about it?
Do about what?
Our predicament!
This is supposed to be
handed over.
You can't ruin it for the next one.
And you were doing so well.
Where am I, exactly?
Because the last thing I remember
is being forced to regenerate.
That's why we're here.
To stop you moving
any further through.
You are not finished.
We are not finished.
"We" being...?
Vestiges of your consciousness.
Fragments of yourself.
From the past.
Guardians of the Edge.
Sorry, why are you not wearing...?
I don't do robes.
There's always one.
Has to be different.
I am a manifestation
of our consciousness.
I can wear what I like.
Could we just focus on this,
whatever this is?
You said Guardians of the Edge.
The edge of what?
DOCTOR GASPS
Existence.
It's symbolic, obviously.
Consciousness will do that.
But this is the place
you pass through
during the process of regeneration.
Go past here, there's no way back.
But time's running out!
We can't let the Master
permanently hijack our existence.
Yes.
Very aware of that.
But I was thinking,
in the immediate aftermath
of regeneration, the body's weak,
unstable while it re-forms.
Very good.
Even more so
with a forced regeneration.
So until it's settled,
he may be vulnerable.
We need help from the outside,
which is easier said than done.
Unless one of us, or all of us,
were really clever.
I mean, this is why
you manifested here!
To remind me there's always a way.
Things always work out!
Right?
Hello?
Come on.
I need to get back to UNIT.
If I can work with the others
to get the Doctor back... Hi!
YAZ SQUEALS
If you're seeing this, I'm dead.
What?
Is that a bad way to start?
Bit overdramatic?
How's it looking?
I have been working on this
literally for ever.
It should adapt and respond to
its environment and whoever
it's interacting with.
It's an interactive AI holo-me!
Built from data of my behaviour
across thousands of years.
And it should only activate
under the gravest circumstances.
Like if I'm no longer around.
Now, that would be disastrous.
But I will have very subtly
inserted a sonically triggered
nano-implant under your skin
and passed it off
as static electricity.
Ow! Oh!
If I remember to do that.
I must remember to do that.
You could have told us
you'd done that.
Whoa! The emotional receptors
on the AI
are a bit oversensitive.
Apparently, you're annoyed with me?
Apparently, I should apologise
for something?
I've got a plan.
Tell me if I'm doing this right.
TARDIS THRUMS
Who said miracles don't happen?
The Doctor's gone?
Worse than gone.
And we're the only ones to help her.
Could you go through it again,
but slowly? No! We're on our way
to our next pick-up. I hope.
Doctor, I need information.
Hiya.
Hi, Vinder! How's she doing that?
Sh! Doctor...
How do you reverse
a forced regeneration?
No, no, no, no.
Forced regeneration isn't something
you ever want to be dealing with.
Is that what's happened to me?
It's a hologram.
Can't hurt the feelings
of a hologram.
Yeah.
How do we get real you back?
Real you.
No. Impossible.
Unless...
No.
Calibrating. I'm thinking.
What...what was that?
Other interfaces, other me's.
Sorry,
I'm processing the information.
Only one chance.
I've seen it
in extreme circumstances.
It's incredibly dangerous.
Anything could happen.
Are these extreme circumstances?
CYBERMAN: Conversion pod
established.
ASHAD: Let the conversions begin.
Their army shall become ours.
HE GROANS
What are you doing?
You're supposed to
be getting out of here.
Yeah, well, I didn't.
I don't have time to factor you in!
I have spent the past 30 years
living like a nomad.
I have done land mines, coups,
I have been hijacked,
and I've nearly drowned
trying to help people.
I've seen off two husbands,
and somewhere out there
is an adopted son
who hasn't called me
for six weeks.
And if that's not enough,
I was an air hostess
in the early '80s,
and, trust me, compared to that,
a building full of Cybermen
is nothing.
Now, what's the plan?
Containment
and structural termination.
They've taken out all the systems,
but in the basement
there's a manual activation override
for the structural
termination system.
It'll level the building,
leave everything inside entombed.
You said basement.
We're at the top of the building,
with Cybermen in between.
There is a way out. It's not pretty.
But if you can get down there,
I'll distract the Cybermen.
How are you going to do that?
SCREAMING
KATE: Attention, Cybermen.
I am the commanding officer
of this facility
and I have an offer for you...
..if you can find me, that is.
With me!
SCREAMING
Er...OK.
That's high.
Oh, come on.
This used to be easy.
I used to be good with heights.
Just do it.
Just step off.
ACE YELLS
How do you brake?!
What?!
ACE YELLS
Hi. Did you do that?
Can you fly the TARDIS?
Does she let you?
I never got to fly the TARDIS.
Whoa. Nice vibe.
Where's the Doctor? Hi.
I'm Ace. Inston-Vee Vinder.
Ace, how would you feel
about me dropping you
under a Bolivian volcano
so you can stop the Daleks from
flooding the world with lava?
BAT SCRAPES
Wicked.
Vinder, our mission is
even more dangerous than that.
TARDIS THRUMS
Better.
TARDIS DOOR SHUTS
I'm sorry.
Are you?
Truly?
Came back, didn't I?
We could have fun, you know?
I am fun.
Different type of fun, but fun.
We could travel.
You'll see.
TARDIS THRUMS
HOLO-DOCTOR: Good hiding place.
TEGAN GASPS
Great. Now I'm hallucinating.
What...? What are...?
You're affecting the interface
of your hologram implant!
It's reacting
to your emotional memory.
I should have accounted for that.
You sort of look like
you used to, but...
..not quite.
I could say the same to you.
Surprised you remember.
You think you left and I never
thought of you again.
I never forget any of you.
I remember everything.
Yeah?
Well, what am I thinking,
seeing all these Cybermen?
DISTANT MARCHING
Adric.
Now... Brave heart.
What?
I missed you.
Missed you too.
Now, please, don't get killed. Go!
TEGAN GRUNTS
DALEK: Tectonic plate depth
achieved.
Progress plan
to next phase of activation.
I think I might have
slightly overestimated myself here,
Professor.
Although...
I have souped up the Nitro 9.
Nitro 999!
Just what we need. Good work, Ace.
How are you doing that?
In case you need help, but it
looks like you're doing fine.
So it's fine for me to blow
stuff up when you decide?
Nothing's changed.
It's never fine to blow stuff up.
Sometimes, sadly,
it's the only solution.
But only after fair warning.
Now it's getting freaky.
I was only ever trying
to teach you good habits, Ace.
Obviously, I failed.
You never failed me, Professor.
You made me the person I am today.
I'm sorry we fell out.
I'm sorry I judged you.
I didn't understand
the burden you carried.
All children leave home
sooner or later.
The joy is to watch them fly.
So...we're good?
Oh, we're more than good.
We're ace!
Now, let's get that Nitro 999 going.
DALEK 1: Power levels
now increasing.
DALEK 2: Prepare to engage
circuit four.
DALEK 3: All sectors
now engaging full power.
ACE SHOUTS, GRAHAM YELPS
Oh, you, er...
Easy, love.
Arnold Palmer...son.
Volcano inspector.
"Graham, friend of the Doctor." Oh!
"Former bus driver, worried
about the amount of Daleks
"in here and what he's going
to do about it."
I can't get the hang of this.
Listen, those metal things -
they are from outer space,
and they seem to be drilling
to disrupt the tectonic plates.
We've got to get rid of them
a bit sharpish. I know.
Want to see how I dealt
with them in 1963?
196...? How old are you?
Excuse me!
A gentleman never asks that,
and never on the first date.
I'm Ace.
Yes, you are.
CYBERMAN: Human
structural defences removed.
UNIT commander detected
in this area.
KATE: That's far enough.
Any further,
and that laser shield
will shred at least some of you.
You should know that reinforcements
are already on the way
from all around the world.
ASHAD: Let them come.
They will be recruits
for the new Cyber Army.
We will spread from this building
in fire and glory
to conquer humanity.
You underestimate us.
I understand you.
I was like you - weak and feeble.
Actually, I'm neither.
I have knowledge of this planet...
..of its security infrastructure,
of its leaders.
You have no reason to offer this.
Release all the soldiers you hold.
Save them from conversion.
Let them go...
..and you can have me.
I'm of greater strategic value.
You calculate this may earn you time
for reinforcements to arrive.
You are wrong.
The Doctor is not coming.
The Doctor will never
save you again.
I choose to believe otherwise.
Your surrender is accepted.
Your conversion shall begin.
TEGAN GASPS
Argh!
TEGAN GROANS AND STRAINS
CLANGING
Rabbits!
Renegade human in the walls.
LASER FIRE
TEGAN SCREAMS
TEGAN YELLS
MASTER: Ah, thank you for waiting,
my precious fam.
And now it's time to kill...
..everyone.
Unleash the volcanoes.
DALEK: Volcanic eruptions
shall commence.
COMMANDER DALEK:
Disruptor pulse activation.
Destabilising tectonic plates.
DALEK 1: Every volcano
on planet Earth
shall be activated!
DALEK 2: All humans
shall be exterminated.
CYBERMASTER: Tectonic
disruption in progress.
Volcanic eruptions increasing
across the surface of planet Earth.
YAZ: You're not the Doctor.
You'll never be the Doctor.
On reflection, Yaz,
I think they make much better
companions than you.
I think it's time
for your execution.
Yeah? Well,
if they're much better than me,
why didn't they spot her come in?
What's going on? Who are you?
I'm the Doctor, mate.
Who the hell are you?
Shoot her.
Are you sure
you want to do that, boys?
Fire!
So...it was just
the genetic material
you put into them, was it?
Maybe you should have
included the brains.
Next time,
check for signs of a hologram.
Schoolboy error.
But then you were
a rubbish schoolboy, too.
Was this you?
Out-thought by the Doctor.
Get in the machine.
Or you'll what?
VINDER: You heard her.
Quickly.
And who are you?
Did you stow away in my TARDIS?
It's not your TARDIS.
If you're a friend
of the Doctor's...
..you aren't going to use that.
MASTER GRUNTS
I'm freelance.
You going to let him do this
to me, Yaz? Huh?
To your Doctor?
You're not my Doctor!
Because you know the greatest
strength my Doctor has?
She's spent her life
gathering friends.
She can't help it.
And she is loved.
Because she taught us
to never give up,
even if someone steals
your very existence.
HIGH-PITCHED WHIR
They're starting.
Yaz, over there.
We've got to harness
their regenerative energy.
Right, burst of two seconds,
and then link it into that.
No! This is weird. You were
a tour guide in Gloucester
the last time I saw you.
Nice trick to use
a different interface
to confuse this lot.
Now!
No! Will it be enough?
Hopefully. Enough to reverse.
MASTER ROARS
It's happening.
Is it safe? I hope so.
I erased you, Doctor.
Don't let me go back to being me.
What's happening?
Concentrate! Reunite.
Yes. Where there's hope...
Good luck... Doctor.
MASTER GROANS
DOCTOR PANTS
Hi.
What did I miss?
What am I wearing?!
Forced regeneration.
Forced degeneration.
You brought me back!
Yaz, you saved my life.
You're welcome.
Guess that's me done.
My AI hologram worked.
Oh, I am a genius.
See you around.
Vinder, what are you doing here?
Oh! Whoa, you all right?
Whole new lease of life.
If memory serves me...
..we've got a lot to do. Come on.
ASHAD: Your soldiers offered
pitiful resistance.
They shall begin their ascension,
as you shall now receive yours.
I bestow upon you
the greatest of gifts.
Your conversion shall begin.
KATE: No, no...
No...
No, no...
No, no!
KATE SCREAMS
Oh, my God, it's worse
than a cockpit. Extra wrinkle.
Right, divert that power
into that circuit.
You're not even here!
I'm everywhere, me.
I'm using your ocular nerve
to scan, analyse and process.
The Cyber conversion unit
is powering itself from here,
but if we change that, then
they'll get a nasty surprise!
BEEPING
SMASH, TEGAN YELLS
CYBERMAN: Human rebel located.
You will be deleted.
TEGAN SCREAMS
Human resistance
no longer anticipated.
KATE SCREAMS
Daleks are setting off
volcanoes in 2022,
and here, in 1916,
there's a big Cyber planet
which could convert
the whole of Earth.
There's definitely a fix for both.
But it's got to be quick.
Just piecing it all together.
We used to be friends...
..him and me.
So how do we fix
all those problems?
Have you not figured it out yet?
Obvious, isn't it? We're going
to need some help, though.
All hands on deck.
Oi! Pepper pot!
Now, Graham!
DALEK: Vision impaired!
How long are the timers? Run!
Timer still needs work. Yeah.
Pack a load of Nitro onto this.
Right. Should bring it down.
Well, I hope the timers
last longer on this batch,
cos the moment
this little lot goes up,
we've got to get
to the surface fast,
get past a load of angry Daleks,
and I'd like to make it
out of here alive.
Ready? Ready.
BEEPING
TARDIS THRUMS
Graham! Hey, Doc!
BOTH: How did you get here?
It's about to blow, Professor!
DALEK: Sabotage!
The Doctor is still alive!
TARDIS THRUMS
Exterminate!
BOTH YELL
BOTH GASP
I'd only just signed the lease.
Wow.
Remind me never to mess
with either of you.
I thought that was a given!
And, yes, I would like
to go in the TARDIS.
Ah.
Kate?
SCRABBLING
MASTER GRUNTS
TARDIS THRUMS
OK.
So now it really is crowded
in here, just how I like it.
There you go. I'm going to need
every single one of you.
Stand there.
No, no, no, not that! No?
There. Yes. Good. OK.
Everybody OK?
THEY ALL TALK AT ONCE
No, sorry. No time.
Where's Ryan?
Patagonia. Vinder, is that your ship
on the surface of this Cyber
planet? Don't speak. No time.
Come with me.
Another problem to solve.
When I say now,
activate everything.
Chop chop, Vinder.
She's still not explaining
anything, then?
How is it bigger on the inside?
Never happier than
when I'm fixing things.
What a ship! Stellar engineering.
Proper build.
HISSING
Whoo! Bit of wormhole damage.
Still loads of miles in this,
if you've got an excellent engineer.
Which I am!
Repairs complete.
What are you waiting for?
Get in. Start her up.
You need to be off this planet
while the wormhole's still there.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thanks for being there for me.
How's your family, by the way?
Send them my love.
Remember, when I say now,
get off the planet's surface.
Safe travels.
Everyone still in position?
Good. I'm in the Master's TARDIS.
He's clever,
I'll give him that.
Using a TARDIS to power
the spatiotemporal movement
of a Cyber conversion planet.
What a mind, what a TARDIS!
Type 75.
Bit flashy for my tastes,
but way more powerful than mine.
But he's pushed his TARDIS
right to the edge,
burned out half his systems,
marooned himself here. So,
I'm linking the TARDISes.
I'm using mine to jump-start his.
So when I say now,
activate the control I gave you
and we'll have
a double-powered TARDIS.
Now.
Go, go, go!
TARDIS THRUMS
Ha! She did it!
Thank you, Doctor!
Vinder heading home, tick.
She really doesn't like it!
Are you sure this is going to work?
No, this has to work.
No margin for error.
TARDIS THRUMS
Yes! Temporal hop, 106 years,
done.
Now...for conversion.
I really hope this works.
Did she just freeze volcanoes
into steel?
Yes, I did.
Turning multiple planet-threatening
situations into public art!
You're welcome.
OK, don't get cocky.
Now, one last thing
and we're done.
Do you think we can let go yet?
DOCTOR: I'm sorry
for what was done to you.
I'm sorry that you were taken
and that you've been harnessed.
I'll see you released.
But I need one more thing
from you.
Channel your energy
down into this planet.
Disintegrate everything.
And then you'll be free!
Yes, that's it!
What a creature!
What a universe!
I'll never understand it.
HE YELLS
HE GROANS
MASTER: Doctor!
You lost.
You gambled and you lost.
And now your body is failing
because of
what you put it through.
Maybe.
But if I can't be the Doctor...
..neither can you.
SHE SHOUTS
She's fine.
She's fine!
DOCTOR GASPS SOFTLY
Extended fam.
RUMBLING
TARDIS THRUMS
Did we do it?
We did it.
Well, you did it.
Where is everyone?
I took them home.
Did you?
That's clever.
Well...
..Croydon, so close enough.
How long was I out?
A while.
CLOISTER BELL RINGS
DOCTOR GASPS
Why's the Cloister Bell ringing?
Doctor...
Look at your hand.
CLOISTER BELL CONTINUES RINGING
No!
SOFTLY: No.
That's not right.
I need more time.
I want more time!
CRIES OUT
You know what this means, right?
Yeah?
It's all right.
It's all right, Yaz.
One last trip.
Where would you choose?
What flavour ice cream?
BOTH LAUGH
CLOISTER BELL CONTINUES RINGING
How many times do you think
you've saved Earth?
I've lost count.
But look at it.
How could you not love
a planet like that?
I don't want it to end.
A wise person once said to me...
..goodbyes only hurt
because what came before
was so special.
Oh, and it's been so special.
You...
..and Graham...and Ryan...
and Dan.
Nobody else got to be us.
Nobody else got to live our days.
Nobody.
And my hearts are so full of love
of all of you.
Oh, I have loved
being with you, Yaz.
And I have loved being me.
I think I need to
do this next bit alone.
Let's not say goodbye.
TARDIS THRUMS
DISTANT ARGUING
GRAHAM: Look, it's definitely left,
not right.
DAN: Mate, I know
how to read a map.
Yeah, I understand that,
but...let me have a look.
I've got it here!
Just let me, please.
BOTH: Yaz!
How...? How is she?
How was she?
What are you doing here?
Didn't you get your invite?
I'm Graham. And...
..apparently I've got to be
the first one to talk, so...
CLEARS HIS THROAT
Right.
I have this problem.
See, I met this person,
and I got whooshed away
across all space and time.
I mean, I had the most amazing
adventures, really.
I mean, you wait till you hear,
cos I'm going to tell you 'em all.
LAUGHTER
But... But I came back,
and I actually can't tell anyone,
because...they'd have me put away.
LAUGHTER
And that's... That started me
thinking, though.
"I can't be the only one.
I can't."
And look! I'm not.
I reckon there are more people
out there too.
So maybe this is
where we share stories...
TARDIS THRUMS
..about the Doc.
I will also say...I may want
to recruit you for some work.
LAUGHTER
Dan.
I've, er...
I've only been back a month, and...
..I've got to say, I'm glad
I'm not on the verge of
being exterminated any more.
LAUGHTER
But I do miss her.
Sorry...did you say...
..her?
How many Doctors are there?
I think we're going to be here
quite some time.
Look after the next one.
You OK?
Is she OK?
Going to take in one last sunrise.
Of course she's OK.
She's the Doctor.
BIRDS CALL, WAVES LAP
Oh, the blossomiest blossom.
That's the only sad thing.
I want to know what happens next.
Right, then.
Doctor Whoever-I'm-about-to-be...
..tag,
you're it.
HE GASPS
I know these teeth.
What?
What?!