DOCTOR: Oh, it's a sanctuary base!
Deep space exploration.
"Welcome to hell.”
DOCTOR: What are you lot doing here?
-That's a black hole.
-But that's impossible.
This lump of rock is suspended
in perpetual geostationary orbit
around that black hole, without falling in.
There's some sort of power source
holding us here.
We're drilling down to try and find it.
The Tardis is gone.
Well, whatever it is down there,
it's not a natural phenomenon.
And there was some form of civilisation.
They buried something.
-What are they called?
-They're the Ood.
Basic slave race.
There's something happening with the Ood.
THE OOD: And you will worship him.
(GROWLING)
You can tell Toby
we've found his civilisation.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
These are the words of the Beast.
And he has woken.
I have been imprisoned for eternity.
But no more.
BEAST: The Pit is open
and I am free!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Open fire!
We're stabilising. We've got orbit.
Doctor? Doctor, can you hear me?
Doctor, Ida, are you there?
It's me!
But they're coming. It's the Ood.
-They've gone mad.
-How many of them?
All of them, all 50.
Danny, out of the way. Out of the way!
But they're armed. It's the interface device.
I don't know how,
but they're using it as a weapon.
Close door 1.
Open door 1. Close door 1.
Lockdown! Seal door 1!
DANNY: Seal door 25.
Seal door 24. Seal door 23/
Jefferson, what's happening there?
I've got very little ammunition, sir.
How about you?
All I've got is a bolt-gun with, uh,
all of one bolt.
I could take out a grand total of one Ood.
Fat lot of good that is.
Given the emergency,
I recommend strategy nine.
Strategy nine agreed.
Right, we need to get everyone together.
Rose, what about Ida and the Doctor?
Any word?
I can't get a reply. Just nothing.
I keep trying, but it's...
DOCTOR: No, sorry. I'm fine. Still here!
You could have said, you stupid...
(RADIO FEEDBACK)
Whoa, careful!
Anyway, it's both of us, me and Ida. Hello!
But the seal opened up. It's gone.
All we've got left is this chasm.
-ZACK: How deep is it?
-Can't tell. Looks like it goes down forever.
The Pit is open. That's what the voice said.
But there's nothing.
I mean, there's nothing coming out?
No, no, no. No sign of the Beast.
It said Satan.
Come on, Rose. Keep it together.
Is there no such thing? Doctor?
Doctor, tell me there's no such thing.
Ida, I recommend
that you withdraw immediately.
But we've come all this way.
Okay, that was an order. Withdraw!
When that thing opened,
the whole planet shifted.
One more inch
and we fall into the black hole
so this thing stops right now.
But it's not much better up there
with the Ood.
I'm initiating strategy nine
so I need the two of you
back up top immediately. No...
Ida? Ida?
What do you think?
He gave an order.
Yeah, but what do you think?
It said, "I am the temptation.”
If there's something in there,
why is it still hiding?
Maybe we opened the prison
but not the cell.
We should go down.
I'd go.
What about you?
Oh, in a second. But then again...
That is so human.
Where angels fear to tread.
Even now, standing on the edge,
it's that feeling you get, yeah?
Right at the back of your head.
That impulse, that strange little impulse.
That mad little voice saying,
"Go on, go on, go on.
"Go over, go on."
Maybe it's relying on that.
For once in my life, Officer Scott,
I'm going to say...
retreat.
Now I know I'm getting old.
Rose, we're coming back.
Best news I've heard all day.
What are you doing?
He's infected. He brought
that thing on board. You saw it.
Are you gonna start shooting your own
people now? Is that what you're gonna do?
-Is it?
-If necessary.
Well, then you'll have to shoot me,
if necessary. So what's it gonna be?
Look at his face. Whatever it was, it's gone.
It passed into the Ood. You saw it happen.
He's clean.
Any sign of trouble, I shoot him.
You all right?
Yeah.
-I don't know.
-Can you remember anything?
Just... It was so angry.
It was fury and rage and death.
It was him.
It was the Devil.
Come here.
DOCTOR: What's strategy nine?
IDA: Open the airlocks.
We'll be safe inside the lockdown.
The Ood will get thrown out
into the vacuum.
So we're going back to a slaughter?
The Devil's work.
IDA: Okay, we're in. Bring us up.
Ascension in three, two, one.
BEAST: This is the darkness.
This is my domain.
You little things that live in the light,
clinging to your feeble suns
which die, in the end...
ZACK: That's not the Ood.
Something is talking through them.
BEAST: Only the darkness remains.
This is Captain Zachary Cross Flane
of Sanctuary Base 6,
representing the Torchwood Archive.
You will identify yourself.
You know my name.
What do you want?
You will die here, all of you.
This planet is your grave.
It's him. It's him. It's him.
If you are the Beast, then answer me this.
Which one, hmm?
'Cause the universe has been busy
since you've been gone.
There's more religions
than there are planets in the sky.
The Arkiphets, Quoldonity,
Christianity, Pash Pash, Neo-Judaism,
San Claar, the Church of the Tin Vagabond.
Which devil are you?
All of them.
What, then you're the truth
behind the myth?
This one knows me as I know him.
The killer of his own kind.
How did you end up on this rock?
The Disciples of the Light
rose up against me
and chained me in the Pit for all eternity.
When was this?
Before time.
What does that mean?
What did "before time" mean?
Before time and light
and space and matter.
Before the cataclysm.
Before this universe was created.
That's impossible.
No life could have existed back then.
Is that your religion?
It's a belief.
You know nothing. All of you, so small.
The captain, so scared of command.
The soldier,
haunted by the eyes of his wife.
The scientist, still running from daddy.
The little boy who lied,
the virgin and the lost girl.
So far away from home.
The valiant child
who will die in battle so very soon.
-Doctor, what does that mean?
-Rose, don't listen.
What does it mean?
You will die
and I will live.
What the hell was that?
I had that thing inside my head.
-Doctor, what did it mean?
-What do we do?
Captain, what's the situation
with strategy nine?
...the black hole, everything's true!
We've lost pictures.
-How did it know...
-Did anyone get an analysis?
Jefferson.
Stop. Everyone, just stop!
-What do we do?
-Report...
(RADIO FEEDBACK)
If you want voices in the dark,
then listen to mine.
That thing is playing on very basic fears.
Darkness, childhood, nightmares,
all that stuff.
But that's how the Devil works.
Or a good psychologist.
How did it know about my father?
Okay, but what makes his version
of the truth any better than mine, hmm?
'Cause I'll tell you what I can see. Humans.
Brilliant humans. Humans who travel
all the way across space.
Flying in a tiny little rocket
right into the orbit of a black hole,
just for the sake of discovery.
That's amazing!
Do you hear me? Amazing. All of you.
The captain, his officer, his elder,
his juniors, his friends.
All with one advantage,
the Beast is alone, we are not.
If we can use that to fight against him...
The cable's snapped!
Get out!
Doctor, we lost the cable.
Doctor, are you all right?
Doctor?
-Comms are down.
-Doctor, can you hear me?
I've still got life-signs,
but we've lost the capsule.
-ROSE: Say something! Are you there?
-There's no way out.
They're stuck down there.
DOCTOR: How much air have we got?
Sixty minutes.
Fifty-five.
But we've got to bring them back.
They're ten miles down.
We haven't got another ten miles of cable.
(THUDDING)
Captain, situation report?
It's the Ood. They're cutting through
the door bolts. They're breaking in.
-Yes. Same on door 25.
-How long is it gonna take?
Well, it's only a basic frame.
Should take ten minutes.
Eight.
I've got a security frame, might last
a bit longer but that doesn't help you.
Right. So we need to stop them
or get out or both.
I'll take both, yeah? But how?
You heard the Doctor.
Why do you think that thing cut him off?
'Cause he was making sense.
He was telling you
to think your way out of this.
Come on! For starters,
we need some lights.
Zack, there's got to be
some sort of power somewhere.
There's nothing I can do. Some captain!
Stuck in here, pressing buttons.
That's what the Doctor meant.
Press the right buttons.
They've gutted the generators.
But the rocket's got an independent supply.
If I could reroute that...
Mr Jefferson, open the bypass conduits.
Override the safety.
Opening bypass conduits, sir.
Channelling rocket feed.
In three, two, one.
Power.
There we go!
-Let there be light!
-What about that strategy nine thing?
Not enough power, needs 100 percent.
Right, we need a way out. Zack,
Mr Jefferson, you start working on that.
-Toby, what about you?
-I'm not a soldier. I can't do anything.
No, you're the archaeologist.
What do you know about the Pit?
Nothing, we can't even
translate the language.
-Right.
-Hold on. Maybe...
What is it?
Since that thing was inside my head,
it's like the letters make more sense.
Well, get to work.
Anything you can translate, just, anything.
As for you, Danny boy,
you're in charge of the Ood.
-Any way of stopping them?
-Well, I don't know.
Then find out.
The sooner we get control of the base,
the sooner we can get the Doctor out.
Now get going. Shift.
We've got all this cable.
We might as well use it.
The drum is disconnected.
We could adapt it.
Feed it through.
DOCTOR: And then what?
Abseil into the Pit.
Abseil. Right.
We're running out of air with no way back.
It's the only thing we can do,
even if it's the last thing we ever achieve.
I'll get back. Rose is up there.
Well, maybe the key to that
is finding out what's in the Pit.
Well, it's half of a good plan.
What's the other half?
I go down, not you.
Open junctions five, six, seven.
Reroute filters 16 to 24. Go.
There's all sorts of viruses
that could stop the Ood.
Trouble is, we haven't got them on board.
Well, that's handy,
listing things we haven't got.
We haven't got a swimming pool either,
or a Tesco's.
Oh, my God. It says yes! I can do it!
Hypothetically, if you flip the monitor,
broadcast a flare,
it can disrupt the telepathy. Brainstorm!
-What happens to the Ood?
-It'll tank them, spark-out!
There we are, then. Do it!
I know, but...
I'd have to transmit
from the central monitor.
We need to go to Ood Habitation.
That's what we'll do, then.
-Mr Jefferson, sir, any way out?
-Just about.
There's a network of maintenance tunnels
running underneath the base.
We should be able to
gain access from here.
Ventilation shafts.
I appreciate the reference,
but there's no ventilation.
No air, in fact, at all.
They were designed for machines,
not life forms.
But I can manipulate
the oxygen field from here,
create discrete pockets of atmosphere.
If I control it manually,
I can follow you through the network.
Right. So we go down
and you make the air follow us by hand?
You wanted me pressing buttons.
Yep, I asked for it. Okay, we need to get
to Ood Habitation. Work out a route.
IDA: That should hold it. How's it going?
DOCTOR: Fine. Should work.
Doesn't feel like such a good idea now.
Hmm. There it is again. That itch.
Go down, go down, go down, go down!
The urge to jump.
Do you know where it comes from,
that sensation?
Genetic heritage.
Ever since we were primates in the trees.
It's our body's way of testing us,
calculating whether or not
we can reach the next branch.
No, that's not it. That's too kind.
It's not the urge to jump.
It's deeper than that.
It's the urge to fall.
Doctor!
-You okay?
-Not bad, thanks.
The wall of the Pit seems to be
the same as the cavern,
just not much of it.
There's a crust about 20 feet down.
And then...
nothing, just the Pit.
Okay, then. Lower me down.
Well, here we go, then.
-Danny!
-Hold on, just conforming.
Danny, we've got to go now. Come on.
There!
Put that in the monitor
and it's a bad time to be an Ood!
We're coming back.
We're coming back to this room
and we're getting the Doctor out.
Danny, you go first, then Miss Tyler,
then Toby. I'll go last in defensive position.
Now come on, quick as you can!
God, it stinks. You all right?
Yeah, laughing. Which way do we go?
Just go straight ahead.
Keep going till I say so.
Not your best angle, Danny.
Oi, stop it.
-Don't know, could be worse.
-ROSE: Oi!
Straight on till you find junction 7.1.
Keep breathing.
I'm feeding you air. I've got you.
We're at 7.1, sir.
Okay, I've got you.
I'm just aerating the next section.
Getting kind of cramped, sir.
Can't you hurry up?
-I'm working on half power here.
-Stop complaining.
-Mr Jefferson said stop complaining.
-I heard.
-He heard.
-The air's getting a bit thin.
-He's complaining now.
-I heard.
-Danny, is that you?
-I'm not exactly happy.
I'm just moving the air.
I've got to oxygenate the next section.
Now, keep calm or it's gonna feel worse.
(METALLIC RATTLING)
-What was that?
-Mr Jefferson, what was that?
-What was that noise?
-Captain, what was that?
The junction in Habitation 5
has been opened. It must be the Ood.
-They're in the tunnels.
-Open the gate.
-I've got to get the air in!
-DANNY: Just open it, sir!
-Where are they? Are they close?
-I can't tell. I can't see them.
The computer doesn't register Ood
as proper life forms.
Whose idea was that?
Open the gate!
Danny, turn left, immediate left!
The Ood, sir, can't you trap them?
Cut off the air?
Not without cutting off yours.
Danny, turn right, go right.
Go faster. They're gonna catch up.
I'll maintain defensive position.
-You can't stop!
-Miss Tyler, that's my job.
You've got your task, now see to it.
You heard what he said, now shift!
8.2, open 8.2!
Zack, open 8.2!
-I've got to aerate it.
-Open it now!
I'm trying!
Danny, stop it. That's not helping!
Zack, get it open!
Jefferson, I've got to open 8.2
by closing 8.1.
You've got to get past the junction,
now move!
That's an order, now move!
I'm gonna lose oxygen, Jefferson.
I can't stop the automatics!
That's it, come on, come on!
Danny, turn left and head for 9.2.
That's the last one.
Jefferson, you've got to move faster!
John! Move! Move!
-Mr Jefferson! Come on!
-Keep going!
(PANTING)
I regret to inform you, sir, I was a bit slow.
Not so fast these days.
I can't open 8.1, John.
Not without losing air for the others.
And quite right, too, sir.
I think I bought them a little time.
There's nothing I can do, John.
-I'm sorry.
-You've done enough, sir.
Made a very good captain
under the circumstances.
Might I ask, if you can't add oxygen
to this section,
can you speed up the process
of its removal?
I don't understand. What do you mean?
Well, if I might choose the manner
of my departure, sir,
lack of air seems more natural than, well...
let's say, death by Ood.
I'd appreciate it, sir.
Godspeed, Mr Jefferson.
Thank you, sir.
Report.
Officer John Maynard Jefferson, PKD...
deceased, with honours,
43K 2.1.
Zack, we're at the final junction.
9.2.
And, uh,
if my respects could be on record,
he saved our lives.
Noted. Opening 9.2.
ROSE: Lower 9.2! Zack, lower it!
DANNY: Back, back, back!
We can't go back.
Look, 8.2's sealed off. We're stuck!
Come on! Up!
Come on. Toby, come on!
Toby, get out of there!
Help me. Oh, my God! Help me!
It's this way!
Hurry up!
-Get it in.
-TOBY: Danny, get it done.
-Transmit!
-I'm trying. I'm trying. I'm getting it in...
Stop them!
ROSE: Danny, get that thing transmitting.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
You did it! We did it!
Yes! Oh, yes!
Zack, we did it. The Ood are down!
Now we've got to get the Doctor.
I'm on my way.
DOCTOR: You get representations
of the horned beast
right across the universe,
in the myths and legends
of a million worlds.
Earth, Draconia, Vel Consadine.
Daemos, the Kaled God of War.
It's the same image over and over again.
Maybe that idea came from somewhere,
bleeding through.
A thought at the back
of every sentient mind.
-Emanating from here?
-Could be.
But if this is the original,
does that make it real?
Does that make it the actual Devil, though?
Well, if that's what you want to believe.
Maybe that's what the Devil is
in the end, an idea.
That's it.
That's all we've got.
You getting any sort of read out?
Nothing.
Could be miles to go yet.
Or it could be 30 feet.
There's no way of telling.
I could survive 30 feet.
Oh, no, you don't. I'm pulling you back up.
What are you doing?
You bring me back, we're just
gonna sit there and run out of air.
-I've got to go down.
-But you can't.
Doctor, you can't!
Call it an act of faith.
I don't want to die on my own.
I know.
Doctor, are you there?
Doctor, Ida, can you hear me?
The comms are still down.
I can patch them through the central desk
and boost the signal.
Just give me a minute.
I didn't ask. Have you got any sort of faith?
Not really.
I was brought up
Neo-Classic Congregational.
Because of my mum, she was...
My old mum.
But, no, I never believed.
Neo-Classics. Have they got a devil?
No, not as such. Just, um...
the things that men do.
Same thing in the end.
What about you?
I believe... I believe
I haven't seen everything, I don't know.
It's funny, isn't it?
The things you make up, the rules.
If that thing had said it came
from beyond the universe, I'd believe it.
But before the universe?
Impossible.
Doesn't fit my rule.
Still, that's why I keep travelling.
To be proved wrong.
Thank you, Ida.
Don't go!
If they get back in touch...
If you talk to Rose, just tell her...
Tell her...
Oh, she knows.
ROSE: Doctor, are you there?
Doctor, Ida, can you hear me?
Are you there, Doctor?
He's gone.
What do you mean, he's gone?
He fell...
into the Pit.
And I don't know how deep it is,
miles and miles and miles.
What do you mean, he fell?
I couldn't stop him.
He said your name.
I'm sorry.
Ida?
There's no way of reaching you.
No cable, no backup.
You're ten miles down. We can't get there.
You should see this place, Zack.
It's beautiful.
I wanted to discover things,
and here I am.
We've got to abandon the base.
I'm declaring this mission unsafe.
All we can do is make sure
no one ever comes here again.
But we'll never find out what it was.
-Well, maybe that's best.
-Yeah.
-Officer Scott...
-It's all right.
Just go.
Good luck.
And you.
Danny, Toby, close down the feed-links.
Get the retrotopes online.
Then get to the rocket
and strap yourselves in. We're leaving.
I'm not going.
Rose, there's space for you.
No, I'm gonna wait for the Doctor,
just like he'd wait for me.
I'm sorry, but he's dead.
You don't know him.
'Cause he's not.
I'm telling you, he's not.
And even if he was, how could I leave him
all on his own, all the way down there?
No, I'm... I'm gonna stay.
Then I apologise for this.
Danny, Toby, make her secure.
No! No! No! Stop! No! Let me go!
Get off me! I'm not leaving! No!
I have lost too many people.
I am not leaving you behind.
Let's get her on board.
-Did that one just move?
-It's the telepathic field.
-It's reasserting itself!
-Move it. Get to the rocket! Move!
(GROANING SOFTLY)
(GASPING)
I'm breathing.
Air cushion to support the fall.
You can breathe down here, Ida.
Can you hear me, Ida?
Dislocating B clamp, C clamp.
Raising Blu-Nitro to maximum.
-Toby, how's the Negapact feed-line?
-Clear, ready to go, sir.
For God's sake, get us out of here!
Captain, I think we're gonna have
a problem passenger.
Keep an eye on her.
-It's all right, Rose. We're safe.
-I'm not going anywhere!
Get me out of this thing. Get me out!
And liftoff!
(WHOOPING)
The rocket.
Take me back to the planet.
-Take me back!
-Or what?
Or I'll shoot.
Would you, though? Would you really?
Is that what your Doctor would want?
I'm sorry, but it's too late anyway.
Take a look outside. We can't turn back.
This is what the Doctor would have wanted.
Isn't that right?
History of some big battle.
Man against Beast.
I don't know if you're getting this, Ida.
Hope so.
Anyway, they defeated the Beast
and imprisoned it.
And maybe that's the key.
Or the gate or the bars.
(LOW GROWLING)
What's the joke?
Just... We made it. We escaped.
-We actually did it.
-Not all of us.
We're not out of it yet.
We're still the first people in history
to fly away from a black hole.
Toby, read me the stats.
Gravity funnel holding, sir. Oh, it's holding.
I accept that you exist.
I don't have to accept what you are.
But your physical existence, I give you that.
(BEAST GROWLING SOFTLY)
I don't understand.
I was expected down here.
I was given a safe landing and air.
You need me for something. What for?
Have I got to...
I don't know, beg an audience or...
Is there a ritual?
Some sort of incantation
or summons or spell?
All these things I don't believe in,
are they real?
Speak to me! Tell me!
You won't talk or you can't talk.
Hold on, hold on.
Wait a minute. Just let me...
Oh! No. Yes! No.
Think it through.
You spoke before, I heard your voice.
An intelligent voice.
No, more than that. Brilliant!
But looking at you now, all I can see...
is beast.
The animal, just the body.
You're just the body, the physical form.
What's happened to your mind, hmm?
Where's it gone? Where's that intelligence?
Oh, no.
Stats at 53. Funnel stable at 66.5.
Hull pressure constant.
Smooth as we can, sir.
All the way back home.
Coordinates set for planet Earth.
You were imprisoned a long time ago.
Before the universe, after, sideways,
in between, it doesn't matter.
The prison is perfect.
It's absolute. It's eternal. Oh, yes!
Open the prison, the gravity field collapses.
This planet falls into the black hole.
You escape, you die. Brilliant!
But that's just the body.
The body is trapped, that's all.
The Devil is an idea.
In all those civilisations, just an idea.
But an idea is hard to kill.
An idea can escape.
The mind, the mind of the great Beast,
the mind can escape.
Oh, but that's it!
You didn't give me air, your jailers did!
They set this up all those years ago.
They need me alive.
Because if you're escaping,
then I've got to stop you!
If I destroy your prison,
your body is destroyed,
your mind with it.
But then you're clever enough
to use this whole system against me.
If I destroy this planet,
I destroy the gravity field.
The rocket.
The rocket loses protection,
falls into the black hole.
I have to sacrifice Rose.
(LAUGHING)
It doesn't make sense.
We escaped, but there's a thousand ways
it could have killed us.
It could have ripped out the air
or, I don't know, burnt us or anything.
But it let us go. Why?
-Unless it wanted us to escape.
-Hey, Rose, do us a favour.
Shut up.
Almost there. We're beyond the reach
of the black hole in 40, 39...
So that's the trap
or the test or the final judgement,
I don't know.
But if I kill you, I kill her.
Except that implies
in this big, grand scheme
of gods and devils,
that she is just a victim.
But I've seen a lot of this universe.
I've seen fake gods and bad gods
and demigods and would-be gods,
and out of all that,
out of that whole pantheon,
if I believe in one thing, just one thing,
I believe in her.
-What happened? What was that?
-What's he doing?
-We've lost the funnel! Gravity collapse!
-What does that mean?
We can't escape.
We're heading straight for the black hole.
This is your freedom! Free to die!
You're going into that black hole
and I'm riding with you!
It's the planet. The planet's moving.
It's falling.
-I'm the rage and the bile and the ferocity!
-It's Toby!
I am the prince and the fool and the agony!
-I'm the sin and the fear and the darkness!
-It's him!
Stay where you are. The ship's not stable.
What is he? What the hell is he?
I shall never die!
The thought of me is forever.
In the bleeding hearts of men,
in their vanity and obsession and lust!
Nothing shall ever destroy me. Nothing.
Go to hell.
Emergency shield!
We've still lost the gravity funnel.
We can't escape the black hole.
But we stopped him.
That's what the Doctor would have done.
Some victory.
We're going in.
The planet's lost orbit. It's falling!
The planet's gone.
-I'm sorry.
-Accelerate.
I did my best.
But, hey, the first human beings
to fall inside a black hole.
How about that?
History.
What happened?
We're turning.
We're turning around. We're turning away!
DOCTOR: (ON RADIO)
Sorry about the hijack, Captain.
This is the good ship Tardis.
First things first,
have you got a Rose Tyler on board?
I'm here! It's me! Oh, my God!
Where are you?
I'm just towing you home.
Gravity-shmavity.
My people practically invented black holes.
Well, in fact, they did.
Couple of minutes, we'll be nice and safe.
Oh, and Captain, can we do a swap?
Say, if you give me Rose Tyler,
I'll give you Ida Scott. How about that?
-She's alive!
-Yes. Thank you, God.
Bit of oxygen starvation,
but she should be all right.
I couldn't save the Ood.
I only had time for one trip.
They went down with the planet.
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Entering clear space. End of the line.
Mission closed.
I don't know. I can't remember.
Well, it looked like a box.
What do you mean, a box?
Well, down in the hold, a big blue box.
It just appeared. I don't know.
DOCTOR: Zack we'll be off now.
Have a good trip home.
And the next time
you get curious about something...
Oh, what's the point?
You'll just go blundering in.
The human race!
But, Doctor, what did you find down there?
That creature, what was it?
I don't know.
Never did decipher that writing.
But that's good.
The day I know everything,
I might as well stop.
What do you think it was, really?
I think we beat it.
That's good enough for me.
It said I was going to die in battle.
Then it lied.
Right! Onwards, upwards.
Ida, see you again maybe.
I hope so.
And thanks, boys!
Hang on though, Doctor,
you never really said.
You two, who are you?
Oh, the stuff of legend.
(WHOOSHING)
This is the final report of Sanctuary Base 6.
Officer Tobias Zed, deceased, with honours.
43K 2.1.
Also, Ood 1 Alpha 1,
deceased, with honours.
Ood 1 Alpha 2, deceased, with honours...
Lights!
I am your salvation.
(WHOOSHING)
The sound of the universe.
What does it mean?
-His name is the Doctor.
-Doctor what?
Find me that girl!
Here we are, complete strangers,
and I'm flashing you my knickers.
One step closer to catching the Doctor.
Don't I know you?