SAM GARNER: "New York,
the city of a million stories.
"Half of them are true, the other half
"Just haven't happened yet.
"Statues, the man said."”
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
"Living statues that moved in the dark.”
MAN: So, will you take the case,
Mr Garner?
Sure. Why not?
Because you don't believe me.
For $25 a day plus expenses,
I'll believe any damn thing you like.
But you don't believe
that statues can move.
(CHUCKLES) And you're right, Mr Garner.
They can't.
Of course they can't...
...when you're looking.
Good night, Mr Grayle.
GARNER: "The address Grayle gave me was
an apartment block near Battery Park.
"He said it was where the statues lived.
"I asked him
why he didn't go look himself.
"He didn't answer.
"Grayle was the scariest guy I knew.
"If something scared him,
"I kind of wanted to shake its hand."
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hello?
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
What the...
(FLOOR CREAKING)
(KNOCKS)
Hello? Anyone home?
(MAN GRUNTING SOFTLY)
Hello?
(KNOCKS)
Who are you?
They're coming for you.
They're going to send you back.
Who's coming? Back where?
In time. Back in time.
I'm you.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
(CRASHING STEPS)
You got to be kidding me.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
DOCTOR: “New York growls at my window,
"but I was ready for it.
"My stocking seams were straight,
my lipstick was combat-ready,
"and I was packing cleavage
that could fell an ox at 20 feet..."
Doctor, you're doing it again.
-I'm reading!
-Aloud. Please, could you not?
There's something different about you,
isn't there?
-What's the book?
-Melody Malone.
She's a private detective
in old town New York.
She's got ice in her heart
and a kiss on her lips
and a vulnerable side
she keeps well-hidden.
Oh, you've read it?
You read it, aloud,
and then went, "Yowzah!"
You know, only you
could fancy someone in a book.
I'm just reading. I just like the cover.
Ooh! Can we see the cover?
No. No, I'm busy.
It's your hair. Is it your hair?
Oh, shut up. It's the glasses.
I wear reading glasses now, on my nose.
See? There you go.
I don't like them.
They make your eyes look all liney.
No, actually. Sorry. They're fine.
Carry on.
Okay. I'm going to go and get us
some more coffee. Who wants more coffee?
-Me, too. I'll go.
-Rory?
Do I have
noticeable lines on my eyes now?
-Yes.
-No.
You didn't look.
I noticed them earlier...
Didn't notice them.
I specifically remember
not noticing them.
You're welcome on the firepit,
Centurion.
Do I have to come over there?
You can if you like.
-Well, we have company.
-I'll get a babysitter.
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
Do you know, it is so humiliating
when you do that.
-Coffee?
-Coffee.
Can I have a go?
Oh.
Actually, that is much better.
That is exciting.
Read to me.
I thought you didn't like
my reading aloud.
Shut up and read me a story.
Just don't go, "Yowzah!"
Why did you do that?
I always rip out the last page
of a book, then it doesn't have to end.
I hate endings.
"As I crossed the street,
I saw the thin guy.
"But he didn't see me.
"I guess that's how it began."”
(DISTORTED, SQUEAKY LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
"I followed the skinny guy
for two more blocks before he turned
"and I could ask
exactly what he was doing here.
"He looked a little scared,
"so I gave him my best smile
and my bluest eyes."
Beware the yowzah.
Do not, at this point, yowz.
Doctor? What did the skinny guy say?
He said, "I just went to get coffees
for the Doctor and Amy.
"Hello, River."
RIVER: Hello, Dad.
Where am I?
(WHISPERS) How the hell did I get here?
I haven't the faintest idea.
But you'll probably
want to put your hands up.
Melody Malone?
You're Melody!
Get in.
What's River doing in a book?
What's Rory doing in a book?
He went to get coffee. Pay attention.
He went to get coffee and turned up
in a book. How does that work?
I don't know. We're in New York.
What is going on?
Where did you get this book?
-It was in my jacket.
-How did it get there?
How does anything get there?
I've given up asking.
Date, date. Does she mention a date?
When is this happening?
Yes. Hang on. Uh...
Ooh! April 3rd, 1938.
(SIREN WAILING)
You didn't come here
in the Tardis, obviously.
-Why?
-You couldn't have.
Couldn't have?
What does she mean, "couldn't have"?
This city's full of time-distortions,
be impossible to land the Tardis here,
like trying to land a plane
in a blizzard.
Even I couldn't do it.
Even who couldn't do it?
Don't you two fall out.
She's only in a book.
(CHUCKLES) 1938. Easy one.
(ALARM BLARING)
What was that?
1938. We just bounced off it.
(ALARM STOPS)
RORY: Well, how did you get here?
Vortex manipulator.
Less bulky than a Tardis.
A motorbike through traffic.
You?
I'm...not sure.
AMY: The Weeping Angels.
DOCTOR: That makes sense.
AMY: Makes what?
DOCTOR: That's what happened to Rory.
That's what the Angels do.
It's their preferred form of attack.
They zap you back in time,
let you live to death.
Well, we've got a time machine.
We can just go and get him.
Well, tried that, if you've noticed,
and we are back where we started
in 2012.
We didn't start in a graveyard.
What are we doing here?
Don't know. Probably causally linked,
somehow. Doesn't matter.
Extractor fans on!
Well, we're going to get there somehow.
We're in the rest of the book.
I'm what?
Page 43,
you're going to break something.
I'm what?
"Why do you have to break mine?"
I asked the Doctor.
He frowned and said, "Because Amy read
it in a book and now I have no choice."
Stop! No, no. Stop!
You can't... You can't read ahead.
-You mustn't, and-and you can't do that.
-But we've already been reading it.
Just the stuff that's happening now,
in parallel with us.
-That's as far as we go.
-It could help us find Rory.
And if you read ahead
and find that Rory dies?
This isn't any old future, Amy,
it's ours.
Once we know what's coming, it's fixed.
I'm going to break something because
you told me that I'm going to do it.
-No choice now.
-Time can be rewritten.
Not once you've read it.
Once we know what's coming,
it's written in stone.
RIVER: Well, early Chin Dynasty,
I'd say.
GRAYLE: Correct.
Are you an archaeologist
as well as a detective?
Okay. Landing a plane
in a tiny-winy blizzard.
I could push through,
but if I'm out by a nanosecond,
the engines will phase
and I'll shatter the planet.
-I need landing lights.
-Landing lights?
Yes. I need a signal to lock on to.
What did she say? Early what dynasty?
Early Chin, just as you say.
You're very well-informed.
And you're very afraid.
That's an awful lot of locks
for one door.
RORY: River, I'm translating.
RIVER: It's a gift of the Tardis,
it hangs around.
This one,
put him somewhere uncomfortable.
-Oh, great.
-With the babies, sir?
Yes. Why not?
Give him to the babies.
Ah-ah-ah!
(RORY GROANS)
The lights are out.
You'll last longer with these.
What do you care?
(SCOFFS) It's funnier.
(DOOR LOCKING)
(SQUEAKY GIGGLING)
RORY: Hello?
(WHOOSHING)
Ah. Hello. Yes.
(EXCLAIMS SOFTLY)
Special permission from the Emperor.
Hello, sweetie!
Let's see.
Crime boss with a collecting fetish.
Whatever you don't want anyone else
to see has got to be your favourite,
or possibly your girlfriend.
So, girlfriend, then.
-(DEVICE BLEEPING)
-What are you doing?
Oh, you know, texting a boy.
(BEEPING)
Landing lights.
We have a signal. Locking on.
(GRUNTING)
GRAYLE: These things are all over
and people don't seem to notice.
It never moves while you're looking.
-Oh, I know how they work.
-So I understand.
Melody Malone,
the detective that investigates Angels.
-Badly damaged.
-I wanted to know if it could feel pain.
You realise it's screaming?
The others can hear.
Is that why you need all the locks?
(GASPS)
GRAYLE: You're going to tell me
all about these creatures.
And you're going to do it quickly.
(RIVER GASPS)
(SHUDDERING)
(FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
(HIGH-PITCHED GIGGLING)
RORY: Hello, is someone there?
(WINCES)
(FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
(GIGGLING CONTINUES)
Come on. Oh, come on!
The Angels are predators.
They're deadly.
What do you want with them?
I'm a collector.
What collector could resist these?
I'm only human.
That's exactly what they're thinking.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
What's that? What's happening?
Is it an earthquake?
What is it?
RIVER: Oh, you bad boy.
You could burn New York.
What does that mean?
It means, Mr Grayle,
just you wait till my husband gets home.
(GRAYLE SCREAMS)
Come on!
Just a moment. Final checks.
Since when?
Rory?
Sorry I'm late, honey.
Traffic was hell.
(CHUCKLES)
Shock.
-He'll be fine.
-Not if I can get loose.
So where are you now, Dr Song?
How's prison?
Oh, I was pardoned ages ago.
And it's Professor Song to you.
-Pardoned?
-Mmm.
Turns out the person I killed
never existed in the first place.
Apparently there's no record of him.
It's almost as if
someone's gone around deleting himself
-from every database in the universe.
-Mmm, you said I'd got too big.
And now no one's ever heard of you.
Didn't you used to be somebody?
Well, aren't you the woman
who killed the Doctor?
-Doctor who?
-Ha.
She's holding you very tight.
At least she didn't
send me back in time.
I doubt she's strong enough.
Well, I need a hand back.
So which is it going to be?
Are you going to break my wrist or hers?
Oh, no. Really?
Why do you have to break mine?
Because Amy read it in a book.
And now I have no choice.
-You see?
-Well, what book?
Your book.
Which you haven't written yet,
so we can't read.
I see. I don't like the cover much.
But if River's going to write that book,
she'd make it useful, yeah?
Well, I'll certainly try.
But we can't read ahead,
it's too dangerous.
I know, but there must be something
we can look at.
What, a page of handy hints,
previews, spoiler-free?
Chapter titles.
Hmm?
-He's in the cellar.
-Give me.
Doctor?
Doctor, what is it?
What's wrong? Tell me.
Doctor? Doctor, what is it? Tell me.
Okay. I know that face. Calm down.
-(GRUNTING) No!
-Calm down! Talk to me!
-Doctor?
-No!
You get your wrist out.
You get your wrist out
without breaking it.
-How?
-I don't know. Just do it!
Change the future!
Rory?
-No! They're Angels.
- (EXCLAIMS)
DOCTOR: Baby Angels.
Did they get Rory?
Where is he? Did they take him?
Yes, I think so. Yes.
(BABIES GIGGLING, FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
So, is this what's going to happen?
We just keep chasing him back in time
and they keep pulling him further back?
-(DEVICE CHIMES)
-He isn't back in time.
I'm reading a displacement
but there are no temporal markers.
He's been moved in space
but not in time
and it's not that far from here,
by the look of it.
You got out.
So, where is he?
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(PASSING VEHICLE HONKING)
(DEVICE BLEEPING)
Come on, come on, come on. Where is he?
If it was that easy,
I'd get you to do it.
But how did you get your wrist out
without breaking it?
You asked. I did. Problem?
(CHUCKLING)
You just changed the future.
It's called marriage, honey.
Now, hush. I'm working.
DOCTOR: She's good, eh?
Oh! Have you noticed?
Really, really good.
Ah. Wherever it is,
it's within a few blocks.
There's a car out front.
Shall we steal it?
Show me!
(GROANS)
(SHUDDERING)
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Okay. Um, when all those numbers
on both units go to zero,
that's when we've got a lock, okay?
-That's how we find Rory.
-Got it.
DOCTOR: Why did you lie to me?
When one's in love with an ageless god
who insists on the face
of a 12-year-old,
one does one's best to hide the damage.
-(SOFTLY) It must hurt. Come here.
-Yes.
The wrist is pretty bad, too.
(EXCLAIMS) No. No, no.
Stop that. Stop that. Stop it!
There you go.
How's that?
Well...
Let's see, shall we?
That was a stupid
waste of regeneration energy.
Nothing is gained
by you being a sentimental idiot!
-River!
-No! You embarrass me.
River!
Tell you what.
Stick to the science part.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Okay. Why did you lie?
Never let him see the damage.
And never ever let him see you age.
He doesn't like endings.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
There you are.
Got it!
He's in a place called Winter Quay.
The car. Yes, let's go.
(GROANING)
(EXCLAIMS SOFTLY)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
RIVER: Why would they send him here?
Why not zap him back in time
like they normally do?
We'll know that
when we know what this place is.
(DEVICE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
AMY: Winter Quay.
-Rory?
-RIVER: He's close.
Rory!
-Rory.
-Amy.
(DEVICE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Doctor.
Look at this.
Why's it smiling?
Amy. Rory!
Get out of here.
Don't look at anything. Don't touch...
Who's that?
(GROANS)
Amy.
Amy, please...
(COUGHING)
Amy.
Please.
Rory?
He's here.
Amy.
Would someone please tell me
what is going on?
I'm sorry, Rory.
But you just died.
DOCTOR: This place is policed by Angels.
Every time you try to escape,
you get zapped back in time.
So, this place belongs to the Angels?
They built it?
Displacing someone back in time
creates time energy.
And that is what the Angels feed on.
But normally, it's a one-off,
a hit-and-run.
If they could keep hold
of their victims,
feed off their time energy
over and over again...
This place is a farm. A battery farm.
How many Angels in New York?
It's like they've taken over
every statue in the city.
Yeah, the Angels take Manhattan
because they can.
Because they've never had
a food source like this one.
The city that never sleeps.
(CRASHING FOOTSTEPS IN DISTANCE)
What was that?
I don't know.
But I think they're coming for you.
What does that mean?
What is going to happen to me?
What is physically going to happen?
The Angels will come for you.
They'll zap you back in time
to this very spot,
30, 40 years ago.
And you will live out
the rest of your life in that room
until you die in that bed.
And will Amy be there?
-No.
-How do you know?
Because he was so pleased
to see you again.
Okay.
Well, they haven't taken me yet.
What if I just run?
What if I just get the hell out of here?
-Then that never happens.
-It already happened, Rory.
You've just witnessed your own future.
Doctor, he's right.
No, he isn't.
If Rory got out,
it would create a paradox.
(CRASHING CONTINUES)
-What is that?
-This is the Angels' food source.
The paradox poisons the well.
It could kill them all.
Oh, this whole place
would literally un-happen.
It would be almost impossible.
Loving the "almost".
But to create a paradox like that
takes almost unimaginable power.
What have we got, hey? Tell me.
Come on. What?
I won't let them take him.
That's what we got.
(CRASHING FOOTSTEPS GETTING CLOSER)
Whatever that thing is,
it is getting closer.
DOCTOR: Rory.
Even if you got out, you'd have to
keep running for the rest of your life.
They would be chasing you forever.
Well, then, better get started.
Husband, run!
-River, I'm not sure this can work.
-Husband, shut up.
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMS)
-Up. \ hat good's up -W
Better than down.
-We can't keep doing this.
-Any ideas?
Yeah, the usual.
Run!
Um, okay. Fire escape.
RORY: I always wanted to visit
the Statue of Liberty.
I guess she got impatient.
What? What is it? What?
Just keep your eyes on that.
-Oh, God.
-Is there a way down?
RORY: Uh...
No. But there's a way out.
What are you doing?
RORY: Oh.
AMY: Rory, what are you doing?
Rory?
-Stop it. You'll die.
-Yeah. Twice.
In the same building, on the same night.
Who else could do that?
Just come down, please.
This is the right thing to do.
This will work.
If I die now, it's a paradox, right?
The paradox killed the Angels.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Go on.
Please, because I am really scared.
Great.
It's the one time you can't manage it.
(BOTH GASP)
Oh, God.
Amy.
I'm going to...need a little help here.
-No. Just stop it.
-No, just think it through.
This will work.
This will kill the Angels.
-It will kill you, too.
-Will it?
River said that this place would be
erased from time, never exist.
But if this place never existed,
what did I fall off?
You think you'll just come back to life?
-When don't I?
-Rory.
And anyway, what else is there?
Die of old age downstairs,
never seeing you again?
Amy, please,
if you love me, then trust me
and push.
-I can't.
-You have to!
Could you?
If it was me, could you do it?
To save you,
I could do anything.
Prove it.
-No, I can't take you, too.
-You said we'd come back to life.
Money where your mouth is time.
-Amy, pl...
-Shut up.
Together
or not at all.
What the hell are you doing?
AMY: Changing the future.
It's called marriage.
Amy!
Doctor!
What's happening?
The paradox. It's working.
The paradox is working!
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(BOTH GASP)
-Where are we?
-Back where we started.
You collapsed the timeline.
The paradox worked.
We all pinged back where we belong.
What? In a graveyard?
This happened last time.
Why always here?
Does it matter? We got lucky.
We could have blown New York
off the planet.
I can't ever take
the Tardis back, though,
the timelines are too scrambled.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
I could have lost you both.
Don't ever do that again.
RORY: What did... What did we do?
We fixed it. We solved the problem.
I was talking to myself.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(EXHALES)
It could do with a repaint.
-I've been busy.
-Does the bulb on top need changing?
-I just changed it.
-So, Rory and Amy, then.
Yes, I know. I know.
I'm just saying.
They're going to get terribly bored
hanging round here all day.
-Doctor.
-Ha!
Look, next time,
can we just go to the pub?
DOCTOR:
I want to go to the pub right now.
Aren't there video games there?
I love video games.
Right. Family outing, then.
Amy.
-Come and see this.
-What?
There's a gravestone here
for someone with the same name as me.
What?
Doctor?
Ah.
Where the hell did that come from?
It's a survivor.
Very weak, but keep your eyes on it.
Where's Rory?
I'm sorry.
Amelia, I'm so, so sorry.
No. No, we can just go and get him
in the Tardis.
One more paradox.
Would rip New York apart.
-That's not true. I don't believe you.
-Mother, it's true.
Amy, what are you doing?
That gravestone, Rory's,
there's room for one more name,
isn't there?
What are you talking about?
Back away from the angel.
Come back to the Tardis.
We'll figure something out.
The angel, would it send me back
to the same time, to him?
I don't know. Nobody knows.
-But it's my best shot, yeah?
-No!
Doctor, shut up! Yes. Yes, it is.
-Amy...
-Well, then.
-I just have to blink, right?
-No!
It will be fine. I know it will.
I'LL be with him. Like I should be.
Me and Rory together.
Melody?
Stop it! Just, just stop it!
You look after him.
And you be a good girl
and you look after him.
DOCTOR: You are creating fixed time.
I will never be able to see you again.
I will be fine. I'll be with him.
DOCTOR: Amy, please.
Just come back into the Tardis.
Come on, Pond, please.
Raggedy Man,
goodbye.
DOCTOR: No!
(WHOOSHING)
(SCREEN HUMS)
(RIVER TYPING)
River.
They were your parents.
Sorry. I didn't even think.
It doesn't matter.
-Of course it matters.
-What matters is this, Doctor.
Don't travel alone.
Travel with me, then.
(TARDIS STARTS UP)
Whenever and wherever you want.
But not all the time.
One psychopath per Tardis,
don't you think?
(TARDIS HUMMING)
Okay.
This book I've got to write,
Melody Malone.
I presume I send it to Amy
to get it published?
Yes. Yes.
I'LL tell her to write an afterword.
For you.
Maybe you'll listen to her.
The last page!
AMY: "Afterword by Amelia Williams.
"Hello, old friend.
"And here we are. You and me.
"On the last page.
"By the time you read these words,
Rory and I will be long gone.
"So know that we lived well
and were very happy.
"And above all else,
know that we will love you always.
"Sometimes I do worry about you, though.
"I think once we're gone,
"you won't be coming back here
for a while
"and you might be alone,
which you should never be.
"Don't be alone, Doctor.
"And do one more thing for me.
"There's a little girl
waiting in a garden.
"She's going to wait a long while,
so she's going to need a lot of hope.
"Go to her, tell her a story.
"Tell her that if she's patient,
“the days are coming
that she'll never forget.
"Tell her she'll go to sea
and fight pirates.
"She'll fall in love with a man
"who'll wait 2,000 years
to keep her safe.
"Tell her she'll give hope
to the greatest painter who ever lived
"and save a whale in outer space.
"Tell her this is the story
of Amelia Pond
"and this is how it ends."
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)