ASHAD: The Cybermen
were defeated.
The victors of
a billion battles, broken.
An empire of might and terror,
fallen.
Their weaknesses exploited.
Their armies outfought.
Their conquests surrendered.
Every empire has its time.
And every empire falls.
But that which is dead
can live again...
...in the hands of a believer.
(BABY GURGLES)
MICHAEL: And you say
you just found it in the lane?
I did.
Like that?
Like that.
No note?
We'll look after him.
(STAMMERS)
Until you find the parents.
That's right.
(BABY CRIES)
Well?
It's official.
(MEG GASPS)
He's ours!
Oh!
(BOTH LAUGH)
Oh, our beautiful baby boy.
Aren't you, Brendan?
- Woohoo!
- There you go.
Let's go. Let's go.
- Ready for your first day?
- Yeah.
- Oh, oh, in you go!
- Argh!
The muscles of ya! Good lad.
That's a good lad.
Oh!
Aaah...
If it gets worse,
I'll call the doctor.
(PANTING)
Half a mile out.
The exact coordinates
Shelley gave us...
...are just down there.
GRAHAM: You want us to lug
all this stuff down there?
What's wrong, Graham?
Can't take
the commando lifestyle?
RYAN: Hey!
No commando jokes, please.
I don't need that image
in me head.
Any ideas
what we're walking into?
This planet, this time period -
we're in the very far future,
immediate aftermath
of the Cyber Wars.
Cybermen have hunted down
and wiped out
the majority of the human race.
Sorry. It was never a good time
to break that news to you.
If it's any consolation,
it almost wiped out
the Cybermen too.
Yeah, but almost
isn't good enough, is it?
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- No.
I'm getting a handful
of human life signs down there.
When you say a handful,
how much are we talking?
Seven.
- Seven humans left?
- If I had to guess,
I'd say that's the last
remaining human settlement
this side of the universe
right now.
How are the repairs?
Piece of cake.
Gravraft's completely fixed,
completely fine,
we're good to go.
- Really?
- No.
But you always look at me
with those puppy dog eyes
and say, "Please tell me
it's good news."
How long will it take?
A day, maybe more.
I promise
I'm doing everything I can.
I know you are, but those
last signal bursts indicated
- that we don't...
- (REVERBERATING BOOM)
It's too soon.
You said
there weren't any more.
You said they wouldn't find us!
- They always find us.
- I said I hoped
there weren't any left.
You said it was too good
to be true.
Yeah, well, sometimes
I just want to be wrong.
Question -
would you like some help?
(BLASTER POWERS UP)
You don't need to use that
against us.
Who are you?
Where did you come from?
Doctor, Graham, Ryan and Yaz.
Don't worry about
where we're from -
concentrate on how we can help.
(BLASTER POWERS DOWN)
All right. Set this all up
like I showed you.
(SONIC BUZZES)
Two cyber shuttles,
just landing.
- Who's in charge?
- I-I guess
I am, as much as anyone is.
Fought Cybermen before?
No. We've run from them.
- Escape craft?
- Damaged in planet fall.
I've been trying to fix it,
but we've got no spare parts.
- I've botch-built a couple...
- Don't need your life story.
Get everybody
into the buildings
and tell them, do not run.
Please, do as I say.
You can trust us.
GRAHAM: Bish bash bosh.
- What's that?
- This, cockle,
- is a neural inhibitor system.
- A what?
Yeah, I didn't have a clue
either.
As far as I understand it,
your basic Cyberman
is part-human,
part-machine.
Now, they have suppressed
all emotion
and sensations of pain,
which means
if we can un-suppress those
and they realise what's
happening to their bodies,
it sends them a bit mad,
which is one way
of stopping them.
And that is what this gizmo
is supposed to be doing.
- And will it definitely work?
- Well, I hope so, son,
cos we've come a long way.
Now, do us a favour,
get yourself safe.
There's a good lad.
- What is that thing?
- Particle projector.
The Doctor's customised it
to project particles of gold
into the air.
Cybermen are allergic to gold,
right?
I did hear that once.
I'm going to go and get
the gravraft going.
- Force field?
- Yeah.
Hmm. Yeah, pretty rudimentary.
Yeah, well,
you got a better one?
We ain't got nothin'.
Oi, Fuskle! Here.
He's my little brother.
He don't say much,
not any more.
It's a force field, mate.
And people.
It's got to be good news.
Will you tell him what it does?
It's for any Cyberman
that comes near.
See?
We're going to be all right.
Yedlarmi. And Fuskle.
Well, give him your hand, then.
If you're not going to speak,
at least give him your hand.
- (SONIC BUZZES)
- What are you doing?
Trying to see
where they're coming from.
But they're sending
a jamming signal,
trying to confuse us as to
what they are and how many.
What weapons have you got,
Feekat?
Two guns - one's broken.
So basically nothing?
We're not soldiers.
I was a teacher.
Ravio was a nurse.
We've got a childminder,
a driver, a builder.
We're just ordinary humans,
refugees,
and we've all
lost everything...
...and everyone.
All to the Cybermen.
And nobody cares.
I care.
Me and my friends, we care.
Please,
get inside the building.
We'll fight whatever's coming.
(REVERBERATING BOOM)
Activation time, fam!
Get close. I don't know
how many they are
or which direction
they're coming from.
Quick!
(PROJECTOR POWERS UP)
(ELECTRIC BUZZING)
(WHOOSHING)
Hey. Do you hear that sound?
Stay. Seriously, mate.
I know you're scared.
We're all scared.
Cyberdrones.
Fam, get down!
They're targeting the defences!
(GRAHAM YELLS)
Fuskle!
DOCTOR: No!
Get down!
I said don't run!
Come on!
(YELLS)
Fuskle, don't run!
- No!
- Get back here!
- Fuskle!
- GRAHAM: We can't outrun them!
Fuskle!
Argh!
FEEKAT: Stay in here.
- (DRONES SHRIEK)
- (WHOOSHING)
(UNSTEADY BREATHING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
Please. Run. Get to your ship.
I am sick of running.
- I want to fight 'em.
- It won't be
a fight, it'll be a massacre.
The drones
are just the advance guard.
I'll buy you some time.
Go. Now!
Come on.
Let's go. You and Ravio
get the gravraft started.
Ethan and I
will grab the supplies.
The systems didn't stop 'em,
Doc.
I know.
They destroyed everything
we brought with us.
- I know.
- We haven't got
anything else
to defend ourselves
- or them.
- I know!
(METALLIC RUMBLING)
Listen to me. Do not argue.
Go with the humans.
Help them.
Get them out of here.
You won't make it
back to the TARDIS alive.
Make sure you're with them.
- What about you?
- I'll hold them off.
How are you going to do that?
- This isn't a discussion.
- We're not
- just going to leave you.
- Yes, you are!
You have to, all of you.
No questions. Get out.
I've been so reckless with you.
- What are you talking about?
- You're human!
If they capture you,
they'll convert you.
(CLUNKING FOOTSTEPS)
I'll find you.
Get safe - now!
(CLUNKING FOOTSTEPS)
Yeah, me again!
(WHIR)
Here to stop you for good
this time.
It's just you and me.
(STOMPING FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
CYBERGUARD:
Strategic defences destroyed.
- Life signs identified.
- Or not.
All humans will be deleted.
Rethink.
Keep the others safe.
Act as bait. See ya!
GRAHAM: Go, go, go!
(YAZ YELPS)
Three targets acquired. Delete.
RYAN: Keep going!
(YAZ SCREAMS)
Surrender, humans.
YAZ: Get out of here!
There are Cybermen behind us!
We're not ready.
I haven't got Feekat and Ethan.
Listen to Yaz - get inside.
Graham, where's Ryan?
Get inside the gravraft!
No, no, we've got to find
our friends!
Get inside
if you want to stay alive!
- Ryan!
- Get inside!
Go! Expedite takeoff - now!
What are you doing?
We can't take this lot.
(SHOTS RICOCHETING)
Fuskle's dead because
their stuff didn't work.
Yedlarmi, I'm sorry.
Their weapons
are going to destroy
the outer shell -
we need to go now!
- Not without the others.
- The others are dead.
We all know it's true.
If they haven't got here
by now,
that thing must've got 'em.
Look, we've only come in here
for shelter,
and our friends
are still out there.
Sit down!
Our friends are still outside!
No! You need to let us out!
It's too late.
(BANG!)
(GRUNTS)
Shh!
What are you still doing here?
I told you to get out.
We got separated.
- (BEEPING)
- Hey, what's that?
Final fallback option
to get us out alive.
(SONIC BUZZES)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(WHIRRING)
What's it doing?
Shh!
I know you're here.
Surrender!
WHISPERS: Hey.
Stay here.
- Ethan, no!
- ETHAN: I'm here.
It's just me.
No-one else.
I surrender.
You can take me.
You show courage.
But you're a liar!
So few of you now.
Should I let you live?
You could tell the tale -
speak of their deaths,
of my power,
to every other species.
Spread my message.
Tell them, "Be afraid.
"All humanity have been erased.
"All Llife will fall.
"And the Cybermen
will rise again."
Not if I have
anything to do with it.
Run!
Go!
Doctor, we've got to find Yaz
and Graham.
I saw them get on the gravraft.
They're gone.
What?
Concentrate, Ryan,
we have to get out of here.
We can't make it to the TARDIS,
no escape ship,
a relentless Cyberman
and very limited options.
Well, one option.
How fast are you feeling?
Come on.
RYAN: Are we going
to steal their ship?
DOCTOR: Yes, we are!
Hot-wiring a Cyberfighter.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, it's warp.
Of course! Which makes it
trickier, unless you're me,
which I am, which is good,
cos I used to hot-wire
warp drives for fun
on a weekend as a teenager.
Not that we had weekends.
Or teenagers.
Basically, I used to do this
a lot and people got mad.
But now it's going
to save all our lives,
so who was right all along
and is now the real winner?
There's a faster way.
Here. Let me.
Hey, do you need help
with that, kid?
Who are you calling kid?
(SHIP POWERS UP)
This is going to
make him cross.
Here we go.
Hold on. Hate these controls.
(GRUNTS)
CYBERGUARD: Cyber shuttle theft
in progress, leader.
Human life signs aboard.
(GROWLS)
- Mam!
- Sorry.
Very smart.
Ready, then, son?
It's a good form.
You've done a good job on this.
Very neat handwriting.
And why do you want to be
a guard, Brendan?
He wants to serve.
Best leave the lad to
speak for himself, eh, Pat?
Right.
I wanna make a difference.
I was with him
the day he found you.
Look at you now.
GRAHAM: Yaz, where are we?
What are we doing here?
I think we're stuck
with this lot.
How are we going to get back
to the Doc and Ryan?
Don't worry, we'll find them.
Well, and how
are we going to do that?
Me and you, together?
No-one else stands a chance.
(BEEPING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
you're pushing it too hard.
Don't tell me
how to work this thing.
Who's the one who salvaged
this thing in the first place?
Yeah, and who patched it up?
You'll wreck it if you push it
past half power, seriously.
Look how low
the life support has got.
We won't get there
at anything less than 90%.
We won't make it at all
if you push it past 90!
Make it where?
To Ko Sharmus.
And the Boundary.
It's where we've been trying
to get to.
Our only point of safety.
Yeah,
that's what we've been told.
You've got to believe,
Yedlarmi.
Do we?
- How's that working for us?
- It's the best we've got.
And what Boundary
are you talking about?
Supposedly
a way out of this galaxy.
A gateway,
a direct route out of here,
into another random part
of the universe.
We get through there,
the Cybermen can't follow.
The Boundary patterns
are never the same twice.
It's our best hope
of safe harbour.
Energy parcelling's cratering.
Didn't I say
you were pushing it too hard?!
- It's fine.
- What did I tell you?
- It's fine!
- 14 breaches
- in the shell lining.
- Oxygen pressure's dropping.
Energy cells compromised.
Contents getting critical.
- Ah!
- OK, it's not fine.
The whole system's
melting down!
It can't, not here.
It's going to blow. Get down!
(ALARM BLARES)
- (BOOM)
- (RYAN GROANS)
This is rough.
It's making me feel sick.
Cyber warp tech -
not designed for humans. Ooh!
Have a humbug.
It'll help. Added ginger.
I've programmed in
the destination of Ko Sharmus.
It's where the others
will be heading.
Now, if this is warp drive,
we'll get there before them.
I've been scanning,
but I can't see them.
Maybe we're already ahead.
What?
You're good at this.
First thing my dad taught me.
How to hijack Cyberships,
how to take 'em apart,
how to burn 'em to the ground.
I was four.
Born in wartime.
So this is all
you've ever known?
The war made us pariahs,
cos of what was
always coming for us.
The last Cybermen,
intent on destroying
the last humans.
(THE DOCTOR YELPS)
Ah! Here he is, the bad penny.
We were just talking
about you.
We know where you are.
We will find you.
Yeah, yeah. Have you not asked
that great slab of Cyber Al
you absorbed about me?
I'm the Doctor.
Consult the Cyberium, mate.
I've stopped you lot
so many times before,
and I'll do it again,
time after time after time.
No.
The Cyberium does know you.
Both you and humanity
will be destroyed,
and I shall bring
the Cyber race
to its greatest ever glory.
Quite a grudge
you've got against humanity,
especially considering
you used to be one.
When the glorious
Cyber Empire arrived,
I was a willing recruit.
But as I took
my rightful place,
as I began
my blessed ascension...
...] was denied.
At first...
...I cursed myself,
hid in the shadows, ashamed.
But now I understand
I was not discarded.
I was chosen...
...to revive the glory
of the Cyber race.
There's no glory
in being a Cyberman.
And there's definitely no glory
in you.
I mean, talk about
an identity crisis.
You despise who you are.
That anger and hatred
that's driving you?
Those are human emotions.
The real Cybermen,
they don't do emotions.
So you loathe your own being
because of what's driving you.
Now that's what I call
an inner conflict.
Yes.
You are correct.
Oh. Am I? I didn't expect you
to take it that well.
I'll have to bill you
for therapy at this rate.
The Cyberium
has given me understanding.
It has distilled my purpose.
I am the perfect vessel.
Everything is in me
for the ascension
of the Cybermen...
...and beyond.
What do you mean beyond?
What's beyond that?
All your deaths.
The death of everything...
...is within me.
BRENDAN: Stop there, thief!
Eh, come on, then.
Give me the bag.
Everybody gets
their stuff back.
(GUN COCKS)
You don't need to do that.
Move round now.
All right, all right.
Look, I know
you don't want to use that.
(GUNSHOT)
(THUD)
Brendan!
Brendan...
(GASPS FOR AIR)
(BREATHES ERRATICALLY)
I-I'm fine.
I'm fine!
Which way did he go?
Come on.
I was lucky.
MEG: It's a lovely picture.
You look very dashing.
Ma, put it away.
(GROANING)
(GRAHAM EXHALES)
We're still alive!
- Give it time.
- I wish you was
a bit more glass half-full,
sunshine.
He's right, though.
If anyone's got any heartfelt
end-of-life speeches,
now is probably the moment.
Er...
Well...
Oh, God, you're not actually
going to do that, are you?
There must be
something we can do.
(FLICKS SWITCHES)
Why is all this shut down?
We've got to conserve
what little power
we've got left.
(METALLIC THUD)
What was that?
(SCRAPING)
I don't know.
Any idea where we are?
Middle of space.
Dying slowly.
Yes, thank you, Eeyore,
I got that much.
Oi, you.
How many times have we had
to get out of trouble together?
There's only three of us now.
We're just the scraps.
Yeah, but we're still not gonna
go down without a fight.
(THUD)
YAZ: What are those noises?
We were passing through
the old battlegrounds
when everything failed.
Who knows what's out there?
I'm going to take a look.
Oi, careful, will ya?
(THUD)
What's out there? Can you see
what's making the noises?
Yeah.
I can.
(THUDS CONTINUE)
And?
Bits of dead Cybermen...
...floating in space.
Must be one of
the last battle sites.
They're definitely dead,
though, right?
Look, we're turning.
What else can you see?
Dormant ships.
Loads of 'em.
That's hope right there.
Right, Graham?
Yaz, jump down,
let's have a look.
There you go, look.
Now, that one at the front,
there's an opening in it,
like a docking bay.
If we could just get in there,
and get across there...
We'd never reach it.
We don't have the power.
Well, what about life support?
Yeah.
Channel the remaining energy
of those systems.
That's what you need -
burst of acceleration.
It might work.
We could vent the air pressure.
It could spin us enough.
We'll lose all the oxygen,
we'll be dead.
We're dead anyway!
At least let's have a go, eh?
- OK.
- YEDLARMI: So,
we channel every last bit
of life support
towards propulsion.
Everything off.
Shut everything down.
Any system that's still got
even the tiniest hint of power
has got to go.
- YEDLARMI: We must be mad.
- YAZ: Not mad.
Hopeful.
- OK.
- Don't panic.
And don't take
any deep breaths,
cos they ain't gonna come.
We've been stranded
in space before.
GRAHAM: Yeah.
Here we go.
Yeah.
- (ALARM BLARES)
- Woo!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS, EXHALES)
We landed.
I think we did! (LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
YEDLARMI:
Look at the size of this place.
RAVIO: We must've come in
through the docking bay
entrance.
BESCOT: Well, good job
they left the doors open.
We triggered automation sensors
as we came in,
set everything going again.
You two are lucky.
We're not lucky, sunshine.
We're persistent -
we never give up.
Luckily for you.
- Let's have a look around.
- Right.
CYBERGUARD 1:
Exiting warp, leader.
The trail of the human craft
ends here.
CYBERGUARD 2: Human life signs
registering on carrier ship.
Yes.
The Cyberium sees all.
Their destiny and ours,
intertwined.
The site
of our greatest defeat...
...and soon a shrine
for our rebirth.
THE DOCTOR ON COMMS:
Shuttle calling Ko Sharmus.
Anyone hear me?
Anyone there on Ko Sharmus,
talk to me.
Please?
What I'd give for
a friendly voice right now.
Go on, pleeease.
Shuttle calling Ko Sharmus.
(SHAKILY)
Ko Sharmus responding.
Hello? Hello?
We've made it!
This is the Doctor, who's that?
I've told you.
This is Ko Sharmus.
Ko Sharmus?
You're a person, not a planet?
Wh-who are you?
What do you want?
We're human.
We've come to cross
the Boundary.
No, I don't think so.
What do you mean?
There are no more humans.
Well, we've got news for you.
First things first,
we're on a stolen Cybership,
but we're not Cybermen,
we're friendly,
and there's more on the way.
Very much looking forward
to meeting you.
Now forgive me,
I need to jump off.
I have to land this thing
properly.
(GRINDING)
I'll just park this thing
over the ridge.
RAVIO: (EXHALES)
It's so cold in here.
Ah, see?
That is cos you're alive
and breathing, cos of us.
Are you going to keep
going on about that?
Yes - every hour on the hour.
(LAUGHS)
What are you laughing at?
You.
What about me?
You've come a long way,
Graham O'Brien.
Thanks, Yaz.
I raided
one of these carriers once -
nearly got fried to death.
Good times.
Cyber Control should be
just down here.
Wait.
Is this a Cybership?
War carrier.
We get this working,
it can get us to Ko Sharmus,
maybe even find your friends.
GRAHAM: War carrier?
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
What was it carrying?
YEDLARMI: This is
the control deck all right.
- (POWERS UP)
- Systems still intact.
Full power banks.
This'll get us to Ko Sharmus.
We could even use it
to cross the Boundary.
Use it as a settlement ship
till we find
the best habitable planet.
- Yeah, that could work.
- Oh, careful,
son, you sounded slightly
positive there for a sec.
I'm going to take a look around
the rest of the carrier,
see what else is here.
I'll come with you -
it's safer with two.
Go careful.
GRAHAM: I was born careful!
That's actually true.
It's going to take a while
to reboot -
have to go one section
at a time.
(METALLIC CREAKING)
Level 139.
It's always been
my favourite level.
It's as good as any.
At least he's got the power
back on, though, eh?
(WHOOSHING)
- (THUD)
- Aah!
They must have got us moving.
Yeah.
You know, I'm starting to think
we're in with a good chance
of surviving today.
Oh, not just today -
you've still got a lot of life
ahead of you.
Yeah, well,
I hope you're right.
How do you reckon we get in?
(DOORS CREAK)
(AIR HISSES)
Right. Let's have a butcher's.
Butcher's hook?
Look?
It's cockney rhyming slang.
No, don't worry about it.
You are really strange.
Excuse me,
I'm the most normal bloke
you're ever going to meet.
No, strange is a compliment!
I like strange.
Oh?
Oh...
Well...
(MACHINERY POWERS UP)
What do you reckon these are,
then?
- (CLANK)
- (POWERS UP)
Oop. Hello.
- (DOOR CREAKS)
- (RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
This was a troop carrier...
...bringing soldiers
to the front.
Fresh Cybermen ready to fight.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZES)
Warrior class.
GRAHAM: There's got to be over
a thousand Cybermen in here.
I counted ten doors
on each level.
Well, how many levels
on this ship?
Several hundred.
And we're in the middle
of stealing it.
We are home.
The Cyberium
has called me to this task.
And now its vision
shall be fulfilled.
CYBERGUARDS: Hail the Cyberium.
DOCTOR: Afternoon!
Or is it morning?
Loving the coastline.
KO SHARMUS: Three of you.
Not just one, but three of you.
(SHAKILY) I don't believe it.
There's me
having lost all hope.
Consider us your hope restored.
I'm the Doctor.
This is Ryan and Ethan.
Do you mind
if I have a shufty around?
How are your defences here?
Come on.
Did this settlement
start with you?
Yes.
Myself and handful of others...
...fleeing the Cybercamps.
So you fought in the war?
Yes.
For a long time.
Then I was captured and held
in 3 human internment camp
for processing.
Sent for upgrade.
I was one of the lucky ones
who got away.
We had heard tell
of this place.
We didn't really believe it,
but we managed to get here.
The war hadn't made it
this far,
so we built shelter
and over time, others came.
The word spread.
So...where's everyone else?
There's only me.
I helped everyone else
through the Boundary.
And then, cos I'm an idiot...
...I felt like it was
my duty to wait...
...in case others came.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
But it's been a long time.
You sacrificed your own life
on the chance others
were still out there?
You make it sound more noble
than it is.
So it's true?
The Boundary, it's real?
Of course it's real.
Will you show us?
(ALARM BLARES)
I think this is trying
to tell us something.
Oh, no.
We've been boarded.
- Open the comms channel.
- Yeah, yeah, I'm doing it.
Graham, Ravio,
head to the control deck.
Cybermen just boarded.
(ON COMMS) Graham, Ravio,
this is Yaz.
Cybermen have boarded
and are on your level.
Get back here
as quick as you can.
Yaz calling Graham and Ravio,
can you hear me?
Yes, thank you!
Wait.
(WHIRRING)
Abandoned no longer.
Ascension is near!
No wonder
they almost wiped us out.
The systems on this ship
are the most advanced
I've ever seen.
Have you seen
the speed we're going at?
It'd barely take us any time
to get to Ko Sharmus.
Yeah, bringing
hundreds of thousands
of dormant Cybermen with us.
We can't do that.
We cannot take Cybermen
to the Boundary.
What are our other options?
Surrender this ship?
Land on another planet and
set the Cybermen loose there?
We're gonna
keep all of you safe.
We're gonna find the Doctor
and we're gonna
take them Cybermen down.
Aren't we, Graham?
Yes, we are, Yaz.
Totally. Very much so.
That's some
high-level self-delusion.
None of us are giving up, eh?
Not now.
Glass half-full, right?
What do you think
they're doing down there?
Let me activate the ob system.
GRAHAM: They've opened up
those containers.
Awaken, my soldiers.
The ascension shall begin.
(ROBOTIC SHRIEKING)
(SHRIEKING INTENSIFIES)
We're carrying a Cyberman
that makes
other Cybermen scream.
RYAN:
So where's this Boundary?
Cos that's just the sea.
This is where it starts,
every time.
I've seen people go through.
And I hope they're alive
and well elsewhere.
That's quite a risk
everyone's taking.
A leap into the unknown.
It was preferable
to the alternative.
If you want to see it,
step closer.
It responds to proximity.
A bit further...
...and it will respond.
(RUMBLING)
Here it comes.
How is that possible?
I don't know, but it's good,
isn't it?
KO SHARMUS: It's the last
way out of this galaxy.
SERGEANT:
It's a sad day for us all here.
But if any man can be said
to have earned
a peaceful retirement,
it's our Brendan.
On behalf
of the local community
and everyone past and present
who you've helped,
we'd like to present you
with this memento.
May we all live up
to the standards you've set us.
#- Thank you, Brendan.
- Thank you, sir.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(TICKING)
Hello, Brendan.
Would you mind coming with us
to the back office?
(CLOCK TICKS)
We have to get rid of
everything, I'm afraid.
Thank you for your service.
We're sorry
you won't remember it.
(SCREAMS)
We're coming out of vortex.
We're not far away.
Close enough to send a signal,
warn 'em we're coming.
I can help you do that.
Guys, they're all waking up
down there.
We know you're here.
My warriors are coming for you.
Yaz looking for The Doctor,
all frequencies.
Yaz looking for The Doctor.
Yaz, we can hear you.
Can you hear me?
YAZ: Doctor!
Where are you?
We're on a Cyber battle
cruiser with that Cyber guy
and a lot of Cyber troops
that are waking up.
They're coming!
They're right outside the door!
Yaz, get off that ship - now.
- We can't!
- (BANGING ON DOOR)
We're trapped,
and they're about to break in.
(BANGING CONTINUES)
Yaz...
Yaz!
(RUMBLING)
ETHAN: What is that?
That's not possible.
I've never seen it
look like that before.
That's my home planet.
That's Gallifrey.
How is Gallifrey here?
Wow! Ahh!
Ah!
That's a good entrance, right?
Be afraid, Doctor.
Because everything
is about to change...
...forever.
THE MASTER: Look upon my work,
Doctor, and despair.
We don't stand a chance here.
We are stuck on a ship
stacked with Cybermen.
THE MASTER: I told you before
that everything you knew
was a lie.
Well, now you get to
face the truth.
KO SHARMUS:
You can be a pacifist tomorrow.
Today, you have to survive.
Set course for Gallifrey.
Brace yourself.
This is going to hurt.