-Will it be me, Uncle?
-Yeah, it's going to be you.
I only wish
I could go in your place, Idris.
Nah, I don't,
'cause it's really going to hurt.
(SIGHS) It's starting.
-What will happen?
-Oh.
(CLEARING THROAT) Nephew will drain
your mind and your soul from your body
and leave your body empty.
-I'm scared!
-I expect so, dear.
But soon you'll have a new soul.
(CHOKING)
There'll be a Time Lord coming!
And then we discovered
it wasn't the robot king after all,
it was the real one.
Fortunately,
I was able to re-attach the head.
-Do you believe any of this stuff?
-I was there.
DOCTOR: Oh, it's the warning lights.
I'm getting rid of those.
-They never stop!
-RORY: Hey.
You're still thinking about it,
aren't you?
Oh, shh!
We saw him die.
-Yeah, 200 years in the future.
-Yes, but it's still going to happen.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
-What was that?
-The door.
It knocked.
Right. We are in deep space.
Very, very deep.
(KNOCKING)
And somebody's knocking.
Oh, come here.
Come here,
you scrumptious little beauty.
-A box?
-Doctor, what is it?
I've got mail.
Time Lord emergency messaging system.
In an emergency, we wrap up
our thoughts in psychic containers
and send them through time and space.
Anyway, there's a living Time Lord
still out there
and it's one of the good ones!
You said there weren't
any other Time Lords left.
There are no Time Lords left anywhere
in the universe,
but the universe
isn't where we're going.
See that snake? The mark of The Corsair.
Fantastic bloke.
He had that snake as a tattoo
in every regeneration.
Didn't feel like himself
unless he had the tattoo.
Or herself, a couple of times.
Ooh, she was a bad girl!
Whoa! What is happening?
We are leaving the universe!
How can you leave the universe?
With enormous difficulty!
Right now I'm burning up Tardis rooms
to give us some welly.
Goodbye, swimming pool.
Goodbye, scullery.
Sayonara, squash court seven!
-(AMY SCREAMING)
-Whoa!
Okay. Okay. Where are we?
Outside the universe,
where we've never, ever been.
(POWERING DOWN)
Is that meant to be happening?
The power. It's draining.
Everything's draining!
But it can't. That's...
That's impossible.
What is that?
It's as if the Matrix, the soul
of the Tardis, has just vanished.
(BEEPING)
Where would it go?
(GASPING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
AMY: So what kind of trouble is
your friend in?
DOCTOR: He was in a bind,
a bit of a pickle, sort of distressed.
Well, you can just say you don't know.
What is this place? The scrapyard
at the end of the universe?
Not end of, outside of.
How we can we be outside the universe?
The universe is everything.
Imagine a great big soap bubble
with one of those tiny little bubbles
on the outside.
-Okay.
-But it's nothing like that.
Completely drained, look at her.
Wait.
So we're in a tiny bubble universe,
sticking to the side
of the bigger bubble universe?
Yes. No. But if it helps, yes.
This place is full of rift energy.
She'll probably refuel
just by being here.
Now, this place, what do we think, eh?
Gravity's almost Earth-normal,
air's breathable, but it smells like...
-Armpits.
What about all this stuff?
Where did this come from?
Well, there's a rift, now and then
stuff gets sucked through it.
Not a bubble. A plughole.
The universe has a plughole
and we've just fallen down it.
WOMAN: Thief! Thief! You're my thief!
AUNTIE: She's dangerous!
Guard yourself.
Look at you! Goodbye! No, not goodbye.
What's the other one?
UNCLE: Watch out! Careful.
Keep back from her.
Welcome, strangers, lovely.
-Sorry about the mad person.
-Why am I a thief? What have I stolen?
Me. Are you going to steal me?
No, you have stolen me.
You are stealing me. Oh!
Tenses are difficult, aren't they?
Oh! Well, we are sorry, my dove.
She's off her head.
-They call me Auntie.
-And I'm Uncle. I'm everybody's uncle.
Just keep back from this one, she bites!
-Do I? Excellent. (BITES)
-Ow!
-No, no, no!
-Whoa!
-Ow! Ow, ow!
-Oh, biting's excellent!
It's like kissing,
only there's a winner!
-Sorry. She's doolally.
-No, I'm not doolally. I'm...
I'm... It's on the tip of my tongue.
I've just had a new idea about kissing.
Come here, you!
AUNTIE: No, Idris, no!
Oh, but now you're angry.
No, you're not. You will be angry.
The little boxes will make you angry.
Sorry? The little what? Boxes?
-(LAUGHING) Your chin is hilarious.
-Oil.
It means the smell of dust after rain.
-What does?
-Petrichor.
But I didn't ask.
Not yet. But you will.
AUNTIE: No. No, Idris.
I think you should have a rest.
Rest, yes, yes, good idea!
I'll just see if there's an off switch.
ALL: Whoa!
Is that it? Is she dead now? So sad.
She's still breathing.
Nephew, take Idris somewhere
she cannot bite people, hmm?
Oh, hello!
Doctor, what is that?
Oh, no. It's all right. It's an Ood.
Oods are good, love an Ood.
Hello, Ood.
Can't you talk?
Oh, I see, it's damaged.
May I?
It might be on the wrong frequency.
Nephew was broken when he came here.
Why, he was half dead.
House repaired him.
House repaired all of us.
MAN: If you are receiving this message,
please help me.
Send a signal to the High Council
of the Time Lords on Gallifrey.
Tell them that I am still alive!
I don't know where I am.
I'm on some rock-like planet.
What was that? Was that him?
No, no, it's picking up something else.
But that's...
That's not possible. That's...
Who else is here?
Tell me. Show me! Show me!
Just what you see.
It's just the four of us. And the House.
Nephew, will you take Idris somewhere
safe where she can't hurt nobody?
The House? What's the House?
House is all around you, my sweets.
You are standing on him.
This is the House. This world.
Would you like to meet him?
-Meet him?
-I'd love to.
This way. Come, please. Come.
What's wrong? What were those voices?
Time Lords.
It's not just the Corsair.
Somewhere close by
there are lots and lots of...
Time Lords.
IDRIS: I'm...
I'm...
Big word, sad word.
Why is that word so sad? No.
Will be sad. Will be sad.
Come. Come, come.
Now you can see House
and he can look at you and he...
I see.
This asteroid is sentient.
We walk on his back, breathe his air,
eat his food...
-Smell its armpits.
-HOUSE: And do my will.
You are most welcome, travellers.
Doctor, that voice,
that's the asteroid talking?
Yes. So you're like a sea urchin?
Hard outer surface.
That's the planet we're walking on.
Big, squashy, oogly thing inside.
That's you.
HOUSE: 7hat is correct Time Lord.
Ah! So you've met Time Lords before?
Many travellers
have come through the rift,
like Auntie and Uncle and Nephew.
I repair them when they break.
-So there are Time Lords here, then?
-Not any more.
But there have been many Tardises
on my back in days gone by.
Well, there won't be any more after us.
Last Time Lord. Last Tardis.
A pity. Your people were so kind.
Be here in safety, Doctor.
Rest, feed, if you will.
We're not actually going to stay here,
are we?
Well, it seems like a friendly planet.
Literally. Mind if we poke around a bit?
You can look all you want. Go, look.
House loves you.
Come on then, gang.
We're just going to see the sights.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Oh! What was that?
Do fish have fingers?
Like a nine-year-old
trying to rebuild a motorbike.
What am I saying? Why am I saying that?
Thief? Where's my thief? Thief!
Thief!
(SHUSHING)
So as soon as the Tardis is refuel led,
we go, yeah?
No. There are Time Lords here.
I heard them and they need me.
You told me about your people
and you told me what you did.
Yes, yes. But if they're like
the Corsair,
they're good ones and I can save them.
And then tell them
you destroyed all the others?
I can explain. Tell them why I had to.
You want to be forgiven.
Don't we all?
What do you need from me?
My screwdriver. I left it in the Tardis.
It's in my jacket.
-You're wearing your jacket.
-My other jacket.
-You have two of those?
-Okay. I'll get it.
But Doctor, listen to me.
Don't get emotional
because that's when you make mistakes.
-Yes, boss.
-I'll call you from the Tardis.
Rory, look after him.
Rory, look after her.
Yeah.
I told you to look after him.
He'll be fine. He's a Time Lord.
It's just what they're called.
It doesn't mean
he actually knows what he's doing.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Hey, we're here.
Screwdriver's in your jacket, yeah?
Yeah, it's around somewhere.
Have a good look.
(DOOR LOCKS)
-Did you do that?
-I didn't do anything.
Right. Jacket.
Come on. Where are you?
Now, where are you all? Where are you?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Well, they can't all be in here.
(DISTANT CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(VOICES CLAMOURING)
-Please, do you read me?
-Help!
-Damage to our engines...
-Can you hear me? Please respond...
-Contraction and constriction of...
(CALLS FOR HELP CONTINUE, OVERLAPPING)
Just admiring your Time Lord
distress signal collection.
Nice job. Brilliant job.
Really thought I had some friends here.
But this is what the Ood translator
picked up,
cries for help from the long dead.
How many Time Lords have you lured here
the way you lured me?
And what happened to them all?
House... House is kind and he is wise.
House repairs you when you break!
Yes, I know!
But how does he mend you?
-You've got the eyes of a 20-year-old.
-Thank you.
No. No. I mean it, literally.
Your eyes are 30 years younger
than the rest of you.
Your ears don't match,
your right arm is two inches longer
than your left.
And how's your dancing?
'Cause you've got two left feet.
Patchwork people.
You've been repaired
and patched up so often,
I doubt there's anything left
of what used to be you.
I had an umbrella like you once.
Oh, now,
it's been a great arm for me, this.
Corsair.
He was a strapping big bloke,
wasn't he, Uncle?
Big fella.
I got the arm and then Uncle
got the spine and the kidneys.
Kidneys.
You gave me hope
and then you took it away.
That's enough to make anyone dangerous.
God knows what it will do to me.
Basically, run!
Poor old Time Lord. Too late.
House is too clever.
(MOBILE RINGING)
No sonic screwdriver.
Also, the doors seem
to have locked behind us.
Rory thinks there is a perfectly
innocent explanation,
but I think you lied to us.
Time Lord stuff.
Needed you out of the way.
What, we're not good enough
for your smart new friends?
"Boxes will make you angry."
How could she know?
-Doctor, what are you talking about?
-Stay put. Stay exactly where you are.
We don't have much...choice.
How did you know about the boxes?
You said they'd make me angry.
-How did you know?
-Ah, it's my thief.
Who are you?
It's about time.
He's not trusting us.
And he's being emotional.
This is bad. This is very, very bad.
Yeah. I think it probably is.
Sometimes I hate being right.
I don't understand. Who are you?
Do you really not know me?
Just because they put me in here?
-They said you were dangerous.
-Not the cage, stupid. In here.
They put me in here.
I'm the... Oh, what do you call me?
We travel. I go... (WHOOSHING)
-The Tardis?
-Time and relative dimension in space.
Yes, that's it. Names are funny.
It's me!
I'm the Tardis.
No, you're not.
You're a bitey mad lady.
The Tardis is up-and-downy stuff
in a big blue box.
Yes, that's me. A type 40 Tardis.
I was already a museum piece
when you were young.
And the first time
you touched my console you said...
I said you were the most beautiful thing
I had ever known.
And then you stole me. And I stole you.
I borrowed you.
Borrowing implies the eventual intention
to return the thing that was taken.
What makes you think
I would ever give you back?
-You're the Tardis?
-Yes.
-My Tardis?
-My Doctor.
Oh! We have now reached the point in the
conversation where you open the lock.
-Are all people like this?
-Like what?
So much bigger on the inside?
I'm...
Oh, what is that word?
It's so big, so complicated.
-And so sad.
-But why?
Why pull the living soul from a Tardis
and pop it in a tiny human head?
What does it want you for?
-Well, it doesn't want me. (SNIFFS)
-How do you know?
-House eats Tardises.
-House what? What do you mean?
I don't know. Something I heard you say.
-When?
-In the future.
-House eats Tardises?
-There you go. What are fish fingers?
-When do I say that?
-Any second.
Of course! House feeds on rift energy
and Tardises are bursting with it.
And not raw, lovely and cooked,
processed food.
-Mmm. Fish fingers.
-Do fish have fingers?
But you can't eat a Tardis,
it would destroy you. Unless, unless...
Unless you deleted
the Tardis Matrix first.
(LAUGHS) So it deleted you.
But House can't just delete
a Tardis consciousness,
that would blow a hole in the universe.
So it pulls out the Matrix,
sticks it into a living receptacle,
and it feeds off
the remaining Artron energy.
(GASPS)
You were about to say all that.
I don't suppose you have to now.
I sent Amy and Rory in there.
They'll be eaten. Amy! Amy!
Rory, get the hell out of there!
-Doctor, something's wrong.
-Yeah. It's House.
He's after the Tardis.
Just get out, both of you!
We can't. You locked the door, remember?
But I've unlocked it.
You stupid well haven't!
Doctor, I don't like this.
(GRUNTS)
-Open!
-Doctor?
Open this door!
Rory, hold my hand.
Amy. Rory!
(WHOOSHING)
Amy? Amy, can you hear me?
Okay. Right. I don't...
I really don't know what to do.
That's a new feeling.
Listen, whatever happens,
at least we're together.
-And we're in the Tardis, so we're safe.
-Yeah.
HOUSE: You're half right.
I mean, you are in the Tardis.
What a great adventure.
I should have done this
half a million years ago.
So, Amy, Rory,
why shouldn't I just kill you now?
-It's gone.
-Eaten?
No, it left. Not eaten, hijacked.
But why?
It's time for us both to go,
Unkie, together.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Go? What do you mean
go? Where are you going?
Well, we're dying, my love.
It's time for Auntie and Uncle
to pop off.
-I'm against it but...
-It's your fault, isn't it, sweets?
'Cause you told House
it was the last Tardis.
House can't feed on them
if there's none more coming, can he?
So now he's off to your universe
to find more Tardises.
-It won't.
-AUNTIE: Oh, it will think of something.
(GROANS)
Actually, I feel fine.
Not dead. You can't just die!
We need to go to where I landed, Doctor.
Quickly.
-Why?
-Because we are there in three minutes.
We need to go...now!
-Ow!
-What?
Roughly how long do these bodies last?
(WHIZZING)
-You're dying.
-Yes, of course I'm dying.
I don't belong in a flesh body.
I could blow the casing in no time.
No, stop it. Don't get emotional.
Hmm. That's what the orangey girl says.
You're the Doctor. Focus.
On what? How?
I'm a madman with a box without a box!
I'm stuck down the plughole
at the end of the universe
on a stupid old junkyard!
-Oh.
-Oh what?
-No, I'm not.
-Not what?
'Cause it's not a junkyard.
Don't you see? It's not a junkyard.
-What is it then?
-It's a Tardis junkyard!
Come on! Oh, sorry, do you have a name?
Seven hundred years, finally he asks.
-So what do I call you?
-I think you call me...
Sexy.
Only when we're alone!
We are alone.
Oh. Come on, then, Sexy.
HOUSE: Corridors. I have corridors.
So much to learn about my new home.
But you haven't answered
my question, children.
Uh, question?
You remember. Tell me why
I shouldn't just kill you both now?
Well, because... Rory, why?
Because
killing us quickly wouldn't be any fun.
And you need fun, don't you?
That's what Auntie and Uncle were for,
wasn't it? Someone to make suffer.
I had a PE teacher just like you.
You need to be entertained
and killing us quickly
wouldn't be entertainment.
So entertain me. Run.
DOCTOR: A valley of half-eaten Tardises.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
I'm thinking that
all of my sisters are dead,
that they were devoured and that
we are looking at their corpses.
Ah. Sorry. No, I wasn't thinking that.
No. You were thinking you could build
a working Tardis console
out of broken remnants
of 100 different models.
And you don't care that it's impossible.
DOCTOR: It's not impossible
as long as we're alive.
Rory and Amy need me.
So, yeah. We're going to build a Tardis.
So are we having fun yet?
I'm rather enjoying the sensation
of having you running around inside me.
-(SCREAMS)
-No!
I've turned off the corridor
anti-grav, so do be careful.
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
Whoa!
Bond the tube directly
into the tachyon diverter.
Yes, I have actually rebuilt a Tardis
before, you know.
I know what I'm doing.
You're like a nine-year-old trying to
rebuild a motorbike in his bedroom.
And you never read the instructions.
-I always read the instructions!
-There's a sign on my front door.
You have been walking past it
for 700 years. What does it say?
That's not instructions!
There's an instruction at the bottom.
What does it say?
-"Pull to open.”
-Yes. And what do you do?
-I push!
-Every single time. 700 years.
Police box doors open out the way.
I think I have earned the right
to open my front doors any way I want.
Your front doors? Have you any idea
how childish that sounds?
-You are not my mother.
-And you are not my child.
You know,
since we're talking with mouths,
not really an opportunity
that comes along very often,
I just want to say, you know,
you have never been very reliable.
And you have?
You didn't always take me
where I wanted to go.
No, but I always took you
where you needed to go.
You did.
Look at us. Talking! Wouldn't it
be amazing if we could always talk?
Even when you're stuck inside the box?
But you know
I'm not constructed that way.
I exist across all space and time
and you talk and run around
and bring home strays.
(GROANS)
You okay?
One of the kidneys has already failed.
It doesn't matter. We need to finish
assembling the console.
Using a console without a proper shell.
It's not going to be safe.
This body has about
18 minutes left to live.
The universe we're in
will reach absolute zero in three hours.
Safe is relative.
Then we need to get a move on, eh,
old girl?
No!
-Amy!
-No!
(GRUNTING)
Amy!
RORY: Amy.
Rory?
Where have you been?
I stepped through that door
and it came back here.
-But you've been hours.
-No, I haven't.
It's House,
and it's messing with the Tardis.
Come on, walk this way.
-No!
-No! Oh!
You'll need to install the time rotor.
DOCTOR: Well, how is this
going to make it through the rift? How?
We're almost done. Thrust diff user.
-Ah, retroscope. Blue thingy.
-Oh, Doctor.
Do you ever wonder why I chose you
all those years ago?
-I chose you. You were unlocked.
-Of course I was.
I wanted to see the universe,
so I stole a Time Lord and I ran away.
And you were the only one mad enough.
Right. Perfect. Look at that.
What could possibly go wrong?
That's fine. That always happens.
No! Hang on. Wait.
RORY: Amy?
Oh, my God.
Rory?
You left me. How could you do that?
How could you leave me?
How long have you been here?
Two thousand years I waited for you!
You did it to me again!
I didn't mean to. I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry.
(SCREAMS)
Rory, what are you doing?
They come for me at night.
Every single night,
they come for me and they hurt me.
Amy, they hurt me over and over
and over and over...
-Rory.
-(SHOUTING) How could you leave me?
How could you do that to me?
Right. Okay, let's go.
Follow that Tardis!
(POWERING DOWN)
Oh, no, come on. There's rift energy
everywhere, you can do it.
Okay, diverting all power to thrust.
Let's be having you.
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
-No, no, no, no!
-What's wrong?
It can't hold the charge.
I can't even start. There's no power!
Will you...
I've got nothing!
Oh, my beautiful idiot.
You have what you've always had.
You've got me.
(WHOOSHING)
(GASPS)
(AMY SHUDDERING)
No! No!
(SOBBING)
Rory.
I'm so, so sorry!
-Amy?
-(GASPS)
It's messing with our heads.
Come on, run.
-Whoo-hoo!
-We've locked on to them!
They'll have to lower the shields
when we're close enough to phase inside!
Can you get a message to Amy?
The telepathic circuits are online!
Which one's Amy? The pretty one?
(GROANS)
-Rory, what's wrong?
-It's like I'm getting a message.
Hello, pretty!
What the hell is that?
Don't worry. Telepathic messaging.
No, that's Rory.
You have to go to the old control room.
I'm putting the route in your head.
When you get there,
use the purple slider on
the nearest panel to lower the shields.
-The pretty one?
-You'll have about 12 seconds
before the room goes into phase
with the invading Matrix.
I'll send you the passkey
when you get there. Good luck.
What was that?
It was that woman.
That mad woman and the Doctor.
-The Doctor?
-We have to keep going.
How's he going to be able
to take down the shields anyway?
The House is in the control room!
I directed him
to one of the old control rooms.
There aren't any old control rooms!
They were all deleted or remodel led!
I archive them! For neatness!
I've got about 30 now!
But I've only changed the desktop,
what, a dozen times?
So far, yes!
You can't archive something
that hasn't happened yet!
You can't.
(AMY GASPS)
What happened to the lights?
The lights are fine.
It's messing with our heads again.
-(WHISPERING) Okay. Stay there a second.
-What is it? What?
Just hang on.
Don't leave me.
I can hardly see, you idiot!
(RORY SCREAMS)
Rory?
-Rory?
-RORY: It's okay.
(AMY SIGHS)
I'm fine. Come towards my voice.
AMY: What happened? Where are you?
RORY: I just banged my head.
Just keep coming.
Reach out your hand.
This way. Come on, run!
Keep going!
You're doing it, You Sexy Thing!
See, you do call me that.
Is it my name?
-You bet it's your name!
-Whoo!
(DOCTOR GROANING)
I can see. Now, Rory, I can see.
That was the Ood thing, the Nephew,
and it's still coming.
I know. So where is this place?
This is where she told me to go.
She said she'd send me the passkey!
(GROANS)
-Crimson. Eleven. Delight. Petrichor.
-Petrichor.
-What do I do, do I say it?
Crimson. Eleven. Delight. Petrichor.
I said it.
-Petrichor. Petrichor.
-I said it!
Petrichor.
She told you what it meant.
The smell of wet dust, remember? So...
Always the meaning, not the word.
-The meaning of what?
-The Tardis interface is telepathic.
You don't say it, you think it.
-It's coming.
-Quiet!
(WHISPERING) Crimson. Eleven. Delight.
And the smell of dust after rain.
Crimson. Eleven. Delight.
The smell of dust after rain.
What is this place?
Another control room?
RORY: Right, shields.
(CONTROLS BEEPING)
Got it.
They did it! Shields down.
HOUSE: How did you find this place?
It's not on my internal schematics.
I had hoped you two could join Nephew
as my servants.
But you two are nothing but trouble.
Nephew,
kill them.
(GROANS)
We're coming through!
Get out of the way
or you'll be atomised!
-Where are you coming through?
-I don't know!
Oh, great. Thanks.
-(DOCTOR GROANS)
-It's not going to hold!
Hold on!
(SCREAMING)
Doctor.
(AMY CHUCKLES)
Not good. Not good at all.
-How do you walk around in these things?
-Well, we're not quite there yet.
Just hold on. Amy, this is...
Well, she's my Tardis.
Except she's a woman.
She's a woman and she's my Tardis.
-She's the Tardis?
-And she's a woman.
She's a woman and she's the Tardis.
Did you wish really hard?
Shut up! Not like that.
Hello. I'm...
-Sexy.
-Oh! Still shut up.
HOUSE: 7he environment
has been breached.
Nephew, kill them all.
Where's Nephew?
He was standing
right where you materialised.
Ah! Well, he must have
been redistributed.
-Meaning what?
-You're breathing him.
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Another Ood I failed to save.
Doctor, I did not expect you.
Well, that's me all over, isn't it?
Lovely old unexpected me.
The big question is now you're here,
how to dispose of you?
I could play with gravity...
(ALL GASPING)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
Or I could evacuate the air
from this room and watch you choke.
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(ALL GASPING)
You really don't want to do that!
Why shouldn't I just kill you now?
Because then I won't be able
to help you! Listen to your engines.
Just listen to them. You don't have
the thrust and you know it.
Right now I'm your only hope
for getting out of your little bubble
through the rift and into my universe.
-And mine's the one with the food in!
-(GASPING) Water...
You just have to promise not to kill us.
That's all. Just promise.
-You can't be serious.
-I'm very serious.
I'm sure it's an entity of its word.
RORY: Doctor, she's burning up.
She's asking for water.
Hey. Hang in there, old girl.
Not long now. It'll be over soon.
I always liked it
when you called me "old girl".
You want me to give my word?
Easy. I promise.
Fine. Okay. I trust you.
Just delete, ooh,
30% of the Tardis rooms,
you'll free up thrust
enough to make it through.
Activate sub-routine sigma nine.
Why would you tell me this?
Because we want to get back
to our universe as badly as you do.
And I'm nice.
Yes. I can delete rooms
and I can also rid myself of vermin
if I delete this room first.
Thank you, Doctor, very helpful.
Goodbye, Time Lord.
Goodbye, little humans. Goodbye, Idris.
(WHOOSHING)
Yes. I mean you could do that,
but it just won't work.
Hardwired fail-safe.
Living things
from rooms that are deleted
are automatically deposited
in the main control room.
But thanks for the Lift.
We are in your universe now, Doctor.
Why should it matter to me
in which room you die?
I can kill you just as easily here
as anywhere.
Fear me.
I've killed hundreds of Time Lords.
Fear me. I've killed all of them.
I don't understand.
There isn't a forest in here.
Yeah, you're right.
You've completely won.
Oh, you can kill us
in oodles of really inventive ways,
but before you do kill us,
allow me and friends Amy and Rory
to congratulate you
on being an absolutely worthy opponent.
Congratulations.
Yep, you've defeated us,
me and my lovely friends here,
and last but definitely not least,
the Tardis Matrix herself,
a living consciousness
you ripped out of this very control room
and locked up into a human body,
and look at her.
Doctor, she's stopped breathing.
-Enough! That is enough.
-No. It's never enough!
You forced the Tardis into a body
so she'd burn out safely a very long way
away from this control room.
A flesh body
can't hold the Tardis Matrix and live.
Look at her body, House.
And you think I should mourn her?
No.
I think you should be very, very careful
about what you let back
into this control room.
You took her from her home.
But now she's back in the box again
and she's free!
No! Doctor, stop this!
Ah! Stop this now!
Look at my girl, look at her go!
Bigger on the inside!
-You see, House?
-Make her stop!
-That's your problem.
-(HOUSE GROANING)
The size of a planet,
but inside you are just so small.
Make it stop!
Finish him off, girl.
HOUSE: (GROANING) Don't do this!
(HOUSE SCREAMING)
IDRIS: (ECHOING) Doctor? Are you there?
It's so very dark in here.
I'm here.
I've been looking for a word.
A big, complicated word, but so sad.
I've found it now.
What word?
Alive.
I'm alive!
Alive isn't sad.
It's sad when it's over.
I'll always be here.
But this is when we talked.
And now even that has come to an end.
There's something
I didn't get to say to you.
Goodbye?
No, I just wanted to say...
hello.
Hello, Doctor.
It's so very, very nice to meet you.
Please.
I don't want you to.
(WHOOSHING)
I love you.
Where? (SNIFFING)
How's it going under there?
Yeah. Just putting a firewall
around the Matrix. Almost done.
-Are you going to make her talk again?
-Can't.
-Why not?
-Spacey-wacey, isn't it?
Well, actually, it's because
the Time Lords discovered that
if you take an 11th-dimensional Matrix
and fold it into a mechanical, then...
Yes, it's spacey-wacey!
Sorry. At the end, she was talking.
She kept repeating something.
-I don't know what it meant.
-What did she say?
"The only water in the forest
is the river."
She said we'd need to know that someday.
-It doesn't make sense, does it?
-Not yet.
-You okay?
-No.
I watched her die. I shouldn't
let it get to me, but it still does.
I'm a nurse.
Letting it get to you,
you know what that's called?
Being alive. Best thing there is.
Being alive right now
is all that counts.
Nearly finished.
Two more minutes, then we're off.
The Eye of Orion's restful,
if you like restful.
I can never
really get the hang of restful.
What do you think, dear?
Where shall we take the kids this time?
Look at you pair.
It's always you and her, isn't it?
Long after the rest of us have gone.
A boy and his box,
off to see the universe.
Well, you say that
as if it's a bad thing.
But honestly,
it's the best thing there is.
The House deleted all the bedrooms.
I should probably make you two
a new bedroom.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
(AMY AND RORY TALKING QUIETLY)
Okay, um, Doctor, this time
could we lose the bunk beds?
No, bunk beds are cool.
A bed with a ladder.
You can't beat that.
It's your room.
Up those stairs, keep walking
till you find it. Off you pop.
Doctor, do you have a room?
Are you there?
Can you hear me?
No. I'm a silly old...
Okay. The Eye of Orion,
or wherever we need to go.
Hello!
(LAUGHING)
Whoo-hoo!
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN: The flesh.
It's fully programmable matter.
It acts like life, but it still needs
to be controlled by us.
MAN: They can't remain stable
without us plumbed into them.
Trust me. I'm the Doctor.
(HISSES)