DOCTOR: Get down!
-Did they see you?
-I don't know.
-But did they see you?
-I was too busy running!
Martha, it's important,
did they see your face?
-No, they couldn't have.
-Off we go.
Ah! They're following us.
How can they do that?
You've got a time machine.
Stolen technology. They've got
a time agent's vortex manipulator.
They can follow us wherever we go.
Right across the universe.
They're never going to stop.
Unless... I'll have to do it.
-Martha, you trust me, don't you?
-Of course I do.
-'Cause it all depends on you.
-What does? What am I supposed to do?
Take this watch
because my life depends on it.
This watch, Martha, this watch is...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
Pardon me, Mr Smith, you're not
dressed yet. I can come back later.
No, it's all right, it's all right,
put it down.
I was...
Sorry, sorry.
Sometimes I have
these extraordinary dreams.
-What about, sir?
-I dream I'm this...
adventurer.
This daredevil, a madman.
"The Doctor”, I'm called.
And last night,
I dreamt that you were there,
as my...companion.
A teacher and a housemaid, sir?
That's impossible.
I'm a man from another world, you know.
Well, then it can't be true
'cause there's no such thing.
This thing, the watch...
It's funny how dreams slip away.
But I do remember one thing.
It all took place in the future.
In the year of our Lord, 2007.
I can prove that wrong for you, sir.
Here's the morning paper.
It's Monday November 10, 1913,
and you're completely human, sir.
-As human as they come.
-Mmm. That's me.
Completely human.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Good morning, sir.
Headmaster.
"The French were all but spent,
"with only two battalions
of the old guard remaining.
"The final reserve force
was charged with protecting Napoleon.
"But by evening,
the advance of the allied troops
"had forced them to retreat."”
Morning, sir.
Yes, hi.
Head in the clouds, that one.
I don't know why you're so sweet on him.
He's just kind to me, that's all.
Not everyone's that considerate,
what with me being...
-A Londoner?
-Exactly. Good old London town!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Now then, you two.
You're not paid to have fun, are you?
Put a little backbone into it.
-Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
-You there. What's your name again?
Martha, sir. Martha Jones.
Well, tell me then, Jones,
with hands like those,
how can you tell when something's clean?
(LAUGHING)
-That's very funny, sir.
-Careful now, don't tense about it.
I'd like to smack my bucket
over his head.
Oh, I wish!
Just think, though.
In a few years' time, boys like that
will be running the country.
1913.
They might not.
-Excuse me, ma'am.
-Oh, good morning, Mr Smith.
Oh! Here we go.
-Let me help you.
-No, no, I've got it, no.
Er... Just to retrieve...
So, if you could take these...
Thank you.
-There we are.
-Good.
No harm done.
-So, how was Jenkins?
-Oh, just a cold, nothing serious.
I think he's missing his mother
more than anything.
Ah, can't have that.
He received a letter this morning,
so he's a lot more chipper.
-I appear to be holding your books.
-Yes, so you are, sorry. Sorry.
-Yes, just let me...
-No, why don't I take half?
Brilliant idea. Brilliant. Perfect.
Division of lab our.
-We make quite a team.
-Don't we just?
So these books, were they being taken
in any particular direction?
Yes, um, this way.
I always say, Matron, you give the boys
a good head of steam,
they'll soon wear themselves out.
Truth be told,
when it's just you and me,
I'd much rather
you call me Nurse Redfern.
Matron sounds rather, well, matronly.
Ah! Nurse Redfern it is, then.
Though we've known each other all of
two months, you could even say Joan.
-Joan?
-That's my name.
Well, obviously.
-And it's John, isn't it?
-Yes, it is, yes.
Have you seen this, John? The annual
dance at the village hall tomorrow?
It's nothing formal,
but rather fun by all accounts.
Do you think you'll go?
I hadn't thought about it.
It's been ages since I've been
to a dance, only no one's asked me.
Well, I should imagine that you'd be...
I mean... I mean,
I never thought you'd be one for...
There's no reason why you shouldn't,
if you do, you may not...
I probably won't,
but even if I did, then I...
-I couldn't, um... I wouldn't want to...
-The stairs.
-What about the stairs?
-They're right behind you.
(GROANS)
Stop it. I get boys
causing less fuss than this.
But it hurts.
-Is he all right?
-Excuse me, Martha.
It's hardly good form to enter
a master's study without knocking.
Sorry. You're right, yeah.
But is he all right?
They said you fell down the stairs, sir.
It was just a tumble, that's all.
-Have you checked for concussion?
-I have.
And I dare say
I know a lot more about it than you.
Sorry. I'll just tidy your things.
I was just telling
Nurse Redfern, Matron,
about my dreams.
They are quite remarkable tales.
I keep imagining that I'm someone else
and that I'm hiding.
Hiding. In what way?
Erm...
They're almost every night and...
-This is going to sound silly.
-Tell me.
I dream, quite often, that...
That I have two hearts.
Well then, I can be the judge of that.
Let's find out.
(HEART BEATING)
I can confirm the diagnosis.
Just one heart. Singular.
I have, um, I have written down
some of these dreams
in the form of fiction.
-Not that it would be of any interest.
-I'd be very interested.
Yeah? Well...
Never actually
shown it to anyone before.
"A Journal of Impossible Things."
Look at these creatures.
Such imagination.
-Oh. It's become quite a hobby.
-Oh.
It's wonderful.
You have quite an eye
for the pretty girls.
Oh, no, no, she's just an invention.
This character Rose. I call her Rose.
Seems to disappear later on.
Oh, that's the box, the blue box.
It's always there.
Like a magic carpet...
This fun little box that transports me
to faraway places.
-Like a doorway?
-Mmm.
I sometimes think
how magical life would be
if stories like this were true.
JOAN: If only.
It's just a dream.
Ma'am.
-That book.
-Oh, I'll look after it, don't worry.
-He did say I could read it.
-But it's silly, that's all.
Just stories.
-Who is he, Martha?
-I'm sorry?
It's like he's left the kettle on,
like he knows he has something
to get back to,
but he can't remember what.
-It's just him.
-You arrived with him, didn't you?
He found you employment here
at the school, isn't that right?
I used to work for the family.
He just sort of inherited me.
Well, I'd be careful.
If you don't mind my saying,
you sometimes seem
a little familiar with him.
Best remember your position.
Yes, ma'am.
Ah, Latimer, here you are.
Latin translation.
Blasted Catullus.
I want it done by morning.
-Yes, sir.
-And no mistakes.
I want it written
in my best handwriting.
Listen, Father says he's been promoted.
That means more money.
-Might end up in a better school.
-Ah, you should enjoy it, sir.
My uncle had a six-month posting
in Johannesburg.
Says it was the most beautiful
countryside on God's earth.
-What are you talking about?
-Africa.
-Your father.
-Have you been reading my post?
-What?
-Who said Africa?
I've only just read the word myself.
-How did you know that?
-I haven't...
-Have you been spying on me?
-No. I just guessed.
-What's that supposed to mean?
-I'm good at guessing, that's all.
Idiot.
Sometimes I say things
and they turn out to be correct.
Just little things. Tiny things.
I can't help it.
It's just some sort of luck.
Right. Well, never mind
that little toad. Who's for beer?
You've got beer?
No, but Baxter's hidden a secret supply
in Blackdown Woods.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Make sure the bursar's down the pub
before you go past his window.
-A bottle for everyone, is it?
-And none for the filth.
And hurry back, Baines. I'm parched.
Ooh, it's freezing out here. Why can't
we have a drink inside the pub?
Don't be ridiculous.
You do get these notions.
It's all very well those suffragettes,
but that's London. That's miles away.
Don't you want to scream sometimes,
having to bow and scrape and behave?
-Don't you just want to tell them?
-I don't know.
Things must be different
in your country.
Well, they are.
Thank God I'm not staying here.
You keep saying that.
Just you wait. One more month
and I'm as free as the wind.
Wish you could come with me, Jenny.
You'd love it.
-Where you gonna go?
-Anywhere.
Just look up there.
Imagine you could go all the way
out to the stars.
You don't half say mad things.
That's where I'm going.
Into the sky, all the way out.
Hmm!
Did you see that?
-See what?
-Did you see it, though?
Right up there, just for a second.
Martha, there's nothing there.
Matron, are you all right?
Did you see that?
There was something in the woods.
-This light.
-Anything wrong, ladies?
Far too cold
to be standing round in the dark.
JOAN: There. There. Look, in the sky.
Oh, that's beautiful.
All gone. Commonly known as a meteorite.
It's just rocks falling to the ground,
that's all.
Came down in the woods.
No, no, they always look close,
but actually they're miles off.
Nothing left but a cinder.
Now, I should escort you
back to the school.
-Ladies?
-No, we're fine, thanks.
Then I shall bid you good night.
Jenny, where was that?
On the horizon,
where the light was headed.
That's by Coopers Field.
You can't just run off! It's dark.
You'll break a leg!
I say, hello?
Some kind of aeroplane?
You chaps all right?
What? That's... That's impossible.
Some kind of door.
(ECHOING) Hello?
Is there anyone there?
There you are.
Nothing there. I told you so.
And that's Coopers Field?
As far as the eye can see,
and no falling star.
Now, come on, I'm frozen to the bone.
Let's go.
As your Mr Smith says, "Nothing to see.”
But I don't understand. Who are you?
MALE VOICE: We are the Family.
FEMALE VOICE: Far more important,
who are you, little thing?
My name's Baines. Jeremy Baines.
Please, can I go?
FEMALE VOICE: I'm so sorry, Baines,
Jeremy Baines,
but I don't think you can ever leave.
But who are you? Why can't I see you?
MALE VOICE. Why would you want
to see us?
I want to know what you look like.
FEMALE VOICE: Oh, that's easily answered
because very soon,
we will look so familiar.
Where is he? Promises a beer
and then vanishes into the night.
There he is. Let him in.
Well, Baines, you dolt. Thought you'd
been caught by the rozzers.
Well, then?
Where is it, man?
Where's the blessed beer?
There was no beer. It was gone.
Damn it all, I've been waiting.
Pretty poor show, Baines, I have to say.
(SNIFFS)
What's the matter with you?
Caught the sniffles out there?
Yes, I must have. It was cold.
Very cold.
Well, don't spread it about.
I don't want your germs.
Come on, might as well get some sleep.
Come on, chaps, maybe tomorrow.
Jackson's got some beer in the pavilion.
Hello.
Talking to a machine.
DOCTOR: Get down!
Ah! They're following us.
They can follow us wherever we go.
Right across the universe.
They're never gonna stop.
-Martha, you trust me, don't you?
-Of course I do.
'Cause it all depends on you.
Martha, this watch is me.
Right, okay, gotcha.
No! Hold on! Completely lost.
Those creatures are hunters.
They can sniff out anyone.
And me being a Time Lord,
well, I'm unique.
They can track me down across
the whole of time and space.
Huh. And the good news is?
They can smell me, they haven't seen me,
and their life supplies are running out,
so we hide.
-Wait for them to die.
-But they can track us down.
That's why I've got to do it.
I have to stop being a Time Lord.
I'm gonna become human.
Never thought I'd use this.
All the times I've wondered.
-What does it do?
-Chameleon Arch.
Rewrites my biology.
It literally changes every single cell
in my body. I've set it to human.
The Tardis will take care of everything.
Invent a life story for me,
find me a setting and integrate.
It can't do the same for you.
You'll just have to improvise.
I should have just enough
residual awareness to let you in.
Hold on, if you're going to rewrite
every cell, isn't it going to hurt?
Oh, yeah. It'll hurt.
Is this working?
Martha, before I change,
here's a list of instructions
for when I'm human.
One, don't let me hurt anyone.
We can't have that, but you know what
humans are like.
Two, don't worry about the Tardis.
I'll put it on emergency power so they
can't detect it. Just let it hide away.
Four... No.
Wait a minute. Three, no getting
involved in big historical events.
Four, you. Don't let me abandon you.
And five...
But there was a meteor, a shooting
star, what am I supposed to do then?
And 23, if anything goes wrong,
if they find us, Martha,
then you know what to do.
Open the watch.
Everything I am is kept safe in there.
I've put a perception filter on it so
the human me won't think anything of it.
To him, it's just a watch.
But don't open it unless you have to.
"Cause once it's open,
then the Family will be able to find me.
It's all down to you, Martha.
Your choice.
Oh! And thank you.
I wish you'd come back.
(KNOCKING)
You told me to come
and collect that book, sir.
Good lad, yes, yes!
The Definitive Account of Mafeking
by Aitchinson Price.
Where did I put it?
And I wanted a little word.
Your marks aren't quite good enough.
I'm top 10 in my class, sir.
Now, be honest, Timothy.
You should be the very top.
You're a clever boy.
You seem to be hiding it.
Where is that book?
And I know why. Keeping your head low
avoids the mockery of your classmates.
But no man should hide himself,
don't you think?
-Yes, sir.
-You're clever.
FEMALE VOICE: Time Lord.
You should be proud of it. Use it.
(WHISPERING VOICES)
Time Lord.
FEMALE VOICE: Timothy, hide us.
DOCTOR: The secret lies within.
I'm trapped. I'm caged.
Inside the cold, in the dark, waiting.
FEMALE VOICE: Reach out, boy. Reach out.
DOCTOR: Always waiting.
Fascinating details about the siege,
really quite remarkable.
-Are you all right?
-Yes, sir. Fine, sir.
Right, then. Good.
And remember, use that brain of yours.
The power of a Time Lord.
You're really not looking yourself,
old chap. Anything bothering you?
No, sir. Thank you, sir.
DOCTOR: You are not alone.
Keep me hidden.
(WHISPERING VOICES)
FEMALE VOICE: Burn with the light.
Burn and turn!
MAN: Now, boys, come along now.
Classes are ready...
Come along, Jenkins.
BAINES: There is a trace,
but somehow scattered.
The scent is confused.
Nevertheless, we'd best arm ourselves.
Activate the soldiers.
That is my property!
And you are trespassing on my land!
Come on, who's in there?
Is it one of those idiot boys
from the school, is it? Eh?
Come on. I suppose...
Well, how did you...
No! No! Help me!
Help me!
(SCREAMS)
SMITH: Concentrate.
Hutchinson, excellent work.
-Cease fire!
-Good day to you, Headmaster.
Your crew's on fine form today,
Mr Smith.
Excuse me, Headmaster.
We could do a lot better.
Latimer's being deliberately shoddy.
-I'm trying my best.
-You need to be better than the best.
Those targets are tribesmen
from the Dark Continent.
That's exactly the problem, sir.
They only have spears.
Oh, dear me.
Latimer takes it upon himself
to make us realise how wrong we all are.
I hope, Latimer, that one day
you may have a just and proper war
in which to prove yourself.
Now, resume firing.
(BOMB WHISTLING)
-Under the wire!
-Keep your heads down!
One minute past the hour. It's now.
Hutchinson, this is the time. It's now.
Stoppage. Immediate action.
Didn't I tell you, sir?
The stupid boy's useless.
Permission to give Latimer
a beating, sir.
-It's your class, Mr Smith.
-Permission granted.
Right. Come with me, you little oik.
(SNIFFS)
Anything the matter, Baines?
I thought... No, sir, nothing, sir.
As you were, Mr Smith.
Er, Pemberton, Smythe, Wicks, take post.
Ah!
Nurse Redfern.
I'll give you back your journal
when next I see you.
No, no, no, you don't have to.
If you'll excuse me, Mr Smith,
I was just thinking about the day
my husband was shot.
His name was Oliver.
He died at the Battle of Spion Kop.
We were childhood sweethearts.
But, you see, I was angry
with the army for such a long time.
And you still are.
I find myself as part of that school,
watching boys learn how to kill.
Don't you think discipline
is good for them?
Does it have to be
such military discipline?
If there's another war,
those boys won't find it so amusing.
Well, Great Britain's at peace,
long may it reign.
In your journal, in one of your stories,
you wrote about next year, 1914.
It was just a dream.
All those images of mud and wire.
You told of a shadow. A shadow
falling across the entire world.
Well, then, we can be thankful
it's not true.
I'll admit, mankind doesn't need warfare
and bloodshed to prove itself.
Everyday life can provide honour
and valour and...
Let's hope that from now on this country
can find its heroes in smaller places.
In the most
ordinary of...
Of deeds.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(BABY CRYING)
Are you all right?
-Lucky.
-That was luck?
Miss Redfern, might I invite you
to the village dance this evening
as my guest?
You extraordinary man!
Oh, it's all becoming clear now.
The Doctor is the man you'd like to be,
doing impossible things
with cricket balls.
Well, I discovered a talent,
that's certainly true.
But the Doctor
has an eye for the ladies.
-The devil!
-A girl at every fireplace.
Ah! Now, there I have to protest, Joan.
That is hardly me.
Says the man dancing with me tonight.
That scarecrow's all askew.
Ever the artist.
Where did you learn to draw?
-Gallifrey.
-Is that in Ireland?
-Yes, it must be.
-You're not Irish.
Not at all, no. My father, Sidney,
was a watchmaker from Nottingham
and my mother, Verity, was...
-Well, she was a nurse, actually.
-Oh?
-We make such good wives.
-Really? Right.
Yes.
Well, my work is done,
what do you think?
Masterpiece.
All sorts of skills today.
Can I see?
Oh, goodness. Do I look like that?
Are you sure that's not me?
No, it's certainly this page.
You like it?
-You've made me far too beautiful.
-Well, that's how I see you.
Widows aren't supposed to be beautiful.
I think the world
would rather we stopped.
Is that fair?
That we stop?
That's not fair at all.
I've never, um...
(DOOR OPENING)
Martha, what have I told you
about entering unannounced?
Wasn't on the list.
(VIDEO FAST FORWARDING)
Four, you. Don't let me abandon you.
That's no good.
What about the stuff you didn't tell me?
What about women?
Oh, no, you didn't think of that.
What the hell am I supposed to do, then?
Thank you.
You had to, didn't you?
You had to go and
fall in love with a human.
And it wasn't me.
FEMALE VOICE: The darkness is coming.
DOCTOR: Keep me away
from the false and empty man.
MALE VOICE: The last of the Time Lords,
the last of that wise and ancient race.
(VOICES MINGLING)
Who's that playing silly beggars?
Nearly broke me neck.
Who's that, then? Is that you, Saul?
(JENNY WHIMPERING)
I don't understand.
It's Mr Clark, isn't it?
What have I done wrong?
Nothing at all.
In fact,
you're just what we need, girl.
She works at the school.
And whatever's happening seems to be
centred around that establishment.
The faintest of traces,
but they all lead back there.
It's Baines, isn't it?
This isn't very funny, sir.
Just shut up, stop talking,
cease and desist. There's a good girl!
Mother of mine is dying to meet you.
And here she is.
-Stop mocking me, sir!
-No!
Mother of mine just needs a shape.
We go through shapes so very fast.
Yours is perfectly adequate.
If a little grim.
Mother of mine,
embrace her.
You look wonderful.
You'd best give me some warning.
Um... Can you actually dance?
Um... I'm not certain.
There's a surprise.
Is there anything you're certain about?
Yes. Yes.
There you are. Come look what I've got.
Mr Pool didn't want his afternoon tea,
so cook said I could have it.
And there's enough for two.
What are you standing there for?
-Are you all right?
-I must have a cold coming on.
Problem is, I keep thinking about them,
but I don't know what to do.
-Thinking about who?
-Mr Smith and Matron,
'cause it's never gonna last,
he's gonna leave in a few weeks.
Why?
It's like his contract comes to an end
and she's going to be heartbroken.
-Leave for where?
-All sorts of places.
Oh, I wish I could tell you, Jenny,
but it's complicated.
-In what way?
-I just can't.
It sounds so interesting.
Tell me. Tell me now.
-Would you like some tea?
-Yes, thanks.
I could put a nice bit of gravy
in the pot and some mutton.
Or sardines and jam, how about that?
I like the sound of that.
Right. Hold on a tick.
-They've found us!
-This is ridiculous.
-Martha, I've warned you.
-They've found us and I've seen them!
They look like people, like us,
like normal.
I'm sorry, but you've got
to open the watch.
Where is it?
Oh, my God! Where's it gone?
Where's the watch?
What are you talking about?
You had a watch,
a fob watch, right there.
Did I? I don't remember.
I can't think
what concern it is of yours.
But we need it. Oh, my God, Doctor.
We're hiding from aliens
and they've got Jenny
and they've possessed her
or copied her or something,
and you've got to tell me,
where's the watch?
Oh, I see.
Cultural differences.
It must be so confusing for you.
Martha, this is what we call a story.
Oh, you complete...
This is not you. This is 1913.
Good. This is 1913.
I'm sorry, I'm really sorry,
but I've got to snap you out of this.
Martha!
Wake up! You're coming back
to the Tardis with me.
How dare you! I'm not going anywhere
with an insane servant.
Martha, you are dismissed. You will
leave these premises immediately.
Now, get out!
The nerve of it! The absolute cheek!
You think I'm a fantasist,
what about her?
The funny thing is,
you did have a fob watch.
Right there. Don't you remember?
Oh! Sorry!
Sorry!
Martha?
Not now, Tim, I'm busy!
Mr Smith?
No one home.
The maid
was definitely hiding something.
A secret around this Mr Smith.
We both scented him, though,
he was plain and simply human.
But maybe he knows something.
Where is he?
She's infatuated.
You're a dangerous man.
-You've taken my arm in public.
-I'm very scared.
Spare a penny
for the veterans of the Crimea, sir?
Yes, of course. There you are, then.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please take your partners for a waltz.
-You can dance.
-Quite surprised myself.
Oh, I say! Sorry.
I think this might help.
That makes it easy, Son of mine,
because Daughter of mine's
already there.
We've been invited to the dance.
Oh, staff entrance I think, miss.
Yeah, well, think again, mate.
Please don't. Not again.
He's different from any other man
you've ever met, right?
Yes.
And sometimes he says
these strange things,
like people and places
you've never heard of, yeah?
But it's deeper than that.
Sometimes when
you look in his eyes, you know,
you just know
that there's something else in there.
Something hidden.
Right behind the eyes,
something hidden away.
-In the dark.
-I don't know what you mean.
Yes, you do.
I don't mean to be rude,
but the awful thing is
it doesn't even matter what you think.
But you're nice and you're lucky.
And I just wanted to say sorry
for what I'm about to do.
Oh, now, really, Martha,
this is getting out of hand.
I must insist that you leave.
Do you know what this is?
Name it.
Go on, name it.
John, what is that silly thing?
John?
You're not John Smith.
You're called the Doctor.
The man in your journal, he's real.
He's you.
Evening, all! Spare a penny, sir?
I didn't spare you.
You will be silent!
All of you!
I said, silent!
Mr Clark, what's going on?
Mr Smith, everything I told you,
just forget it.
Don't say anything.
We asked for silence!
Now then,
we have a few questions for Mr Smith.
No, better than that.
The teacher, he's the Doctor.
I heard them talking.
You took human form.
Of course I'm human!
I was born human, as were you, Baines!
And Jenny and you, Mr Clark.
What is going on? This is madness!
Ooh, and a human brain, too.
Simple, thick and dull.
But he's no good like this.
We need a Time Lord.
Easily done.
(ALL GASP)
-Change back.
-I don't know what you're talking about.
Change back!
I literally do not know...
-Get off me!
-She's your friend, isn't she?
Doesn't this scare you enough
to change back?
-I don't know what you mean!
-Wait a minute.
The maid told me about
Smith and the matron.
-That woman, there.
-Then let's have you!
Have you enjoyed it, Doctor?
Being human?
Has it taught you wonderful things?
Are you better, richer, wiser?
Then let's see you answer this.
Which one of them
do you want us to kill?
Maid or matron?
Your friend
or your lover?
Your choice.
We are the Family of Blood.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
Save us.
I am not the Doctor.
TIM: He's like the night
and the storm and the heart of the sun.
He's ancient and forever.
He burns at the centre of time
and he can see the turn of the universe.