-(ZYGON GROWLING)
-(SHUDDERING)
The Doctor will save me.
Excuse me, I'm going
to need my inhaler.
Any second now you are
going to stop that countdown.
-Both of you. Together.
-(TIMER BEEPING)
And then you are going to negotiate
the most perfect treaty of all time.
Safeguards all round,
completely fair on both sides.
And the key to
perfect negotiation.
Not knowing
what side you're on.
So, for the next few hours,
until we decide
to let you out.
No one in this room
will be able to remember
if they are human or Zygon.
Whoopsy daisy!
(DEVICES WHIRRING)
(TIMER BEEPING)
Cancel the detonation!
-Hello.
-Do you want to...
-No, you can if you...
BOTH: Should
we do it together?
Operation Double.
The Zygon peace treaty.
-I'm Osgood.
-I'm also Osgood.
Remember that,
it'll be important later.
Operation Double
is a covert operation,
outside of
normal UNIT strictures,
to resettle and rehouse an alien race,
in secrecy, on planet Earth.
With UNIT's help, 20 million Zygons have
been allowed to take human form,
been dispersed
around the world
and are now living amongst us.
We're making this
in case something goes wrong.
In case UNIT is infiltrated.
In case something occurs
to unmask the Zygons.
Or in case one
or both of us dies.
(SOBBING)
The Zygons a peaceful race.
Their shape-changing abilities should
not be considered a weapon.
It's a survival mechanism.
They embed themselves
in other cultures,
and live out their lives
in their new bodies
in peace and harmony.
Mainly.
Any race is capable of
the best and the worst.
Every race is peaceful and warlike.
Good and evil.
My race is no exception.
And neither is mine.
If one Zygon goes rogue.
Or one human.
Then the ceasefire will break.
That's why the Doctor left us this.
He called it the Osgood box.
If you've been paying attention,
you'll be able to guess why.
This is the last resort.
The final sanction.
Pray this box is never needed.
Because if it is, that means
the ceasefire is breaking.
And with 20 million
shape-changing Zygons
dispersed around the world...
That is the nightmare scenario.
-(GUNFIRE)
-(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
-(GLASS SHATTERING)
- (SHRIEKS)
(INHALING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(GROWLING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MOBILE CHIMES)
-(ZYGON GROWLING)
- (SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMING)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(GUITAR PLAYING AMAZING GRACE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Come on, kids, no pushing.
Hi, this is Clara Oswald. I am probably
on the tube or in outer space.
-Leave a message.
-(LINE BEEPS)
Hello, it's Doctor Disco.
I'm in the 21st century.
I don't know what month.
I'm staking out some of the most
dangerous creatures imaginable.
Operating under deep cover.
Trying not to attract suspicion.
Give me a call, Clara.
Nightmare scenario.
I'm worried.
Okay. Hey, monster, hi.
Cinderella.
Down, off monkey bars.
Listen to me, we've got to talk.
Get me Colonel Walsh.
And I need you to coordinate
the Operation Double Locations.
There are 20 million Zygons.
And most of the data was with...
Her.
KATE: Do what you can.
Start with any that have intelligence
flags from the past six months.
-(COMPUTER BEEPING)
-Walsh coming through.
WALSH: (ON COMPUTER)
Walsh, Turmezistan.
Any new arrivals?
One. Pictures aren't very good.
Can you zoom in on the prisoner?
It's her. Get into her files,
we have to assume they
have been compromised.
JAC: Um, too late.
The encryption system
has already been hacked.
And they've sent through
another video.
Look, I admire you, okay?
I think you're ingenious.
Pretending to be a couple
of seven year olds.
It's a splendid way to
conceal your blobbyness.
But let's not pretend,
you are very blobby.
In fact, you two are the big blobs,
and you are not to withdraw
the ceasefire.
Fine, fine. Bury your heads.
Listen to me. Listen.
There are other factions.
I know there are
other blobby factions
that you don't control.
They're planning something.
And if we don't get
together and stop it,
it will be the end of this.
Of all of you.
This is our jurisdiction, Doctor.
These are our creatures.
We are close to finding them.
They are our children
and we will deal with them.
You kids are out of control.
-I'm taking this out of your hands.
-(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Don't even think about
going anywhere.
Are you phoning me
with your backside again
or are you really sending me
a distress signal?
KATE: I'm really
sending you a distress signal.
They've kidnapped Osgood
and they've stolen the
location of every Zygon on Earth.
Doctor, the ceasefire
has broken down.
(GAS HISSING)
Hey! Away! Away!
Got a situation!
Out of the way!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Move! Move away!
(GIRL SCREAMING)
(TYRES SQUEALING)
"UNIT troops will be destroyed
"wherever they are in the world.
"The enemies of our race
will be destroyed
"wherever they are in the world.
"The war is about to begin.
"There will be truth.
"Or there will be
consequences."”
-(LINE RINGING)
-Hi this is Clara Oswald.
I'm probably on the tube
or in outer space.
-Leave a message.
-(LINE BEEPS)
Call me now.
(MOBILE PHONE CHIMES)
(CHUCKLES)
(LINE RINGING)
-(LINE BEEPS)
-DOCTOR: Hello, it's Doctor Disco.
-Hello.
-Oh, hello.
Sandeep, hello.
You okay?
I can't find my
mummy and daddy.
Well, why don't you wait here
and I can go see
if I can find them.
Hello?
(GASPS) Oh, sorry. Um...
Your little boy is out there.
He couldn't find you.
MAN: Daddy's here.
We can take him.
(SANDEEP SCREAMING)
Is he... Is he okay?
Everything's fine.
(LINE RINGING)
Did you just call yourself
"Doctor Disco"?
KATE: This is where the Zygon
High Command had their secret base.
CLARA: A junior school?
KATE: Terms of the settlement,
Operation Double, were these.
Twenty million Zygons,
the entire hatchery,
were allowed to be born
and to stay on Earth.
They were permitted
to permanently take up
the form of the nearest
available human beings.
In this case,
a large percentage of
the population of the UK.
KATE: He left us with an
impossible situation, Doctor.
Yes, I know. It's called "peace”.
What about the two little
girl commanders?
Weren't they helping him?
KATE: Well, they've been
almost impossible to deal with
since Osgood left.
Secretive, uncommunicative.
We've known there's something going on.
Some radicalisation.
Some revolution in
the younger brood.
They said they had it under control.
The Zygon Command Centre.
That's the control polyp
for all Zygons on Earth.
JAC: It's horrible.
Could you...
Would you mind? Thank you.
If this has been compromised...
Zygons are wide open.
They'll be starting to panic,
starting to worry.
Doctor, do you want to
be alone with that thing?
It's a command computer.
You operate it by
titivating the fronds.
Are you enjoying that?
I snogged a Zygon once.
Old habits...
(POLYP GROANS)
Still got the old magic.
So Osgood's
been kidnapped, right?
I though Osgood was dead.
There have always been two of her
ever since the ceasefire.
We never knew
which one was real.
-Both of them.
-Okay. Which one was Zygon?
Both of them. They would
have maintained a live link.
They were both Zygon and human
at the same time.
They not only
administered the peace,
they were the peace.
When the other Osgood died,
the survivor went
pretty much mad with grief.
Then she just disappeared.
Went undercover in the States.
Now, of course,
the rebels have her.
(SQUELCHING)
Ah. Okay.
Zygons hatched and
dispersed all over,
but something's gone wrong.
Mexico border, North Asia,
West Africa, Australia.
Panic, paranoia.
What would happen
if they knew who we were?
(TABLET CHIMES)
We've received another video.
That's the Zygon High Command.
It's Jemima and Claudette.
ZYGON: We have been betrayed.
We were sold.
Our rights were violated.
We demand the right
to be ourselves.
No more lies.
No more lies!
(GROWLING)
We are now
the Zygon High Command.
All traitors will die.
"Truth or consequences”.
DOCTOR: So, we have a Zygon
revolution on our hands.
We need to open negotiations.
I am not negotiating with them.
As far as they are concerned
everyone's a traitor.
If you're not gonna negotiate,
what are you gonna do?
They're holed up in this
settlement in Turmezistan.
It's where they've taken Osgood.
I'm going to order
Colonel Walsh to bomb it.
Isn't there a solution that
doesn't involve bombing everyone?
The treaty has been
comprehensively violated, Doctor.
This is a splinter group.
The rest of the Zygons,
the vast majority,
they want to live in peace.
You start bombing them
you'll radicalise the lot.
It's exactly what
the splinter group wants.
"Truth or Consequences".
What exactly does that mean?
It's just the usual
kind of nonsense
these idiots call themselves.
-It's in New Mexico.
-KATE: What?
It's a town in New Mexico,
Truth or Consequences.
Um, they renamed
it after a TV show
for a bet or something.
It's a Trivial Pursuit question.
I used to memorise
Trivial Pursuit questions
so I could win.
That's the last place
we received signal
from Osgood's phone, isn't it?
New Mexico.
Okay, Kate Stewart,
no bombs for you.
Go to Truth or Consequences.
See what you can find out.
The Doctor will go
to Turmezistan,
negotiate peace,
rescue Osgood, prevent this war.
'Cause that's what he does.
Clara, Jac, you stay here.
This is your country.
Protect it from
the scary monsters,
and also from the Zygons.
Bye.
Oh. Um, do you still have
the presidential aircraft?
I thought you didn't like
being president of the world.
No. But I like poncing
about in the big plane.
How many troops do you have?
(SCOFFS) Not many.
Usually, on bigger cases,
we can draft in from the regular army,
we can't do that now.
Secrecy of the project
has to be maintained.
Have you got any
snazzy weapons?
There was an attempted
Zygon invasion before,
in the '70s, '80s,
one of our staff
was a naval surgeon,
who worked at Porton Down
when they captured Zygons,
developed Z-67.
It's a nerve gas.
Unravels their DNA.
Basically, turns them inside out.
-Where do you keep it?
-(CHUCKLES)
We don't. It was taken.
The formula. The lot.
Who took it?
Somebody with a Tardis.
They are ready for you, ma'am.
Keep in touch.
Oh! I just need to swing by home
and grab a couple of things.
Yeah, of course.
MAN: Quick.
Before someone sees us.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
(SANDEEP SCREAMING)
It's really slow, we can catch them.
Come on.
-CLARA: It's slower than usual.
-JAC: What's wrong with it?
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Is there a cellar or somewhere
else they could have gone?
No.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Ugh. What is that?
No, don't.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
(SANDEEP SCREAMING)
MAN: All together.
Put them all together.
I think we need to get
some reinforcements.
MAN: Over there.
Put them there.
Approaching target at 1006512.
-Confirm strike order.
-Order confirmed.
At ease.
I'm the president of the world.
I'm here to rescue people,
and generally establish
happiness all over the place.
The Doctor.
Doctor Funkenstein.
Yes, we know who you are.
LISA: Going to strike altitude.
What's going on here?
Fun and games?
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
74. Negative.
MAN: (ON RADIO)
We're 700 metres lower.
700 metres lower
than planned. Over.
You're not bombing that town.
That's where they're
holding my friend.
They're dangerous, and your friend
is almost certainly dead.
I'm not gonna
allow them to disperse.
You can't track a shapeshifter.
Visual on the target.
WALSH: Confirm strike.
Colonel.
Confirm strike.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Strike aborted.
Well, that's interesting.
(DOG BARKING)
(ZYGON GROWLING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
Hello?
You one of them?
I'm a friend. I've come to help.
Alone?
Have you come to help alone?
What happened here?
You must have brought back-up.
Where's your back-up?
-Tell me!
-First, tell me why I need it.
We think it's
a Zygon training camp.
We never see more than one or two of
them outside at any one time,
but they always take
different shapes.
We don't know
how many there really are.
We don't know how
they come and go.
Whether they go
through tunnels,
or whether they turn into dogs
and run out across the hills.
So that's what we'll find out.
We should have that gas.
We should be able
to rip them inside out.
Colonel, take it easy.
They are trying to unsettle you.
They are trying to
make you paranoid, panicked.
Any living thing in this world,
including my family and friends,
could turn into a Zygon
and kill me any second now.
It's not paranoia when it's real.
I've been looking into this.
There have been reports
all over London
of strange activity in lifts.
I've patched into CCTV
from Scotland Yard,
all the elevators I could find.
Now, this is SOAS.
People dragging bundles.
They go down, down,
down, down, down,
a few minutes go by and then...
They're all gone.
There is something very wrong
happening underneath London.
The Brits came two years ago.
We didn't want them.
They just... (SIGHS)
They just turned up.
No jobs, nowhere to live, no money.
And they were...
They were odd.
(SIGHS) They started
getting into fights.
-A couple of them got killed.
-More than a couple.
What happened here?
Well, after the murders
they started banding together.
And then, one day,
one of them changed.
"Changed"?
One of them was
walking down West Main,
and suddenly...
It turned into a...
(EXHALES) A reptile.
They just came for us.
They turned into monsters
and they came for us.
And (STUTTERS)
we couldn't fight them.
You can't tell who's who.
(SIGHS) They can turn
your own family against you.
Have you seen her?
Yeah, she was here.
She was at the motel
asking questions. Before.
(SIGHS) Everybody's gone.
Where?
(SIGHS)
WALSH: (ON RADIO)
Okay, listen carefully.
Once we get to the village we have a
30-minute window before the air strike.
We all know what
a rabbit warren this place is,
but we've got intel they're
holed up inside the church.
Hitchley, you take the front,
Stormit, draw their fire,
the Doctor and I
will take the back.
This is our object.
We need to get her back safely.
Try to kill as few of
them as possible.
I need to have someone
to negotiate with.
You know what
they're capable of.
Do not fall victim to it.
Trap open. Code green.
HITCHLEY: Let's move out.
Come out.
Throw down your weapons.
Come out!
We have you surrounded.
Come out of there!
Come out!
We have you surrounded.
I don't have any weapons.
Please.
-Take aim. On my command.
-(GUNS COCKING)
No. No, don't. Please.
Johnny, you don't understand.
You're not my mother.
Don't use my name.
They took us here.
They came to the
house and took us.
They took your sister, me.
You stay where you are.
It's not us who are the imposters.
Don't let them trick you.
It's your commanders.
Your chief.
They're the aliens.
WALSH: (ON RADIO)
Do not fall victim.
Ask for details.
She is a copy. Ask her something
only your mum could know.
Mom, I'm gonna have to
ask you some questions.
Don't do this. You know it's me.
Don't let them trick you.
Date and place of my birth.
They brought us here.
They're using us against you.
I'm scared.
Please. I'm so scared.
Name of my favourite teddy bear.
I don't remember.
I'm sorry, I don't.
(ON RADIO) Don't kill me
because I can't remember.
Hitchley.
Stay back. All of you,
stay back from them!
That is not your mother.
It's an alien hostile.
WOMAN: We're not those
creatures, we're hostages.
Kill it!
I can prove it.
I can prove who we are.
Just come inside, I'll show you.
Don't go in there.
-Please.
-You are not my mom.
Oh, God.
You're going to kill me.
-Mom, please.
-WOMAN: You are.
You're going to kill me.
I love you.
I forgive you and I love you.
(SOBBING)
Do it!
What proof?
Don't go in there.
You're going to your death.
(ON RADIO) Hitchley, kill it.
HITCHLEY: Let's go.
Over and out, ma'am.
Oh, damn it!
Damn it!
This is poisonous.
Just let me go in and talk.
(GUNSHOTS)
WALSH: They've executed my men.
DOCTOR: Where are the Zygons?
We need to bomb
the hell out of this place,
it's infested with these things.
We can't tell who
the enemy is any more.
We can't count them,
and we can't track them.
I'm not gonna let you do that.
I just lost my men.
I'll quite happily bomb
the hell out of anywhere.
We need to move.
Strike's on its way.
I need to find Osgood.
You've got 10 minutes.
-OSGOOD: Help! Help!
-DOCTOR: Osgood?
-Osgood?
-Doctor.
-Doctor, I'm here.
Osgood!
Help! Doctor, I'm down here.
-Osgood!
-Doctor.
Doctor!
-Osgood.
(PLANES PASSING)
Got to get you out.
They're gonna bomb this place.
-What do the Zygons want?
-They're training,
practising new skills.
Doctor, what are you doing here?
-(DEVICE WHIRRING)
-Rescuing you.
In quite a dashing way,
I might add.
They fled through the tunnels.
They're going back to the UK.
If you're here, they've
got you out of the way.
-Who's left in the UK?
-Clara.
ZYGON: (SCREECHING) Clara!
DOCTOR: Oh, hello.
(EXPLOSION)
They've started.
So much for "10 minutes”.
(EXPLOSION)
KATE: You've found something?
What do you want me to see?
(FLIES BUZZING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
-Oh, God.
Were those all people?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING
IN DISTANCE)
JAC: Oh, it's an odd
world nowadays, isn't it?
It's always been an odd world.
Mmm-hmm. I mean,
doesn't it feel sometimes
that things are
coming to an end,
everything is just going nuts?
You're middle-aged,
that's what it is. No offence.
Everybody middle-aged always thinks
the world is about to come to an end.
(CHUCKLES) Never does.
It's here.
Oh, my God.
(ON MOBILE PHONE)
Hi, this is Clara Oswald.
I'm probably on the tube
or in outer space.
-Leave a message.
-(LINE BEEPS)
Can you change your
voicemail message, please?
It's getting very boring.
Oh, I see you've accessorised it.
Yes.
The old question marks.
You used to wear question marks.
Oh, I know. Yes, I did.
They were nice. Why don't
you wear them any more?
Oh, I do.
I've got
question mark underpants.
Makes one wonder
what the question is.
Which one are you,
human or Zygon?
-I don't answer that question.
-Why not?
Because there isn't
a question to answer.
I don't accept it.
My sister and I were the living
embodiment of the peace we made.
I will give all the lives
that I have to protect it.
You want to know
who I am, Doctor?
I am the peace.
I am human and Zygon.
Like a hybrid.
A hybrid, if you like.
Well, I am proud to
know you, Osgood.
And I promise that
I won't tell anyone
that you're a human.
Zygons need to keep
the human original alive
to refresh the body print.
If you were a Zygon,
you would have changed back
within days of your sister's death.
Those were the old rules.
Before, Zygons could pluck
loved ones from your memory
and wear their faces.
Zygons only need to
keep the original alive
if they need more
information from them.
If the interrogation is over,
then the original can die.
Oh, my God.
These are Zygon pods.
I think you might be right.
About what?
The end of the world.
(SNARLING)
Bit of first things firstness.
What's your name?
My name is... Well...
Well, you can call me the Doctor.
But then you knew that, didn't you?
You want something.
What is it?
You are the president of the world.
I suppose so.
We want the world. (LAUGHING)
Okay. It looks like whole buildings
full of people have been pinched.
In fact, it looks like a whole
London full of people
have been pinched.
But, we've got here early,
and they're still growing.
We have to neutralise these
before they hatch.
Take your positions.
Do you know what?
I'm enjoying this.
-Clara.
-What?
We don't know
that's what these are.
Oh, come on. These are
eggs or pods or whatever.
Look.
Oh, my God, that's me.
I think we should wait.
Look, they're here.
They're growing duplicates of us.
We have to destroy them.
I've seen this happen before.
It happened to that little boy,
they took his parents
and then they took him.
But I don't see how
these are duplicates.
That's not how Zygons work.
They don't grow duplicates.
They kidnap the original,
so these...
These are the humans.
Retreat.
Retreat! This is a trap!
This is an ambush! (GASPS)
(SHUDDERING)
JAC: No!
Oh, no, Miss Oswald, please.
-Please.
-Kill the traitors.
(JAC SCREAMING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SANDEEP SCREAMING)
Is he... Is he okay?
Hello, Clara.
My name is Bonnie.
We want the truth
of who we are
to be acknowledged.
We want to live as ourselves,
at any cost.
We want a home.
DOCTOR: Well, you can't
have the United Kingdom.
There's already people living there.
They'll think you're
gonna pinch their benefits.
We're already there, Doctor.
The invasion has
already taken place,
bit by bit over the last year.
We've won the first battle.
And now, we are
going to begin the war.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
There's hundreds more.
They killed everybody.
We have to find out
what forms they took,
how many of them there were.
How did this happen?
Somebody once caught
the briefest of glimpses
of a Zygon in its proper form.
(SIGHS) A child,
who hadn't learnt to
preserve its body print.
It had been left alone to
learn these things for itself.
And then, word went
around these primitives
that we were monsters.
IIWell?
There isn't any back-up,
is there?
I just had to be sure.
BONNIE: (ON PHONE)
Commander calling.
"Truth or Consequences',
what is your status?
Repeat. Commander calling.
"Truth or Consequences',
what is your status?
Commander, UNIT neutralised
in North America.
"Truth or Consequences".
-Copy that.
-(DISCONNECTS CALL)
Bonnie speaking.
UNIT neutralised in the UK.
More or less.
(LINE RINGING)
-(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
-Answer it. Say goodbye.
This plane will never land.
Really? Clara.
Doctor.
Clara?
There you are.
Clara, I'm glad you're okay.
Listen.
You're breaking up.
The invasion has happened.
You're probably
surrounded by Zygons.
Get to the Tardis.
Get yourself safe.
And apparently, my plane
is never going to land.
But let's see what we're
going to do about that.
I'm sorry, but Clara's dead.
Kate Stewart is dead.
The UNIT troops are all dead.
"Truth or Consequences".
Clara!