Attention, Albert Hall, London, UK,
Planet Earth!
I am the Vlinkstatic
X-Form Robo-Neuro-Actoform
Designation Number 5576, but you can
call me "The Vlinx!"
Hello!
AUDIENCE: Hello!
I said, "Hello"!
AUDIENCE: HELLO!
Thank you.
And it is my greatest function to
introduce a very special guest -
human beings, please welcome...
The Doctor!
VWORP!
Hello!
AUDIENCE CHEER
Hello, there, Royal Albert Hall.
HE LAUGHS
OK, look at you!
ALARM BLARES
Emergency, emergency!
The Albert Hall is being invaded!
Save yourselves, because here
comes...
MELODIC CACKLING
..The Pantheon of Discord!
SING-SONG: Ta-dah!
AUDIENCE CHEER AND BOO
I am...Maestro, the God of Music,
And music is MINE!
THEY CACKLE,
AUDIENCE CHUCKLE
Oh, scream all you like!
Yeah, yeah, yeah -
you tiny little human pimples!
THEY LAUGH
Cos the Doctor can't stop me this
time!
My powers are vast and godlike,
and my hairstyle is exquisite,
don't you think?
And now, I have an orchestra in the
world's finest auditorium!
And I will feast, because I know
that when humans hear bad music,
it creates a dissonance in your
heads.
AUDIENCE LAUGH
Yeah, dissonance!
Get me and my fancy vocabulary,
chickadees.
Ha! Diss-o-nance!
And that pain becomes food and drink
for me.
Now, you will suffer,
and I will grow in power as I
command this orchestra to play
the world's worst song EVER!
THEY LAUGH
That's right, boys, and girls, and
everyone,
it's your all-time LEAST favourite
song - "I've Got A Dog"!
THEY CACKLE,
CHEERING
And a-one, and a-two...
MUSIC: "I've Got A Dog"
by Murray Gold
Oh... Mmm...
Tasty... More, more!
THEY CACKLE
# I've got a Dog
He's called Fred
# My dog is alive
He's not dead
# I love my dog... #
Tasty!
THEY CACKLE
# He loves me too
I haven't got a cat
# Only a dog
My Dog, my Dog... #
Whoops! Excuse me.
# My Dog, my Dog... #
I am FEASTING, after all! Ha!
# I have a dog
I love my dog... #
Emergency message from the Doctor!
He recommends that everyone starts
clapping - IMMEDIATELY!
Human beings must clap!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
But I love the applause - it is
music to my ears.
Everyone SHOULD adore me!
The Doctor has an astute grasp of
logic,
because applause takes place
ONLY when the music has stopped!
Therefore, clapping will cancel out
Maestro's powers.
Recommendation - applause from all.
Don't just clap, stand up, cheer!
No!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Stomp your feet!
Make a lot of noise!
No, no, no! STOP, I beg of you!
Go crazy! No, stop, please!
I'm going to...
..EXPLODE!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Operation Maestro a complete
success!
Congratulations!
And don't forget - Maestro is so
wrong. There is no bad music.
If it's an orchestra, or a band, or
the wind in the trees,
or your next-door neighbour singing
in the shower, music is beautiful,
and the God of Music has no power
over you,
because music belongs to everyone.
The amazing human race -
sailing through the cosmos and
singing to the stars. Forever.
Love you. Bye-bye.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
VWORP!