DOCTOR: Get down!
-Ah! They're following us.
-And the good news is?
Their life spans are running out,
so we hide, wait for them to die.
I have to stop being a Time Lord.
I'm going to become human.
Chameleon Arch. Rewrites my biology.
"A Journal of Impossible Things."
-Such imagination!
-It's become quite a hobby.
He's different from any man
you've ever met, right?
Yes.
He had to go and fall in love
with a human. And it wasn't me.
If they find us, Martha, open the watch.
Sometimes I say things
and they turn out to be correct.
They've found us.
-Oh, my God! Where's the watch?
-What are you talking about?
This is not you. This is 1913.
Change back!
We need a Time Lord.
Which one of them
do you want us to kill?
Doesn't this scare you enough
to change back?
Your friend or your lover?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
JENNY: Make your decision, Mr Smith.
BAINES: Perhaps if that human heart
breaks, the Time Lord will emerge.
-Time Lord.
-Tim!
(SCREAMING)
All right!
One more move and I shoot.
-Oh, the maid is full of fire!
-And you can shut up!
Careful, Son of mine.
She's all for you
so that you can live forever.
Shoot you down.
Try it. We'll die together.
Would you really pull the trigger?
Looks too scared.
Scared and holding a gun
is a good combination.
Do you want to risk it?
Doctor, get everyone out.
There's a door at the side.
It's over there. Go on!
MARTHA: Do it, Mr Smith, I mean you!
Do what she said. Everybody out now!
Don't argue, Mr Jackson.
They're mad, that's all we need to know.
Susan, Miss Cooper, outside, all of you!
Move yourself, boy.
Back to the school, quickly!
-And you, go on, just shift.
-What about you?
Mr Smith, I think you should escort
your lady friend to safety, don't you?
Mr Hicks, warn the village.
Get everyone out.
Latimer, get back to the school.
Tell the headmaster...
Don't touch me! You're as bad as them.
Don't try anything.
I'm warning you, or sonny boy gets it.
-She's almost brave, this one.
-I should have taken her form.
Much more fun, so much spirit.
-What happened to Jenny? Has she gone?
-She is consumed. Her body's mine.
You mean she's dead?
Yes, and she went
with precious little dignity.
All that screaming.
BAINES: Get the gun!
Good work, soldier.
Don't just stand there, move!
God, you're rubbish as a human. Come on!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(WEAPON FIRING)
Run! Ah, this is super.
We've been in hiding for too long.
This is sport!
I can smell the schoolteacher.
He's gone back to his academy.
And what do we know about her?
This body has traces of memory.
Was once her friend.
Martha would go walking to the west.
Husband of mine,
follow the maid's scent.
Go to the west.
Find out what she was keeping secret.
Soldiers!
As for you, Mother of mine,
let's go to school.
-What are you doing?
-Maybe one man can't fight them,
but this school teaches us
to stand together.
Take arms! Take arms!
-Stop doing that!
-You want me to fight, don't you?
-Take arms! Take arms!
-1 say, sir, what's the matter?
Enemy at the door, Hutchinson,
enemy at the door.
Take arms!
-They're sounding the alarms.
-I wouldn't be so pleased, Son of mine.
These bodies are silly and hot,
they can damage and die.
That's why we need the Time Lord.
Indeed, they will have guns.
Perhaps a little caution.
Sister of mine,
you're such a small little thing.
Find a way in and spy on them.
-You can't do this, Doctor. Mr Smith!
-Maintain position over the stable yard.
They're just boys,
you can't ask them to fight.
-They don't stand a chance!
-They are cadets, Miss Jones.
They are trained to defend the King
and all his citizens and properties.
What in thunder's name is this?
Before I devise an excellent
and endless series of punishments
for each and every one of you,
could someone explain,
very simply and immediately,
exactly what is going on?
Headmaster, I have to report,
the school is under attack.
Really? Is that so?
Perhaps you and I
should have a word in private.
No, I promise you, sir.
I was in the village with Matron.
It's Baines, sir, Jeremy Baines,
and Mr Clark from Oakham Farm.
They've gone mad, sir. They've got guns.
They've already murdered people
in the village. I saw it happen.
-Matron, is that so?
-I'm afraid it's true, sir.
-Murder? On our own soil?
- I saw it, yes.
Perhaps you did well then, Mr Smith.
And what makes you think
the danger is coming here?
-Well, sir, they said, um...
-Baines threatened Mr Smith, sir.
Said he'd follow him. We don't know why.
Very well.
You boys remain on guard,
Mr Snell, telephone for the police.
Mr Phillips, with me.
We shall investigate.
No! It's not safe out there.
Mr Smith, it seems your
favourite servant is giving me advice.
You will control her, sir.
Got to find that watch.
DOCTOR: Hold me, keep me safe.
Keep me dark, keep me closed.
The time is not right, not yet.
Not while the Family is abroad. Danger!
So, Baines,
and one of the cleaning staff.
There's always a woman involved.
Am I to gather that some practical joke
has got out of hand?
Headmaster, sir. Good evening, sir.
Come to give me a caning, sir?
-Would you like that, sir?
-Keep a civil tongue, boy.
Now, come on, everyone. I suspect
alcohol has played its part in this.
Let's all just calm down.
Who are these friends of yours, Baines,
in fancy dress?
Do you like them, Mr Phillips?
I made them myself.
I'm ever so good at science, sir. Look.
Molecular fringe animation,
fashioned in the shape of straw men.
My own private army, sir.
It's ever so good, sir.
Baines, step apart from this company
and come inside with me.
No, sir. You, sir,
you will send us Mr John Smith.
That's all we want, sir, Mr John Smith,
and whatever he's done with
his Time Lord consciousness.
Then we'd be very happy
to leave you alone.
You speak with someone else's voice,
Baines. Who might that be?
We are the Family of Blood.
-Mr Smith said there had been deaths.
-Yes, sir, and they were good, sir.
Well, I warn you, the school is armed.
All your little tin soldiers.
But tell me, sir,
-will they thank you?
-I don't understand.
What do you know of history, sir?
What do you know of next year?
-You're not making sense, Baines.
-1914, sir.
Because the Family has travelled
far and wide looking for Mr Smith,
and, oh, the things we have seen.
War is coming.
In foreign fields,
war of the whole wide world
with all your boys
falling down in the mud.
Do you think they will thank the man
who taught them it was glorious?
Don't you forget, boy,
I have been a soldier.
I was in South Africa.
I used my dead mates for sandbags.
I fought with the butt of my rifle
when the bullets ran out,
and I would go back there tomorrow
for King and country.
Etcetera, etcetera.
Run along, Headmaster.
Run back to school.
And send us Mr Smith!
(JENNY LAUGHING)
Mr Phillips has been murdered.
Mr Smith, can you tell me why?
Honestly, sir, I have no idea.
And the telephone line has been
disconnected. We are on our own.
Well, if we have to make a fight of it,
then make a fight we shall.
Hutchinson, we'll build a barricade
within the courtyards.
Fortify the entrances,
build our defences.
Gentlemen, in the name of the King
we shall stand against them.
ALL: Yes, sir.
BOY: Right, come on. Let's get moving.
Down!
Barricade the kitchens.
Secure the passageway to the stables.
You little coward.
You will do your duty, Latimer,
with the rest of us.
Sandbags to the north and west!
Williams, you take charge. Pemberton,
load the spare magazines with bullets.
SMITH: Take the magazine cut-off out.
They've got an army.
So do we.
Soldiers.
Soldiers!
Ashington, we need water for
the Vickers gun. See to it.
Faster, all of you, faster.
Lockley, when firing commences,
you're in charge of the gathering.
Peterson, that's not acceptable.
Report to your senior officer.
War comes to England
a year in advance.
LUCY: Family of mine, wait.
Hold the soldiers back.
The Time Lord is playing
some sort of trick.
BAINES: Discover him, Sister of mine.
I know it sounds mad,
but when the Doctor became human,
he took the alien part of himself
and he stored it inside the watch.
It's not really a watch,
it just looks like a watch.
And "alien" means not from abroad,
I take it?
The man you call John Smith,
he was born on another world.
-A different species.
-Yeah.
Then tell me, in this fairy tale,
who are you?
Just a friend.
I'm not... I mean, you haven't
got a rival, as much as I might...
-Just his friend.
-And human, I take it?
Human, don't worry. More than that,
I don't just follow him around,
I'm training to be a doctor.
Not an alien doctor,
a proper doctor, a doctor of medicine.
Well, that certainly is nonsense.
Women might train to be doctors,
but hardly the skivvy
and hardly one of your colour.
Oh, do you think?
Bones of the hand.
Carpal bones, proximal row:
scaphoid, lunate, triquetral, pisiform.
Distal row:
trapezium, trapezoid, cap it ate, ha mate.
Then the metacarpal bones
extending in three distinct phalanges:
proximal, middle, distal.
-Well, you read that in a book.
-Yes, to pass my exams!
-Can't you see this is true?
-I must go.
If we find that watch, we can stop them.
Those boys are going to fight.
I might not be a doctor,
but I'm still their nurse.
They need me.
Son of mine, Wife of mine.
Father of mine, what have you found?
His Tardis.
The Doctor can't escape.
You're with Armitage and Thwaites,
they know the drill.
-Joan, it's not safe.
-I'm doing my duty, just as much as you.
Fine evening we've had together.
Not quite as planned.
Tell me about Nottingham.
Sorry?
That's where you were brought up,
tell me about it.
Well, it lies on the River Leen
with its southern boundary
following the course of the River Trent,
which flows from Stoke to the Humber.
That sounds like an encyclopaedia.
Where did you live?
Broadmarsh Street,
adjacent to Hockley Terrace
in the district of Radford Parade.
More than facts.
When you were a child,
where did you play?
All those secret little places,
the dens and hideaways
that only a child knows.
Tell me, John, please, tell me.
How can you think I'm not real?
-When I kissed you, was that a lie?
-No, it wasn't, no.
But this Doctor sounds like some...
Some romantic lost prince.
Would you rather that?
-Am I not enough?
-No, that's not true, never.
I've got to go.
Martha was right about one thing.
Those boys, they're children.
John Smith wouldn't want them to fight,
never mind the Doctor.
The John Smith I was getting to know,
he knows it's wrong.
-Doesn't he?
-Mr Smith, if you please!
What choice do I have?
Get those bags piled up, filth.
They're going to mean the difference
between life and death for us.
-Not for you and me.
-What are you babbling about?
We go to battle together.
We fight alongside.
I've seen it. Not here, not now.
-What's that supposed to mean?
-It means you and I both survive this.
And maybe...
Maybe I was given this watch
so I could help.
I'm sorry.
-Latimer, you filthy coward!
-Oh, yes, sir, every time.
What do I do?
What do I do? What do I do?
VOICES: Beware!
-Beware of what?
-VOICES: Her!
Keep away.
-Who are you?
-I saw you at the dance.
You were with that family,
you're one of them.
-What are you hiding?
-Nothing.
-What have you got there?
Show me, little boy.
I reckon, whatever you are,
you're still in the shape of a girl.
How strong is she, do you think?
Does she really want to see this?
-Time Lord!
-Inside the device.
Everything he is, concealed away
in the hands of a schoolboy.
But now we know
that's all we need to find,
the boy and the watch.
What are we waiting for? Attack!
(BANGING)
Stand to!
At post!
BOY: Enemy approaching, sir.
(BANGING)
Steady.
Find the biting point.
Fear...
Fire!
Cease fire!
Just straw.
Like he said. Straw!
Then no one is dead, sir.
We killed no one.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Stand to!
You, child, come out of the way!
Come into the school!
You don't know who's out there.
It's the Cartwright girl, isn't it?
Come here, come to me.
Mr Rocastle, please, don't go near her.
-You were told to be quiet.
-Just listen to me, she's part of it.
Matron, tell him.
I think... I don't know, I think
you should stay back, Headmaster.
-Mr Smith.
-She was with Baines in the village.
Mr Smith, I've seen
many strange sights this night,
but there is no cause on God's earth
that would allow me
to see this child
in the field of battle, sir.
-Come with me.
-You're funny.
That's right. Now, take my hand.
So funny.
Now, who's going to shoot me?
Any of you, really?
Put down your guns.
But, sir, the Headmaster.
I'll not see this happen, not any more.
You will retreat in an orderly fashion
back through the school.
Hutchinson, lead the way.
-But, sir...
-1 said, lead the way.
Well, go on, then. Run!
-BAINES: Soldiers!
-Come on!
BAINES: Reanimate!
Let's go, quick as you can!
Don't go to the village, it's not safe!
-And you, ladies.
-Not till we've got the boys out.
One of these boys has got the watch.
-JENNY: This one?
-No.
-This one?
-JENNY: This one?
-No.
Get off me! I said get off!
Ah! This one, is that him?
No.
Right, then we can kill this lot.
MALE VOICE: Lord of time.
-That's him.
-Upstairs!
Well, don't just stand there, outside!
Come on, out!
I insist, the pair of you, just go!
If there are any more boys inside,
I'll find them.
I think... Retreat!
CLARK: Doctor!
Doctor!
Come back, Doctor. Come home!
Come and claim your prize.
Out you come, Doctor,
there's a good boy.
Come to the Family.
Time to end it now!
MARTHA: You recognise it, don't you?
JENNY: Come out, Doctor!
Come to us.
I've never seen it in my life.
Do you remember its name?
I'm sorry, John, but you wrote about it.
The blue box, you dreamt of a blue box.
I'm not...
I'm John Smith.
That's all I want to be, John Smith!
With his life and his job.
And his love. Why can't I be John Smith?
Isn't he a good man?
-Yes, yes, he is.
-Why can't I stay?
But we need the Doctor.
And what am I, then? Nothing?
I'm just a story.
One more phase
and we won't have to hunt.
The Doctor, Mr Smith,
the boy, the watch,
they will come to us.
BAINES: Soldiers, guard this thing.
This way, I think I know
somewhere we can hide.
-We've got to keep going.
-Just listen to me for once, John.
Now, follow me.
BAINES: Power up. Fully armed and ready.
Mother, Father and Sister of mine,
prepare the armaments.
I doubt that England is ready for this.
Fix targets, and counting down.
Here we are. It should be empty.
Oh, it's been a long time
since I've run that far.
But who lives here?
If I'm right, no one.
Hello?
No one home. We should be safe here.
Whose house is it, though?
The Cartwrights'.
That little girl at the school,
she's Lucy Cartwright,
or she's taken Lucy Cartwright's form.
If she came home this afternoon,
and if the parents tried to stop
their little girl, then...
they were vanished.
Stone cold.
How easily I accept these ideas.
I must go to them
before anyone else dies.
You can't.
Martha, there must be something
we can do.
Not without the watch.
You're this Doctor's companion,
can't you help?
What exactly do you do for him?
Why does he need you?
Because he's lonely.
And that's what you want me to become?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
What if it's them?
I'm not an expert,
but I don't think scarecrows knock.
I brought you this.
MARTHA: Hold it.
-I won't.
-Please, just hold it.
It told me to find you.
It wants to be held.
You've had this watch all this time?
Why didn't you return it?
Because it was waiting.
Then because I was so scared
of the Doctor.
Why?
Because
I've seen him.
He's like fire and ice and rage.
He's like the night and the storm
and the heart of the sun.
-Stop it.
-He's ancient and forever.
He burns at the centre of time,
and he can see the turn of the universe.
Stop it! I said stop it.
And he's wonderful.
I've still got this, the journal.
Those are just stories.
Now we know that's not true.
Perhaps there's something in here...
(EXPLOSION)
What the hell?
This will flush him out,
this will do it!
Super, super fun!
JOAN: They're destroying the village.
The watch!
John, don't.
DOCTOR: Closer.
-Can you hear it?
-Like he's asleep.
-Waiting to waken.
-Why did he speak to me?
Oh, low level telepathic field,
you were born with it.
Just an extra synaptic engram,
causing...
-Is that how he talks?
-That's him!
All you have to do is open it,
and he's back.
(EXPLOSION)
You knew this all along and yet
you watched while Miss Redfern and I...
I didn't know how to stop you.
He gave me a list of things to
watch out for, but that wasn't included.
Falling in love?
That didn't even occur to him?
-No.
-Then what sort of man is that?
And now you expect me to die?
It was always going to end, though.
The Doctor said the Family has got
a limited life span,
that's why they need to consume
a Time Lord.
Otherwise, three months and they die.
Like mayflies, he said.
So your job was to execute me?
People are dying out there.
They need him, and I need him.
'Cause you've got no idea
what he's like.
I've only just met him,
it wasn't even that long ago, but...
He is everything.
He's just everything to me,
and he doesn't even look at me,
but I don't care.
'Cause I love him to bits.
And I hope to God
he won't remember me saying this.
It's getting closer.
I should have thought of it before.
I can give them this!
Just the watch.
Then they can leave
and I can stay as I am.
You can't do that!
If they want the Doctor,
they can have him.
-He'll never let you do it.
-And if they get what they want, then...
Then it all ends in destruction.
I never read to the end.
Those creatures will live forever,
to breed and conquer.
A war across the stars, for every child.
Martha, Timothy,
would you leave us alone, please?
(SOBBING)
If I could do this instead of you,
then I would.
I'd hoped...
But my hopes aren't important.
He won't love you.
If he's not you,
then I don't want him to.
I had one husband and he died and I...
I never thought, ever again...
And then you.
-You're so...
-And it was real, I wasn't...
I really thought...
Let me see.
Blasted thing.
Blasted, blasted thing.
I can't even hear it,
it says nothing to me.
(BABY CRYING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
They're all safe, aren't they?
The children,
the grandchildren.
Everyone's safe.
-And they all send their love, John.
-Well, then.
It's time.
Thank you.
Did you see?
The Time Lord has such adventures.
But he could never
have a life like that.
And yet I could.
What are you going to do?
We'll blast them into dust,
then fuse the dust into glass
then shatter them all over again!
Just...
Just stop the bombardment.
That's all I'm asking.
I'll do anything you want, just stop.
Say please.
Please.
(CONTROLS DEACTIVATING)
Wait a minute.
Still human.
Look, I can't pretend to understand,
not for a second,
but I want you to know,
I'm innocent in all this.
He made me John Smith.
It's not like I had any control over it.
He didn't just make himself human,
he made himself an idiot.
Same thing, isn't it?
I don't care about this Doctor
and your family,
I just want you to go!
So I've made my choice.
You can have him.
Just take it, please, take him away!
At last!
Don't think that's saved your life!
Family of mine,
now we shall have the lives
of a Time Lord.
It's empty!
-Where's it gone?
-You tell me!
Oh, I think the explanation might be
you've been fooled
by a simple olfactory misdirection.
A little bit like
ventriloquism of the nose.
It's an elementary trick
in certain parts of the galaxy.
But it has got to be said,
I don't like the look
of that hydrokinometer.
It seems to be indicating
you've got energy feedback
all the way through
the retrostabilisers,
feeding back into
the primary heat converters.
Oh!
'Cause if there's one thing
you shouldn't have done,
you shouldn't have let me press
all those buttons.
But, in fairness,
I will give you one word of advice.
Run.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Get out! Get out!
BAINES: He never raised his voice,
that was the worst thing.
The fury of the Time Lord.
And then we discovered why,
why this Doctor, who had fought
with gods and demons,
why he'd run away from us and hidden.
He was being kind.
He wrapped my father
in unbreakable chains
forged in the heart of a dwarf star.
He tricked my mother
into the event horizon
of a collapsing galaxy,
to be imprisoned there
forever.
He still visits my sister,
once a year, every year.
I wonder if one day
he might forgive her,
but there she is, can you see?
He trapped her inside a mirror.
Every mirror.
If ever you look at your reflection
and see something move behind you,
Just for a second, that's her.
That's always her.
As for me, I was suspended in time,
and the Doctor put me to work
standing over the fields of England
as their protector.
We wanted to live forever.
So the Doctor made sure that we did.
Is it done?
It's done.
The police and the army are at school.
Parents have come to take the boys home.
I should go.
They'll have so many questions.
I'm not sure what to say.
Oh.
You look the same.
Goodness,
you must forgive my rudeness. I...
I find it difficult to look at you.
Doctor, must call you Doctor.
Where is he?
-John Smith.
-He's in here, somewhere.
Like a story.
-Could you change back?
-Yes.
-Will you?
-No.
I see.
Well, then.
He was braver than you, in the end.
That ordinary man.
You chose to change,
he chose to die.
-Come with me.
-Sorry?
Travel with me.
-As what?
-My companion.
But that's not fair.
What must I look like to you, Doctor?
-I must seem so very small.
-No.
We could start again. I'd like that.
You and me, we could try, at least.
'Cause everything
that John Smith is and was,
I'm capable of that, too.
-I can't.
-Please come with me.
-Why not?
John Smith is dead,
and you look like him.
But he's here.
Inside.
If you look in my eyes...
Answer me this,
just one question, that's all.
If the Doctor had never visited us,
never chosen this place on a whim,
would anyone here have died?
You can go.
Right, then, motto bene.
How was she?
Time we moved on.
-If you want, I could go and...
-Time we moved on.
Erm, meant to say,
back there last night,
I would've said anything
to get you to change.
-Oh, yeah, course you would.
-I wasn't really...
-No, no, no.
-Good.
-Fine.
-So there we are, then.
There we are, then, yes.
And I never said.
Thanks for looking after me.
Doctor, Martha.
Tim Timothy Tim!
I just wanted to say goodbye,
and thank you.
Because I've seen the future,
and I now know what must be done.
It's coming, isn't it?
The biggest war ever.
-You don't have to fight.
-I think we do.
But you could get hurt.
So could you,
travelling around with him,
but it's not going to stop you.
Tim, I'd be honoured if you'd take this.
I can't hear anything.
No, it's just a watch now.
But keep it with you for good luck.
Look after yourself.
You'll like this bit.
(WHOOSHING)
SOLDIER: Incoming!
DOCTOR: In June, 1914,
an archduke of Austria
was shot by a Serbian.
And this then lead, through nations
having treaties with nations,
like a line of dominoes falling,
to some boys from England walking
together in France on a terrible day.
One minute past the hour.
It's now.
Hutchinson, this is the time, it's now.
(SHELL WHISTLING)
To the right, to the right!
We made it.
Thank you, Doctor.
Come on, old chap.
-Leave me. I'm not going to make it.
-Oh, yes you are.
Didn't I promise you
all those years ago?
Now, come on, and that's an order!
...they went with songs to the battle.
They were young,
straight of limb, true of eye,
steady and aglow.
They were staunch to the end
against odds uncounted.
They fell with their faces to the foe.
They shall not grow old
as we that are left grow old.
Age shall not weary them
nor the years condemn.
At the going down of the sun
and in the morning,
we will remember them.
Don't blink.
Blink and you're dead.
Don't turn your back,
don't look away and don't blink.
Good luck.