And why are we chasing it?
It's mauve and dangerous, and about
30 seconds from the centre of London.
Excuse me, there's this thing
that I need to find.
Would've fallen from the sky.
Nancy, the thing I'm looking for,
you know what I'm talking about, don't you?
(ROSE SCREAMING)
I've got you, you're fine.
-Hello.
Jack Harkness, I've been hearing
all about you on the way over.
It's 1941, the height of the London Blitz,
and something else has fallen on London.
He said it was a warship,
he stole it.
Parked it somewhere,
somewhere a bomb's going to fall on it,
unless we make him an offer.
It's a con. I was conning you.
That's what I am. I'm a con man.
Mummy.
There's something chasing you
and the other kids.
Mummy. Mummy!
You mustn't let him touch you.
-What happens if he touches me?
-He makes you like him.
Right, everybody out, across the back garden,
under the fence. Now, go, move!
You'll find them everywhere,
in every bed in every ward.
Hundreds of them.
They've all got the same injuries,
scarring on the back of the hand,
and the gas mask seems to be
fused to the flesh.
-What was the cause of death?
-They're not dead.
Are you my mummy?
It's me Nancy!
-Don't let them touch you.
-What happens if they touch us?
You're looking at it.
ALL: Mummy. Mummy...
Go to your room.
I mean it, I'm very, very angry with you.
I'm very, very cross.
Go to your room!
I'm really glad that worked.
Those would have been
terrible last words.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME MUSIC)
Jamie.
-Why are they all wearing gas masks?
-They're not.
Those masks are flesh and bone.
-How was your con supposed to work?
-Simple enough, really.
Find some harmless piece of space junk,
let the nearest Time Agent
track it back to Earth,
convince him it's valuable
and name a price.
When he's put 50% upfront...oops!
German bomb falls on it,
destroys it forever.
He never gets to see what he's paid for,
never knows he's been had.
I buy him a drink with his own money
and we discuss dumb luck.
-The perfect self-cleaning con.
-Yeah. Perfect.
The London Blitz is great
for self-cleaners.
Pompeii's nice if you want to make
a vacation of it, though.
But you've got to set your alarm
for Volcano Day.
(JACK LAUGHING)
-Getting a hint of disapproval.
-Take a look around the room.
This is what your piece of
harmless space junk did.
It was a burnt-out medical transporter,
it was empty.
Rose.
-Are we getting out of here?
-We're going upstairs.
I programmed the flight computer
so it wouldn't land on anything living.
I harmed no one!
I don't know what's happening here
but I had nothing to do with it.
I'll tell you what's happening.
You forgot to set your alarm clock.
It's Volcano Day.
(SIREN WAILING)
-What's that?
-The all clear.
I wish.
(NANCY EXCLAIMS)
I thought you were Jamie.
-Dad! Dad!
-Ruddy kids!
-Get off of me!
-Give us a hand.
-Get your hands off me now!
-You! Get in!
Get her in there.
She's nicked!
-Mr Spock?
-Doctor.
Have you got a blaster?
Sure.
The night your space junk landed,
someone was hurt.
-This is where they were taken.
-What happened?
Let's find out. Get it open.
-What's up with your sonic screwdriver?
-Nothing.
Sonic blaster, 51st century.
Weapon factories of Villengard.
-You've been to the factories?
-Once.
They're gone now, destroyed.
Main reactor went critical, vaporised the lot.
Like I said. Once.
There's a banana grove there now.
I like bananas. Bananas are good.
-Nice blast pattern.
-Digital.
-Squareness gun? I like it.
-Yeah.
-What do you think?
-Something got out of here.
Yeah. And?
Something powerful. Angry.
Powerful and angry.
A child?
-I suppose this explains "mummy"”.
-How could a child do this?
-Do you know where you are?
-Are you my mummy?
Are you aware of
what's around you?
Can you...see?
Are you my mummy?
-What do you want? Do you know...
-I want my mummy!
Are you my mummy?
I want my mummy.
Mummy? Mummy?
-Doctor, I've heard this voice before.
-Me, too.
Mummy?
Always "are you my mummy?"
Like he doesn't know.
Mummy.
Why doesn't he know?
Are you there, Mummy? Mummy?
The police are on their way.
I pay for
the food on this table.
The sweat on my brow, that food is.
The sweat on my brow.
Anything else you'd like?
I've got a whole house here.
Anything else you'd like to
help yourself to?
Yeah.
I'd like some
wire cutters, please.
Something that can cut through
barbed wire.
Oh, and a torch.
Don't look like that, Mr Lloyd.
I know you got plenty of tools in here.
I been watching this house for ages.
And I'd like another look round
your kitchen cupboards.
I was in a hurry the first time.
I want to see if there's anything I missed.
The food on this table...
It's an awful lot of food,
isn't it, Mr Lloyd?
A lot more than on
anyone else's table.
Half this street thinks
your missus must be messing about
with Mr Haverstock, the butcher.
But she's not, is she?
You are.
Wire cutters. Torch. Food.
And I'd like to use your bathroom
before I leave, please.
Oh, look! There's
the sweat on your brow.
Mummy? Please, Mummy. Mummy?
Doctor?
-Can you sense it?
-Sense what?
Coming out of the walls.
Can you feel it?
Funny little human brains.
How do you get around in those things?
When he's stressed,
he likes to insult species.
-Rose, I'm thinking!
-He cuts himself shaving.
He does half an hour on life-forms
he's cleverer than.
There are these children.
Living rough round the bomb sites.
They come out during air raids,
looking for food.
Mummy, please.
Suppose they were there when this thing,
whatever it was, landed.
-It was a med-ship, it was harmless.
-You keep saying. Harmless.
-Suppose one was affected. Altered.
-Altered how?
I'm here!
It's afraid, terribly afraid and powerful.
It doesn't know it yet.
But it will do.
(FAINT WHIRRING)
It's got the power of a god
and I just sent it to its room.
(WHIRRING)
Doctor.
I'm here! Can't you see me?
What's that noise?
End of the tape.
It ran out about 30 seconds ago.
I'm here now!
Can't you see me?
I sent it to its room.
This is its room.
Are you my mummy?
Mummy?
Doctor?
Okay, on my signal
make for the door.
-Mummy?
-Now!
Mummy?
-Go, now, don't drop the banana!
-Why not?
Good source of potassium.
Give me that.
Mummy? I want my mummy.
Digital rewind. Nice switch.
It's from the groves of Villengard,
thought it was appropriate.
There's really a banana grove in Villengard?
And you did that?
Bananas are good.
-Doctor!
-Come on!
ALL: Mummy! Mummy!
It's keeping us here
till it can get at us.
-It's controlling them?
-It is them.
It's every living thing in this hospital.
Okay. This can function
as a sonic blaster,
a sonic cannon and
it's a triple-enfolded sonic disruptor.
-Doc, what you got?
-I've got a sonic... Never mind.
-What?
-It's sonic, okay? Let's leave it at that.
Disruptor? Cannon? What?
It's sonic, totally sonic.
I am soniced up.
-A sonic what?
-Screwdriver!
Going down.
Doctor, are you okay?
-Could've used a warning.
-The gratitude.
-Who has a sonic screwdriver?
-I do.
Lights?
Who looks at a screwdriver and thinks,
"Ooh, this could be more sonic?"
-You've never been bored?
-There's got to be a light switch.
Never had a long night?
Never had a lot of cabinets to put up?
-Mummy.
Door.
-Damn it!
-Mummy?
It's the special features,
they really drain the battery.
The battery?
It's so lame.
I was going to send for another one
but somebody's got to blow up the factory.
I know. First day I met him,
he blew my job up.
That's practically
how he communicates.
Okay, that door
should hold it for a bit.
-The door? The wall didn't stop it.
-It's got to find us first!
Come on, we're not done yet.
Assets.
I've got a banana and, in a pinch,
you could put up some shelves.
-Window?
-Barred. Sheer drop. Seven storeys.
And no other exits.
The assets conversation went in a flash,
didn't it?
-Where'd you pick this one up, then?
-Doctor.
She was hanging from a barrage balloon,
I had an invisible spaceship.
I never stood a chance.
Okay. One,
we've got to get out of here.
Two, we can't get out of here.
Have I missed anything?
Yeah. Jack just disappeared.
I thought as much.
What are all of you doing here?
Different house
every night I told you.
We thought you were dead.
Or you'd run off.
I didn't. I knew
you'd come back for us.
Found that old thing in the junk.
-Thinks he's can write now.
-Writing a letter to me dad.
You don't even know where your dad is.
How you gonna send it?
-I don't know, stick it in an envelope.
-You can't even read or write.
I don't need to,
I've got a machine.
Will you stop
making that noise?
I'm sorry, Jim.
On you go, you write a letter
to your dad if you want to.
I know we should
have went somewhere else
but we need you, see,
for the thinking.
What if I wasn't here?
What if one night
I didn't come back for you?
There's a war on,
people go out.
They don't always come back.
It happens.
What would you do then?
They're wire cutters.
I need you to
think about that.
-Someone's got to look after this lot.
-Why? Are you going somewhere?
The bomb site.
The one at the railway station.
-Why?
-The child.
That's where he was killed.
That's where it all started.
And I'm gonna find out how.
-He'll get you.
-And then he'll come for us.
-He always comes for us.
-No, Ernie, he doesn't.
He always comes after me.
There are things I haven't told you.
Things I can't tell you.
As long as you're with me,
you're in danger.
Even right now. Sitting here.
You're in danger because of me.
You're the one
that keeps us safe.
You think so, Ernie?
Then answer this.
Jim is sitting
there right next to you.
So who's typing?
Is he coming?
Ernie, as long as you're with me,
he's always coming.
Plenty of greens.
And chew your food.
Okay, so he's
vanished into thin air.
Why is it always the great-looking ones
who do that?
-I'm making an effort not to be insulted.
-I mean, men.
Okay, thanks, that really helped.
Rose? Doctor? Can you hear me?
(STATIC)
Back on my ship.
Used the emergency teleport.
Sorry I couldn't take you.
It's security-keyed
to my molecular structure.
I'm working on it,
hang in there.
How are you speaking to us?
Om-Com. I can call anything
with a speaker grill.
-Now there's a coincidence.
-What is?
-The child can Om-Com, too.
-He can?
Anything with a speaker grill.
Even the Tardis phone.
What, you mean
the child can phone us?
And I can hear you.
Coming to find you.
-Doctor, can you hear that?
-Loud and clear.
I'll try to block out the signal.
Least I can do.
Coming to find you, Mummy.
Remember this one, Rose?
(MOONLIGHT SERENADE PLAYING)
Our song.
What you doing?
Trying to set up a resonation pattern
in the concrete, loosen the bars.
-Do you think he's coming back?
-Wouldn't bet my life.
Why don't you trust him?
-Why do you?
-Saved my life.
Bloke-wise, that's up there with flossing.
I trust him because he's like you.
Except with dating and dancing.
-What?
-You just assume I'm...
-You just assume I don't dance.
What? Are you
telling me you do dance?
900 years old, me.
I've been around a bit.
I think you can assume at some point
I've danced.
-You?
-Problem?
Doesn't the universe implode
or something if you dance?
Well, I've got the moves
but I wouldn't want to boast.
(STILL PLAYING MOONLIGHT SERENADE)
You've got the moves?
Show me your moves.
Rose, I'm trying to resonate concrete.
Jack will be back. He'll get us out.
So come on.
The world doesn't end
because the Doctor dances.
-Barrage balloon?
-What?
You were hanging
from a barrage balloon.
Oh. Yeah.
About two minutes after you left me.
Thousands of feet above London,
middle of a German air raid,
Union Jack all over my chest.
I've travelled with a lot of people
but you're setting new records
for jeopardy friendly.
Is this you dancing?
Because I've got notes.
Hanging from a rope,
thousands of feet above London.
Not a cut, not a bruise.
Yeah, I know.
Captain Jack fixed me up.
We're calling him Captain Jack now,
are we?
His name's Jack
and he's a captain.
-He's not really a captain, Rose.
-Do you know what I think?
I think you're
experiencing captain-envy.
You will find your feet
at the end of your legs.
You may care to move them.
If ever he was a captain,
he's been defrocked.
-Yeah? Shame I missed that.
-Actually, I quit.
Nobody takes my frock.
Most people notice
when they've been teleported.
You guys are so sweet.
Sorry about the delay.
Had to take the Nav-Com
off-line to override the teleport security.
You can spend 10 minutes
overriding your own protocols.
Maybe you should remember
whose ship it is.
I do. She was gorgeous.
Like I told her,
be back in five minutes.
-This is a Chula ship.
-Yeah, just like that medical transporter.
Only this one is dangerous.
They're what fixed up my hands up.
Jack called them...
-Nanobots? Nanogenes?
-Nanogenes, yeah.
Subatomic robots.
There are millions of them in here. See?
Burned my hand on the console
when we landed. All better now.
They activate
when the bulkhead's sealed.
Check you out for damage,
fix any physical flaws.
Take us to the crash site.
I need to see your space junk.
Soon as I get the Nav-Com back online.
Make yourself comfortable.
Carry on with whatever it was
you were doing.
-We were talking about dancing.
-It didn't look like talking.
Didn't feel like dancing.
Halt! Don't move!
So, you used to be a Time Agent
and now you're trying to con them?
If it makes me sound any better,
it's not for the money.
For what?
Woke up one morning
when I was still working for them,
found they'd stolen two years
of my memories.
-I'd like them back.
-They stole your memories?
Two years of my life.
No idea what I did.
Your friend over there doesn't trust me.
And for all I know, he's right not to.
Okay. We're good to go.
The crash site?
-As you were. You feeling any better?
-Just a touch, sir.
Chain her up where Jenkins
can keep an eye on her.
No. Not in here. Not with him.
You shouldn't have broken in here
if you didn't want to stay.
You don't understand.
Not with him.
This is
a restricted area, miss.
You can just sit
here for a bit.
We're going to have to ask you
a few questions.
Found these, sir.
Very professional,
a little bit too professional.
Didn't just drop in by accident then,
did you?
My little brother died here.
I wanted to find out what killed him.
Take the men, check the fence
for any other breaches.
And search the area,
she may not have come here alone.
-Yes, sir!
-Please.
Listen, you can't leave me here.
-Watch her, Jenkins.
-Yes, Mummy.
-Jenkins?
-Sorry.
Sir, I don't know
what's the matter with me.
Look, lock me up, fine, but not here.
Please, anywhere but here.
You'll be all right, miss.
I'm just a little...
Just a little...
What's the matter with you?
-Please, let me go.
-Why would I do that?
Because you've got a scar
on the back of your hand.
Yes, but I don't see
what that's got to do with anything.
You feel like
you're gonna be sick.
Like something's
forcing its way up your throat.
I know because
I've seen it before.
-What's happening to me?
-In a minute you won't be you anymore.
You won't even remember you.
And unless you let me go,
it's going to happen to me, too.
-Please.
-What are you talking about?
-What's your mother's name?
-Matilda.
-You got a wife?
-Yes.
Wife's name?
You got kids?
What's your name?
Please, let me go.
It's too late for you. I'm sorry.
But please let me go.
What...
Mummy!
There it is.
They've got Algy on duty.
Must be important.
We've got to get past him.
Are the words "distract the guard”
heading in my general direction?
I don't think that'd
be such a good idea.
Don't worry, I can handle it.
I've got to know Algy quite well
since I've been in town.
Trust me, you're not his type.
I'll distract him.
Don't wait up.
Relax.
He's a 51st century guy.
He's just a bit more flexible
when it comes to dancing.
How flexible?
By his time,
you lot are spread out across half the galaxy.
-Meaning?
-So many species, so little time.
What, that's what we do
when we get out there?
That's our mission?
We seek new life and...
Dance.
Hey, tiger. How's it hanging?
-Mummy?
-Algy, old sport, it's me.
-It's me, Jack.
Jack?
Are you my mummy?
Stay back! You men, stay away.
The effect's becoming airborne,
accelerating.
-What's keeping us safe?
-Nothing.
-Here they come again.
-All we need.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Didn't you say a bomb
was gonna land here?
Never mind about that.
If the contaminant's airborne now,
there's hours left.
-Till what?
-Till nothing.
Forever.
For the entire human race.
And can anyone
else hear singing?
# ...the tree tops
# When the wind blows
the cradle will rock
# When the bow breaks
the cradle will fall
# Down will come
baby cradle and all
# Rock-a-bye baby
on the tree tops
# When the wind blows
the cradle will rock #
You see? Just an ambulance.
That's an ambulance?
It's hard to explain.
It's from another world.
-They've been trying to get in.
-Of course they have.
They think they've got their hands on
Hitler's latest secret weapon.
-What are you doing?
-The sooner you see this thing's empty,
the sooner you'll know
I had nothing to do with it.
Didn't happen last time.
It hadn't crashed last time.
There'll be emergency protocols.
Doctor, what is that?
Mummy.
Doctor!
-Captain, secure those gates.
-Why?
Just do it!
Nancy, how did you get in here?
-I cut the wire.
-Show Rose.
Setting 2,428-D.
-What?
-Reattaches barbed wire. Go!
Who are you?
Who are any of you?
Never believe me if I told you.
You just told me that was
an ambulance from another world.
There are people running round
with gas masks calling for their mummies
and the sky's full of Germans
dropping bombs on me.
Tell me, do you think
there's anything left I couldn't believe?
We're time travellers.
From the future.
-Mad, you are!
-We have a time travel machine.
It's not that. All right,
you got a time travel machine.
I'll believe you.
Believe anything, me.
But what future?
Nancy, this isn't the end.
I know how it looks,
it's not the end of the world or anything.
How can you say that?
Look at it.
Listen to me.
I was born in this city.
I'm from here,
in like 50 years' time.
-From here?
-I'm a Londoner.
-From your future.
-But...
-But you're not...
-What?
-German?
-Nancy.
The Germans don't come here.
They don't win.
Don't tell anyone I told you so.
But you know what?
-You win.
-We win?
Come on.
It's empty. Look at it.
What do you expect
in a Chula medical transporter?
Bandages? Cough drops?
-Rose?
-I don't know.
-Yes, you do.
-Nanogenes!
It wasn't empty, Captain.
There was enough nanogenes in there
to rebuild a species.
-Oh, God.
-Getting it now, are we?
When the ship crashes,
the nanogenes escape.
Billions upon billions of them.
Ready to fix all the cuts and bruises
in the whole world.
But what they find first is a dead child.
Probably killed earlier that night.
And wearing a gas mask.
And they brought him back to life?
They can do that?
What's life? Life's easy.
A quirk of matter.
Nature's way of keeping meat fresh.
Nothing to a nanogene.
One problem, though.
These nanogenes,
they're not like the ones on your ship.
This lot have never seen
a human being before.
Don't know what a human being's
supposed to look like.
All they've got to go on is one little body,
and there's not a lot left.
But they carry right on.
They do what they're programmed to,
they patch it up.
Can't tell what's gas mask and what's skull,
but they do their best.
And then off they fly, off they go,
work to be done.
"Cause you see, now they think
they know what people should look like.
And it's time to fix all the rest.
And they won't ever stop.
They won't ever stop.
The entire human race
is gonna be torn down
and rebuilt in the form of one terrified child
looking for its mother.
-And nothing in the world can stop it!
-I didn't know.
Mummy.
Rose?
Mummy. Mummy...
It's bringing the gas mask people here,
isn't it?
The ship thinks it's under attack.
It's calling up the troops. Standard protocol.
But the gas mask people aren't troops!
They are now.
This is a battlefield ambulance.
The nanogenes don't just fix you up,
they get you ready for the front line.
-Equip you, program you.
-That's why the child's so strong?
Why it could do that phoning thing?
It's a fully equipped Chula warrior, yes.
All that weapons tech in the hands
of an hysterical four-year-old
looking for his mummy
and now there's an army of them.
Mummy. Mummy.
Why don't they attack?
Good little soldiers.
Waiting for their commander.
The child?
-Jamie.
-What?
Not the child. Jamie.
-So how long until the bomb falls?
-Any second.
What's the matter, Captain?
Bit close to the volcano for you?
-He's just a little boy.
-I know.
-He's just a boy who wants his mummy.
There isn't a little boy born
who wouldn't tear the world apart
to save his mummy.
-And this little boy can.
-So what are we gonna do?
I don't know.
-It's my fault.
-No.
-It is. It's all my fault.
-How can it be your...
Mummy. Mummy.
-Mummy
-Mummy!
Mummy!
Nancy, what age are you?
207217 Older than you look, yes?
Doctor, that bomb, we've got seconds.
-You can teleport us out.
-Not you guys.
The Nav-Com's back online.
Gonna take too long
to override the protocols.
So it's Volcano Day.
Do what you've got to do.
Jack?
How old were you five years ago?
Old enough to give birth, anyway.
He's not your brother, is he?
A teenage single mother in 1941.
So you hid. You lied.
You even lied to him.
Are you my mummy?
He's gonna keep asking, Nancy.
-He's never gonna stop.
-Mummy.
Tell him.
Nancy, the future of the human race
is in your hands.
Trust me and tell him.
Are you my mummy?
-Yes, I am your mummy.
-Mummy?
-I'm here.
-Are you my mummy?
I'm here.
-Yes.
Are you my mummy?
He doesn't understand,
there's not enough of him left.
I am your mummy.
I will always be your mummy.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
What's happening?
-Doctor, it's changing her, we should...
-Shh!
Come on. Please!
Come on, you clever little nanogenes.
Figure it out.
The mother, she's the mother.
It's got to be enough information.
Figure it out.
-What' s happening?
-See? I.
Recognising the same DNA.
Come on.
Give me a day like this.
Give me this one.
Welcome back!
20 years to pop music, you're gonna love it.
What happened?
The nanogenes recognised
the superior information. The parent DNA.
They didn't change you
because you changed them.
-Mother knows best.
-Jamie.
-Doctor, that bomb.
-Taken care of it.
-How?
-Psychology.
-Doctor!
-Good lad.
The bomb's already started detonation.
I've put it in stasis, but it won't last!
Change of plan!
Don't need the bomb.
Can you get rid of it,
safely as you can?
-Rose?
-Yeah?
Goodbye.
By the way. Love the T-shirt!
-What are you doing?
-Software patch.
Gonna email the upgrade.
You want moves, Rose.
I'll give you moves.
Everybody lives, Rose.
Just this once!
Everybody lives!
Dr Constantine,
who never left his patients.
Back on your feet,
constant doctor.
World doesn't want to get by
without you just yet
and I don't blame it one bit.
These are your patients.
All better now.
Yes, so it seems.
They also seem to be standing around
in a disused railway station.
Is there any particular reason for that?
Yeah, well, you know, cutbacks.
Listen, whatever was wrong
with them in the past
you're probably gonna find
that they're cured.
Just tell them what a great doctor you are,
don't make a big thing of it.
Okay?
Dr Constantine.
Mrs Harcourt!
How much better you're looking!
My leg's grown back.
When I come to the hospital,
I had one leg.
Well, there is a war on,
is it possible you miscounted?
Right, you lot. Lots to do.
Beat the Germans, save the world.
Don't forget
the welfare state!
Setting this to self-destruct,
soon as everybody's clear.
History says there
was an explosion here.
-Who am I to argue with history?
-Usually, the first in line.
The nanogenes will clean up the mess
and switch themselves off,
'cause I just told them to.
Nancy and Jamie will go to
Dr Constantine for help, ditto.
All in all, all things considered. Fantastic!
Look at you beaming away
like you're Father Christmas.
Who says I'm not?
Red bicycle when you were 12.
-What?
-And everybody lives, Rose.
Everybody lives.
I need more days like this!
-Doctor.
-Go on, ask me anything. I'm on fire.
What about Jack?
Why did he say goodbye?
Okay, computer,
how long can we keep the bomb in stasis?
Stasis decaying at 90% cycle.
-Detonation in three minutes.
-Can we jettison it?
Any attempt to jettison the device
will precipitate detonation.
-100% probability.
-We could stick it in an escape pod?
There is no escape pod on board.
Okay, see the flaw in that.
I'll get in the escape pod.
There is no escape pod on board.
-Did you check everywhere?
-Affirmative.
-Under the sink?
Okay.
Out of 100,
exactly how dead am I?
Termination of Captain Jack Harkness
in under two minutes.
100% probability.
Lovely. Thanks.
-Good to know the numbers.
-You're welcome.
Okay, then!
Think we'd better initiate
emergency protocol 417.
Affirmative.
A little too much vermouth.
See if I come here again.
Funny thing.
Last time I was sentenced to death
I ordered four hyper-vodkas
for my breakfast.
All a bit of a blur after that.
Woke up in bed
with both my executioners.
Lovely couple.
They stayed in touch.
Can't say that
about most executioners.
Anyway.
Thanks for everything, computer.
It's been great.
(MOONLIGHT SERENADE PLAYING)
Well! Hurry up, then!
Okay, all right and turn.
Okay, try and spin me again.
But this time, don't get my arm up my back.
No extra points for a half-nelson.
I'm sure I used
to know this stuff.
Close the door, will you?
Your ship's about to blow up,
there's gonna be a draft.
Welcome to the Tardis.
-Much bigger on the inside.
-You'd better be.
I think what the Doctor is trying
to say is, you may cut in.
-Rose! I've just remembered!
-What?
(IN THE MOOD BY THE GLENN MILLER BAND)
I can dance!
Actually, Doctor,
I thought Jack might like this dance.
I'm sure he would, Rose,
I'm absolutely certain.
But who with?
Whoo!
And I was having
such a nice day.
According to Intelligence,
the target is the last surviving member
of the Slitheen family.
A criminal sect from the planet
Rexicoricophalvitorius
masquerading as a human being,
zipped inside a skin suit.
Its nuclear power station right in
the heart of Cardiff city
will bring jobs for all.
And it just so happens to be
right on top of the rift.
If this power station went into meltdown,
the entire planet would go...
Go on then, run!
It's the rift,
the rift's opening.
The whole city's going to disappear!
Time and space
are ripping apart.
Never mind Cardiff,
it's going to rip open the planet!