ROSE: Doctor! Doctor, look out!
Doctor, he's going! Quick!
DOCTOR: Where's he gone?
Do you see him?
ROSE: There he is. Stop! No!
DOCTOR: Where is he?
ROSE: Watch out!
DOCTOR: Where?
(SNARLING)
That's what it did, it went...
(ROARING)
And if you think
that was the most exciting day of my life,
wait till you hear the rest.
Oh, boy.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
So there I was, with that thing going...
Here, boy. Eat the food. Come on.
Look at the lovely food, isn't that nice?
Isn't it? Yes, it is! Get out of here, quickly.
(IN BABY TALK) That's a boy!
Who'd like a porky choppy, then?
I said run!
(SCREAMING)
-Wrong one! You made it worse!
-You said blue.
I said not blue!
Hold on.
(DOCTOR AND ROSE SCREAMING)
Don't I know you?
(WHOOSHING)
You can't imagine it, the Doctor's machine.
The most beautiful sound in the world.
That wasn't the first time I met the Doctor
and it certainly wasn't the last.
Oh, no.
I just put that bit at the beginning
because it's a brilliant opening.
But this is the story of me
and my encounters with alien life forms.
But be warned!
Because it is gonna get scary.
I need a remote control zoom.
I'm having to do that with a lean,
the scary. Anyway.
But don't worry 'cause it's not just me
sitting here talking. Oh, no.
-That's Ursula on camera.
-Hello.
My good friend Ursula Blake
on my brand-new camera.
That was my family home, down there.
I did try
but there's two women live there now.
They're a bit severe. So, never mind.
But that is where it all started
"cause that's when I first met the Doctor.
What was it?
I must've been three or four years old.
Middle of the night I went downstairs,
and there was this man.
URSULA: So what happened? Elton?
Tell me, why was he there?
I don't know. I still don't know.
All those years ago.
Okay, first things first.
My name is Elton, not to be confused with...
(ELTON JOHN PLAYING DANIEL)
I left school, I got a job,
transport manager at Rita Logistics,
modest little haulage company,
perfectly normal life, and then...
it all went mad!
ELTON: Two years ago I was in town,
I was stocking up,
you know, nothing special,
all the usual stuff.
When all of a sudden...
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Shop-window dummies come to life.
I survived, obviously.
Twelve months later, I'm back in town.
I'm up West looking for a new suit,
something nice and smart,
when I hear this plane overhead...
(ENGINES ROARING)
(BELL TOLLING)
But it wasn't over yet.
'Cause then, Christmas Day.
I'm in bed, fast asleep, nice and cosy,
7:45 in the morning,
when all of a sudden...
And I'm stuck in bed, all right,
'cause there's glass everywhere,
and I was barefoot.
I had to invent
this rudimentary pulley system
Just to reach my boots,
and by the time I'd done that...
And that's when it all started happening.
That's how I met Ursula.
His name is the Doctor.
-That's how I met Victor Kennedy.
-You stupid man!
-That's how I met Jackie Tyler.
-You don't meet many Eltons.
And that's how I finally met the Doctor.
And realised the truth.
I should say this isn't,
you know, my whole life.
It's not all spaceships and stuff.
'Cause I'm into all sorts of things.
I like football.
I like a drink. I like Spain.
And if there's one thing I really, really love,
then it's Jeff Lynne
and the Electric Light Orchestra.
'Cause you can't beat a bit of ELO.
(MR BLUE SKY PLAYING)
So, great big spaceship
hanging over London, imagine the theories.
The internet went into meltdown.
But I kept on digging.
Something was going on. Oh, yes.
And then one day,
on some obscure little blog
by someone called Ursula Blake.
It was, like, chance in a million.
It was him, it was that man again.
But the photo was new.
It was taken on Christmas Day,
but Christmas just gone,
and he looked exactly the same.
His name is the Doctor.
-Doctor what?
-That's all anyone knows.
At Christmas Day,
I was taking photos all over the place.
I went mad with it all,
spaceships and lasers and everything.
We all went to Trafalgar Square that night
'cause everyone was celebrating
just being alive,
and I snapped him in passing, that's all.
He was just some bloke.
I didn't realise he was significant
until Mr Skinner pointed it out.
Who's Mr Skinner?
Oh, there's a few of us. The inner sanctum.
All studying this Doctor.
I've seen him, the Doctor, I swear to you.
I saw him when I was a kid.
He was in my house and he was downstairs.
Don't tell me, he looked
exactly the same then as he does now.
Yes. Yes.
Oh, my God, you believe me.
I'm not the only one...
ELTON: So that's how I met Ursula.
All thanks to the Doctor.
Turns out we read all the same sites
and she only lived half a mile away.
She was like a proper mate. Poor Ursula.
(SCREAMING)
But like she said,
there was this little community,
the select few,
all with their stories of the Doctor.
ELTON: This little gang used to meet up
underneath the old library
on Maccateer Street.
Mr Skinner, first name Colin,
but we always called him Mr Skinner.
I don't know why, we just did.
...to me, the Doctor isn't a man,
he's more a collection of archetypes.
ELTON: Then there was Bridget.
...all these different Doctors come and go,
but the single constant factor
is this faux police box.
It keeps cropping up throughout history.
She lived way up north,
but she travelled down without fail
Just for the meetings.
Then there was Bliss.
What I'm trying to do
is sum up the Doctor. What he means to us.
ELTON: She was ever so sweet Bliss.
Bless Bliss, we used to say.
What he could represent
and what he should represent
and what he never won't represent
sort of thing.
We should have a name.
You know, as a group.
Names are very important.
What we need is a good, strong name,
like a team. Something like...
London Investigation 'N' Detective Agency.
-LINDA for short.
-Say it again?
London Investigation 'N' Detective Agency.
_IINII?
-Fish 'n' chips.
Rock 'n' roll. Chaka Demus 'n' Pliers.
Ah!
-LINDA, I like it. It's not too solemn.
- Ilike the 'N'...
-We're the men from LINDA.
-And the women.
LINDA united.
Did you think of that on the spot?
No, I've wanted to use it for years.
I give you LINDA.
ALL: LINDA!
So we'd all meet up every week
and we'd talk about the Doctor for a bit.
But after a while, Bridget started cooking.
Oh, my God, that's gorgeous!
No, really. Wow.
The rest of you, get your hands off!
ELTON: Next thing you know,
Mr Skinner started his readings,
'cause he was writing his own novel.
SKINNER: "That's the last time you ride
the Ghost Train, Johnny Franzetta.
"Now say your prayers!”
To be continued.
ALL: No!
ELTON: Time went on. We got to know
each other better and better.
I only started all this
because my daughter disappeared.
But it wasn't aliens that took her away.
It was just drugs.
I come down to London every week
and I just keep looking for her.
Oh, Bridget.
# I gave my love a chicken
# It had no bone
# I gave my love a cherry
# It had no stone #
# I've got a brand-new pair of roller skates
# You've got a brand-new key #
ELTON: Then it turned out
that Bridget could play the piano,
and I confessed my love of ELO.
Next thing you know, musical LINDA.
# You got me running
Going out of my mind
# You got me thinking
that I'm wasting my time
# Don't bring me down #
Just for fun.
# Don't bring me down
# Grroosss
# Grroosss #
You go.
(INSTRUMENTS CLANGING)
SKINNER: Now, careful. Mind the cables
ELTON: And that's when it all changed.
That Tuesday night in March.
That's when he arrived.
Lights.
ELTON: That's when we met
Victor Kennedy.
And the golden age was gone.
So, we meet at last, LINDA.
Pleased to meet you, sir.
I'm sorry, was the music too loud?
No, no, no. I don't shake hands.
Back, back. I suffer from a skin complaint.
-Eczeema.
-Oh, you mean eczema.
Oh, this is worse, much worse.
I blister to the touch.
Back, back, all of you, further, further.
Thank you.
Sorry, don't mind me asking,
but who are you?
I am your salvation.
URSULA: That's the Doctor.
ELTON: That's really him.
Forgotten your purpose in life.
You, with your band and your cakes
and your blubbing,
and all the while he still exists, the Doctor.
Look at him. Just look!
Move back, move back, all of you.
Hold on, wait for this bit.
The picture cuts out,
but the sound still continues.
Listen.
Listen to the sound of the universe.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
VICTOR: Yes.
Oh, that's...
-What is it? What's wrong?
-Leave him!
You've heard it before, haven't you?
When? When was it? Where?
Where were you?
I'd forgotten. Till now.
But it was that night.
What night?
I was just a kid.
That's why I went downstairs,
it woke me up.
That noise.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
But what is it? What does it mean?
That is the sound of his spaceship.
VICTOR: Right then, homework!
Using the Torchwood files,
we're able to look at all the old databases
in a completely new light.
We're able to build up
a more detailed profile of the Doctor.
I've allocated tasks to each of you.
I'd like you to...
Careful, watch the eczeema.
I would like you to complete your targets
and meet back here this time next week,
one step closer to catching the Doctor.
Well, don't just sit there! Move!
Um, Bliss? It is Bliss, isn't it?
-Yeah.
-Yes.
Could I have a word with you
in private, please?
-Course you can, yeah.
-Thank you.
Goodbye, goodbye.
ELTON: Better get to work. Lots to do.
I never thought of it as work.
It's what we've always wanted, though.
To find the Doctor.
Yeah, I suppose.
(BLISS SCREAMING)
All of a sudden, without anyone saying so,
we were working for Victor Kennedy.
ELTON: But we had to admit, he was right.
His methods were much more rigorous.
It felt like we were getting
closer and closer to the Doctor.
-Mr Kennedy?
-Yes.
We were wondering...
No sign of Bliss. Do you know where she is?
Yes. Didn't she tell you?
She's getting married.
She left a message.
It'll never last. Stupid girl.
Come on, back to work!
But we did get lucky once.
A police box, newly arrived.
It says newly arrived today.
It's in Woolwich.
Well, don't just stand there!
Move! Move! Go! Go!
But don't get excited.
That's where you came in.
ELTON: Woolwich, police box,
red bucket blue bucket
me so stupid, etcetera.
-Useless!
-I just froze.
You met him and you froze?
-You stupid man!
-You can't hit me 'cause you don't touch.
-You get a rash and an itch and everything.
-I can use this!
Use that cane on him
and you'll get one hell of a smack off me.
And then a good kick.
Is that completely understood,
Mr Kennedy?
Duly noted.
Ursula Blake, most likely to fight back.
Right then, we'll change tack.
We'll approach this sideways.
If we're to discover the truth
about the Doctor,
then we need to try and find her.
VICTOR: Now, when it comes to
the Doctor's companion,
the Torchwood files are strangely lacking.
It seems the evidence has been corrupted,
something called Bad Wolf virus.
At least we've got these photographs.
They're first-hand evidence. Elton?
It was a London accent, definitely.
She's from London.
So we hit the streets. We get out there.
We take the photograph.
Someone's got to know
who she is somewhere.
But London's a big place. I should know,
my own daughter's out there.
Bridget, don't make this personal.
I don't like to be touched literally
or metaphorically, thank you very much.
I haven't got the time.
Bleeding hearts, outside.
Find me that girl! Go! Now! Move!
ELTON: And so it began,
the impossible task.
To scour the mean streets.
To search a major capital city
for an unknown girl.
To hunt down that face
in a seething metropolis of lost souls.
To find that one girl in ten million.
Oh, that's Rose Tyler.
She lives just down there.
Bucknall House, number 48.
Her mother's Jackie Tyler.
Nice family, bit odd.
(MR BLUE SKY PLAYING)
0i, Jackie!
Hello, sweetheart. I'll see you
down the Spinning Wheel tonight, yeah?
Pub quiz. Get them in!
All right.
ELTON: I'd been trained for this.
Victor Kennedy's classes
covered basic surveillance and espionage.
Step one, engage your target.
Find some excuse to start a conversation.
But how was I going to do this? How?
Excuse me, luv, you couldn't give us a quid
for two fifties, could you?
Yeah. Just...
Oh, lovely. Cheers.
Step two, without provoking suspicion,
get on first-name terms with the target.
My name's Jackie, by the way.
I'm Elton.
Oh, you don't meet many Eltons, do you?
Apart from the obvious.
Step three,
ingratiate yourself with a joke
or some humorous device.
I tell you what, Elton.
Here we are complete strangers
and I'm flashing you my knickers.
ELTON: Step four, find some subtle way
to integrate yourself
into the target's household.
Mind you, I'm only down here
'cause my washing machine's knackered.
I don't suppose you're any good
at fixing things, are you?
Here we are. It was the fuse.
There's nothing wrong with the machine.
That's fine, all working.
Oh, Elton, I should have you on tap.
I used to have this little mate
called Mickey, he did all that stuff.
He's gone now, bless him.
Well, if you need me, give us a call.
I'll jot down my number.
You do that and I'll make us a cup of tea.
Go on, go and sit down.
Put the telly on if you want.
I can't bear it silent.
JACKIE: It's just me these days,
rattling about.
There's my daughter,
but she's gone travelling.
I keep her bedroom
all nice and ready though,
just in case she comes back.
-And her name is?
-Rose.
That's a nice name, Rose.
-So, where is she travelling?
-All over.
She's got her mobile.
I get a call now and then.
Not as often as I'd like.
Still, at that age,
who can be bothered phoning home?
Yeah.
Who's she with? Is it mates, is it? Or...
Just mates, yeah.
Well, if I had you
making a nice cup of tea like this,
I wouldn't stray far from home.
You're a charmer. Say it again.
Magnificent! Oh, I could kiss you!
Except I can't, of course. The eczeema.
-I've even got a picture of her on my phone.
-That's amazing.
You've achieved steps one to four
in precise order. How did you manage it?
I had to work very hard. She keeps
everything very close to her chest.
That's a hell of a chest.
But how do you move on?
Step five, that's the problem.
Step five. That's this week's homework.
I want a full plan of attack
from each of you.
Now, go on! Vamoose! Avanti!
There's work to do.
And, Elton, keep infiltrating.
You will do anything to get
that information, boy, anything.
Yes, sir.
Oh... Oh, Bridget. Bridget? Oh, yes.
Could I have a word with you
in private, please?
Mr Skinner's giving me a lift.
Oh, I can drop you at the station.
I'm sure Mr Skinner won't mind, will you?
Not at all.
-All right, Bridget, I'll see you next week.
-All right, then.
Bye-bye.
Now, Mr Skinner, I don't mean to pry,
but did you give Bridget
a little kiss back there?
I think I did.
And if you get your way, might there be
more little kisses between the two of you?
I think there might.
-I knew it!
-That's brilliant.
Now, let's not get excited. We'll see.
(BRIDGET SCREAMING)
ELTON: Infiltration went well
'cause Jackie kept phoning up,
needing this and needing that.
It was strange, the amount of things
that needed doing.
It's like that flat was jinxed.
It's weird, these fuses,
they keep on blowing.
You must be near a substation
'cause then you get the power surges.
Still, there we go. Fixed!
Here we are.
A little reward for my favourite handyman.
I shouldn't really, I've got the car outside.
You could always splash out on a taxi,
or whatever.
See what happens.
Right.
-Cheers.
-Cheers!
-Very nice. What's that, French?
-I suppose so.
They know how to do things, the French.
Is it from Rose? I mean, is she in France?
My daughter won't be coming back tonight,
just in case you're wondering.
We've got the place to ourselves.
Right.
-Nice music.
-Il Divo.
Yeah.
You were saying... Power surges.
-From the substation, yeah.
-Is that why it gets so hot in here?
-Is it hot?
-Oh, I think so.
-You should take your jacket off.
-No, I'm fine.
No, look, you must be boiling.
Oh, look at your shirt! Sorry!
(STUTTERING) I'm fine, it's all right.
-I've ruined it.
-No, honestly, it's fine.
-Take it off, I'll put it in the wash.
-Oh, come on, it's only a little drop.
Oops.
There now.
Ruined.
ELTON: And there I was,
the ultimate step five.
The perfect infiltration.
Target, Jackie Tyler.
Attaboy!
You're right, it is a bit hot,
but it's about to get hotter.
I'll see you soon. All right, be careful. Bye.
-Everything all right?
-That was my daughter.
Oh, look at you. I'm sorry.
I was just being stupid.
-Is she okay?
-She's so far away.
I get left here sometimes
and I don't know where she is.
Anything could be
happening to her, anything.
And I just go a bit mad.
Oh, put your shirt back on.
Where is she?
Doesn't matter.
I'm sorry. You better go.
Actually...
ELTON: And that's when it struck me.
Funny the things you think of
with your shirt off.
But that's when I realised
what was really important.
Never mind about Rose.
I'm not even gonna ask.
And I will put my shirt back on
because I'm gonna go out
and get us both a pizza.
'Cause I reckon you need cheering up.
She goes swanning off
and who's left to care about you, eh?
So I say, nice bit of pizza.
We'll put the telly on nice and loud,
we'll annoy that woman next door,
just you and me, as proper mates.
Yeah? Mates.
Go on, say yes.
Yes.
ELTON: All of a sudden,
a lot of things made sense.
I'd got so lost in conspiracies
and aliens and targets,
I'd been missing the obvious.
'Cause I did like Jackie,
but I liked someone else even more.
(MR BLUE SKY PLAYING)
Right. Let's get inside, then.
The pizza's getting cold.
I went in your coat.
For once in my life I thought, "I'll pay.”
I thought, "He's such a nice man,
"he won't accept anything
so I'll just slip a tenner in his pocket.”
And look what I found.
A photograph of my daughter.
No, no, no. It's not like that. I can explain.
-I bet you can.
-I wasn't being pervy or anything.
I wasn't after her.
-I was looking for the Doctor.
-Oh, I know that.
I worked that out.
'Cause it's never me, is it?
No, but that's how it started,
but I changed my mind.
Let me tell you something.
About those who get left behind.
Because it's hard.
And that's what you become, hard.
But if there's one thing I've learnt,
it's that I will never let her down
and I'll protect them both
until the end of my life.
So whatever you want,
I'm warning you, back off.
But, Jackie, I only wanted to meet him.
-I thought you liked me.
-I do.
Just get out of here! I said get out!
And leave me alone!
She was right. It's shameful.
-We used that woman.
-I knew I couldn't trust you!
You broke cover. You stupid little man,
you failed step five.
I don't care about step five!
'Cause it's all gone wrong, Mr Kennedy,
ever since you turned up.
We used to come here every week
and we'd have a laugh.
We were friends.
No wonder they stopped coming.
I mean, there's no Bliss anymore,
and even Bridget, she hasn't turned up.
I've been phoning and phoning,
there's no reply.
Who can blame her?
I'm sorry, Victor, but you're on your own,
'cause I am leaving
and so are you, Mr Skinner.
And as for you, Ursula,
you're coming with me.
And we're going to the Golden Locust
and we're gonna have a Chinese.
-What's that got to do with it?
-I mean, you and me. Together.
Having a meal. If you want.
Oh, I'd love it.
But you can't leave.
You'll never know
what he was doing, the Doctor.
You'll never know what he was doing
in your house all those years ago.
No, I'll never know.
Ursula, get your stuff.
Mr Skinner, are you coming?
Not to the Chinese if you don't mind.
Just sort of walking out.
I certainly am.
Victor, good luck. Goodbye.
Mr Skinner, would you stay
for a minute, please?
We're walking out.
I've got numbers for Bridget.
I've kept records. I've got old numbers.
We could track her down together,
you and I.
That's more like the old team spirit.
You two have a nice time.
-I hope you find her.
-I'll email you.
Just come a little closer.
(SKINNER SCREAMING)
-I love prawns. Crispy aromatic duck.
-Do you?
Oh, I left my phone.
-Really?
-Yeah.
It's not in my pocket.
-So much for the big exit.
-Yeah.
Come on, hurry up.
I'm not stopping, I just left my...phone.
-Victor?
-Take your phone and go.
Where's Mr Skinner?
He's gone to the toilet.
But we haven't got toilets,
we have to use the pub on the corner.
Well, that's where he is, then.
SKINNER: Help me!
-What was that?
-It was nothing. It was nothing!
SKINNER: Help me!
VICTOR: Shut up!
That's Mr Skinner.
Victor, look at your hands.
VICTOR: (DISTORTED VOICE)
Look at the rest of me.
You've dabbled with aliens,
now meet the genuine article.
Oh, my God!
-You're a thing.
-A thing?
This thing is my true form.
Better than that crude pink shape
you call a body.
What happened? Where am 17
Ursula, is that you?
That's Mr Skinner.
What have you done to him?
I've absorbed him.
-Colin? Is that you? Colin?
-Bridget, my love.
Oh, my God! That's Bridget.
-Colin, where are you?
-I'm here, Bridget. It's all right, I'm close.
You've absorbed them both.
What about Bliss? Where is she?
(BLISS MUMBLING)
What?
BLISS: I said you really don't want to know.
You've absorbed them.
You're some sort of absorb at hon!
An absorbaling.
-An Abzorbaloff.
-Yes, I like that.
Let them go. I'm ordering you.
-Let those people go.
-Oh, but they taste so sweet.
Just think about the Doctor.
Ooh, how will he taste!
All that experience, all that knowledge.
And if I've got to absorb Jackie Tyler
to get to him, then so be it.
Don't you dare!
If I have to beat them out of you!
Oh! Oh! No, no, please don't hit me!
Look at me,
I'm such a slow and clumsy beast.
Please don't hit me.
Well, then. Give them back.
What, you mean like this?
Just one touch! That's all it takes!
No. Oh, no, no.
-No!
-Leave her alone!
-Don't touch me.
Oh, Elton.
I'm so sorry you can't touch me.
Ursula.
Most likely to fight back indeed.
Leave her alone!
(SCREAMING)
Yes!
No, that's not fair!
She tastes like chicken.
Elton, where are you?
Please. Mr Kennedy, please.
I'm asking you.
I'm begging you, give her back to me.
I can't.
Once they've been absorbed,
the process is irreversible.
Wait a minute. Now I've been absorbed,
I can read his thoughts.
Oh, my God! Elton, you're next.
Get out of here.
Now you've seen him, he can't let you go.
Just run. Go on, never mind me. Get out!
Isn't she the clever one?
-Run, Elton! Run!
-Save yourself, boy!
Run for your life!
(BLISS MUMBLING)
(GROWLING)
Oh, what's the matter?
Have you given up so soon?
There's no point. Where would I go?
-Everything I ever wanted...
-Has been absorbed.
Oh, Elton. Don't say that.
-But it's true.
-Then join us. Join us, little man.
Come on.
It's everlasting peace. Come on, join us.
Dissolve into me.
(WHOOSHING)
Someone wants a word with you.
You upset my mum.
A great big absorbing creature
from outer space
-and you're having a go at me?
-No one upsets my mum.
At last. The greatest feast of all,
the Doctor.
Interesting. A sort of absorbatrix...
-Absorbaklon... Abzorbaloff...
-Abzorbaloff, yes!
Is it me or is he a bit Slitheen?
-Not from Rexicoricophalvitorius, are you?
-No. I'm not that swine!
I spit on them!
I was born on their twin planet.
Really? What's the twin planet
of Rexicoricophalvitorius?
-Clom.
-Clom?
Clom. Yes, and I'll return there victorious,
once I possess your travelling machine.
-Well, that's never gonna happen.
-Oh, it will.
You'll surrender yourself to me, Doctor,
or this one dies.
You see, I've read about you, Doctor.
I've studied you. So passionate.
So sweet.
You wouldn't let an innocent man die.
And I'll absorb him
unless you give yourself to me.
Sweet, maybe. Passionate, I suppose.
But don't ever mistake that for nice.
Do what you want.
-He'll die, Doctor.
-Go on, then.
So be it.
Mind you,
the others might have something to say.
-Others?
-URSULA: He's right!
The Doctor's right! We can't let him.
Oh, Mr Skinner.
-Bridget, pull! For God's sake, pull!
-No! No!
If it's the last thing we ever do.
Bliss! All of us, together, come on!
-Pull! LINDA united!
-Stop it! Stop!
Pull!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Elton! The cane, break it!
My cane! You stupid man!
(GROANING)
-What did I do?
-The cane created a limitation field.
Now it's broken, he can't stop.
The absorber is being absorbed.
By what?
By the Earth.
URSULA: Bye-bye, Elton.
Bye-bye.
Who was she?
That was Ursula.
(SNIFFLING)
And that's it.
Almost. Because the Doctor
still had more to say.
-You don't remember, do you?
-And then he explained.
That night, all those years ago.
There was a shadow in your house.
DOCTOR: A living shadow in the darkness.
An elemental shade that
had escaped from the Howling Halls.
I stopped it,
but I wasn't in time to save her.
I'm sorry.
ELTON: Because that was the night
my mother died.
(MR BLUE SKY CODA PLAYING)
We forget because we must.
So, there you go.
Turns out
I've had the most terrible things happen,
and the most brilliant things,
and sometimes, well,
I can't tell the difference.
They're all the same thing. They're just me.
You know, Stephen King said once, he said,
"Salvation and damnation
are the same thing."
And I never knew what he meant.
But I do now.
'Cause the Doctor might be wonderful,
but thinking back,
I was having such a special time,
just for a bit.
I had this nice little gang.
(DON'T BRING ME DOWN PLAYING)
And they were destroyed.
It's not his fault.
But maybe that's what happens
if you touch the Doctor,
even for a second.
I keep thinking of Rose and Jackie,
and how much longer
before they pay the price.
URSULA: Oh, now don't get all miserable.
-Come on, Elton. You've still got me.
-Oh, yeah.
'Cause the Doctor said he could do
one last thing with his magic wand.
If I can key into the absorption matrix
and separate the last victim.
It's too late for total reconstruction, but...
(BUBBLING)
Elton! Fetch a spade!
Even then, after all that,
the Doctor saved me one last time.
(GRUNTING)
-Here she is.
-URSULA: Could be worse.
At least I'll never age. And it really
is quite peaceful. You'd be surprised.
It's a relationship of sorts. But we manage.
-We've even got a bit of a love life.
-Oh, let's not go into that.
And I don't care what anyone thinks,
I love her.
Oh.
But the thing is...
There you are,
I even bought a remote zoom.
But what I wanted to say is,
you know, when you're a kid,
they tell you that it's all grow up, get a job,
get married, get a house,
have a kid and that's it.
(SIGHS)
But the truth is,
the world is so much stranger than that.
It's so much darker and so much madder.
And so much better.
-DOCTOR: 30th Olympiad.
-That's great!
(CROWD CHEERING)
-They're not safe.
-They're in the garden.
WOMAN: Get them in, I'm begging you.
In the last six days,
three of your children have been stolen.
We need to find the source of that power.
These? They're kids' pictures. Now get out!
Chloe has a power.
-She's using it to snatch the kids.
-Get out!
If living things can become drawings,
then maybe drawings
can become living things.