MAN: "But who is this creature
with terrible claws,
"and terrible teeth in his terrible jaws?"
Go on, your bit.
"He, he has..." Go on!
I can't do it, Dad.
I can listen to books, anyway.
I know it doesn't come easy, son,
but you've got to keep at it, all right?
You're not on your own with this.
Mo, you'll be late for your shift.
Oh, you're right!
Sorry, EL, got to go.
Now, who loves you more than me?
- No-one.
- Stop saying that!
Mwah!
COMPUTER: Approaching stage four,
target drilling depth.
Stage four target drill depth
scheduled in five,
four, three, two, one.
Stage four target drill
depth achieved.
- Oh!
- Drill depth now 217 kilometres.
Hi. Nasreen here, just to let you know
we have just hit our new target!
21 kilometres, folks!
Further than anyone's ever
drilled into the Earth.
Thanks for your amazing work.
Have a great weekend!
Onwards and downwards.
How much further
do you think we can we go, Mack?
Into the unknown!
- Exciting, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Aye, aye! Stop that!
The real worker's here now!
- Evening, Mo!
- 21k?
Whoo-hoo!
You wanted to grab all the glory
before I come on shift!
Right, off you go, get out,
my gaff for the night.
Brilliant.
(RATTLING)
(SWITCH CLICKS ON AND OFF)
That is mad.
Oh!
Please...
Ahh!
Argh!
Behold...Rio!
- Nuh-uh.
- Not really getting
- the sunshine carnival vibe.
- No!
Ooh, feel that, though, what's that?
(LOW RUMBLING)
Ground feels strange...
Just me. Wait...
- That's weird.
- RORY: What's weird?
Doctor, stop trying to distract us.
We're in the wrong place.
Doctor, it's freezing
and I've dressed for Rio.
We are not stopping here.
Doctor! Are you listening to me?
It's a graveyard!
- You promised me a beach.
- Blue grass.
Patches of it
all around the graveyard.
So, Earth, 2020-ish,
ten years in your future,
wrong continent for Rio, I'll admit,
but it's not a massive overshoot.
Why are those people waving at us?
Can't be.
It is!
- It's you two.
- RORY: No.
We're here.
How can we be up there?!
Ten years in your future.
Come to relive past glories, I'd imagine.
Humans, you're so nostalgic.
We're still together in ten years?
No need to sound so surprised!
Hey, let's go and talk to them!
We can say hi to Future Us!
How cool is that?
No, best not, really best not.
These things get complicated
very quickly, and... Oh, look!
Big mining thing.
Oh, I love a big mining thing.
See, way better than Rio!
Rio doesn't have a big mining thing.
- We're not going to have a look, are we?
- Let's go and have a look!
- Come on, let's see what they're doing.
- If he can't get us to Rio,
how's he ever going to get us back home?
Did you not see, over there?
It all works out fine.
After everything we've seen,
we just drop back into our old lives,
the nurse and the kissogram?
- I guess. He's getting away.
- Hang on.
What are you doing with that?
Engagement ring!
I thought you liked me wearing it.
Amy! You could lose it!
Cost...a lot of money, that!
Hm.
Spoilsport.
- Go on. I'IL catch you both up.
- Doctor!
TONY: The drill's shut down!
There's no sign of Mo.
Nobody's been in or out of
the perimeter between last night...
and...now. What's that?
That wasn't there last night.
How the hell did that get there?
I don't know.
Well, that was quick!
- Was it?
- It's great that you came.
Bit retro.
What is it, portable crime lab?
Oh. Er, sort of.
Ambrose Northover.
I was the one who called.
I run the meals on wheels for
the whole valley. This is my son, Elliot.
Where's your uniform?
Don't be cheeky, Elliot,
he's plain clothes.
CID, is it? Anyway, it's over here.
Um... OK...
"Restricted access".
"No unauthorised personnel”. Hm.
- That is breaking and entering.
- What did I break?!
Sonicing and entering,
totally different.
Come on, then.
You're sure Rory'll catch us up?
It's a family plot, see.
My aunt Gladys died six years ago.
Her husband, Alun,
died a few weeks back.
He lived in the house two doors down.
There's not many of us left up here now.
Mum, he doesn't care about that!
He wants to know about the dead bodies.
Yes. Sorry.
Well, they always wanted to be buried
in the same plot, together.
But when we went to bury Uncle Alun,
Gladys wasn't there. Gone.
Body, coffin, everything.
What?
The mad thing is, on the surface,
the grave was untouched.
No signs of it having been messed with.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Nobody has touched the grave
since my aunt was buried.
But when they dug it open,
the body was gone.
How is that possible?
What about now, can you feel it now?
Honestly, I've got no idea
what you're on about.
The ground doesn't feel like it should.
It's ten years in the future,
maybe how this ground feels
is how it always feels.
Good thought, but no. It doesn't.
- (WHIRRING)
- Hear that? Drill in start-up mode.
After-waves of a recent
seismological shift and blue grass.
Oh, please! Have you
always been this disgusting?
No, that's recent. What's in...
here?
- Hello!
- Who are you?
What are you doing here?
And what are you wearing?
I dressed for Rio!
Ministry of Drills, Earth and Science.
New Ministry, quite big, just merged,
a lot of responsibility, don't like
to talk about it. What are you doing?
None of your business.
Where are you getting
these readings from?
- Under the soil.
- The drill's up and running again.
What's going on?
Who are these people?
Amy, the Doctor.
We're not staying, are we, Doctor?!
Why's there a big patch of earth
in the middle of your floor?
We don't know,
it just appeared overnight.
Good, right, you all need
to get out of here very fast.
NASREEN: Why?
- What's your name?
- Nasreen Chaudhry.
Look at the screens, Nasreen,
look at your readings.
- It's moving.
- Hey, that's specialised equipment!
- Get away from it.
- What is?
Doctor, this steam,
is that a good thing?
Shouldn't think so. It's shifting
when it shouldn't be shifting.
What shouldn't?
The ground, the soil,
the earth, moving, but how? Why?
- AMY: Earthquake?
- TONY: What's going on?
Doubt it. Cos it's only happening
under this room.
It knows we're here.
The ground's attacking us.
- That...that's not possible!
- Under the circumstances, I'd suggest...
run!
- Tony!
- Stay back, Amy!
Stay away from the earth!
It's OK.
- It's pulling me down!
- Amy!
Doctor, help me, something's got me!
Take my hand!
Doctor, the ground's got my legs.
- I've got you.
- OK.
- Don't let go.
- Never.
Doctor, what is it?
Why is it doing this?
Stay calm,
keep hold of my hand, don't let go.
Your drill, shut it down! Go! Now!
- Can you get me out?
- Amy, try and stay calm.
If you struggle, it'll make things worse.
Keep hold of my hand.
Shut down all drilling activity
as quick as you can.
TONY: Reducing main unit power.
I'm not going to let you go.
Doctor, it's pulling me down,
something's pulling me!
Stay calm.
Hold on, if they can just
shut down the drill...
- I can't hold on!
- NASREEN: Tony, we've got to be faster!
I'm doing my best!
Come on, shut down!
What's pulling me?
What is under the earth?
I don't want to suffocate under there.
Amy, concentrate.
Don't you give up!
- Tell Rory...
- No.
Amy!
Amy, no! No! No!
No! No! No!
No.
No!
No. No. No.
Where is she?
She's gone. The ground took her.
- Do you want sugar?
- Oh... Sorry?
In your tea. Mum's asking.
No. Just white, thanks.
There's only one explanation,
as far as I can see.
- What's that, then?
- The graves eat people.
Devour them whole, leaving no trace.
- Not sure about that.
- They didn't steal the body from above.
They couldn't have got in from the sides.
Only other thing is,
they get in from underneath.
Not very likely, though.
"When you've eliminated
the impossible,
"whatever remains, however improbable,
must be the truth."”
Sorry?
Sherlock Holmes.
Got the audio book.
The graves round here eat people.
(SHIVERS)
Is that what happened to Mo?
Are they dead?
It's not quicksand.
She didn't just sink -
something pulled her in, it wanted her.
The ground wanted her?
You said the ground was dormant,
just a patch of earth,
when you first saw it this morning.
And the drill had been stopped.
That's right.
But when you re-started the drill,
the ground fought back.
So, what, the ground wants
to stop us drilling?!
NASREEN: Doctor, that is ridiculous.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINING)
(RUMBLING)
I'm not saying that, and it's not
ridiculous, I just don't think it's right.
Oh! Of course!
Ha! It's bio-programming!
What?!
Bio-programming! Oh, clever.
You use bio-signals to resonate
the internal molecular structure
of natural objects.
It's mainly used in engineering
and construction, mostly jungle planets,
but that's way in the future,
and not here. What's it doing here?
Sorry, did you just say "jungle planets"?
You're not making any sense, man!
'Souse me, I'm making perfect sense,
you're just not keeping up.
The earth, the ground beneath our feet,
was bio-programmed to attack.
Yeah, even if that were possible,
which, by the way, it's not, why?
Stop you drilling. OK, so we find
what's doing the bio-programming,
we can find Amy, we can get her back.
Ssh, ssh, ssh!
Have I gone mad? I've gone mad!
- Doctor...
- Ssh, ssh! Silence! Absolute silence!
- You stopped the drill, right?
- Yes.
And you've only got the one drill?
- You're sure about that?
Yes!
- (WHIRRING)
- So, if you shut the drill down...
why can I still hear drilling?
- It's under the ground.
- That's not possible.
- (HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
- Oh, no, what are you doing?!
Hacking into your records.
Probe reports, samples, sensors, good,
just unite the data, make it all
one big conversation, let's have a look.
So. We are here
and this is your drill hole.
21.009 kilometres.
Well done!
Thank you. It's taken us a long time.
Why here, though? Why drill on this site?
We found patches of grass
in this area, containing trace minerals
unseen in this country for...
20 million years.
The blue grass? Oh, Nasreen,
those trace minerals weren't
X marking the spot, saying "dig here".
They were a warning. "Stay away."
Cos while you've been
drilling down...
...somebody else has been drilling up.
Oh...beautiful.
Network of tunnels all the way down.
No, no, we've surveyed that area.
You only saw what you went looking for.
- (REGULAR BLEEPING)
- Oh...what...what are they?
DOCTOR: Heat signals.
Wait. Dual readings, hot and cold,
doesn't make sense.
And now they're moving.
Fast. How many people live nearby?
Just my daughter and her family.
The rest of the staff travel in.
Grab this equipment and follow me.
Why? What are we doing?
That noise isn't a drill.
It's transport. Three of them, 30km down,
rate of speed looks about 150km an hour.
Should be here in...
ooh, quite soon...
12 minutes.
Whatever bio-programmed
the earth is on its way up. Now.
How can something be coming up when
there's only the Earth's crust down there?
You saw the readings!
Who are you, anyway?
How can you know all this?
- (STRAFING NOISES)
- Whoa!
Did you see that?
No, no, no!
(ELECTRONIC FIZZLING)
Energy signal originating from
under the earth. We're trapped.
Doctor, something weird's going on here,
the graves are eating people.
Not now, Rory!
Energy barricade.
Invisible to the naked eye.
We can't get out and no-one
from the outside world can get in.
What?
OK, what about the TARDIS?
The what?
Er, no, those energy patterns
would play havoc with the circuits.
With a bit of time, maybe, but we've
only got nine and a half minutes.
Nine and a half minutes to what?
We're trapped. And something's
burrowing towards the surface.
Where's Amy?
Get everyone inside the church.
Rory, I'UL get her back.
What do you mean, "get her back"?
Where's she gone?
She was taken.
Into the earth.
How?
Why didn't you stop it?
- I tried. I promise, I tried.
- Well, you should've tried harder!
I'L find Amy.
I'll keep you all safe. I promise.
Come on, please.
I need you alongside me.
(ELECTRONIC FIZZLING)
(SHE TAKES A BREATH)
(STEADY BLEEPING)
Where's Mo? Is he with you?
This flaming door, always sticking!
I thought you were having it fixed!
Dad!
Something's happened to him, hasn't it?
So we can't get out,
we can't contact anyone,
and something, the something that took my
husband, is coming up through the earth.
Yes. If we move quickly enough,
we can be ready.
No, stop. This has gone far enough.
I mean, what is this?
- He's telling the truth, love.
- Come on!
It's not the first time we've had no
phone signals. Reception's always rubbish.
Look, Ambrose, we saw
the Doctor's friend get taken, OK?
You saw the lightning in the sky.
I have seen the impossible today,
and the only person who's made
any sense of it, for me, is the Doctor.
- Him?!
- Me!
Can you get my dad back?
Yes.
But I need you to trust me
and do exactly as I say
from this second onwards,
because we're running out of time.
So tell us what to do.
Thank you. We have eight minutes
to set up a line of defence.
Bring me every phone,
every camera, every piece of recording
or transmitting equipment you can find.
Every burglar alarm, every movement
sensor, every security light!
I want the whole area
covered with sensors.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
Right, guys, we need to be ready
for whatever's coming up.
I need a map of the village,
marking where the cameras are going.
I can't do the words. I'm dyslexic.
Oh, that's all right,
I can't make a decent meringue.
Draw like your life depends on it, Elliot.
6 minutes 40.
(BLEEPING)
Works in quadrants, every movement
sensor and trip light we've got.
If anything moves, we'll know.
Good lad!
AMBROSE: Oi! What are you doing?!
Resources!
Every little helps! Meals on wheels.
What've you got here, then? Warmer
in the front, refrigerated in the back.
Bit chilly for a hideout, mind.
- What are those?
- Like you say, every little helps.
No! No weapons.
It's not the way I do things.
Well, you said we're supposed
to be defending ourselves.
Oh, Ambrose, you're better than this.
I'm asking nicely.
Put them away.
Look at that! Perfect!
Dyslexia never stopped Da Vinci
or Einstein, it's not stopping you.
I don't understand
what you're going to do.
Two-phase plan. First, the sensors and
cameras tell us when something arrives.
Second, if something does arrive,
I use this to send a sonic pulse
through that network of devices,
a pulse which would temporarily
incapacitate most things in the universe.
Knock 'em out. Cool.
- Lovely place to grow up, round here.
- Suppose.
I want to live in a city one day.
Soon as I'm old enough, I'll be off.
- I was the same, where I grew up.
- Did you get away?
- Yeah.
- Do you ever miss it?
So much.
Is it monsters coming?
Have you met monsters before?
- Yeah.
- You scared of them?
No. They're scared of me.
Will you really get my dad back?
No question.
I left my headphones at home.
- How are you doing?
- It's getting darker.
How can it be getting dark so quickly?
Shutting out light within the barricade.
Trying to isolate us in the dark.
Which means...
(RUMBLING)
...it's here.
They're close to the surface now.
(STEADY BLEEPING)
- Tony!
- Like you didn't know.
(BLEEPING STOPS)
I can't open it! It keeps sticking!
The wood's warped.
- Any time you want to help(!)
- Can't you sonic it?
- It doesn't do wood.
- That is rubbish.
Oi! Don't diss the sonic!
See if we can get a fix.
(ELECTRONIC SCRAMBLING)
- No power.
- It's deliberate.
What do we do now?
Nothing. We've got nothing! They sent
an energy surge to wreck our systems.
Is everyone OK? Is anyone hurt?
- Fine.
- All good.
Me too.
(RUMBLING)
(AMBROSE GASPS)
Doctor...what was that?
TONY: Like the holes at the drill station.
AMBROSE: Is this how they happened?
It's coming through
the final layer of earth.
What is?
(SILENCE)
Banging's stopped.
Where's Elliot?
Has...has anyone seen Elliot?
Did he come in?
was he in when the door was shut?
Who counted him back in?
Who saw him last?
I did.
Where is he?
He said he was going to get headphones.
And you let him go?!
He was out there on his own?!
(HE PANTS)
(GROWLING)
Mum! Grandpa Tony! Let me in!
- Elliot!
- Let me in!
He's out there! Help me!
Open the door!
Mum! There's something out here!
Push, Elliot!
Push, Elliot, give it a shove!
] - Mum!
Push! Hurry up!
(SNARLING)
Mum...
- TONY: Come on!
- AMBROSE: Elliot!
Where is he?!
He was here!
He was here! Elliot!
- Ambrose, don't go running off!
- Ambrose!
Elliot! It's Mum!
(BLEEPING)
No-0-0-0-0-0!
Aaargh! Get off me!
(SNARLING)
Argh!
- Dad! Dad!
- DOCTOR: What happened?
My dad's hurt!
Get him into the church now!
Elliot's gone!
They've killed him, haven't they?
I don't think so.
They've taken three people, when
they could've just killed them up here.
There's still hope, Ambrose.
There is always hope.
Then why have they taken him?
I don't know.
I'LL find Elliot, I promise.
But first I've got to stop this attack.
Please, get inside the church.
- Come on, Dad. Come on.
- So, what now?
(DISTANT HISSING)
Cold blood.
(SING-SONG VOICE) I know who they are.
(HE WHISTLES)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
We got it! Defending the planet
with meals on wheels!
- (RUMBLING)
- What...what was that?
Sounds like they're leaving.
Without this one?
RORY: Looks like we scared them off.
I don't think so.
Now both sides have hostages.
Let me out.
Can anybody hear me?
I'm alive in here!
Let me out!
I know you're out there!
My name is Amy Pond, and you'd better
get me the hell out of here
or so help me,
I'm going to kick your backside!
Please?
Shh!
Did you just shush me?
Did you just shush...me?!
No, no, no, don't do that. No gas.
No gas!
(SHE SPLUTTERS)
So, I think I've met
these creatures before.
Different branch of the species, mind,
but all the same...
Let's see if our friend's thawed out.
- Are you sure? By yourself?
- Very sure.
But the sting...
Venom gland takes
at least 24 hours to recharge.
Am I right?
(HEAVY BREATHING)
I know what I'm doing.
I'll be fine.
I'm the Doctor.
I've come to talk.
I'm going to remove your mask.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
You are beautiful.
Remnant of a bygone age on Planet Earth.
And by the way, lovely mode of travel!
Geothermal currents, projecting you up
through a network of tunnels.
Gorgeous! Mind if I sit?
Now.
Your people...
have a friend of mine.
I want her back.
Why did you come to the surface?
What do you want?
Oh, I do hate a monologue.
Give us a bit back. How many are you?
I'm the last of my species.
Really?
No. "Last of the species”,
the Klempari Defence. Ha!
As an interrogation defence,
it's a bit old hat, I'm afraid.
I'm the last of my species.
No. You're really not.
Because I'm the last of my species
and I know how it sits in a heart.
So don't insult me.
Let's start again.
Tell me your name.
Alaya.
How long has your tribe been
sleeping under the earth, Alaya?
It's not difficult to work out.
You're 300 million years
out of your comfort zone.
Question is, what woke you now?
We were attacked.
The drill.
Our sensors detected a threat
to our life support systems.
The warrior class was activated
to prevent the assault.
We will wipe the vermin from
the surface and reclaim our planet.
Do we have to say "vermin"?
They're really very nice.
- Primitive apes.
- Extraordinary species.
You attack them,
they'll fight back. But...
there's a peace to be brokered here.
I can help you with that.
This land is ours.
We lived here long before the apes.
Doesn't give you
automatic rights to it now, I'm afraid.
- Humans won't give up the planet.
- So we destroy them.
- You underestimate them.
- You underestimate us!
One tribe of Homo reptilia
against six billion humans?
You've got your work cut out.
We did not initiate combat.
But we can still win.
Tell me where my friend is.
Give us back the people who were taken.
No.
I'm not going to let you
provoke a war, Alaya.
There'll be no battle here today.
The fire of war is already lit.
A massacre is due.
Not while I'm here.
I'll gladly die for my cause.
What will you sacrifice for yours?
You're going to what?!
I'm going to go down
below the surface,
to find the rest of the tribe,
to talk to them.
You're going to negotiate
with these aliens?
They're not aliens!
They're Earth...liens.
Once known as the Silurian race,
or, some would argue, Eocenes,
or Homo reptilia.
Not monsters, not evil.
Well...only as evil as you are.
The previous owners
of the planet, that's all.
Look...from their point of view,
you're the invaders.
Your drill was threatening
their settlement.
Now, the creature in the crypt.
Her name's Alaya.
She's one of their warriors,
and she's my best bargaining chip.
I need her alive. If she lives,
so do Elliot and Mo and Amy.
Because I will find them.
While I'm gone,
you four people, in this church,
in this corner of Planet Earth,
you have to be the best of humanity.
And what if they come back?
Shouldn't we be examining this creature,
dissecting it, finding its weak points?
No dissecting! No examining!
We return their hostage,
they return ours. Nobody gets harmed.
We can land this, together...
if you are the best you can be.
You are decent,
brilliant people.
Nobody dies today.
Understand?
No, sorry, no, what are you doing?
Coming with you, of course!
What is it, some kind of...transport pod?
Sort of, but you're not...
coming with me.
He's right, you're not.
I have spent all my life excavating
the layers of this planet.
And now you want me to stand back while
you head down into it? I don't think so!
- I don't have time to argue!
- I thought we were in a rush.
- It'll be dangerous.
- Oh, so's crossing the road.
Oh, for goodness' sake,
all right, then! Come on!
- Hey... Come back safe.
- Of course.
Welcome aboard the TARDIS.
Now, don't touch anything.
- Very precious.
- No way!
But...but that's...
This is...
...fantastic!
- What does it do?
- Everything!
I'm hoping, if we're going down,
- that barricade won't inter...fere!
- (CRASHING)
- Did you touch something?!
- No! Isn't this what it does?!
I'm not doing anything!
We've been hijacked, I can't stop it!
They must've sensed
the electromagnetic field!
They're pulling the TARDIS
down into the Earth!
You had to come and see me.
We...are going to keep you safe.
Your tribe are going to give us back
our people, in exchange for you.
No.
Shall I tell you what's
really going to happen, apes?
One of you will kill me.
My death shall ignite a war.
And every stinking ape shall be wiped
from the surface of my beloved planet.
We won't allow that to happen.
I know apes better
than you know yourselves.
I know which one of you will kill me.
Do you?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Whoa! Whoa!
(RUMBLING SUBSIDES)
- Oi.
- Where are we?
(LOOSE EARTH FALLS)
Oh!
- (HE WHISTLES)
- (ECHO)
Looks like we fell through the bottom
of their tunnel system.
Don't suppose it was designed
for handling something like this.
- How far down are we?
- Oh...a lot more than 21 km.
So why aren't we burning alive?
Don't know.
Interesting, isn't it?
- It's like this is every day to you!
- Not every day.
Every other day.
Don't struggle.
(WHISPERING) Close your eyes
and don't struggle.
What? Where am I?
- Why can't I move my body?
- Decontamination, they call it.
They did it to me. While I was conscious.
OK, you're freaking me out now.
Did what? Who did?
Dissected me.
No...
He's coming!
I'm sorry, I...
I wish I could help you!
We're looking for
a small tribal settlement.
Probably housing around...
a dozen Homo reptilia.
Maybe less.
- One...small tribe?
- Yeah.
Maybe a...dozen?
Ah.
Maybe more than a dozen.
Maybe more like an entire civilisation
living beneath the earth.