(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: Finally, this is where
our journey stops.
(SIGHS)
You're going to make this the place?
It's time.
You're ready, Delph.
I don't think I am.
Seventeen years is enough.
This is what I've trained you for.
You call it training,
I call it building doubt.
Every lesson that you've given me,
I feel like I've understood less,
-not more.
-Which is the point.
The more we learn,
the less we realise we know.
This is our faith.
This is our existence.
The Creator would contend
the world is not to be understood.
Only experienced
and built with our gift.
Praise the Creator's will.
Do this, Delph, and you'll shape
our world in worship.
But if I fail...
If Ican'tdoit
after all these years...
Trust in yourself!
Now, come on.
Show me our years of walking
have not been wasted.
Fulfil what we are, what only we can do.
(SIGHS)
(RUMBLING)
(ENERGY PULSING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
WOMAN: What's happening?
Stop, Delph. Now.
It's not possible.
(GASPS)
It cannot be, and yet...
(EXHALES)
(CREATURE BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(ALARM BLARING)
-GRAHAM: Those systems
are lit up like a Christmas tree.
DOCTOR: Nine cries for help,
nine distress signals,
all coming from the same planet.
Not just the same planet,
the same area of the same planet.
Now, listen,
planet of Ranskoor Av Kolos.
Ranskoor Av what?
Kolos. Roughly translated,
means "disintegrator of the soul.”
Ooh, another cheery one.
The TARDIS is reporting that the planet
is transmitting
violent, psychotropic waves
throughout its atmosphere.
The type of waves
that mess with your brain.
Distort reality.
Change moods to the extreme.
These are neural-balancers.
So long as you're wearing one,
it should keep you immune to the waves.
You must keep it on at all times.
What happens if we lose them?
Don't lose them!
GRAHAM: And it has to be us, does it,
answering these signals
from this planet?
No, not at all.
But everyone else has passed them by.
You think we should do the same?
I've locked on to a craft
on the planet's surface.
Here we go.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
This is one of the ships
that sent a distress signal.
It looks pretty abandoned now.
Cryo-sleep chambers.
Long-range craft. Weapons archive.
Been in service for a long time
by the looks of things.
Who sent the signal? Where's the crew?
Doctor.
(GASPS)
-DOCTOR: Hi.
-Who are you?
I'm the Doctor.
This is Yaz,
Ryan, and Graham.
What is that thing?
It's what we travel in.
See? The sign on the front,
we respond to urgent calls.
You look like an urgent call.
What's your name?
Did they send you?
When you say "they," who do you mean?
People from here?
Because we've just arrived here,
remember?
We've never been to this planet before.
So we can't be with them,
whoever they are.
That's right.
Now, is it just you,
or is there any other crew with you?
I don't know.
What's happened to me?
My friends are going to take a look
around your ship if that's okay?
See what you can find out.
I should have left.
And why haven't you?
I can't remember my name.
I used to know before I went outside.
I should never have gone outside.
Why? What happened outside?
The battle.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Who are you? How did you get here?
We've just been talking.
We just arrived.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
We want to help you.
I think this planet is having
a bad effect on you.
Would you consider putting this on?
Neural-balancer.
It'll help calm your mind.
Please.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Put this on.
YASMIN: I think I found an on button.
(WHIRRING)
(WHISPERING) Who do you think
that lot are, then?
I think this is the rest of them.
So there's four in total.
He's the commander.
RYAN: Maybe he killed his own crew.
GRAHAM: Always one for
the cheery option.
YASMIN: We don't know they're dead.
All we know is they're not here.
RYAN: Yeah.
He's taken a neural-balancer.
I'm hoping it'll restore
something in his mind.
He looks pretty broken to me, Doc.
(DEVICE BLEEPING)
Engine's fine.
-(SHIP SYSTEMS POWERING UP)
-Power's still working.
Ship's fine.
He could have left whenever he wanted.
It doesn't make sense.
Here he is.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Paltraki.
My name is Paltraki.
Nice to meet you, Paltraki.
Neural-balancer kicking in?
Don't push too hard.
They work slowly.
It'll come back.
(SHIP ALARM BLARES)
Whoa.
What is that?
We can answer it for you.
Do you want us to activate it?
Get out from the viewing line.
-Do as I say, son.
-Okay.
(STATIC)
(MONITOR BEEPS)
-Paltraki.
-What do you want?
You must return to us.
The Creator commands it.
CREATURE: (BREATHES HEAVILY) Paltraki.
(CREATURE CONTINUES BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you remember me, Paltraki?
I know that voice.
-Is that...
-It can't be.
I want what is mine returned.
(CREATURE BREATHING HEAVILY)
And why would I do that?
For your crew.
Return what you took
or I will dismantle them piece by piece
beamed directly into your ship.
GIRL: (OVER MONITOR)
Paltraki, don't go back.
Don't worry about us.
You got what you came for...
(GIRL SCREAMING)
Two of your crew left.
You have till nightfall.
WOMAN: Please, return what you took.
Do as the Creator desires.
(GASPS)
Is it the same one?
I don't know.
YASMIN: That can't be Tim Shaw.
I thought he was dead.
I sent him back to where he came from,
using his own recall device.
Then why is he here?
Who's the girl?
Her name
was
Umsang.
We fought alongside each other.
What did you take?
Not take.
Recover.
(BUZZING)
What is it?
Our mission is retrieval.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Great. All I'm getting
is contradictions.
Looks mineral. Maybe it's been extracted
from the planet.
The density's blowing the sonic's mind.
If it's that valuable,
they'd want to keep it safe.
It's not just safe.
There's an incredibly sophisticated
stasis lock
embedded in the container's
bio structure and I don't understand it.
Stenza technology.
What is it, Paltraki?
Where did it come from?
-PALTRAKI: I mustn't return it, but...
-(DEVICE BLEEPING)
They have my crew.
Hey, have you seen this?
Some kind of mapping device.
All kinds of stuff on here.
Targets marked on.
Mission briefing. Was this yours?
Maybe, I... I don't know.
We could use it to retrace
-where he was.
-DOCTOR: Yeah.
We want to help you get your crew back.
We'll go with you.
Because we've got unfinished business
with that monster.
Oh, I can Lift it!
I shouldn't be able to.
How can I lift it
with that impossible density?
We're going to find your crew
and work out why this is so important.
Equipment bay. Is it over there?
Do you mind if I take a look?
Okay, Graham?
DOCTOR: Ranskoor Av Kolos
isn't the Stenzas' home planet
so how can that be Tim Shaw?
-YASMIN: Feeling sick?
-Yeah, like travel sick, but worse.
Sickness is how it started.
GRAHAM: So what is that sound?
I think it's the planet.
Obviously it doesn't like intruders.
Doc, can I have a word?
-Of course.
-Just the two of us.
Fine.
Come on, Yaz.
I need to be honest with you,
because I am really grateful
for everything you've done for me.
Well, for us, everywhere we've been,
all the adventures, been amazing.
But, if that is the creature
from Sheffield,
I will kill it if I can.
For what it did to Grace.
Go back to the TARDIS, Graham.
No.
I won't let you do that.
You ain't gonna have a say in it.
You're better than this.
You are. You have to be.
If you kill him,
I can't have you travel with me.
That's if you even live.
-I understand.
-No, you don't.
We're going to rescue hostages. Anything
that compromises them is dangerous.
And if you kill him,
you become the same as him.
I ain't having that.
I'm serious, Graham.
And so am I.
RYAN: That's all you remember, being
back on your ship without your crew?
PALTRAKI: Nothing before that.
There's a reason I should have left.
I can nearly remember.
The Doctor said don't push.
The memories will return.
Hey, Yaz, look.
You all seeing those?
-What happened here?
-PALTRAKI: Those that came before us.
That failed and fell.
The vanquished of Ranskoor Av Kolos.
But that's not all, look beyond.
What are you looking at?
Look at the mists.
Through the battlefield,
on to the edifice.
That was our destination.
RYAN: We're not going
to go through that, are we?
No one in their right mind's
gonna go through there.
RYAN: What do you think's inside?
DOCTOR: Other than Tim Shaw,
I don't know.
Equipment.
I borrowed all this
from your ship, Paltraki.
These throat mics work like commdots.
Side of the neck. Stay in contact.
Take one each.
Grenades, codebreakers
for doors... Also,
a bomb.
What happened to "never do weapons"?
It's a flexible creed.
Doors, locks, walls, buildings,
fair game.
If it can be rebuilt, I'll allow it.
No, no, you stopped me
trying to shoot the Sniperbots before.
You were new. I have to lay down
the rules if someone's new.
Also, don't quote that back to me.
My rules change all the time.
Be careful with them.
You've got your trackers.
As far as I can decipher,
the golden markers
on your devices
relate to your
original mission purpose...
-(DEVICE BLEEPS)
-...for Paltraki and his crew.
Which must connect to this object.
That's where I want you both to head.
See what you can find.
Graham, Ryan,
you've got life signal markers
on your devices.
Head to that area
and rescue Paltraki's crew.
What about you? Where are you heading?
I'm gonna find our friend.
I want to come with you.
No.
What will you do once you find him?
Find out what this is
and why it's so precious to him.
Oh, I might need
a bit of a negotiation leverage.
(SIGHS)
RYAN: What are you doing with those?
DOCTOR: Grenades.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-As insurance policy.
You think that's smart?
I think it's a precaution.
I like precautions.
Always take precautions.
Especially when you don't know
what you're doing.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
DOCTOR: Ah, I should
have brought wellies.
That could have been another precaution,
"always bring wellies."
I love wellies.
In fact, I think I half-invented them.
YASMIN: And you think
this is the best way in?
DOCTOR: (PANTING) Closest thing
to a front door this building's got.
As far as I can tell.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BLEEPS)
Now.
Doorbell.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRS AND BLEEPS)
Oh, entrance activation field.
-Maybe I can bypass...
-(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL PANTING)
Whatever happened to doors?
Don't aliens bother with doors?
-The building dragged us in.
-So they know we're here.
Be quiet and get moving. Come on.
You all know what you have to do.
GRAHAM: You see anything?
RYAN: Of course I can't see anything,
I'm looking at the same things as you.
I know what you're thinking.
Is that right?
You want to get to him for Nan.
Hold that.
Do I really?
Why don't you just concentrate
on what we're supposed to be doing?
You think that's what Nan would want?
No, I think your nan
would want to be alive.
She actually liked being alive
and she was really good at it.
And she'd say to me,
"Graham, if you get the chance,
you send that blue piece of rubbish
"to kingdom come.”
Because you know why?
Your nan...
(WHISPERING) Your nan
might have been kind,
but she was also tougher
than you and me put together.
-And what about the rest of us?
-No.
Me, Yaz, and the Doctor.
I thought we were a team.
Don't wreck what we've got
because you're still angry.
I am not...
Look, we did not get rid
of that thing properly.
Right? And now look what's happened.
-Shut up.
-What, because you know I'm right?
No, really, shut up!
-Huh?
-Run!
Cyberbots!
RYAN: How did they get here?
GRAHAM: He's built an army of them!
No, no, more of them! We're trapped!
(PANTING)
-(WEAPONS POWERING UP)
-(GASPS)
Duck!
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
-RYAN: Thank me later.
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BOTH WHIMPER)
Hi.
WOMAN: Who are you?
DOCTOR: I'm no one.
But I have something
you might be interested in.
Where is the object?
Never talk in the face of a gun.
Point of principle. Please put it down.
It's going to be like that, is it?
Fine.
I've attached
a couple of explosive devices
to your object here on my back.
So shoot and you jeopardise
whatever this thing is.
And what is it?
Come on! Share with the class.
Where is Paltraki?
I'm not answering your questions
if you don't answer mine.
Are his other two crew members
still alive?
Yes.
See, that wasn't so hard.
And good. Thank you.
Why didn't you stop that woman
from being killed?
What's your name?
I am Andinio of the Ux.
Are you kidding, the Ux?
As in the duo species?
Only ever two of you?
Lifespan of millennia?
Only found on three planets
in the whole universe.
I've never met an Ux.
Congratulations, it must be so cool.
Wait, there's something else.
Oh, I can't remember.
What happened here, Andinio?
Make sense of it for me.
The battle zone outside?
They came for the Creator.
We defended him.
(GASPS) I've remembered.
Wait.
Is this yours, this building?
Is it true about the Ux?
Faith-driven dimensional engineers.
Is that why the building feels alive?
This is our shrine.
It feels like an energy
running through it.
Surrender the object and go.
-(WEAPON POWERING UP)
-You have until the count of three.
Show him my face.
What?
Let him see my face.
Your "Creator."
(ENERGY PULSING)
TZIM-SHA: Bring her to me.
But...
How can he know you?
PALTRAKI: Greston.
My first name is Greston.
Just remembered. Memories reconnecting.
What about where you're from?
Stebble.
"Stebble"?
What about you?
-Earth.
-(SCOFFS)
-What kind of a word is that?
-It's better than Stebble, mate.
-Do you have a home there?
-Beautiful home.
Some land
and animals.
Too many facts coming back. It's like
a flood. I don't know
what's important, or...
We were the last fleet.
When the others didn't come back,
they sent for us.
Who sent you?
Why did you come?
The Congress of the Nine Planets
in response to the atrocities.
Which were what?
YASMIN: Cyberbots!
(GASPS) Nice shot.
They have an army of those things.
-Why do you call him the Creator?
-ANDINIO: Our faith
is handed down.
The Creator is the cornerstone.
You're the first to see him.
We are the blessed generation.
Wait, there's only ever two of you.
Where's the other one?
I don't have to answer
all these questions.
That's what my teachers used to say,
usually just as they quit teaching.
I've got so many questions, Andinio,
because there's a battlefield outside
where many people died,
but you're no warrior.
And your words are certain,
but your eyes are full of doubt.
How can you know him?
Yes, how can I?
(DEVICES BEEPING)
Here.
It's here.
YASMIN: More of those mineral samples.
PALTRAKI: Five in total.
I remember.
We landed and fought our way here.
Even though the planet
was playing with our minds,
we never believed any of this
was possible.
But it was.
What is that stuff inside them?
Why is everyone fighting over it?
RYAN: Are you sure it's in here?
GRAHAM: I'm not sure about anything.
But this is where the signals
are telling us to go.
RYAN: What do you reckon these are?
GRAHAM: Not a clue.
(BOTH GASP)
(PANTING)
GRAHAM: It's one of Paltraki's crew.
How do we get her out?
We've got to help her.
See if I can find some light.
One of these panels got to do something.
(DEVICES POWERING UP)
-Hey, that's it, you've got it.
-Ryan, look.
(SIGHS)
RYAN: There's more through here.
What do we do?
We only came to rescue two people.
There's dozens in there.
How are we going to get them all out?
(MACHINE THUDDING)
(MACHINE DEPRESSURISING)
You look in a bad way.
Whereas, I've got a new coat.
What do you think?
Ready him. There will be a new target.
DOCTOR: Ready who? For what?
I said, "Ready him."
Whatever the Creator wills.
Out.
Don't worry, I'll look after him.
Tim Shaw. How long has it been?
Three thousand, four hundred
and seven years.
I bet the seven really dragged.
So what happened to you?
(HELMET DEPRESSURISING)
You did.
You corrupted my recall device,
banishing me across the universe
to this desolate rock
for the rest of my existence.
Unable to leave without dying.
This was my curse
for failure.
Or so I thought.
I arrived on the verge of death,
wracked by the DNA bombs.
DOCTOR: But you got more
than you possibly could have wished for.
The Ux.
The universe provides.
You wanted to be a leader.
Now you're worshipped as a false god.
Why all the ships outside?
What have you made them do?
(TZIM-SHA CACKLES)
Do you know what the Ux are capable of?
I carry the entire hive knowledge
of the Stenza civilisation within me.
Paired with the abilities of the Ux.
They were happy to work for me.
Work at what?
(GASPS AND CHOKES)
(ROARS)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(HISSING)
What every living creature wishes for.
(SIGHS)
Revenge.
(EXHALES)
Two codebreakers, 30 chambers.
-How much time do you reckon we've got?
-Not enough.
What's bothering me
is how do we know these chambers
aren't set to kill the people
if they're tampered with?
Because you know how sick
that creature is.
It still doesn't give you an excuse
to go after him.
Look at the people in here,
it totally proves my point.
They're trained soldiers
and they couldn't beat him
and you still think you can take him?
Oh, yeah? And why do you care
all of a sudden?
According to you, I was never
good enough for your nan anyway!
I said that a long time ago, Granddad.
Yeah, and I've been waiting
too long for that and all.
Maybe, but you've got it now.
(SIGHS)
We're family
and I love you.
-What did you just say?
-I'm not saying it twice.
Don't pretend you couldn't hear me
the first time.
I'm telling you
what she used to tell me.
Be the better man.
Please.
-(COMPUTER BLEEPING)
-Why is it doing that?
RYAN: Motion detector, maybe.
Do you think the robots shooting
each other set off an alarm?
I don't know.
When you say "revenge,"” revenge on who?
You, Doctor.
Oh, no, don't put this on me.
If you had not interfered
I would have become leader.
First of the Stenza.
And, yet, I should thank you.
Thank me, why?
You have made me a god.
You are nothing of the sort.
(SNARLS)
Now, tell me what this is.
Can't your puny mind understand?
YASMIN: Doctor, we found four more
of those objects.
What do you want us to do?
-(ALARM BLARING)
-DOCTOR: Bit busy at the moment, Yaz.
Someone's coming. Over here.
(DEVICES POWERING UP)
By the Creator's will.
Andinio, please!
Please, don't make me do this again.
We cannot understand the higher plan.
Our faith is all we have.
It's wrong.
DELPH: (GASPS) Please.
This cannot be right!
It'll destroy me.
It'll destroy both of us.
Andinio, please, don't!
(GASPS)
(ENERGY PULSING)
What are they doing?
What's happening?
What did you tell her to do?
Make who ready?
TZIM-SHA: It has taken
thousands of years.
Every fragment of scientific
understanding the Stenza ever possessed
allied to the impossible power
of the Ux.
You will see, Doctor,
I must be a god.
I have the powers of one.
Let me guess, they built you a weapon.
That's what your sort like to do.
Is that why all those ships came?
You made a weapon
and they came to stop you?
Presumably it's here.
Somewhere in this building.
Not in this building, Doctor.
This shrine is the weapon.
The Ux worked so hard to keep me alive.
And they're right to worship me.
I am unstoppable!
No one's unstoppable.
Run, tiny creature.
It will make no difference now.
The weapon is activated, Doctor.
The Stenza held people in stasis
as trophies.
But that was never the goal.
Our ultimate goal
was to hold civilisations.
They never found the way.
But I have.
You gave me my destiny.
(ENERGY WEAPON FIRES)
There, that should
hold them off for a bit.
I hope the Doc's
got everything under control.
I'm not getting a reply.
And we have to get these lot out.
(RUMBLING)
YASMIN: The objects,
why are they shaking?
PALTRAKI: I remember.
DOCTOR: Yaz!
What's happening?
(PANTING) Ooh.
Why are they doing that?
PALTRAKI: I remember what they did.
Five objects, five planets,
one weapon.
They stole five planets.
DOCTOR: Oh, no, no!
That's impossible.
PALTRAKI: It's what happened.
Entire planets removed
from their spatial orbit.
(GASPS)
That would've destroyed all life.
Planetary genocide!
Tim Shaw, I didn't like you then,
but now...
(STATIC)
Make them stop.
You're breaking every known
law of the universe.
I'm rewriting the laws
of the universe.
It doesn't work like that.
TZIM-SHA: Stenza technology
allied to the gift
of the Ux can create anything.
Every action has consequences.
And these are yours, Doctor.
I didn't mean it like that.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
I'm so annoyed.
The Ux!
They're creating a rift in space-time.
-(ENERGY PULSING)
-He's harnessed their powers.
(WHIRRING)
You don't understand anything right now.
All these planetary masses cannot
exist in the same place
at the same time.
The technology isn't stable.
You bring another through,
it could destroy everything.
TZIM-SHA: You're bluffing.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
He's one of those people
that really irritates me.
Can we not disconnect them?
He might kill them both if we disrupt it
or destroy this planet.
TZIM-SHA: The target, Doctor,
your responsibility.
You and your friends.
YASMIN: He's targeting Earth!
TZIM-SHA: The site of our first meeting.
Where this war began.
Any world which ever defied or opposed
the Stenza is now my target.
Even in exile, I shall lead.
(LAUGHS) We're in. It worked.
GRAHAM: Hurry up,
I can hear something outside the doors.
(WEAPON COCKS)
Ryan! Come on, son, we haven't got long.
Take my hand. It's okay, you're safe.
It's all right, it's all right.
Chuck us the code breaker, son.
(GRUNTS)
RYAN: We ain't gonna
get them all out in time.
(ALARM BLARING)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING INAUDIBLY)
(SNARLS)
(ALARM WAILING)
(CONNECTOR DEPRESSURISING)
(GROANS)
-(GROWLS)
-(CONNECTOR DEPRESSURISING)
(ROARS)
DOCTOR: Can't stop, but must stop it.
GRAHAM: We could do
with some help down here.
Got a few problems of our own, Graham.
I'll go.
This is Paltraki, I'm on my way.
DOCTOR: Get the hostages
back to your ship.
-Yaz, you go with him.
-No.
I'm with you, whatever happens.
We'll wait for you at the ship
for as long as we can.
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
GRAHAM: Everybody, get down,
they're coming through!
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
I still remember
how to take down robots,
luckily for you.
You found my crew. Thank you.
Nice entrance, by the way.
Now, get them back to your ship.
What about you?
-Oh, we've got a couple more to get out.
-Yeah.
GRAHAM: The codebreakers
take a while to work.
You're gonna have company.
Detonate this as they come through
and don't be long.
All right, this way.
The Ux, I've never met a race like them.
They can affect
the shape of the universe by thought.
All that power,
harnessed to Stenza tech.
Can't disconnect them,
it might kill them.
But, if we don't, what happens to Earth?
Their life versus seven billion others.
There must be a way.
There's always a way.
We're really clever.
What have we got? What can we use?
Us versus the Ux. Think.
If they're psychically generating
all this,
I could block the signals.
BOTH: Neural-balancers!
I could adjust the settings really easy,
make them neural-blockers.
No signals out or in.
Could be enough. Big risk.
If we take our balancers off,
put them on those two...
The planet will be able
to attack our minds.
Then I'll take that risk
to stop Earth being destroyed.
Yeah, good.
I mean, really good.
Except it doesn't solve our problem
with these.
They can't all be here.
We have to put them back in place.
It's too many things to do.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
One thing at a time. It's fine.
All good. Well, almost.
First things first.
-(WHIRRING)
-Ow!
(PANTING)
Take it easy, all right?
There you go.
Ryan, get him out of here!
I will not leave you behind.
I've got to stay here
to time the detonator
to stop them coming after us.
I'll be right behind you.
Promise.
Yeah, yeah, I promise. Go. Go!
Go on!
DOCTOR: Modified neural-balancer on.
Now, you, Yaz, gently does it.
(DEVICE WHIRRING)
Come on, block their signals.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
No! (PANTING)
What have you done?
This is the Creator's work!
No, it isn't.
That creature took advantage
of your faith.
How could he recognise me, Andinio?
We've met before.
He's an exile from a warrior race
called the Stenza.
When we met, he was killing people
for no reason
on the planet he wants you to destroy.
But the Ux had been waiting for him.
For generations!
He is my truth.
He was our truth.
That creature is a lie.
And he debased you and your faith.
Don't you see, you were the creators!
Look what you can do!
You build.
But he made you destroyers.
That's no god. I'm sorry.
Doctor, something's happening
to the containers.
DOCTOR: Oh, no,
I thought this might happen.
These planets cannot be contained
any longer,
else the damage will be colossal.
Yippee ki-yay, robots.
-(EXPLOSION)
-(GROANS)
Too much to do, not enough time.
Oh, no, that's bad.
The mass is returning.
I can't lift it any more.
But the planets need to be returned
to the exact place in the universe
where they came from.
Can you do it? Can you return them?
-It's possible.
-It would take time.
Which we don't have.
(GROANS)
Oh, my head!
It's getting fuzzy.
-How do we do this?
-Argh!
DOCTOR: What have we got left?
Ooh, one possibility.
(PANTING) You two, this set-up...
Us... What else?
Oh!
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Aligned to Stenza power.
Enough for a short-range dog whistle.
Might work. Please work.
Universe, provide for me.
I'm working really hard
to keep you together
-right now.
-(WHIRRING)
-(WHOOSHING)
-What's that noise?
Tim Shaw might have a shrine,
but I've got a ghost monument.
You can do it. It's not far.
Zero in on my summons.
(METALLIC FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
TZIM-SHA: You should run.
Sorry, Ryan.
(WEAPON POWERING UP)
All right, keep going.
Catch up with them!
(PANTING)
Come on, Graham. Waiting now.
Keep going.
My wife died because of you.
Good.
I swore if I ever saw you again,
I'd kill you.
And yet, you falter.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRS)
-DOCTOR: Remote summons.
It's locking on. Got it!
What is that?
(PANTING)
You're not the only ones
who can conjure stuff out of nothing.
Do you mind if we get those back?
Bit headachey now.
(NEURAL-BALANCER BUZZES)
Yaz, come on.
Cables, in the portal. Big thick ones.
Drag them out. You and Andinio
loop them into the systems.
-(GROANS)
-DOCTOR: Very fast.
If we can extend
the dematerialisation field
by three metres,
then split the field...
I must be able to split the field.
They're only tiny and I'm clever.
Oi, Ux,
get in here!
DOCTOR: I know this will be
way beyond your comprehension.
Dimensionally transcendental.
Now, get the cables with Yaz
and lock them into the systems.
Delph, come here.
What are you going to do?
Telepathic circuits.
If it can work for your nani's watch,
it can work for that clever lad.
You brought all these things here.
You have all the coordinates
in your head.
The fastest way is to read what's
in your mind and send them back fast,
but keeping us here.
(PANTING)
Their knowledge, their abilities,
Tim Shaw's tech, our blue box.
We'll lash together
every resource we've got.
Sort of like a super group,
best elements of everyone.
(CONSOLE BLEEPS)
Clear?
Not in the least.
Will it work?
No idea, but I once towed your planet
halfway across the universe
with this TARDIS,
and turned a Slitheen back into an eqg.
So, let's give it a go.
(CRACKING)
You are no warrior.
No.
(WEAPON POWERING DOWN)
I'm the better man.
(SNARLS)
-You are weak and feeble.
-RYAN: Tim Shaw,
-don't diss me granddad, ever.
-(TZIM-SHA SNARLS)
(GROANS)
Hey, you shot him!
Yeah, but just the foot.
Just in... Just in the foot.
Just to shut him up.
Ah, don't tell the Doc, she'd be livid.
-(PANTING AND SNARLS)
-(WEAPON POWERING UP)
Shut up!
And stop with that hand thing.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
What do we do now?
DOCTOR: I know this will be painful.
I wouldn't put you through this
if I could think
of any other way right now.
-It's okay.
-DOCTOR: It's not.
But thank you.
Ready?
ANDINIO: May the will
of the true Creator give me strength.
Ready!
-(EXPLOSION)
-(SCREAMS)
-(DELPH SCREAMING)
-Please, please, please,
no back-up plan.
(YELPS)
I'm sorry, Delph.
(STRAINING)
(SCREAMING)
YASMIN: Stay strong, Andinio.
ANDINIO: Our faith
will survive deception.
My service to the creator
must never be known.
It's working!
Possibly.
-(DELPH SCREAMING)
-Just hold...
Keep at it, all of you!
ANDINIO: We are the Ux.
We are the blessed two.
Our faith wins. Our faith restores.
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-(SIGHS)
-DOCTOR: Delph.
GRAHAM: You brought us all together.
You ain't gonna tear us apart.
You ain't worth killing.
But you can have a taste
of your own medicine.
We're not weak, we're strong
and we sentence you to life.
So, as you're contemplating eternity,
keep one name on your mind.
BOTH: Grace.
(TZIM-SHA GROWLING)
(GROWLS)
(PANTING)
You did it!
You did it, Delph!
Oh, did... Did it work?
You are a couple of awesome Ux.
Thank you.
Praise the true Creator's will.
We are the blessed few.
(DOOR OPENING)
(CHUCKLES)
You ain't half made a mess in here.
Where's Tim Shaw?
Oh, he's taking a very long nap
in a very small stasis chamber.
Of his own making.
-I like that. (CHUCKLES)
-Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, I couldn't do it, Doc.
Yeah, I had the chance... Too weak.
Graham O'Brien,
you're the strongest person I know.
Well, one of a few.
(WIND HOWLING)
PALTRAKI: What about that creature?
ANDINIO: We sealed the building
as we left.
No one can get to him.
I'm sorry for the way he betrayed you.
We can take these people home,
save you the job.
No, I'm going to complete my mission.
-Then take us, too.
-Delph.
This is our home. We must stay here.
No.
We need to understand what's out there.
Find another home.
You'll have to sleep on the floor.
I walked this planet for decades.
Floors are fine.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Where will you go, now?
(EXHALES SHARPLY) No idea.
Come on, fam.
I thought we weren't doing "fam."
I like it.
None of us know for sure
what's out there.
That's why we keep looking.
Keep your faith.
Travel hopefully.
The universe will surprise you.
Constantly.
(CREAKING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Here's a new year message
for you to send...
Earth is protected by me and my mates
this year and every other.