Police, please.
(TREMBLING) Hello?
Yes.
I know who did it.
-Who did it all.
-(SOFT HISSING)
I figured it out.
No. No, I can't speak up.
They might hear me.
Oh, no.
-Oh, no. Listen.
-(FAINT RIPPLING)
Listen.
They are everywhere.
All around.
(LOUD BUZZING)
We've been so blind.
(SCREAMS)
WOMAN: (ON PHONE) Hello? Sir?
Are you in a safe place?
Are you being held against your will?
Sir?
(BUZZING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
You could leave all that stuff
here, you know.
We do have literally acres of room.
Oh, no. It's all right.
Danny"s got a little bit territorial.
The idea of me leaving
so much as a toothbrush here...
But still, he's all right
with us doing this,
which I admit's a little bit weird.
'Cause you'd think if he had a problem
with me leaving stuff in the Tardis
he'd object to me travelling
in the Tardis but he's not, so...
Sorry, stopped listening a while ago.
Okay.
Uh, same time you left,
same place...ish.
Ish?
Don't give me an "ish".
These readings are very, um...
ish-y.
(BEEPING)
(PINGING)
(POWER FLUCTUATING)
Um, Doctor?
Uh-huh?
(GRUNTING)
Well...
Well, I wonder what caused this?
I don't think we're bigger, are we?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Bristol? Doctor, we're in Bristol!
And 120 miles from where we should be.
Impressive!
No, not impressive, annoying.
No, this is impressive.
This is annoying.
The Tardis never does this.
This is huge!
Well, not literally huge,
slightly smaller than usual,
which is huge.
Yes, I get it. You're excited.
When can I go home?
Your house isn't going anywhere.
But then neither is mine
until I get this figured out.
Could you not just let me enjoy
this moment of not knowing something?
I mean, it happens so rarely.
Uh, look.
I don't think this is dangerous
but I wouldn't like you
to get squished accidentally.
Anyway, I need you to help me
find out what's caused this.
Fine.
I'll go and take a look around.
FENTON: It's your filth, Rigsy.
Start with your signature.
Oh, come on, there's no need for this.
FENTON: There you go.
Get on with it.
This is community service,
not a holiday camp.
-(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
-(MACHINE BEEPING)
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-(THUDDING)
-(ALARM BLARING)
Now, that wasn't me, was it?
Oh, that can't be good.
Cheer up, love. Might never happen.
Have some respect. She's grieving.
Oh, sorry, love.
I didn't mean nothing by it.
Sorry about them. They're idiots.
Oh, that's all right, don't worry.
I've heard worse.
I've, er, lost someone, too.
My Aunt Karina.
Deaf as a post.
Didn't really know her that well
but she's still gone.
-Is your one in the mural?
-Oh, no. I haven't actually...
I'm sure they'll get around
to it at some point.
I'm not really with that lot out there,
I just have to do this
community service thing.
I just do graffiti.
Not anything, you know, murdery or...
(CHUCKLES)
So, um, what's all this about?
What's happened to all these people?
You mean, you don't know?
CLARA: Hey, I think
I've found something.
People are missing all over the estate.
-Do you think there's a connection?
-Could be.
And where are you?
-Exactly where I was.
-No, you're not.
I'm here and I can't see...
Oh.
Yes, "oh".
(GIGGLING)
Oh, my God, that is so adorable.
Are you in there?
Yes, I am. And no, it's not adorable.
It's very, very serious.
So, is this more shrink-ray stuff?
Are you tiny in there?
No.
I'm exactly the same size.
It's merely the exterior
dimensions that have changed.
(LAUGHS)
Stop laughing, this is serious.
Well, I can't help it, can I?
With you and your big old face.
-How are you going to get out?
-Well, plainly I can't.
Something nearby is
leeching all the external dimensions.
-Aliens?
-Possibly.
Oh, who am I kidding? Probably.
Sensors are down and I can't risk
taking off with it in this state.
Clara, I need you
to pick up the Tardis.
Carefully. It should be possible.
I've adjusted the relative gravity...
You mean, you've made it lighter?
Clara, it's always lighter.
If the Tardis were to land
with its true weight,
it would fracture
the surface of the Earth.
CLARA: Yeah, maybe a story
for another time. What now?
I've managed to get a rough fix on
the source of the dimensional leaching.
It's roughly northwest. That way.
Please don't do that.
That's just wrong.
Now, listen!
You're going to need these.
Oh, wow!
This is an honour.
Does this mean I'm you now?
No, it does not!
So don't get any ideas.
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
And listen, stick this in your ear.
-Can you hear me?
-Yeah.
-Ow! What just happened?
-Nanotech.
-Just hacked your optic nerve.
-What does that mean?
I see what you see.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Anything?
-Yes, I'm dizzy.
But nothing useful.
-You never did tell me your name.
-No time to fraternise.
-Come on, get rid of him.
-CLARA: I'm, um...
-I'm the Doctor.
-Don't you dare.
Doctor Oswald. (CLEARS THROAT)
But you can call me Clara.
I'm Rigsy.
-So, uh, what are you a doctor of?
-Of lies.
Well, I'm usually
quite vague about that.
I think I just picked the title
'cause it makes me sound important.
Why, Doctor Oswald, you are hilarious.
Could we get back to work,
do you think?
What are you, exactly?
You don't smell like police
but that's some pretty cool gear
you got there.
You like a spy or something?
-Oh, he's a bright one, hang on to him.
-Hmm.
RIGSY: He was the
last one to go missing.
And when he disappeared,
all the doors and windows were locked.
From the inside.
DOCTOR: Oh, now you're talking.
I love a good locked room mystery.
-Yeah, doesn't everyone?
-What?
Huh? Oh, sorry.
I'm talking to somebody else.
He's listening in.
Doctor, Rigsy. Rigsy, Doctor.
-Hello, barely sentient local.
-Another doctor?
How do you sleep at night?
Missing people. Tiny Tardis.
What's the link?
RIGSY: I think this is great that
someone's finally looking into this.
The police won't do anything.
They never do on this estate.
People were thinking that...
no one was listening.
That no one cared.
RIGSY: So, yeah. I think
it's great what you're doing.
Clara, look, I think that we can
manage on our own from now on.
Yeah, well, I think
he could still be useful.
He's a pudding brain. Worse than that,
he's a fluorescent pudding brain.
Okay. Fine. And all those
other missing people,
I suppose you know where they lived?
-(WHIRRING)
-He could still be in the room.
-Sorry, what?
-(LAUGHS)
Sorry, nothing.
I was just thinking out loud.
It's like one of those locked room
things you get in books.
It's always something weird, like...
Like he's still in the room
or something.
RIGSY: Do you want to go and
check out another flat?
You know, I think that you were
wrong about this lad.
I think that he could be very useful.
Vital local knowledge.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah, so try not to scare him off.
How would I scare him off?
(SCREEN BUZZING)
Maybe he's lost in
the desert or something.
Okay, right, are we
missing something here?
Missing man. Locked room. Shrink ray.
-Sorry, did you just say shrink ray?
-What if
he is still in this room,
like you said, only tiny?
You know, like,
underneath the sofa or something.
Clara, this is the scaring off
that we were talking about.
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY) Okay. So, uh..
(STAMMERING) My...
My lunch break's nearly up.
This... This has been, uh...
interesting.
Clara, Local Knowledge is leaving.
Do something!
Rigsy! One sec.
-Doctor, open the doors.
-I didn't mean that!
Look, you want him to stay or not?
-(SIGHS)
-(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
You really do throw your companions
in at the deep end, don't you?
Rigsy, come here.
Meet the Doctor.
(CHUCKLES)
-So what do you think, tiny man idea?
-Yes, it's a lovely thought.
Which is why I set the sonic to
scan for that as soon as we entered.
-Pleased to meet you.
-And you didn't think to tell me?
Well, of course he might
have been squashed
under a policeman's shoe by now.
It's bigger. On the inside.
You know, I don't think
that statement's ever been truer.
What are you, like, aliens or something?
No.
Well, he is.
-(ALARM BLARING)
-CLARA: Doctor?
-(LOUD HISSING)
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Doctor, did you hear that?
-Yes.
Whatever it was, it just drained
a massive amount of energy
from inside the Tardis.
-CLARA: What was it?
-I don't know.
That's the least of my problems,
just get us out of there.
Okay. Go. Rigsy?
This is where we run. Stick with me.
(CLARA GRUNTS)
I mean, this is just embarrassing.
I'm from the race that built the Tardis.
Dimensions are kind of our thing.
So why can't I understand this?
Clara, I need more info.
Where else have people disappeared?
-MI5?
-Yes, this case has got our attention.
Well, you've come to
the right place, ma'am.
First reported disappearance,
a Mr Heath.
It's not on the estate but it's
exactly the same MO as the rest.
Clara, I think that your
shrink ray theory was wrong.
My shrink ray theory?
I thought you were
already scanning for that.
Doctor, what are you doing?
Well, it just struck me.
Locked room mysteries.
Classic solution number one,
they're still in the room.
Classic solution number two,
they're in the walls.
What do you mean, they're in the...
PC FORREST: Have we done
as much as we could? No.
Do we have any suspects? No.
Off the record, I think the top
brass are hoping if they ignore this,
it'll all just go away.
Apparently, they're in the walls.
-(RIGSY GRUNTING
-(MOBILE RINGING)
PC Forrest.
Yes, sir. MI5, sir.
So, you and that bloke in a box.
Do you do this sort of stuff a lot?
Oh, well, he's usually
out of the box but yeah.
I don't know.
Maybe they thought
we weren't doing enough, sir.
(FAINT RIPPLING)
Can I call you back?
RIGSY: So how'd you get this gig?
Did you, like, study science
or aliens or something?
(LAUGHING) No.
Well, it's kind of
more of a right place, right time
or wrong place, wrong time,
depending on how he's behaving.
DOCTOR:
I can hear you, you know.
(RIPPLING)
PC FORREST: Ma'am?
There's something in here, I think.
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
PC Forrest?
Hello?
Doctor, she's gone.
What am I missing?
The Tardis should be able to detect
anything in the known universe.
The known universe.
This universe.
Clara, wait, go back.
Back, back back! That mural.
That is a nervous system.
Scaled up and flattened.
I think we've found PC Forrest.
What's left of her, at least.
Her nervous system?
The mural in the flat.
That wasn't a desert at all.
It's a microscopic blow-up
of human skin.
What?
-Why?
-Whatever they are,
they are... They are experimenting.
They're testing. They are...
They are dissecting.
Trying to understand us.
Trying to understand...three dimensions!
(HISSING)
Ahh! The handle.
Doctor, the handle.
They've flattened the handle.
Fascinating!
Clara, they're in the walls!
(RIPPLING)
Keep away from them,
if they touch you, you're finished.
What happens if they touch us?
-(HISSING)
-I really don't want to find out.
-They can't jump, can they?
-(MOBILE RINGING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hey, you!
I've got our bench.
Did you get held up?
Um... Just a little.
Sorry, Danny.
I think lunch is, um, a bust.
Oh, hon, you're missing some
classic park action.
Clara, the window!
Look! Look! They're climbing the walls!
-(LOUD BUZZING)
-DANNY: Who was that?
Um, that's just a guy on community
support and I'm helping him...
find his auntie.
Nice. Not technically lying.
-(CLARA PANTING)
-Sounds, um, kind of active.
Um, yeah.
Um, there was a thing, um, a thing...
Where are you and are you in trouble?
Uh... No, no, no. I'm fine!
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-(LOUD CRASHING)
-Clara?
(CLARA AND RIGSY SCREAMING)
-(GLASS BREAKING)
-Danny?
-(CAR ALARM BLARING)
-What's happening?
-Uh, er, not much.
Just some nonsense.
-Long story.
-What story?
Uh, tell you later. Love you!
This explains everything.
They're from a universe
with only two dimensions.
And yes, that is a thing!
It's long been theorised, of course,
but no one could go there and prove
its existence without a heck of a diet.
And what long story
are you going to tell Danny, huh?
-Or haven't you made it up yet?
-Sorry, what? What was that?
Excellent lying, Dr Oswald.
Yeah?
Well, I thought
it was pretty weak myself.
I meant to me.
You told me that Danny was okay with
you being back on board the Tardis.
Well, he is.
Yeah, because he doesn't
know anything about it.
-Doctor...
-Congratulations.
-Lying is a vital survival skill.
-Well, there you go.
And a terrible habit.
-(FEEDBACK SCREECHING)
-Doctor, you're breaking up a bit.
(DISTORTED) Yeah, of course I am.
No, really, you are, I can't hear you.
What?
Oh, right, blowing out that window's
possibly affected the earpiece.
-Take it out and sonic it.
-Doing it.
Hey!
They can't do that. Hey!
-What are you doing?
-Our job.
You're on report, by the way.
Late back from lunch.
Does it even still count as lying if
you're doing it for somebody's own good?
-Well, like, technically their own good.
-(WHIRRING)
(BLOWS)
It's a memorial!
Council didn't approve it,
it's graffiti. Stan?
(RIGSY GRUNTING)
Oh.
Look, Clara. Talk to me! Talk to me!
RIGSY:
What are you doing?
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
Clara, the mural!
Clara, it's the mural!
Over there! Look! The mural!
We've found the missing people.
They're in the walls!
-What do I do?
-Act normal.
But get everyone out.
They're very realistic.
Who painted them?
RIGSY: I don't know. A local artist.
Probably a grieving relative.
CLARA:
Did you ever meet them?
Or did they just appear after
people disappeared?
And who are you
when you're at home, love?
Health & Safety. This subway is unsafe.
Everyone needs to leave right now.
This is blank. Try again, sweetheart.
BOTH: What?
It takes quite a lack of imagination
to beat psychic paper.
Stan, do your job.
Clara, stop him!
(STAN YELLS)
-GEORGE: Stan!
-(RIPPLING)
What is this? What are they?
DOCTOR: They're wearing the dead
like camouflage.
CLARA: Forget Stan. Your friend's gone.
Clara, get them out of there!
We need to move. Now.
(LOUD BUZZING AND RIPPLING)
Did they follow us?
'Cause I didn't see them follow us.
Are we safe?
Are we really hiding
from killer graffiti?
Oh, this is insane.
I agree. We'll have to think of
a better name for them than that.
I mean, Stan was one of them.
Flattened, dead.
-But coming after us.
-Clara, this is a vital stage.
This little group is currently
confused and disorientated
but pretty soon,
a leader is going to emerge.
You need to make sure
that leader is you.
I'm on it.
George! George, isn't it?
Can you watch that area?
You hear anything, anything moves,
you shout, okay?
He will do no such thing
till I get some answers.
Who are you?
That's what I want to know.
Impersonating a government official.
Trespassing on council property.
-Seriously?
-Seriously.
Fine.
I'll tell you who I am.
I am the one chance you've got
of staying alive.
That's who I am.
Well done.
Rigsy, how well do you know this area?
Do you know where that door leads?
It's the old Brunswick line.
But it's not safe.
Yeah, well, there's safe
and there's safe.
Yeah, I know it. I used to
go down there all the time.
Yeah, I'll bet you did.
-Painting your filth.
-Yeah, well, you might be glad he did.
Those things come in here,
that is our only way out.
I just hope I can keep them all alive.
Ha, welcome to my world.
So what's next, Doctor Clara?
-Lie to them.
-What?
Lie to them.
Give them hope.
Tell them they're all going to be fine.
-Isn't that what you would do?
-In a manner of speaking.
It's true that people with hope
tend to run faster,
whereas people
who think they're doomed...
Dawdle. End up dead.
So that's what I sound like?
Who's she talking to?
He says it's MI5.
Right, here's something
that might help you.
Do you remember the graffiti
from the estate?
Footprints? Tyre treads?
-Vaguely.
-Well, I don't think it was graffiti.
I think that
that is how those creatures saw us.
The impressions we make
in two-dimensional space.
That was them reaching out,
attempting to talk.
At which point, they moved into
flattening and dissection.
Trying to understand.
Trying to emulate.
But here's the big question.
Do they know they're hurting us?
So, what, you think this is all
one big misunderstanding?
That's a very good question.
Why don't we ask them?
(FEEDBACK WHINING)
DOCTOR: We need to find
a way to communicate.
Why can't the Tardis just translate?
Because their idea of language
is just as bizarre
as their idea of space.
Even the Tardis is confused.
FENTON: This is a bad idea.
What makes this colleague of yours
think those monsters even want to talk?
I know a race made of sentient gas
who throw fireballs as a friendly wave.
I know another race with 64 stomachs
who talk to each other
by disembowelling.
-He's got a hunch.
-My point being
that in a universe as immense
and bizarre as this one,
you cannot be too quick to judge.
Perhaps these creatures
don't even understand
that we need
three dimensions to live in.
(GRUNTS) They may not even know
that they're hurting us.
-Do you really believe that?
-No. I really hope that.
Would have made a nice change,
wouldn't it?
Okay.
Let's start with pi.
Even in a flat world,
they would have circles.
I don't mean edible pie,
I mean circular pi.
Which I realise would also
mean edible pie but anyway.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BEEPING)
(WARBLING THROUGH SPEAKER)
They're responding.
The Tardis is translating now.
It's a number.
-Fifty-five.
-Fifty-five?
-What does that mean?
-Tenth Fibonacci number.
-Atomic number of caesium.
-RIGSY: I know what it means.
We all have numbers on our jackets.
Have to sign them out.
That was the number on Stan's jacket,
the man they found in the subway.
-They're gloating.
-We don't know that.
I mean, it could be an apology,
for all we know.
GEORGE: Really? That's nice of them.
-An apology? Are you seriously...
-(CHITTERING ON SPEAKER)
-Shh, shh, shh. Listen.
-(CHITTERING CONTINUES)
Wait.
DOCTOR: Two-two. 22.
Twenty-two.
That's George.
Looks like your number's up, George.
-Now they're threatening.
-Maybe.
Or maybe they're showing us
they can read.
Oh, grow up. They're picking targets.
-Of course you'd see it that way.
-What do you mean by that?
-CLARA: George?
-Everyone's out to get you, aren't they?
-Well, in this case, they kind of are.
-(SCOFFS)
Clara, be careful.
(RIPPLING)
The tunnel!
CLARA: (PANTING)
Doctor, they've got George.
-I know. I did see.
-What now?
Give me a minute. I'm working on it.
Another flat handle.
They were here.
Not now.
They've stopped chasing us, I think.
-It feels like they're cornering us.
-You can't apply human logic.
You're dealing with creatures
from another dimension.
That's three exits
all blocked by those creatures.
Rigsy, where's the next exit?
The only other one I can think of
is where the old line joins the new.
But it's a fair walk. Getting through
that door would be quicker.
-But we can't, can we?
-I'm just saying.
Clara, I might be able to help
with that door.
Give me five minutes.
It's one of mine. Do you like it?
Yeah. Not bad.
So, this thing
that you've been working on?
I think I've figured out a way
to restore three dimensions.
At least on a small scale,
say a door handle.
So what's that, then? A de-flattener?
We're not calling it a de-flattener.
This should be able to
restore dimensions.
-You see what I called it?
-"2-D-is."
-"Two-dee-iss"?
-No, "two-diss"!
It's called the 2Dis!
Why do I even bother?
Well, give it a go, then.
(PULSATING)
Hmm.
Long way round it is.
-(MACHINERY HUMMING)
-(ALARM BLARING)
Clara, I don't know how
but they're doing it again,
they're leaching the Tardis!
How? Your doors are closed.
They've changed frequency.
This time it's different.
Listen! The Doctor thinks
we might be in trouble.
He thinks they might be close.
-Where, exactly?
-I don't know. He's not sure.
He's getting readings all around.
Oh, well, that's just great.
Sounds important
but means absolutely nothing.
Can you tell your friend...
(SCREAMING)
Of course. The next stage.
3D!
(RIPPLING)
RIGSY: Run!
Doctor? The door.
The handle's flattened.
I've boosted the output.
-And it will work this time?
-Absolutely.
(PULSATING)
Clara, stop! Use it again.
It can reverse the process.
RIGSY:
There's a ladder at the end of this.
We get down into the tunnel,
we can make it into daylight.
-Hang on! Hang on...
-(PULSATING)
FENTON: If it's flat,
we're safe now, aren't we?
RIGSY: They can't get
through, can they?
Wait.
(CRACKLING)
They have a new ability.
Of course they have.
Now they're 3D,
they can restore dimensions.
Clara, do you want the
good news or the bad news?
(SHOUTING) We're in the bad news!
I'm living the bad news!
The good news is I've come up with
a theoretical way to send them
-back to their own dimension.
-Do it! Now!
That's the bad news.
The Tardis doesn't have enough
dimensional energy to pull it off.
Great. What do you want
me to do about it?
Well, apparently,
these things can now pump it out
as fast as they can steal it.
Maybe if I ask them really nicely,
they'll fill you up again. Hey!
-Give me that machine! Hand it over!
-Doctor!
(ALARMS BLARING)
Hello? Doctor?
Look, can we please
deal with this later?
Because we need to move.
(RIPPLING)
Doctor! Doctor,
I dropped you down a hole.
-Where are you?
-I don't know.
(FLICKING SWITCHES)
My shields have gone!
Structural integrity is failing.
Another blow like that and I've had it.
Uh...
I'm on the train lines.
And there's a train coming.
Of course there is.
Short-term rematerialisation?
Not enough power.
Teleport? Not enough power.
Re-route the heart
of the Tardis through...
Not enough power! Not enough power!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
-Look, can't you move the Tardis?
-Clara, there is no power.
The Tardis couldn't
boil an egg at the moment.
Listen, do what you can
to get those people out of there.
You're stronger than you know.
I wonder what they're like with ladders?
No, I mean you, move the Tardis.
Like, Addams Family.
(DOCTOR STRAINING)
(TRAIN ENGINE ROARING)
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
Ha! (SCATTING)
(RUMBLING)
(ROARING INTENSIFIES)
(GROANING)
Doctor?
They'd be here if they were coming,
where are they?
There's no other way down, right?
Hey! I'm talking to you.
-There is.
-(FAINT HISSING)
An old service elevator
near the mouth of the tunnel.
CLARA: We should go.
Oh, no.
(RIPPLING)
And there's another train coming.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLARING)
(WHIRRING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
I don't know if you can still
hear me out there
but the Tardis is now in siege mode.
No way in, no way out.
I managed to turn it on
just before the train hit.
But there's not enough power
left now to turn it off.
What's going on?
Why the red light?
MI5. We've got a, uh...
Blockage. In the tunnel.
Can we ram the...blockage?
-The train's empty, isn't it?
-(FAINT RIPPLING)
CONDUCTOR:
Yeah, it's out of service but...
Well, you need someone
to hold the dead man's handle.
Won't run without it. Is this official?
Because I've always wanted
to ram something.
Can we rig it to drive without that?
Send it in with no driver?
-(STEAM HISSING)
-(ENGINE STARTING)
Rigsy!
Uh, what are you doing?
Look, I'm going to ram them,
buy you some time.
-You'll die.
-Yeah, course I'll die.
-Now, go!
-Well, why do you want to do that?
Just go, okay? Let me do this.
Okay, fine. Yeah.
And I'll always remember you.
Fine. Yeah, great.
'Cause I was just going to do this.
No driver required.
And I really like that hairband.
But I suppose I'll just take it, will I?
And every time I look at it,
I'll always remember
the hero who died to save it.
Come on.
You're not getting off that lightly,
there's work that needs doing.
(RIGSY GRUNTS)
(CLARA GRUNTING)
(CRASHING)
I quite liked that hairband.
(RIPPLING)
RIGSY: What is it?
I think it's the Tardis.
(RIPPLING)
CONDUCTOR:
They wear your skin?
FENTON: I never thought
I'd say this, this is insane,
but I think I preferred them
when they were flat.
What do you mean, flat?
Doctor?
(RADIO STATIC)
What would you do now?
No. What will I do now?
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay. The last thing the Doctor said
was that the Tardis needed energy.
He said if it gets energy,
he can beat them.
No, no, no. What are you doing?
(RATTLING)
Leave her. She's lost it.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, are you?
I think I will be. What's this?
Come on, Graffiti Boy,
I've got a commission for you.
-I'm flattered but I don't think this...
-Well, fine,
if you don't think you're up to it.
What do you need, exactly?
You're going to get us killed.
This plan's insane.
You want to walk, walk.
You want to stay, then, shush!
-CONDUCTOR: They're coming!
-(RIPPLING)
(RIPPLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Life support failing.
I don't know if you'll ever
hear this, Clara.
I don't even know
if you're still alive out there.
(CRACKLING)
DOCTOR: But you were good!
And you made a mighty fine Doctor.
It's not working. You've killed us all.
This is going to save us?
Pumping energy into the wall?
No. Not into the wall,
through the wall.
Rule number one of being the Doctor,
use your enemy's power against them.
(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
CLARA: They can't restore three
dimensions to a door that never existed.
(TARDIS POWERING UP)
(COUGHING)
(BEEPING)
(FLICKING SWITCHES)
(FAINT WHOOSHING)
(WHOOSHING)
It worked. (LAUGHS)
They charged the Tardis.
(PANTING) I tried to talk.
I want you to remember that.
I tried to reach out.
I tried to understand you but I think
that you understand us perfectly.
(ON LOUDSPEAKER)
And I think that you just don't care.
And I don't know
whether you are here to invade,
infiltrate or just replace us.
I don't suppose it really matters now.
You are monsters!
That is the role
you seem determined to play.
So it seems that I must play mine!
The man that stops the monsters.
I'm sending you back
to your own dimension.
Who knows? Some of you
may even survive the trip.
And if you do, remember this.
-You are not welcome here!
-(RIPPLING)
This plane is protected!
I am the Doctor!
And I name you the Boneless!
(BOOMING)
(WHOOSHING)
(CONDUCTOR SIGHS DEEPLY)
(CLARA CHUCKLES)
Hi, Mum.
It's me. Just listen.
CLARA: You all right?
CONDUCTOR: I'm alive.
And I've been inside that.
I think I'm up on the deal.
Come here.
Thank you.
DOCTOR: You look chipper.
-Do people still say "chipper"?
-Apparently.
-You okay?
-I'm alive.
And a lot of people died.
FENTON: It's like a forest fire,
though, innit?
The objective is to save the great
trees, not the brushwood. Am I right?
It wasn't a fire, those weren't trees,
those were people.
They were community-payback scumbags,
I wouldn't lose any sleep.
-I bet you won't.
-Good to be alive, though.
Thank you. Seriously, thank you.
Yes, a lot of people died and
maybe the wrong people survived.
-Yeah, but we saved the world, right?
-We did.
-You did.
-Okay, so on balance...
-On balance?
-Yeah, that's how you think, isn't it?
Largely so other people don't have to.
Yeah, well, I was you today.
I was the Doctor.
And apparently, I was quite good at it.
-You heard that, did you?
-Yeah.
But the power was going off,
so I suppose you were delirious.
You didn't know what you were saying.
Yes.
Ah! The return of the
fluorescent pudding brain!
-You do realise he can hear you now?
-I know.
Your last painting was so good,
it saved the world.
I can't wait to see what you do next.
(LAUGHS)
It's not going to be easy.
I've got a hairband to live up to.
-Thanks.
-Come here.
Admit it, I did well!
(MOBILE RINGING)
Is that PE?
-Just say it.
-(DOCTOR COUGHS)
Why can't you just say it?
Why can't you just say I did good?
-Talk to soldier-boy.
-It's not him.
Come on! Why can't you say it?
I was the Doctor and I was good.
You were an exceptional Doctor, Clara.
Thank you.
Goodness had nothing to do with it.
Clara. My Clara.
I have chosen well.
I think it's lovely.
(GROWLING)
COMPUTER:
You have reached your destination.
No, we haven't. We're supposed to be
in the middle of London.
-You have reached your destination.
-(WOLF HOWLING)
DOCTOR: Oh, stop staying that!
GIRL: She's only saying it
because it's true.
We are in the middle of London.
DOCTOR: We are in
the middle of a forest.
Come on, team, let's do this!
-We will, if you stop calling us a team.
-(LOW GROWLING)
-(PANTING)
-(ROARING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)