(SCREAMING)
They've kidnapped Osgood
and they've stolen
the location of every Zygon on Earth.
Doctor, the ceasefire
has broken down.
Call me now.
They turned into monsters
and they came for us.
We couldn't fight them.
You can't tell who's who.
Oh, come on. These are
eggs or pods or whatever.
Look.
Oh, my God, that's me.
But I don't see how
these are duplicates.
That's not how Zygons work.
These are the humans.
-Please.
-Kill the traitors.
There isn't any back-up,
is there?
(GROWLING)
UNIT neutralised in the UK.
More or less.
(BEEPS)
I'm sorry, but Clara's dead.
(BUZZING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
DOCTOR: Clara!
Clara!
BONNIE: You're breaking up!
DOCTOR:
The invasion has happened.
You're probably
surrounded by Zygons.
Get to the Tardis.
Get yourself safe.
Apparently, my plane
ls never going to land.
Well let's see
what we can do about that.
BONNIE:
I'm sorry, but Clara's dead.
(BEEPING)
Dream jets.
Dream jets, dream jets.
BONNIE:
It's your decision, Doctor.
Truth or consequences.
Doctor?
Missed!
(GRUNTING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(BUZZING)
(PANTING)
(BOTH GROANING)
Oh!
(THUMPING ON DOOR)
(GASPING)
-I know what you are.
-(GASPS)
Please, please.
I'm going to set you free.
(PANTING)
Humans cannot accept
the way we really are.
If we cannot hide,
we must fight.
You are going to be the first.
The first to
make the humans see.
(BUZZING)
(GURGLING)
(GROANING)
Help me. Help me.
Help.
Help me.
(GURGLING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPS)
Commander here.
The first one has been changed.
I'm going to UNIT to
retrieve the Osgood box.
(CLICKS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Doctor?
Any questions?
Why do you have
a Union Jack parachute?
Um, camouflage.
-Camouflage?
-Yes, we're in Britain.
-(PANTING)
-Oh, your specs are broken.
I'll fix them.
You can wear mine, they're sonic.
-Sonic specs?
-Yeah!
Isn't that a bit pointless?
Like a visual hearing aid?
What's wrong with pointless?
I once invented an invisible watch.
Spot the design flaw.
You're talking nonsense to distract
me from being really scared.
It's one of your
known character traits.
-Don't look at my browser history.
-(BUZZING)
-Whoa.
-Yeah, I said don't.
Why didn't that Zygon
blow us up with her big bazooka?
She did blow us up
with her big bazooka.
This is us being blown up
with a big bazooka.
But I mean, she seems to know
what she's doing.
The first thing I'd do if I wanted to
invade the world would be to kill you.
-Thanks.
-I wouldn't even let you get talking.
Like you always do.
Bullet between the eyes, first thing.
-Again, thank you.
-I'd do it 12 times if necessary.
Ah, yes.
Well, why limit yourself?
You've really thought
this through, haven't you?
I am a big fan.
But she gave you a chance to get out.
She hesitated.
If she had
Clara's memory print,
she'd know better
than to give you even a second.
You've gone quiet
'cause I mentioned Clara.
You think she might be dead.
-Yes.
-Are you okay?
I don't know. (EXHALES)
I'm still in the hope phase.
How's that going?
Hell, please,
talk about something else.
(PHONE CHIMES)
Why did they want to
destroy the ceasefire?
Don't think of
them as rational, they're different.
They don't care
about human beings.
about their own people.
They think the rest of
Zygon-kind are traitors.
-It's a splinter group...
-(MOBILE RINGS)
(BEEPING)
Clara.
Well, not Clara.
The Zygon who...
The Zygon who
probably killed her. Read it.
It says, "I'm awake".
What does that mean?
A political awakening?
Why would she be
sending me propaganda
when she just blew me up
with a big bazooka.
Never really met Clara.
Pretty strong, yeah?
She was amazing.
No. Not was, is.
It's not from the Zygon,
it's from Clara.
-How?
-She's not dead.
She's in a pod somewhere.
They need a live feed
to the information in her brain,
but she's fighting back.
She's trying to take control
piece by piece.
Texting?
How much more
human could you get?
The Zygon probably
doesn't even know it sent this.
Or why it
misfired that bazooka.
You don't know,
it's just a theory.
Yes it's just a theory,
but how's that hope phase now?
Worse than ever.
Then we've got a game.
(BEEPING)
(UNLOCKS AND BEEPS)
Hello, if you're watching this,
I have been captured
and interrogated.
During the interrogation,
I've revealed to you
the existence of the Osgood box.
I've revealed its location
and the combination to open this safe.
-And guess what?
-BOTH: 7 lied.
The Osgood box exists, but it's not
here, so stop looking. Really, stop.
The Osgood box
can end the ceasefire.
can start the war.
The Osgood box can
wipe out all humankind.
But there's a reason
it's called the Osgood box.
Haven't you guessed?
(SNARLING)
(SHRIEKING IN RAGE)
(GRUNTING)
Hello! Hi.
Hello.
Dr John Disco. It was my plane.
I had a big plane for purposes
of poncing about.
It went off with a massive
bang about half a mile that way.
Actually, uh...
-It's fine, we're fine, aren't we?
-Yeah, yeah.
Yes, yes. We're fine.
Just, uh, move along.
(RINGING)
She's answered.
-Hello.
-You're dead.
Yes, well, I'm dead now and I think I
might be a bit more dead in a minute.
-What's your plan, Zygella?
-I don't have a plan.
Come on, you don't invade
planets without having a plan.
That's why they're called
planets, to remind you to plan it.
(CHUCKLES) Hey, that's good.
Puntastic.
Dr Puntastic. Oh, come on.
That was a good one, Zygella.
Don't call me Zygella,
my name's Bonnie.
You're winking at me.
I am not winking at you.
Where is the Osgood box?
You do know what
winking means, don't you?
You're sending out
some very mixed messages here.
You know I'm
over 2,000 years old.
I'm old enough
to be your messiah.
I am not winking at you.
Where is the box?
We're gonna need some wheels.
The van.
Okay, non-verbal
communication.
I assume that
you never bothered to learn Morse code.
Specs, setting 137.
Tell me!
-(BUZZING)
-Okay, we'll have to try something else.
Twenty questions.
Where's your pod?
Is it in a tunnel? Is it in London?
Thanks very much. Gotcha.
-(OPENS DOOR)
-(CAR UNLOCKS)
Stay where you are, Clara.
We're coming to get you.
And for God's sake,
don't let her into your memories.
Memories?
What memories, what has she got?
Don't tell her
where the Osgood box is.
And above all
don't tell her what it is.
(BEEPING)
-(STARTS ENGINE)
-(TYRES SCREECHING)
-Obviously, the Zygon could hear that.
-Obviously.
So, she's going to poke around
inside Clara's mind looking for answers.
The mind of Clara Oswald.
She may never
find her way out. (CHUCKLES)
I don't think I've ever
seen you smile before.
Dazzling, isn't it?
-Oh, I got a ping on Clara's phone.
-(BEEPS)
It's the location Bonnie
sent the text from.
A shopping centre, South London.
Ah, London, perpetual city,
cradle of culture, here we come.
Clara, stay safe.
OSGOOD:
She's posted a video link.
NEWSCASTER: A video supposedly
showing an alien in South London
-is posted across the Internet.
-(BEEPS)
OSGOOD: This is the same place
Bonnie texted from.
We need to hurry.
(STATIC)
Hello.
Oh, there's no
point turning over.
There's nothing better
on the other side.
I could erase your mind.
Then why haven't you?
Having trouble?
Let's see what I can do.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLES)
See, this thing
works two ways, you know.
I want those memories.
The trouble is,
you're asking me for them,
which means you
can't access them, right?
I can make you tell me.
No, you can't, otherwise,
you would have done already.
I can kill you.
Go on then.
You think you're calling my bluff?
I am calling your bluff.
You need me alive.
Only as a source of information.
Then you better
start asking questions.
-You better not lie.
-(CHUCKLES)
You see, that's the problem.
I am a brilliant liar.
How are you
ever going to know?
Oh, Clara.
For a moment
I thought you were clever.
(HEART BEATING)
Our hearts are linked.
Beat for beat.
The one thing you and I
can never do is lie to each other.
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, that scared you, didn't it?
(TYRES SCREECHING)
London.
-What a dump.
-London's okay.
-No, it's not. It's a dump.
-(DOG BARKING)
You spend an awful lot of time here
considering it's a dump.
I spent an awful lot of time
being kidnapped, tortured, shot at,
exterminated.
Doesn't mean I like it.
Well, this is where
the video was shot.
Bonnie was here.
Come on, Doctor.
There's electricity
in the air.
It stinks.
It smells like barbecues.
Oh.
(BUZZING)
Now, listen to me.
Here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to ask you questions,
and if you don't tell me the exact
and complete truth,
I will know and I will kill you.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
I will slaughter you in that pod
right now. Am I lying to you?
No.
Good. Then we'll begin.
Where is the Osgood box?
You will answer me, Clara.
Truth or consequences.
Lie and you die.
Where is it?
UNIT HQ,
under the Tower of London.
-Where specifically?
-The Black Archive.
Ah, yes.
The dark little storage
facility for forbidden alien tech
where all of this began.
Who has access to it?
The Osgoods.
Only the Osgoods?
The Doctor sealed it up
after the last time.
He didn't want
UNIT interfering with the ceasefire.
Don't avoid the question.
Do only the Osgoods have access?
The Doctor has access too.
Who else?
Ah, you.
You have access.
Yes.
Is it a key? Or a code?
No, a pass? A key-code.
Give it to me now.
I can't.
Interesting.
-You're not lying.
-No, I'm not.
-But you have access of some kind?
-Obviously.
Give it to me now.
I told you, I can't.
You know I'm not lying.
I can't give you access.
Okay. How do you get in there?
How physically do you get in?
-It's automatic.
-But how? Tell me.
The door is keyed
to my body print.
Ah, yes. Your body print.
You can't give me access
because I have access already.
-I'm you.
-Yes.
And what am I going to find?
What's in the Osgood box?
Clara?
The box ends the ceasefire.
So I'm told. How?
There's a button inside the box.
Press it. It will transmit a signal
that will unmask every
Zygon on the planet for up to an hour.
What's there to smile about?
Ah, mass panic.
Followed by war.
Every Zygon on our side at a stroke.
Twenty million Zygons
against seven billion humans.
That's not a war you can win!
Then we will die in the fire
instead of living in chains.
Most of your own
kind don't want that.
Then it's time we stopped
giving them a choice.
It's time you asked
the most important question.
-Which is?
-I'm waiting.
Why is it called an Osgood box?
I'm not telling you.
Good. I've been looking
forward to hearing you scream.
I'm not telling you because
when you get to the Black Archive,
you'll find out for yourself.
And when you do,
you're gonna want to speak to me again.
Am I lying to you?
See you later.
(STATIC)
What's your name?
Osgood.
No, no, no, your first name.
And what's your first name?
Basil.
Petronella.
Let's just,
uh, stick with what we had.
I need to ask you.
Because it's important.
Because it might matter.
What's important?
Which one are you?
Human or Zygon?
(GROWLING)
(GROWLS)
(GURGLING)
Whoever you are,
we can help you.
It wasn't me.
They attacked me.
They saw me.
I had to... (GROANS)
It's okay. It's okay.
A commander came.
She turned me back.
(GROANS)
We can help. We can help you.
-Doctor, we can help him, can't we?
-I'm not sure.
Please, come back! Come back!
North America.
Reporting back to High Command.
I'm going to the Black Archive.
-I'll open it up, you will follow.
-Of course.
But first, locate the Doctor.
If possible, duplicate him.
And then kill him.
It would be my pleasure.
I can't help you just now, but...
Why?
-I was happy like this. I was happy.
-I understand.
I._..
I can't change. I can't hide.
Let us help you.
No.
You're truth or consequences.
We're not. We're really not.
I'm not part of your fight.
I never wanted to fight anyone.
I just wanted to live here.
Why can't I just live?
We are on your side.
I'm not on anyone's side.
This is my home.
Listen. We are not them.
I can't go back now.
You've taken my life.
No. No, no, no.
Stop, stop, stop.
They will kill me.
There it is, Osgood.
There's their plan.
Unmask everyone.
Provoke fear, paranoia.
Provoke a war.
Doctor.
Kate, are you all right?
Of course I am.
Why wouldn't I be?
-It's just, I heard otherwise.
-I'm fine.
Doctor, we know where
the Zygon Command Centre is.
We know where Clara's pod is.
We can take you there.
Well, how very convenient,
because that's just exactly
what we're looking for.
And here it is.
The Black Archive.
I do like being you, Clara.
Everyone just
waves you on past.
Now,
how does this work?
(BEEPING AND BUZZING)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, they like a good cave,
don't they?
How many of these
pods are occupied?
We don't know.
Which one is Clara's?
Well, that's strange.
It was here before.
Doctor, I think they're Zygons.
Oh, you cheeky little monkeys.
Normalise.
Well, Clara, I think
you're reaching the end of your...
(PHONE RINGS)
-The Doctor is here.
-Don't kill him. We need him alive.
What for?
Because I just found out
why it's called an Osgood box.
There's two of them.
Two Osgoods, two boxes.
Operation Double. What did you expect?
What's in them, Doctor?
Tell me, now.
One box normalises all the Zygons.
-And the other?
-Destroys them.
Which is which?
(LAUGHS)
That would be telling.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Which box normalises the Zygons, Doctor?
Tell me or she dies.
No. This is war.
You pull the trigger,
you pay the price.
Kill her.
The blue one. The blue one.
The blue one
normalises all your people.
Are you lying?
Are you lying to me, Doctor?
No, I'm not. And when you open up
the box, you'll see I'm not lying.
Doctor.
Doctor!
Yeah. I know.
Bring him to me!
(GUNSHOTS)
Sorry, Doctor. Self-defence.
-Who are you?
-I'm me.
How did you survive?
Five rounds, rapid.
(SCREAMS)
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I know you don't approve.
DOCTOR: Why does peacekeeping
always involve killing?
Is this the lot?
No, there are plenty more of them,
they were the nearest.
You are you?
I'm me.
But human or Zygon?
Me.
What are we dealing with?
Twenty million Zygons
about to be unmasked.
They don't know whether
they're human or not.
And you can't fight them,
not with soldiers.
Which leads me to
a very big question.
Oh, I was really
hoping that it wouldn't.
The Z-67, Sullivan's gas,
the gas that kills the Zygons,
you took it.
Well, you know how it is,
Daddy knows best.
That's what's in
the red box, yes?
Of course it is.
If I remember rightly, it causes a chain
reaction in the atmosphere,
turns every Zygon
on Earth inside out.
Let me negotiate peace.
You can't commit mass murder.
Then why did you
leave the gas with us?
The boxes are safeguards
for both species.
You agreed to that.
I never agreed to that!
Yes, you did. Then I wiped your memory.
And you agreed to that too.
But that's why there were two
Osgoods to police the ceasefire.
One human and one Zygon.
To keep the secrets,
keep the peace.
I'm sorry, Doctor, truly.
But the peace is failing already.
Come on.
It's no good, Bonnie.
You can't win.
I don't care.
Hi! Hello! Hello!
Oh, hello, hi!
Hi, stop this. Stop this, please!
Let me take both
of these boxes away.
We'll forgive. We'll forget.
And the ceasefire will stand.
No.
Doctor, which of these
buttons do I press?
Doctor, which one?
Truth or consequences?
DOCTOR: This is the moment
we've all been waiting for.
Make-your-mind-up time.
One of those buttons
will destroy the Zygons,
release the imbecile's gas.
The other one detonates the nuclear
warhead under the Black Archive.
It'll destroy
everyone in London. Bonnie!
Bonnie, sweetheart,
one of those buttons
will unmask every
Zygon in the world.
The other one cancels
their ability to change form.
It'll make them
human beings forever!
There are safeguards
beyond safeguards.
I did this on a very important
day for me.
And this ceasefire will stand.
This is wrong.
No, it's not.
You are responsible
for all of the violence,
all of the suffering.
-No, I'm not.
-Yes.
-No.
You engineered this situation,
Doctor. This is your fault.
No, it's not, it's your fault.
I had to do what I've done.
So did 1.
We've been treated like cattle.
So what?
We've been left to
fend for ourselves.
-So has everyone.
-It's not fair.
Oh, it's not fair?
Oh, I didn't realise that!
It was not fair.
Well, you know what?
My Tardis doesn't work properly.
And I don't have my
own personal tailor.
The things don't equate.
These things have happened, Zygella.
They are facts.
You just want
cruelty to beget cruelty.
You're not superior to people
who were cruel to you.
You're just a whole bunch
of new cruel people.
A whole bunch of
new cruel people
being cruel to some other people
who'll end up being cruel to you.
The only way anyone
can live in peace
is if they're prepared to forgive.
Why don't you break the cycle?
Why should we?
What is it that you actually want?
War.
Ah, ah, right.
And when this war is over,
when you have a homeland
free from humans,
what do you think
it's gonna be like?
Do you know?
Have you thought about it?
Have you given it
any consideration?
Because you're very close
to getting what you want.
What's it gonna be like?
Paint me a picture.
Are you gonna live in houses?
Do you want people to go to work?
Will there be holidays?
Oh, will there be music?
Do you think people will
be allowed to play violins?
Who's gonna make the violins?
Well?
Oh, you don't
actually know, do you?
Because, like every other
tantruming child in history,
Bonnie, you don't
actually know what you want.
So, let me ask you a question
about this brave new world of yours.
When you've killed all the bad guys,
and when it's all perfect
and just and fair,
when you have finally got it
exactly the way you want it,
what are you gonna do
with the people like you?
The troublemakers.
How you gonna protect
your glorious revolution
from the next one?
-We'll win.
-Oh, will you?
Well, maybe. Maybe you will win.
But nobody wins for long.
The wheel just keeps turning.
So, come on.
Break the cycle.
Why are you still talking?
Because I want to get you to see,
and I'm almost there.
Do you know what I see, Doctor?
A box.
A box with everything I need.
A 50% chance...
For us too.
And we're off!
Fingers on buzzers!
Are you feeling lucky?
Are you ready to play the game?
Who's gonna be quickest?
Who's gonna be luckiest?
This is not a game!
No, it's not a game, sweetheart.
And I mean that most sincerely.
Why are you doing this?
Yes, I'd quite
like to know that too.
You set this up, why?
Because it's not a game, Kate.
This is a scale model of war.
Every war ever fought,
right there in front of you.
Because it's always the same.
When you fire that first shot,
no matter how right you feel,
you have no idea who's going to die!
You don't know whose children
are going to scream and burn.
How many hearts will be broken!
How many lives shattered!
How much blood will spill
until everybody does
what they were always gonna
have to do from the very beginning.
Sit down and talk!
(SIGHS)
Listen to me, listen.
I just...
I just want you to think.
Do you know what thinking is?
It's just a fancy word
for changing your mind.
I will not change my mind.
Then you will die stupid.
Alternatively, you could step
away from that box,
you could walk right
out of that door,
and you can stand
your revolution down.
No. I'm not stopping this, Doctor.
I started it, I will not stop it.
You think they'll let me go
after what I've done?
You're all the same,
you screaming kids, you know that?
"Look at me, I'm unforgivable."
Well, here's the unforeseeable,
I forgive you.
After all you've done.
You don't understand.
You will never understand.
I don't understand? (LAUGHS)
Are you kidding me?
Of course, I understand.
I mean, you call this a war?
This funny little thing?
This is not a war!
I fought in a bigger war
than you will ever know.
I did worse things
than you can ever imagine.
When I close my eyes...
I hear more screams than
anyone could ever be able to count.
And you know what you do
with all that pain?
Shall I tell you where you put it?
You hold it tight,
till it burns your hand.
And you say this,
"No one else will ever
have to live like this.
"No one else will
have to feel this pain.
"Not on my watch."
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I know.
I know. Thank you.
Well...
It's empty, isn't it?
Both boxes, there's nothing in them.
Just buttons.
Of course.
But you know
how you know that?
Because you've
started to think like me.
It's hell, isn't it?
No one should have
to think like that.
And no one will.
Not on our watch.
Gotcha!
How can you be so sure?
Because you have
a disadvantage, Zygella.
I know that face.
This is all very well,
but we know the boxes are empty now.
We can't forget that.
DOCTOR: No, well, uh...
You've said that the last 15 times.
You didn't wipe my memory.
No, just Kate's.
Oh, and your little friends
here, of course.
When they wake up,
they won't remember
what you've done.
It'll be our secret.
You're going to protect me?
You're one of us now,
whether you like it or not.
I don't understand how
you could just forgive me.
Because I've been where you have.
There was another box.
I was gonna press another button.
I was gonna wipe out
all of my own kind.
Man, woman and child.
I was so sure I was right.
What happened?
Same thing that happened to you.
I let Clara Oswald
get inside my head.
Trust me,
she doesn't leave.
Zygon High Command,
the ceasefire is back in place.
The rebels are standing down.
You are all...
Safe.
The Tardis.
What does it stand for?
What?
You're kidding me.
Surely you know that.
Well, I've heard a couple
of different versions.
I made it up from the initials.
It stands for
Totally Radically
Driving In Space.
Do you want to come?
All of the future, all of history,
and all of the universe.
More than anything.
But I think I have to stay.
I've got a couple of boxes
to keep an eye on,
and a world to keep safe.
Fair enough.
Clara, would you mind, uh...
Mind what?
I'll see you in the Tardis, okay?
Er, yeah, sure.
Take care, you.
You take care of him.
Don't let him die or anything.
What if he's really annoying?
-Then, fine.
-Got ya.
I need to know. Which one are you?
I'm Osgood.
Human or Zygon?
I'll answer that question one day.
And you know when
that day will be?
The day nobody
cares about the answer.
Gotcha.
Oh, look at his face.
It's almost not fair.
But I don't... How, how...
Think it through, Doctor.
It wouldn't be right, would it?
To carry on using Clara's face.
When there's a vacancy.
-Zygella?
-Osgood.
But which one of you...
It doesn't matter
which of us is which.
All that matters is
that Osgood lives.
And nothing's going to stop us.
You're a credit
to your species, Petronella Osgood.
No, Basil.
We're a credit to both of them.
Oh, and you should know.
I'm a very big fan.
So, you must have thought
I was dead for a while.
-Yeah.
-How was that?
Longest month of my life.
It could only have
been five minutes.
I'll be the judge of time.
Ice creams?
Yes, ice creams, then back to work.
What's today?
You know, same old, same old.
Defending the Earth.
RASSMUSSEN:
You must not watch this.
You can never unsee it.
NAGATA: Twenty-four hours ago
this station fell silent.
We've come to find out why.
CLARA: What are these?
CHOPRA: Morpheus.
DOCTOR: What is Morpheus?
The Morpheus machine concentrates
the whole nocturnal experience.
Now you can go
a whole month without sleep!
Time is money.
DOCTOR: Congratulations, Professor.
You've conquered nature.
You've also created an abomination.
(CREATURE ROARING)
-Run! Run! Run!
-(GUNFIRE)
You can't stop them.
None of us can.