Look, I know. You both have
lives here, beautiful, messy lives.
That is what makes you so fabulously human.
You don't want to give
them up. I understand.
Actually, it's you they
can't give up, Doctor.
And I don't think they should.
Go with him.
Go save every world you can find.
Who else has that chance?
Life will still be here.
You could come, Brian.
Somebody's got to water the plants.
Dear Dad, this is the difficult bit.
If I've got this right, you're
reading this letter a week
after we left in the TARDIS.
The thing is, we're not coming back.
We're alive and well and stuck.
In New York, 50 years before I
was born, we can't come home again.
I won't ever see you again,
and that breaks my heart.
I'm so sorry, Dad.
I thought about this for years,
and I realised there
was one thing I could do.
I could write to you, tell you
everything about how we lived,
how, despite it all, we were happy.
But before I do, I need you to know...
you are the best dad
any son could have had.
And for all the times I drove
you mad and you drove me mad,
all the times I snapped at you...
...I'm sorry.
I miss everything about you.
Especially our awkward hugs.
I bought a trowel. We
have a small yard. I garden.
But one more important bit of business.
The man who delivered the letter, Anthony.
Be nice to him.
Cos he's your grandson.
We finally adopted in 1946.
Anthony Brian Williams,
he can tell you everything.
He'll have the family albums.
And I realise having a
grandson who's older than you
is so far beyond weird.
But I'm sorry.
I love you, Dad.
I miss you.