(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Don't let us down now, Valkyrie.
Fingers crossed, Alan.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I got everything crossed.
Okay, people.
Transmission arriving in...
MAN: (OVER PA)
And we are standing by. Countdown...
-Ten...
-(COUNTER BEEPS)
-Nine.
-Eight.
-(COUNTER BEEPS)
-Seven, six.
-(COUNTER BEEPING)
-Five, four.
-Three.
-(COUNTER BEEPS)
-Two.
-One.
-(COUNTER BEEPS)
(POWER DRAINS)
Sorry, I could never resist a countdown.
-Who the hell are you?
-BILL: Is this Neil Armstrong?
What?
Neil Armstrong.
First man on the moon.
Not quite the first.
What, you mean he wasn't
the first man on the moon?
That is such a human-centric question.
I'm the human in this setup.
NARDOLE: She is, actually.
A bit embarrassing, really.
Who are you people?
DOCTOR: Friendly aliens. Don't mind us.
Just a day out for the kids.
-It's from the chief.
-Is it?
Oh, yes, that's right. Authorising us
to go anywhere we please. So.
Valkyrie.
Valkyrie is...
Probing the Martian ice caps
with a new kind of camera on board.
Uses a different spectrum to see
under the poles
and beam back pictures.
(TYPING ON KEYBOARD)
What the hell...
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: Mars, 1881.
Or thereabouts. According to the TARDIS,
that's when the message was made.
Though we may be a bit early.
So, there were humans on Mars
in Victorian times.
No.
There weren't.
NARDOLE: The TARDIS registered
multiple life forms
below the surface, sir.
It seems like the best place to look.
BILL: Maybe someone's been
messing around with time.
-Like in The Terminator.
-The Terminator?
It's a movie.
-BILL: You haven't seen it?
-I'm a very busy man.
BILL: Well, you'd like it.
It's got killer robots.
Oh, I'll put it on the list.
Even if there are people here,
why would they bother writing messages
on the surface of the planet?
State visit, patriotic fervour.
Rogue graffiti artist.
Doctor...
I see it
Oh, if there's fire,
there's got to be oxygen.
Wait wait. Let's not be rash.
-Okay.
-I'll go first.
What are you doing?
Fire, oxygen. Basic physics, innit?
Could have been basic death.
(HELMETS HISSING)
Wait, how can there be oxygen here?
The indigenous Martians
were superb engineers.
Mind you, there's a lot here
that doesn't make sense.
Oh, it's like the underground tunnels
in 7he Thing.
The what?
BILL: It's a movie.
You'd like that one too. Everybody dies.
Whoa!
(BILL SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Bill!
Bill! Hang on.
DOCTOR: We'll find a way down.
Go back to the TARDIS.
Get ropes, lifting gear,
anything you can find.
(WHIMPERS)
(BEEPS)
Oh!
-(WHIMPERS)
-(ALARM RINGING)
Nardole, what the hell are you doing?
(COUGHS)
(BEEPS)
(WHIRRING)
(HEAVY STOMPING)
(BEEPING STOPS)
(DOOR OPENING)
(LOW GROWLING)
So, this could go very well.
Or very badly.
(HISSING)
Halt!
I say,
we weren't expecting company.
Right.
(WHIRRING)
Uh...
Yeah...
Right.
No...
By the moons, I honour thee.
I'm the Doctor.
What is your name?
(HISSES)
I know your people of old. I was once
honorary guardian of the Tythonian Hive.
-(GUN COCKS)
-MAN: Don't move.
I'll sort this bugger out.
No, no, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
This creature is no threat.
He may look like a monster to you...
(GUNSHOT)
I wasn't talking to you.
You all right, Friday?
FRIDAY: Sir.
Who are you and what the devil
are you doing here?
Well, I could ask you the same question.
And I will.
(BEEPING)
Hello?
Hello, miss?
I was wondering
if I could ask for your help.
Uh, I need to get to Mars...
Er, well, I need to
get back to Mars in fact.
Erm, and it's a little bit urgent,
only the TARDIS is acting up.
And I was wondering if you could tell me
how to fix...
MISSY: (OVER SPEAKER) Of course, I can.
Oh.
Right. Well, thank you.
MISSY: It's probably easier
if I just show you.
Oh. Erm...
Er...
COLONEL: Indian or China, my dear?
BILL: Erm...
(STAMMERS) I don't know...
China?
(POURING TEA)
(WHISPERING) Where's Nardole?
Um...
Well, he seems to have taken the TARDIS.
-What?
-It's...
I'm sure it's only
a temporary thing, you know,
but it means that
for the time being we're...
(CLEARS THROAT) Stuck here on Mars.
You were saying, Colonel.
Oh, uh, well, yes.
(CLEARS THROAT) I was stationed
out there, er, South Africa.
One day, I came across something
in the veld.
Something that was clearly
not of this Earth.
An inter-planetary vessel.
I found Friday here, on board,
in a sort of coma.
Half dead.
Why do you call him that?
Man Friday?
As in Robinson Crusoe?
So...
According to this,
you've been on board Friday's ship
the whole time?
Yes, but we were...
That was... That sounds...
-That sounds... Quite...
-Convincing.
That sounds... Yes, that's right.
On his ship.
Well, I suppose it was
pretty roomy, what! (LAUGHS)
(NERVOUS LAUGHTER)
-It was, yes. Wasn't it? Very roomy.
-Yes.
But the whole, you know, I mean,
getting on board...
I mean, that's all... (EXHALES)
It's all a bit hazy.
Maybe you could tell us everything.
Yes, well, erm... (CLEARS THROAT)
After I woke him up,
Friday asked for my help.
To repair his spaceship?
Yes, and to bring him home.
In return for what?
Er...
Well, now...
That is the question.
(EXPLOSION)
Prepare to fire!
On the double! Go, go, go!
CATCHLOVE: Friday helped
us build the Gargantua.
A remarkable piece of mining equipment
fashioned from
one of his ship's artillery.
(GROANS)
(SOLDIER COUGHING)
CATCHLOVE: He promised us
gemstones, you see.
Silver, gold, treasure
beyond our wildest dreams.
That's why you helped him come home.
To claim Mars
in the name of Queen Victoria.
To loot it of its riches.
Stake a claim.
The Red Planet turned pink.
That was the general idea, old love.
But there's nothing here.
The whole show has been a ruddy washout.
The ship crashed on landing.
I go topside now and then to see
if I can repair the beggar.
That's what I was doing
when I ran across you.
And?
-No joy so far.
-It could have been a fresh start.
For all of us.
But now...
Supplies are running as low as morale.
Things are pretty desperate, I'm afraid.
(STOMPING)
BILL: You told us why you came here.
What does he get out of it?
COLONEL: Nothing.
BILL: Nothing?
Well, he was hoping to find his people,
but it appears that
he was asleep on that ship
for much longer than he anticipated.
Mars is dead.
Dead as a coffin nail.
Friday's the last of his kind.
Is he now?
BILL: You know what Friday is then?
DOCTOR: He's an Ice Warrior.
And they're the proper Martians, right?
They belong here.
Yes. The indigenous species.
DOCTOR: An ancient reptilian race,
they build themselves as sort of
bio-mechanical arm our for protection.
The creature within
is at one with his carapace.
DOCTOR: The Ice Warriors.
They could build a city under the sand,
yet drench the snows of Mars
with innocent blood.
They could slaughter
whole civilizations,
yet weep with the crushing of a flower.
Like the Vikings.
Yes.
-Yes, very much.
-Yeah.
Kirk Douglas and Tony Curtis.
Ah, the theme tune is amazing.
There's this brilliant bit
where, where his eye gets gouged out...
Why have you really come back?
(SIGHS)
I'm old.
And tired.
And spent.
(WHIRRING)
Now then, Vincey. Look lively, lad.
JACKDAW: What's the point though?
-Jackdaw...
-Months we've been digging here.
And what have we got to show for it?
Sweet Fanny Adams, that's what!
ALL: Yeah.
What old Friday promised,
it's a load of gammon.
(ROCKS CLATTERING)
-Jackdaw.
-Wha...
(WIND HOWLING)
You must come at once, sir.
The Gargantua...
She's... She's uncovered something.
Good Lord.
Looks like old Friday
came good after all, eh?
BILL: Oh, it's beautiful.
What is it? A tomb?
DOCTOR: Not just any tomb.
This is the tomb of an Ice queen.
I've a bad feeling about this.
These sarcophagi were sometimes part
of a complex hibernation system.
Sergeant Major, get these civilians
out of here.
No, Colonel, Colonel!
You have to let me examine this.
Well, now, I think not, Doctor.
This is a military matter.
This may not just be a grave
you have uncovered.
This could be the entrance
to an Ice Warrior hive.
(SCOFFS) What?
Sergeant Major Peach,
I gave you an order.
I'm in charge here, Catchlove.
Yes, sir.
-Of course, sir.
-Post a guard.
No one's to come near this thing
until the morning. Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
DOCTOR: The last thing
I'm going to do is take sides.
But isn't that obvious?
Friday's been using you all along.
His aim was to get back to Mars
and find his queen.
CATCHLOVE: Nonsense.
He was leading us to the riches
he promised us.
The simple fact
is you don't belong here.
The sooner you get off this planet,
the better.
CATCHLOVE: Don't belong?
We're British.
Mars is part of the Empire now.
(SIGHS)
What happened to not taking sides?
I'm trying to save their lives.
Let's face it. In this scenario,
the humans are the invaders.
On the other hand, the Ice Warriors
have vastly superior armaments
which will wipe the humans out.
So what am I supposed to do?
Here you go, Sarge.
Much obliged, I'm sure, Jackdaw.
Don't I get none?
R-H-I-P, son.
Eh?
"Rank has its privileges."
Christ alive.
Look at the guild on that thing.
That would set up a fellow
for life, Vincey,
even just a little bit of it...
Now then, you horrible, old man.
Don't go getting no fancy notions.
I'm sure the Colonel will be
distributing this munificence
in a fair and decent fashion.
And we can all look forward to...
To...
A rosy future.
Sarge?
Jackdaw, what have you done?
Acquired that from the infirmary.
He'd be as right as ninepence come dawn.
-But by then, I'll be gone.
-Gone?
Gone where? In case you've forgotten,
we're marooned on ruddy Mars.
You don't know what I know, sir.
Captain Catchlove's further on
with his repairs than he's let on.
Oh, yes, my old love.
Jackdaw's going home.
But this time, he'll be minted.
Come on, give us a hand.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
JACKDAW: Right.
-Keep an eye out, will you?
-No.
You ain't getting me involved
in this lie, Jackdaw.
Oh, go on. Be a sport.
You'll get your share of the rhino.
I promise.
# It's the same the whole world over
(GRUNTS)
# It's the poor what gets the blame
# It's the rich what gets the pleasure
(GROANS)
Z Ain't it all a bleed in" shame? #
(LAUGHING)
(WHISPERING) Someone's coming, Jackdaw.
We'll ruddy swing for this.
Jackdaw?
Come on, mate. Don't muck about.
IRAXXA: What manner
of fleshy worm are you?
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Speak.
SOLDIER: What the hell?
That was
unwise.
(PULSATING)
(SCREAMS)
(HISSES)
(PULSATING)
FRIDAY: Your Majesty.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
By the moons, I honour thee.
Iraxxa, My Empress, My Queen.
My sentinel.
You have fulfilled your pledge.
I am resurrected.
Forgive me, Majesty,
but we have slept
longer than anticipated.
By my calculations, Majesty,
we have slept for 5,000 years.
Five thousand years!
-(ALARM BELL RINGING)
-SOLDIER: Guards, guards, hurry!
SOLDIER: Move, move!
Come on, you lot!
COLONEL: What the devil?
What the hell is going on here, Friday?
Colonel, let me speak to them.
I can do this. I can sort this out.
Who the devil is this?
She is Iraxxa, Empress of Mars.
The deuce she is.
You think you can just
go about slaughtering
my men willy-nilly, do you, madam?
Your men?
What does the pink thing say?
Pink thing!
Sergeant Major!
-Call to arms!
-No, no, no, wait.
Wait, Catchlove, wait.
Your Honour must be satisfied.
An eye for an eye.
I am in command here.
All right.
By the moons, I honour thee.
I am the Doctor.
And I beg leave to intercede.
You know my race.
I do.
And I ask mercy for these primitives...
-Primitives!
-Shh!
DOCTOR: Majesty,
the world you knew is dead.
(HISSES)
The atmosphere has all but evaporated.
(WHISPERS) The surface is lifeless.
If there are others
who sleep here,
they cannot survive on Mars
without help.
You must cooperate
if you want to survive.
He speaks the truth, Majesty.
The war, all that we've fought for
is less than the dust now.
And you?
Female.
What do you say?
Me?
We are both surrounded
by noisy males.
I would value your opinion.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, er...
They're not lying to you.
There's no need
for anyone else to die today.
The humans saved his life.
IRAXXA: Is this true?
His cryogenic cell was damaged.
They saved him.
And made him their pet!
FRIDAY: It was necessary
to dissemble, Majesty.
I thought only of your resurrection.
It was a tactical decision.
An Ice Warrior's duty is to command.
CATCHLOVE: Present!
Iraxxa, listen to me.
The Mars you ruled is gone.
But don't let it end this way!
Fight this.
For the future.
Not a dead past.
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
-You bloody fool!
-SOLDIER: Sorry, sir.
Down, put your gun down. Halt.
Majesty.
Are you all right?
You ask for mercy for these creatures.
Indeed.
Then I grant it.
Thank you.
They will die...
(WHISPERS) Quickly.
(HISSES)
No! Colonel! Get your men out of here!
Colonel!
Retreat, retreat!
(HISSES)
Catchlove, listen to me.
Your only chance is to come to terms.
But we have the Gargantua.
-Is she primed and aimed, Sergeant?
-Yes, sir.
No, no, I forbid you.
That is not the way...
Oh, forbid. You forbid?
Well, this farce
has gone on long enough.
PEACH: Arms at the ready!
Ready...
No, no. Don't shoot him, for God's sake.
Put it down!
DOCTOR: Put your guns down.
CATCHLOVE: What the devil!
(ALL CHEERING)
That'll hold him.
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
CATCHLOVE: We're about to go to war,
so it's time you knew
the truth.
Listen to me, men.
The Colonel is not what he appears.
The hero of Isandlwana!
-Show them your famous wounds.
-No, no, no.
-No, please. No, no, no, please.
-Show them!
The mark of a rope.
While you were fighting
for Queen and country,
the Colonel here
was dancing the Newgate Polka.
This...
This is the mark of the rope
that failed to hang him for desertion.
They tried to hang him
but they bungled it.
He's a paper tiger.
Not fit to command.
Look, it doesn't matter who's in charge
of your stupid expedition.
You don't stand a chance
against the Ice Warriors.
What? All two of them?
There will be more, you idiot.
The hive is active.
Don't you see? They'll do anything
to defend their home planet.
Well, I dare say the British army
is more than a match
for a bunch of upright crocodiles.
-Sergeant Major!
-Sir.
I'm assuming command.
Take the Colonel
and put him in the brig.
Sergeant Major Peach,
I gave you an order.
Very good, sir.
Private!
If you would be so good
as to come this way, sir.
Oh, and for the last time,
get these wretched people
out of my sight.
-Put them in the brig too.
-Go on.
There's no room for civilians here.
-This isn't over, Catchlove.
-CATCHGLOVE: No.
It ain't.
Not now Neville Catchlove's in charge.
DOCTOR: You'll regret this.
In a couple of hours,
you'll be begging for help.
It will take time
to revive all of my warriors.
But perhaps enough are awoken
to go on the offensive.
CATCHLOVE: If either
of those creatures get out of there,
-we'll be ready for them.
-Yes, sir.
-Carry on, Sergeant Major.
-We won't let you down, sir.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
There's no setting for wood.
Why is there still no setting for wood?
But you got a plan?
Yes, of course, I've got a plan.
I'm all plans. I'm made of plans.
Who the deuce are you two, really?
You speak of us as though
we're a different species.
You seem to know all about these, uh,
these Ice Warrior.
You seem to know
a lot about most things.
BILL: Well...
-We're sort of police.
-Speak for yourself.
(LAUGHS)
What? You can deal with
big, green Martians
and rocket ships, but you can't
deal with us being the police.
No. (STAMMERS) No, it's just such
a fanciful notion.
A woman in the police force.
-(LAUGHS)
-Listen.
Yeah.
I'm going to make allowances
for your Victorian attitudes
because...
Well, you actually are Victorian.
(STAMMERS) But anyway. Is it true?
You deserted?
BILL: Why?
Oh...
Cowardice.
Simple cowardice.
I thought I had it in me to command,
Miss Potts,
but when push came to shove,
I flunked it.
Deserted my post.
Catchlove's the only one who knew
and he's bled me dry.
(SIGHS) It could have been
a fresh start.
For all of us.
(COLONEL SIGHS)
How's it looking out there?
All quiet.
It's traditional at this point to say...
Too quiet.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Always liked the Colonel, I did.
Seemed a decent chap.
We must take orders
from the Captain now, son.
Them's the rules.
Sir.
VINCEY: Blimey, Sarge,
this is quite...
(RUMBLING)
...to tell your kids.
I mean Mars!
PEACH: You just face front and mark
your man when you see him, Vincey lad.
I should have known, I should.
VINCEY: Wait till Alice hears all this.
PEACH: Set a date, have you, son?
You and your Alice?
Oh, not yet. When I have enough
put by to make us comfy.
Then we'll get married in that
little church with the twisted spire
back home, down by the river.
Oh, it's so green there, Sarge.
It's beautiful.
I miss the trees.
And the grass.
(SCOFFS) I never want to see red again
in all my puff.
I just wanna see...
(VINCEY GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
(LASER PULSATING)
How in God's name
did they get behind us?
Turn it!
For God's sake, 90 degrees!
SOLDIER: It won't work, sir!
We need more men!
Catchlove, this is senseless slaughter!
(EXPLOSION)
(SOLDIERS YELLING)
Front, commit!
Fire!
Come on, lads,
there's only three of them!
Sleep no more, my warriors,
sleep no more.
It is time.
(THUDS)
BILL: Doctor, what do we do?
There's no way out!
SOLDIER: Close it! Close the gap!
(ALL YELLING)
(LASER PULSATING)
CATCHLOVE: Retreat! Retreat!
Run for it!
Sir, what do we do?
(SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, sod this, for a game of soldiers.
(HISSING)
- (HISSING)
-(GUNSHOTS)
BILL: Friday?
FRIDAY: Doctor, we must work together.
Rise, my Ice Warriors! Rise!
(GUNSHOT)
CATCHLOVE: Regroup!
For the honour of the regiment!
SOLDIER: No way!
(SCREAMS)
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
where are you going?
I'm sorry, Doctor.
Blue funk, can't help it.
I can't do it. I'm sorry.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
I need a distraction.
-You got one.
-Good luck.
(LASERS FIRING)
-(INDISTINCT YELLING)
-(GUNSHOTS)
Oi! Queenie!
Let's talk.
Woman to woman.
You valued my opinion before.
IRAXXA: Perhaps.
But this is war.
Why?
Why does it have to be war?
FRIDAY: You're Majesty, she's right.
You have forged a new alliance, I see.
Uh, we can stand together.
It's too late.
Mars stands alone.
We are strong.
Soon, all my warriors will wake.
We do not require assistance.
(LASER PULSATING)
DOCTOR: Your Majesty!
Oh, Your Majesty!
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Stand down or I'll fire.
Fire at what?
Well, geography
was never my strong suit,
but aren't we underneath
Mars' north pole?
Over our heads,
millions of tons of snow and ice.
One good blast from the Gargantua here,
your army will be on ice forever.
Trapped in an eternal winter.
Like...
Like Frozen.
It's a movie.
You would destroy yourself
at the same time.
Well, that's a price
worth paying, isn't it?
It's a simple choice, Iraxxa,
the oldest in the book.
We must live together...
Or die together.
(GROWLS)
(LASERS CHARGING)
You dare to touch me!
CATCHLOVE: Yes, I dare.
Don't do this, Captain.
Don't mess this up.
No choice, old boy. (CHUCKLES)
You, you see, I suddenly remembered
I need a bit of a hand getting
that ruddy ship off the ground.
And who better to ask
than the Ice Queen herself?
Call off your dogs, Your Majesty.
Call them off.
That's better.
'Course, er, I will have to dynamite
the lifts to stop you following,
but, erm...
Well, war is hell, what? (CHUCKLES)
You want to escape, I can help.
Just leave Iraxxa with her people.
Don't mess this up.
Oh, thank you, Doctor, but, erm,
I think I prefer my plan.
(DOOR OPENS)
Gentlemen!
It's been a privilege, however brief,
to command you, but...
All good things come to an end.
COLONEL: I think you'll find, Captain...
-That I'm in command, here.
-(GUNSHOT)
You sacrificed one of your own
without tactical advantage.
No, I didn't sacrifice him.
I executed him.
Do you now expect
your life to be spared?
No. No, no, no.
I expect it to be taken.
And I give it willingly.
BILL: No, no, no, wait...
-(SHUSHES)
-Stop this, Doctor. Stop it.
Some time ago,
I was hanged for cowardice.
The execution took longer than expected,
and I fear I have not used my time well.
I should be happy for you
to complete the work
they failed to do so long ago.
It will be a pleasure.
-No, please don't do this.
-Bill, quiet!
He saved your life!
Your Majesty, I have a request,
if that may be permitted.
Speak.
That man was not one of us.
Please do not judge mankind
by his cruelty
or, indeed, by my cowardice.
Spare my friends and my world.
Your request does you credit, soldier.
It will be considered.
(LASER CHARGING)
God save the Queen!
ALL: God save the Queen!
You will die with honour.
With bravery.
And in the service of those
you swore to protect.
Thank you.
You don't know what that means.
But not today.
In battle...
Soldier.
To die in battle
is the way of the Warrior.
Pledge your allegiance to me
and my world,
and I will ensure
you have the opportunity.
My life and my service are yours.
To the end.
To the death,
my friend.
To the death.
You knew that would happen.
Always been my problem.
-COLONEL: What?
-Thinking like a warrior.
(ELECTRICITY WHIRRING)
(BEEPS)
Ugh.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
There we are.
Er, I've sent out a sort of
round robin e-mail.
All being well,
the first intelligent space-going system
will be in touch fairly soon.
IRAXXA: Thank you, Doctor.
Mars is dead,
but the Ice Warriors will live on.
Will they make it?
Oh, yes.
In fact, this might be the beginning
of the Martian Golden Age.
ALPHA CENTAURI: Are you receiving us?
Mars, are you receiving?
This is Iraxxa,
Queen Empress of Mars.
Ah, excellent! We have received
details of your situation.
We would be happy to send a fleet
to your aid at once.
A physical marker of some sort would
be appreciated to guide our ships.
To whom am I speaking?
This is Alpha Centauri.
Welcome to the universe.
(BILL GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
Big enough?
For the ship to see?
I think so.
You gonna be okay?
Well that's twice I've been executed.
Whatever happens now,
it's gonna be better than I expected.
Ah, there's nothing for me
back on Earth and...
To help forge a new world, well
that would be my privilege.
(SIGHS) Seems a shame, though.
What does?
Well no one back on Earth
will ever know that we got here.
All will be forgotten.
Oh, not quite forgotten, Colonel.
You've changed the mind-set
of a very stubborn Martian monarch.
And one day...
Even though the ice cap may obscure it,
someone's going to notice that.
(TARDIS WHIRRING)
(THUDS)
So, er...
What did I miss?
Where have you been?
(STAMMERING) Yeah, er,
before you go getting all frowny,
er, well, er...
Are you all right?
This can't happen.
This is not what we agreed to.
I'm gonna have to put you
back in the vault, you know that.
Sure.
That's fine.
What?
But, Doctor, please, tell me, really,
are you all right?
DOCTOR: The Ninth Legion
and the keeper of the gate.
-They disappeared.
-Except they didn't.
Where is my friend
and what destroyed the Roman army?
(ROARS)
NARDOLE: Something here managed
to wipe out 5,000 Romans.
-(SCREAMS)
-CROW: (CAWING) Doc-tor.
(SNARLS)
DOCTOR: Every hour of sunlight
that feeds it makes the world darker,
and the beast stronger.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)