(PHONE RINGING)
I said, no.
A sapphire waterfall.
It's a waterfall made of sapphires!
This enormous jewel
the size of a glacier
reaches the Cliffs of Oblivion and then
shatters into sapphires at the edge,
then fall 100,000 feet
into a crystal ravine.
-I bet you say that to all the girls.
-Oh, come on. They're boarding now.
It's no fun if I see it on me own.
Four hours, that's all it'll take.
No. That's four hours there
and four hours back.
That's like a school trip.
I'd rather go sunbathing.
You be careful. That's extonic sunlight.
Oh, I'm safe. It says in the brochure
this glass is 15 feet thick.
All right. I give up.
I'll be back for dinner. We'll try that
anti gravity restaurant, with bibs.
That's a date. Well, not a date.
Oh, you know what I mean. Oh, get off.
-See you later.
-0j!
And you be careful, all right?
Nah! Taking a big space truck
with a bunch of strangers
across a diamond planet called Midnight?
What could possibly go wrong?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
HOSTESS: Complimentary juice pack
and complimentary headphones.
WOMAN: Just the headphones, please.
There you go.
That's the headphones
for channels 1 to 36.
Mobile link for 3D vidgames,
complimentary earplugs,
complimentary slippers,
complimentary juice pack
and complimentary peanuts.
I must warn you that some
products may contain nuts.
-That'd be the peanuts.
-Enjoy your trip.
Oh, I can't wait. Allons-y.
-I'm sorry?
-It's French for "let's go".
Fascinating.
-Headphones for channels 1 to 36...
-No, thank you. Not for us.
Earplugs, please. Thank you.
They call it the sapphire waterfall,
but it's no such thing.
Sapphire's an aluminium oxide,
but the glacier is just a compound
silicon with iron pigmentation.
-Juice packs?
-Oh, thank you.
-Yes, certainly.
-And the pills.
All measured out for you. There you go.
-Hobbes. Professor Winfold Hobbes.
-I'm the Doctor. Hello.
-It's my 14th time.
-Oh, my first.
-And I'm Dee Dee. Dee Dee Blasco.
-Don't bother the man.
Where's my water bottle?
...complimentary slippers,
complimentary juice pack
and complimentary peanuts.
I must warn you that some
products may contain nuts.
Don't be silly. Come and sit with us.
Look, we get slippers.
-Jethro, do what your mother says.
-I'm sitting here.
Oh, he's ashamed of us,
but he doesn't mind us paying, does he?
Oh, don't you two start.
Shall I save the juice pack
or have it now?
Look, peach and clementine.
Ladies and gentlemen
and variations thereupon,
welcome on board the Crusader 50.
If you would fasten your seat belts,
we'll be leaving any moment.
Doors.
(BEEPING)
Shields down.
I'm afraid the view is shielded
until we reach the Waterfall Palace.
Also, a reminder.
Midnight has no air, so please
don't touch the exterior door seals.
Fire exit at the rear
and should we need to use it, you first.
Now I will hand you over to Driver joe.
Driver Joe at the wheel.
There's been a diamond fall
at the Winter Witch Canyon,
so we'll be taking a slight detour,
as you'll see on the map.
The journey covers 500 kliks
to the multifaceted coast.
Duration is estimated at four hours.
Thank you for travelling with us
and, as they used to say
in the olden days, "Wagons roll.”
(BEEPING)
For your entertainment, we have
the music channel playing retrovids
of Earth classics.
Also, the latest artistic installation
from Ludovic Klein.
Plus for the youngsters, a rare treat.
The animation archives.
Four hours of fun time. Enjoy.
(MUSIC, ANIMATION
AND ART EXHIBITION ALL BLARING)
# Do it, do it again
Do it, do it again... #
(MUSIC STOPS)
Well, that's a mercy.
Uh, I do apologise, ladies and gentlemen
and variations thereupon.
We seem to have had a failure
of the entertainment system.
-Oh!
-Well, what do we do?
We've got four hours of this?
Four hours of just sitting here?
Tell you what. We'll have to
talk to each other instead.
(ALL LAUGHING)
So Biff said, "I'm going swimming."
Oh, I was all ready.
Trunks and everything. Noseplug.
He had this little nose plug.
You should have seen him.
And I went marching up to the lifequard,
and he was a Shamboni,
-you know, with those big foreheads.
-Great big forehead!
And I said, "Where's the pool?”
And he said, "The pool is abstract.”
-It wasn't a real pool!
-It was a concept.
-And you were wearing your nose plug?
-I was like this.
I'm just a second year student,
but I wrote a paper on
the lost moon of Poosh.
Professor Hobbes read it, liked it,
took me on as researcher,
just for the holidays.
Well, he said researcher,
but most of the time
he's got me fetching and carrying.
But it's all good experience.
-And did they ever find it?
-Find what?
-The lost moon of Poosh.
-No, not yet.
Well, maybe that'll be
your great discovery one day.
-Here's to Poosh.
-Poosh.
No, no. I'm with this
friend of mine, Donna.
She stayed behind in the Leisure Palace.
You?
No. It's just me.
Oh, I've done plenty of that,
travelling on my own.
I love it.
Do what you want, go anywhere.
I'm still getting used to it.
I've found myself single
rather recently, not by choice.
-What happened?
-Oh, the usual.
She needed her own space, as they say.
A different galaxy, in fact.
I reckon that's enough space, don't you?
Yeah.
I had a friend who went to
a different universe.
-Well, what's this? Chicken or beef?
-I think it's both.
So this is Midnight.
Do you see? Bombarded by the sun.
Extonic rays, raw galvanic radiation.
Dee Dee, next slide.
It's my pet project.
Actually, I'm the first person
to research this because, you see,
the history is fascinating
because there is no history.
There is no life in this entire system.
There couldn't be.
Before the Leisure Palace Company
moved in,
no one had come here in all eternity.
No living thing.
But how do you know?
I mean, if no one can go outside...
Oh, his imagination. Here we go.
-He's got a point, though.
-Exactly.
We look upon this world through glass,
safe inside our metal box.
Even the Leisure Palace
was lowered down from orbit.
And here we are now, crossing Midnight,
but never touching it.
(BANGING AND RATTLING)
We've stopped.
Have we stopped?
-BIFF: Are we there?
-We can't be. It's too soon.
HOBBES: No, they don't stop.
Crusader vehicles never stop.
If you could just return to your seats,
it's just a small delay.
Well, may be just a pit stop.
There's no pit to stop in.
I've been on this expedition 14 times.
They never stop.
Well, evidently we have stopped,
so there's no point in denying it.
We've broken down.
-Thanks, Jethro.
-In the middle of nowhere.
That's enough. Now stop it.
Ladies and gentlemen
and variations thereupon,
we're just experiencing a short delay.
The driver needs to stabilise
the engine feeds.
It's perfectly routine, so if you
could just stay in your seats...
-No, I'm sorry, sir, I...
-There you go. Engine expert. Two ticks.
Sorry, if you could just sit down...
You're not supposed to be in there!
Sorry. If you could return
to your seat, sir.
Company insurance. Let's see
if we can get an early assessment.
So what's the problem, Driver Joe?
We're stabilising the engine feeds.
Won't take long.
Um, no, because that's the engine feed,
that line there, and it's fine.
And it's a micro petrol engine, so
stabilising doesn't make sense, does it?
Sorry, I'm a doctor. I'm very clever.
So what's wrong?
We've just stopped.
Look, all systems fine.
Everything's working,
but we're not moving.
Yeah, you're right.
No faults. And who are you?
Claude. I'm the mechanic, trainee.
-Nice to meet you.
-I've sent a distress signal.
They should dispatch a rescue truck,
top speed.
-How long till they get here?
-About an hour.
Well, since we're waiting,
should we take a look outside?
Uh...
Lift the screen a bit.
It's 100 percent extonic out there.
We'd be vapourised.
No! Those windows are Finitoglass.
They'll give you a couple of minutes.
Go on. Live a little.
CLAUDE: Wow.
DOCTOR: That is beautiful.
CLAUDE: Look at all those diamonds,
poisoned by the sun.
-No one can ever touch them.
-Joe, you said we took a detour.
-Just about 40 clicks to the west.
-Is that a recognised path?
No, it's a new one.
The computer worked it out on automatic.
So we're the first.
This piece of ground,
no one's ever been here before.
-Not in the whole of recorded history.
-Did you just...
-No, sorry. It was nothing.
-What did you see?
Just there, that ridge.
Like a shadow, just for a second.
What sort of shadow?
(ALARM BEEPING)
Extonic rising. Shields down.
-Look, look, there it is! There it is!
-Where!
What was it?
Just something shifting,
something sort of dark,
like it was running.
-Running which way?
-Towards us.
Right, Doctor. Back to your seat.
And, uh, not a word.
Rescue's on its way.
If you could close the door. Thank you.
What did they say? Did they tell you?
What is it? What's wrong?
Oh, just stabilising.
Happens all the time.
I don't need this. I'm on a schedule.
This is completely unnecessary.
Back to your seats. Thank you.
Excuse me, Doctor.
They're micro petrol engines,
aren't they?
-Now, don't bother the man.
-My father was a mechanic.
Micropetrol doesn't stabilise.
What does stabilise mean?
Well, a bit of flim-flam.
Don't worry, they're sorting it out.
-So it's not the engine?
-Just a little pause, that's all.
-How much air have we got?
-Professor, it's fine.
-What did he say?
-Nothing.
VAL: Are we running out of air?
HOBBES: I was just speculating.
Is that right, miss?
Are we running out of air?
-Is that what the captain said?
-If you could all just remain calm...
-How much air have we got?
-Mum, just stop it.
-Everything is under control.
-It doesn't look like it.
-He said it!
-It's fine!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Quiet!
Thank you.
Now, if you care to listen
to my good friend Dee Dee...
Oh, um...
It's just that, well,
the air's on a circular filter,
so we could stay breathing for 10 years.
DOCTOR: There you go.
And I've spoken to the captain.
I can guarantee you, everything's fine.
(POUNDING)
What was that?
It must be the metal.
We're cooling down. It's just settling.
Rocks. Could be rocks falling.
What I want to know is
how long do we have to sit here?
(POUNDING)
What is that?
-There's someone out there.
-Don't be ridiculous.
Like I said, it could be rocks.
We're out in the open.
Nothing could fall against the sides.
(POUNDING)
-Knock, knock.
-Who's there?
Is there something out there?
Well, anyone?
(POUNDING)
What the hell is making that noise?
I'm sorry, but the light
out there is extonic.
That means it would destroy
any living thing in a split second.
It is impossible for
someone to be outside.
(POUNDING)
Well, what the hell is that, then?
Sir, you really should
get back to your seat.
Hello.
(POUNDING)
It's moving.
(RATTLING)
It's trying the door.
There is no "it".
There's nothing out there. Can't be.
(CLANGING)
(BANGING)
(POUNDING)
That's the entrance. Can it get in?
No. That door's on 200-weight hydronics.
-Stop it. Don't encourage them.
-Well, what do you think it is?
-VAL: Biff, don't!
-Mr Kane, better not.
It's cast iron, that door.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Three times! Did you hear that?
It did it three times.
It did it three times!
All right, all right,
everyone calm down.
Yeah, but it answered. It answered.
Don't tell me that thing's not alive.
It answered him.
(BANGING)
I really must insist
you get back to your seats!
No, don't just stand there
telling us the rules!
You're the hostess!
You're supposed to do something!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What the hell's making that noise?
She said she'd get me.
Stop it! Make it stop! Make it stop!
Don't just stand there looking at me.
It's not my fault. He started it with...
-Calm down!
-...he made it worse!
Why couldn't you leave it alone?
Stop staring at me!
-The rescue's coming...
-Calm down!
(POUNDING)
It's coming for me.
Oh, it's coming for me.
It's coming for me!
It's coming for me.
(POUNDING)
Get out of there!
(ALL GRUNTING)
All right? Okay.
Arms, legs, neck, head, nose. I'm fine.
Everyone else?
How are we? Everyone all right?
HOBBES: Earthquake, must be.
But that's impossible.
The ground is fixed. It's solid.
We've got torches.
Everyone take a torch.
They're in the back of the seats.
Oh, Jethro. Sweetheart, come here.
Never mind me. What about her?
VAL: What's happened to the seats?
BIFF: Who did that?
VAL: They've been ripped up.
It's all right, it's all right,
it's all right, it's over.
We're still alive.
Look, the wall's still intact, eh?
-HOSTESS: Joe, Claude?
-We're safe.
Driver Joe, can you hear me?
I'm not getting any response.
The intercom must be down.
What happened? What was that?
Is it the driver?
Have we lost the driver?
-The cabin's gone.
-Don't be ridiculous.
It can't be gone. How can it be gone?
-You saw it.
-There was nothing there.
-Like it was ripped away.
-What are you doing?
That's better. A little bit of light.
Thank you. Motto bene.
Do you know what you're doing?
The cabin's gone.
You better leave that wall alone.
-The cabin can't be gone.
-No, it's safe.
Any rupture would automatically
seal itself.
Unless something sliced it off.
-You're right, the cabin's gone.
-But if it gets separated...
It loses integrity.
I'm sorry. They've been reduced to dust.
The driver and the mechanic.
They sent a distress signal.
Help is on its way.
They saved our lives.
We are gonna get out of here, I promise.
We're still alive
and they're gonna find us.
Doctor, look at her.
Right, yeah, sorry.
Have we got a medical kit?
JETHRO: Why won't she turn around?
-HOBBES: What's her name?
-Silvestry. Mrs Sky Silvestry.
Sky?
Can you hear me?
You're all right.
Can you move, Sky?
Just look at me.
That noise from outside, it's stopped.
-Well, thank God for that.
-But what if it's not outside any more?
-What if it's inside?
-Inside? Where?
It was heading for her.
Sky?
It's all right, Sky.
Just want you to turn around, face me.
Sky?
Sky.
-Are you all right?
-Are you hurt?
-You don't have to talk.
-I'm trying to help.
-My name's the Doctor.
-Okay, can you stop?
-I'd like you to stop.
-Why's she doing that?
-She's gone mad.
-Stop it.
-1 said, stop It.
-I don't think she can.
-Now stop it. This isn't funny.
-Shh, shh, shh, all of you.
-My name's Jethro.
-Jethro, leave it. Just shut up.
-Why are you repeating?
-What is that? Learning?
-Copying?
-Absorbing.
The square root of piis 1.77...
BOTH: ...of pi is 1.77245385090551602729
8167483341.
Wow.
-But that's impossible.
-She couldn't repeat it.
-Tell her to stop.
-She's driving me mad.
-Just make her stop.
-Stop staring at me.
(ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
Now, stop. Stop it, all of you.
(ALL TALKING)
-666.
Make her stop.
(HUMMING)
-That's the backup system.
-Well, that's a bit better.
What about the rescue?
How long's it going to take?
About 60 minutes, that's all.
Then I suggest we all calm down.
This panic isn't helping.
And that poor woman
is evidently in a state of...
(ECHO) ...self-induced hysteria.
We should leave her...
Doctor.
I know.
Doctor, now step back.
-I think you should leave her...
-Leave her...
Alone.
What's she doing?
-How could she do that?
-She's talking with you.
And with me.
Oh, my God! Biff, what's she doing?
She's repeating.
At exactly the same time.
That's impossible.
There's not even a delay.
Oh, man, that is weird.
I think you should all be
very, very quiet.
-Have you got that?
-How's she doing it?
-Mrs Kane, please be quiet.
-How can she do that?
She's got my voice! She's got my words!
Darling, be quiet. Hush, now, hush.
She's doing it to me.
Just stop it.
All of you, stop it, please.
Now then, Sky, are you Sky?
Is Sky still in there? Mrs Silvestry?
You know exactly what I'm going to say.
How are you doing that?
Roast beef.
Bananas.
The Medusa Cascade.
Bang!
Rose Tyler, Martha Jones,
Donna Noble, Tardis.
Shamble, bobble, dibble, dooble.
Oh, Doctor, you're so handsome.
Yes, I am. Thank you.
A K Mo.
First she repeats, then she catches up.
What's the next stage?
Next stage of what?
It's not her, is it?
That's not Mrs Silvestry any more.
I don't think so, no.
(SOBBING)
I think the more we talk,
the more she learns.
Now, I'm all for education,
but in this case, maybe not.
Let's just move back.
Come on, come with me.
Everyone, get back, all of you,
as far as you can.
Doctor, make her stop.
Val, come with me.
Come to the back. Stop looking at her.
Come on. Jethro, you, too.
Everyone, come on.
50 minutes, that's all we need.
50 minutes till the rescue arrives and
she's not exactly strong. Look at her.
-All she's got is our voices.
-I can't look at her. It's those eyes.
We must not look at goblin men.
-What's that supposed to mean?
-It's a poem, Christina Rossetti.
"We must not look at goblin men,
We must not buy their fruits:
"Who knows upon what soil they fed
Their hungry thirsty roots?"
-Actually, I don't think that's helping.
-She's not a goblin or a monster.
-She's just a very sick woman.
-Maybe that's why it went for her.
-There is no "it".
-Think about it, though.
That knocking went all the way
around the bus until it found her.
And she was the most
scared out of all of us.
Maybe that's what it needed.
That's how it got in.
For the last time, nothing can
live on the surface of Midnight.
Professor, I'm glad
you've got an absolute definition
of life in the universe, but perhaps
the universe has got ideas of its own.
Now trust me, I've got previous.
I think there might well be some
consciousness inside Mrs Silvestry,
but maybe she's still in there
and it's our job to help her.
-You can help, but I'm not going near.
-No, I've got to stay back.
'Cause if she's copying us, then
maybe the final stage is becoming us.
I don't want her becoming me
or things could get a whole lot worse.
-Oh, like you're so special.
-As it happens, yes, I am.
So that's decided.
We stay back and we wait.
When the rescue ship comes,
we can get her to hospital.
We should throw her out.
I beg your pardon?
-Can we do that?
-Don't be ridiculous.
That thing, whatever it is,
killed the driver and the mechanic
and I don't think she's finished yet.
-She can't even move.
-Look at her. Look at her eyes.
She killed Joe and she killed Claude
and we're next.
She's still doing it.
Just stop it! Stop talking! Stop it!
-Biff, don't, sweetheart!
-But she won't stop!
We can't throw her out, though.
We can't even open the doors.
No one is getting thrown out.
Yes, we can
'cause there's an air pressure seal.
Like when you opened the cabin door,
you weren't pulled out.
You had a couple of seconds
'cause it takes the pressure wall
about six seconds to collapse.
Well, six seconds exactly.
That's enough time to throw someone out.
Thanks, Dee Dee. Just what we needed.
-Would it kill her outside?
-I don't know.
But she's got a body now.
It'd certainly kill the physical...
No one is killing anyone!
I wouldn't risk the cabin door twice,
but we've got that one.
All we need to do is grab
hold of her and throw her out.
Now listen, all of you, for all we know
that's a brand-new life form over there
and if it's come inside to discover us,
then what's it found?
This little bunch of humans.
What do you amount to? Murder?
'Cause this is where you decide.
You decide who you are.
Could you actually murder her,
any of you?
Really?
Or are you better than that?
I'd do it.
-So would I.
-And me.
-I think we should.
-What?
-I want her out.
-You can't say that.
I'm sorry,
but you said it yourself, Doctor.
-She's growing in strength.
-That's not what I said.
I wanna go home.
I'm sorry. I want to be safe.
You'll be safe. Any minute now.
The rescue truck is on its way.
And what happens then, Doctor?
If it takes that thing back
to the Leisure Palace,
if that thing reaches civilisation,
what if it spreads?
No, because when we get back to
the base, I'll be there to contain it.
You haven't done much so far.
He's just standing at the back
with the rest of us.
She's dangerous.
It's my job to see that this vessel
is safe. We should get rid of her.
Now hang on. I think perhaps
we're all going a little bit too far.
-At last! Thank you.
-Two people are dead!
Don't make it a third!
Jethro, what do you say?
-I'm not killing anyone.
-Thank you.
-He's just a boy.
-What, so I don't get a vote?
There isn't a vote.
It's not happening, ever!
If you try to throw her out that door,
you'll have to get past me first.
-Okay.
-Fine by me.
Oh, now you're being stupid.
Just think about it.
Could you actually take hold of someone
and throw them out of that door?
Calling me a coward?
-Who put you in charge anyway?
-I'm sorry.
-You're a doctor of what exactly?
-He wasn't even booked in.
The rest of you, tickets in advance,
he just turned up out of the blue.
VAL: Where from?
I'm just travelling.
I'm a traveller, that's all.
-Like an immigrant?
-Who were you talking to?
Before you got on board, you were
talking to someone. Who was that?
Just Donna. Just my friend.
-What were you saying to her?
-He hasn't even told us his name.
The thing is though, Doctor,
you've been loving this.
Oh, Jethro, not you.
No, but ever since all the trouble
has started, you've been loving it.
It has to be said,
you do seem to have a certain glee.
All right, I'm interested, yes.
I can't help it.
'Cause whatever's inside her,
it's brand-new and that's fascinating.
What, you wanted this to happen?
-No!
-You were talking to her.
All on your own, before all the trouble,
right at the front,
you were talking to that Sky woman,
the two of you together.
-I saw you!
-We all did.
-You went into the cabin.
-What were you saying to her?
-I was just talking.
-Saying what?
You called us "humans”,
like you're not one of us.
-That's what he said.
-And the wiring.
He went into that panel
and opened up the wiring.
-That was after.
-But how did you know what to do?
Because I'm clever!
I see.
-Well, that makes things clear.
-And what are we, then? Idiots?
-That's not what I meant.
-If you're clever, then what are we?
You've been looking down on us
from the moment we walked in.
Even if he goes,
he's practically volunteered.
Oh, come on!
Just listen to yourselves, please!
Do you mean... We throw him out as well.
If we have to.
Look, just...
Hang on, sorry, yes, hold on, just...
I know you're scared.
And so am I. Look at me, I am.
But we have all got to calm down
and cool off and think.
-Perhaps you could tell us your name.
-What does it matter?
-Then tell us.
-John Smith.
-Your real name.
-He's lying. Look at his face.
-His eyes are the same as hers.
-Why won't you tell us?
It's a symptom.
He's been lying to us
right from the start!
No one's called John Smith.
Come off it!
Listen to me right now
because you need me, all of you!
If we are going to get out of this,
then you need me!
So you keep saying. You've been
repeating yourself more than her.
If anyone's in charge, it should
be the professor. He's the expert!
Mum, just stop. Just look.
-You keep out of this, Jethro.
-Look at her!
She's stopped.
-When did she...
-No, she's still doing it.
She looks the same to me.
No. She's stopped.
-Look, I'm talking and she's not.
-BIFF: What about me? Is she...
Look. Look at that.
She's not doing me. She's let me go.
Mrs Silvestry?
Nor me. Nothing.
-Sky?
-What are you doing?
She's still doing him.
Doctor, it's you.
She's only copying you.
-Why me? Why are you doing this?
VAL: She won't leave him alone.
Do you see?
-I said so. She's with him.
-They're together.
How do you explain it, Doctor?
If you're so clever...
-I don't know.
-Sky, stop it.
-I said, stop it. Just stop it.
Look at the two of them.
BOTH: Mrs Silvestry,
I'm trying to understand.
You've captured my speech.
What for?
What do you need?
You need my voice in particular.
The cleverest voice in the room.
Why? Because I'm the only one
who can help?
Oh, I'd love that to be true.
But your eyes,
they're saying something else.
Listen to me, whatever you want,
if it's Llife or form
or consciousness or voice,
you don't have to steal it.
You can find it without hurting anyone.
And I'll help you.
That's a promise.
So, what do you think?
SKY: Do we have a deal?
DOCTOR: Do we have a deal?
-Hold on. Did she...
-She spoke first.
-She can't have.
-She did. She spoke first.
Oh, look at that.
-Oh, look at that. I'm ahead of you.
-I'm ahead of you.
Did you see?
She spoke before he did, definitely.
He's copying her.
Doctor, what's happening?
SKY: I think it's moved.
I think it's moved.
-I think it's letting me go.
DEE DEE: What do you mean?
Letting you go from what?
BIFF: He's repeating now.
He's the one doing it. It's him.
JETHRO: He's separating.
Mrs Silvestry, is that you?
Yes. Yes. It's me.
-Yes. Yes. It's me.
-I'm coming back.
-Listen, it's me.
-I'm coming back. Listen, it's me.
It's like it's passed into the Doctor.
It's transferred.
Whatever it is, it's gone inside him.
No, that's not what happened.
Look at her.
Look at me.
-I can move.
-Look at me.
I can feel again.
-I'm coming back to life.
-I can move.
I can feel again.
-And look at him.
-I'm coming back to life.
-He can't move.
-And look at him.
He can't move.
-Help me.
-Professor.
-Get me away from him.
-Please.
Oh, thank you!
JETHRO: They've completely separated.
BIFF: It's in him.
Do you see?
I said it was him all the time.
She's free. She's been saved.
-Oh, it was so cold.
-It was so cold.
-I couldn't breathe.
-I'm sorry.
-I must have scared you so much.
No, it's all right. I've got you.
Oh, there you are, my love. It's gone.
-Everything's all right.
-I wouldn't touch her.
But it's gone. She's clean.
It passed into him.
-That's not what happened.
-Thank you for your opinion, Dee,
but clearly Mrs Silvestry
has been released.
-No!
-Just leave her alone.
She's safe, isn't she?
-Jethro, it's let her go, hasn't it?
-Think so, yeah. Looks like it.
Professor?
I'd say, from observation,
the Doctor can't move,
and when she was possessed,
she couldn't move, so...
Well, there we are, then.
Now the only problem
we've got is this Doctor.
-It's inside his head.
-DOCTOR: It's inside his head.
-It killed the driver.
-And the mechanic.
-And now it wants us.
I said so.
-He's waited so long.
-In the dark...
-...and the cold...
-...and the diamonds...
-...until you came.
-Bodies so hot...
-...with blood...
-...and pain.
God, make him stop.
Someone make him stop.
-But she's saying it!
-And you can shut up!
But it's not him, it's her!
He's just repeating.
But that's what the thing does.
It repeats.
Let her talk.
What do you know?
Fat lot of good you've been.
Just let her explain.
Well, I think,
I mean, from what I've seen,
it repeats, then it synchronises,
then it goes on to the next stage
and that's exactly what
the Doctor said would happen.
-What, and you're on his side?
-No!
JETHRO: The voice is the thing.
DEE DEE: And she's the voice.
She stole it! Look at her.
It's not possessing him,
it's draining him.
She's got his voice.
That's not true 'cause it can't be
"cause I saw it pass into him.
-I saw it with my own eyes.
-So did I.
-DEE DEE: You didn't.
-It went from her to him.
-You saw it, didn't you?
-I don't know.
VAL: Oh, don't be stupid, Jethro!
Of course you did!
-I suppose he was right next to her.
-Everyone saw it! Everyone!
You're just making it up.
I know what I saw
and I saw her stealing his voice.
She's as bad as him.
Someone shut her up.
-I think you should be quiet, Dee Dee.
-I'm only saying...
And that's an order!
You're making a fool of yourself,
pretending you're an expert in mechanics
and hydraulics when I can tell you,
you are nothing
more than average at best.
Now shut up!
-That's how he does it.
-He makes you fight.
-Creeps into your head...
-...and whispers.
-Listen.
-Just listen.
-That's him.
-Inside.
BIFF: Throw him out.
VAL: Get him out of my head!
We should throw him out.
Don't just talk about it.
Just... You're useless!
-Do something!
-I will!
You watch me.
I'm going to throw him out.
-Yes!
-Throw him out!
-Get rid of him!
-Now!
-Don't!
-It'll be you next.
I don't think we should do this.
-It was your idea. Professor, help me.
-I can't...
What sort of a man are you? Come on!
-Throw him out!
-Come on!
Just do it! Throw him out!
-Professor, help me!
-Get him out!
Grab hold of him!
Not like that! Are you stupid?
-Cast him out.
-Into the sun.
I want him out!
-And the night.
Help me! Get him out!
(ALL SHOUTING)
-Get him out!
-Do it!
-Do it.
-Do it now.
-Faster.
-Just do it!
-That's the way.
-You can do it.
Motto bene!
-Throw him out!
-Motto bene!
-Get him out!
-Allons-y.
Allons-y.
-That's his voice!
-The starlight waits!
It's taken his voice!
-The emptiness.
-Get him out!
-The Midnight sky.
It's her.
-Throw him out!
-Get him out!
She's taken his voice!
One, two, three, four, five, six...
It's gone. It's gone.
It's gone. It's gone. It's gone.
I said it was her.
WOMAN: Repeat, Crusader 50,
rescue vehicle coming alongside
in three minutes.
Door seals set to automatic.
Prepare for boarding.
Repeat, prepare for boarding.
The hostess.
What was her name?
I don't know.
DONNA: What do you think it was?
No idea.
Do you think it's still out there?
Well, you'd better tell them, this lot.
Yeah. They can build
a Leisure Palace somewhere else.
Let this planet keep on turning
round an extonic star,
in silence.
Can't imagine you without a voice.
Motto bene.
No. Don't do that.
Don't.
Found a body, sir.
The Doctor is dead.
How could anything be worse than this?
What happened? What did they find?
Oh, my God. The stars are going out.
-Who are you?
-I was like you.
Turn around! Show me your face!
I've been pulled across
from a different universe
'cause every single universe
is in danger.
There's something on your back!
What am I supposed to do?
Powering up!
None of this is meant to happen.
You're going to die.