We're in the very far future.
RYAN: Seven humans left.
Cyberdrones.
(SCREAMING)
No!
Go with the humans. Help them.
Get them out of here.
You won't make it
back to the TARDIS alive.
We know where you are.
We will find you.
The Boundary - it's where
we've been trying to get to.
A gateway, a direct route
out of here
into another random part
of the universe.
Whoa! Wow!
Be afraid, Doctor,
because everything
is about to change.
DOCTOR: How are you here?
MASTER: Take my hand.
Never.
Take my hand
or I turn them into
tiny human dolls right here.
How have you connected
Gallifrey to that Boundary?
Fine. You really want me
to show you I'm serious?
Eenie, meenie, miney...
Miney.
Fine, I'll play your game.
- I'll be back.
- She won't.
And it's not a game.
Good luck, humans.
RYAN: We have to go
through there.
- We have to go and get her.
- No,
we have to wait for the others.
(RUMBLING)
They're here.
(BESCOT GRUNTS)
- Over here!
- Go, go, go, go!
BESCOT: I'll cover you!
Come on! Bescot!
Argh!
No!
The ship is ours.
Look upon my work, Doctor,
and despair.
Remember how we used to run
through those streets
as children?
The alleys where we'd hide
from Borusa
as we skipped classes?
All gone now.
Come on,
ask me why I did this.
Why did you do this?
Not telling you. (LAUGHS)
Oh, crack a smile.
- Proud of yourself?
- Definitely.
All this death -
finally made you happy?
Ecstatic.
And has it calmed all the rage?
I don't think
anything will ever do that.
We're going to take a tour
through the capital,
or its ruins, at least.
Things I need to show you.
And, um, I know you're worried
about your friends.
Plotting how to get away.
I can see it in your eyes.
But you can't help them,
so don't even think about it.
Down you come. That's it.
Yaz, come on.
Where's Bescot?
They killed her.
We have to go back for her.
No, no, no.
No, you can't do that, mate.
Listen, don't tell me
what I can't do.
She had nightmares
about being captured
and converted.
I can't let that happen.
Do you really think
that she would want you
to go back there
and risk your life?
I owe her. And what difference
does it make anyway?
We don't stand a chance here.
We are stuck on a ship
stacked with Cybermen.
Four humans sticking out
on every surveillance system
they've got.
He's right,
and I've been thinking
about that. I've got an idea.
It's a bit of a mad one -
quite dangerous
and it might not work -
but we've got form with plans
like that, ain't we, Yaz?
Yeah, our speciality.
How dangerous?
GRAHAM: We use their arm our
so they don't notice us.
That way, we can move around
and get off the ship.
So you want us to disguise
ourselves as Cybermen?
Have you ever opened one up?
Well, I guess
it won't be pleasant.
They're full of human remains.
Well, I don't need it
spelling out, do I?
You can't fake being a Cyberman
for any length of time.
We only need to do it
for long enough
to get us out of here.
If you do the bodies,
I could disable
the suit connection
into the shared neural network.
It's insane.
Well, I didn't say it was
a perfect plan, did I?
But it is
the best one we've got.
This is my weapon store.
This all you got?
Well, it's quite hard
to get deliveries out here,
you know.
I had hoped I'd fought
my last battle a long time ago.
Still... (CHUCKLES)
This old general
still knows a few tricks.
I'm not too sure about weapons.
Yeah, well,
I'm sure about Cybermen.
Now, you fight them or you die.
They don't have any mercy.
You can be a pacifist tomorrow.
Today, you have to survive.
MASTER: Ah!
The Citadel,
the heart of Gallifrey.
Recognise the old place?
I was thinking
I might knock through there,
put a wet room there,
screening room there.
(CHUCKLES)
Torture room in the cellar,
naturally.
Oh.
And see through there?
The Panopticon.
Well, what's left, which, uh...
...which isn't much.
We had some fun there,
didn't we, eh?
Graduated.
Assassinated presidents.
(GIGGLES)
The best of times!
But I thought here would be
a fitting place to end this.
(CHIMES)
Oh. Oop. Excuse me.
Check my notifications.
(BEEPS)
Oh, goo die!
The Cybermen are here,
at the Boundary.
Better extend
the hand of friendship.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Breaker 1-2 calling all Cybes.
Calling all Cybes.
CYBERGUARD: Leader,
incoming holo-transmission
from beyond the Boundary.
(EXHALES EXCITEDLY)
Hello, Cybercarrier!
Ooh, you look rough.
Or is that a choice?
Don't mean
to conversion-shame you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Who are you?
You may call me Master.
I want you to think of me
as your new best friend.
Now,
the Boundary between worlds,
this...
...beautiful anomalous fluke -
come through it.
Join me.
Why would we join you?
Because I have a planet
going spare right here.
The planet formerly known
as Gallifrey.
No. Don't bring them here.
This is between you and me.
(BUZZES)
Don't heckle, dear.
I can always decide
to cut you short.
I promise
I'll roll out the red carpet.
It's red because it's drenched
in the blood of our people.
(GIGGLES)
I've sent you
the navigation patterns.
Come right to the hearts.
Do what so many
of your predecessors
fantasised about...
Land your ship
in the ruins of Gallifrey.
On the way through,
you should send
a death squadron.
Do you call it
a death squadron?
A deletion squad.
No, a recruitment patrol,
a human-juicing party,
to eliminate the three humans
left alive on that planet.
They're weak.
It shouldn't take much.
See you in a bit.
Send three execution units
to the surface.
And set course for Gallifrey.
KO SHARMUS ON COMMS:
Here they come.
Gird your loins, gentlemen.
Uh... I don't...
- I don't how to do that.
- Me neither.
RAVIO: Transmat.
KO SHARMUS: As my first
commanding officer used to say,
"Be brave.
"Be swift
"Most of all, be lucky."
(ELECTRIC ZAPPING AND DRILLING)
(DRILLING CONTINUES)
All right?
Yeah, yeah. You?
Yeah.
Listen, Yaz, um...
If we don't get out of this...
- We will get out of this.
- Yeah, well...
I know, but I'm just saying,
if we don't...
...] want you to know I...
I think you're
such an impressive young woman.
Never thrown by anything.
Always fighting.
Thanks.
You said to the Doc
that you thought
she was the best person
you'd ever met.
You know what, Yaz?
I think you are.
You ain't got a time machine
or a sonic...
...but you're never afraid
and you're never beaten.
I'm going to sound like a...
...like a proper old man,
but you're doing
your family proud, Yaz,
you really are.
In fact, you're doing
the whole human race proud.
S-Sorry.
I haven't offended you, have I?
It's the nicest thing
anyone's ever said to me.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
You're not such a bad human
yourself either.
(INDIGNANT) Not su...?
Is that it?
I've just said all them
lovely things about you,
and all you give me is,
"You're not such a bad human"?
Mate, I'm from Yorkshire -
that's a love letter.
We're ready.
GRAHAM: Oh, OK.
(GRUNTS)
(RAPID BEEPING)
Leader, unit malfunction
in deep storage vault
Micron-Alpha.
Show surveillance.
Surveillance unavailable,
Leader.
- The humans.
- Shall I activate a unit?
No. They are mine.
Why would you give Gallifrey
to the Cybermen?
You're about to have
much bigger things
to think about.
I told you before
that everything you knew
was a lie.
Well, now you get
to face the truth,
with me at your side.
Do you really think
I'm going to believe
anything that comes
out of your mouth?
Do you remember this place,
Doctor?
Next to the Panopticon,
the Chamber of the Matrix,
the Repository
of all Time Lord knowledge,
a data bank of
every Time Lord consciousness,
living and dead.
Every experience
and every memory.
The lived history of our race.
I...I destroyed a lot
of things, but not this...
...trove of secrets.
This is what started it all.
I-T was just playing,
hacking the system.
(STAMMERS)
I-I got lost in there.
And then I found everything.
Ah!
Truth and reconciliation time,
Doctor.
Well, maybe not reconciliation.
But time you saw the truth
for yourself.
What truth?
(YELPS)
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
Paralysis field.
- (GROANS)
- (LAUGHS)
Whatever you want with me...
...fine.
But save my friends.
Don't let the Cybermen
take them.
If the history between us
means anything to you...
I do believe you're appealing
to my better nature.
And we both know
I don't have one.
I'm not going to help them,
and neither are you.
And the history between us
does mean something.
It's the rage and pain
in my hearts.
I'm sending you
deep into the Matrix
to understand the truth...
...of Gallifrey
and of the Time Lords.
Brace yourself.
This is going to hurt.
(MUFFLED BREATHING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(SNIFFS)
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
(METAL CLANKS)
(ON COMMS) Leader,
we are on optimal proximity
to Boundary.
Boundary gateway is reopening.
GRAHAM;
We've got to get off this ship.
(BREATHES SLOWLY)
MASTER: Welcome, Doctor.
Are you suffering comfortably?
Then, I'll begin.
Once upon a time...
No.
Once upon several times,
before the Time Lords,
before everything we know,
there was an explorer.
Her name was Tecteun...
...from a little-regarded,
sparsely populated planet
called Gallifrey.
Tecteun was the first
of Gallifrey's indigenous race,
the Shobogans,
to develop space travel.
Dangerous,
unsophisticated space travel.
She took risks to explore
the worlds and galaxies
beyond her home.
And it was on one of these
distant deserted worlds
on the far edge
of another galaxy
she found something...
...impossible.
A gateway.
A boundary into another
unknown dimension or universe.
Tecteun glimpsed the infinite
through that gateway.
And beneath the monument
she found...
...a child.
Abandoned.
Alone.
Thrown through, seemingly,
from the other unknown realm.
Tecteun had a choice to make -
abandon or save the child?
She chose
to rescue the foundling
and adopt this refugee
from another realm as her own.
Together,
they explored the universe.
The child grew older,
and finally Tecteun
returned to Gallifrey
with her new child.
Like any parent,
Tecteun wanted
to understand her child.
She searched for clues
as to the child's identity -
where she might be from,
what species she could be.
But the child would not yield
any secrets
Tecteun could understand.
The child remained a mystery...
.until...
Playing with a friend,
like any other child...
...there was an accident.
A catastrophe...
...Tor Tecteun,
for the child she'd saved,
now lost to her.
Or so she thought.
The child regenerated.
The first regeneration
of any person
on the planet of Gallifrey.
(LOW RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER)
Boundary force field gateway
now closed.
There is no escape for humans.
First trap's sprung. They fell
for the old bio-dampener
Decoy Human Signal trick -
textbook! (LAUGHS)
Thought they'd last longer
than that.
KO SHARMUS: All right, Ryan,
they're on the march.
You know what to do.
We're relying on you.
Did I mention I've never been
the greatest shot?
Now!
(TICKING)
Whoa! I did it!
In the hoop! Swish! (LAUGHS)
Great shot!
You come for humans,
you come for me,
Ryan Sinclair!
We defeated the Cybermen.
Well, me. Technically, it's me.
Oh!
There are always more.
Get inside now.
Now!
MASTER: Ah! Ah!
Come in.
Come in!
No, don't...don't worry
about her.
She's fully under my control.
Congratulations.
You have managed something
no other Cyberman
ever achieved,
maybe - maybe -
even dreamed of!
Gallifrey is yours.
Offered as a gift.
From an admiring Master.
I know our races
have been enemies.
I lived through
the Great Cyber War.
I saw the atrocities
perpetrated on your race.
I want to help put that right.
(SNIFFS)
Why?
I fear we have
a common interest.
The new Cyber-army
shall have one goal -
the destruction
of all organic life.
Ah! So that's your thinking.
But how are you going
to manage that?
The Death Particle.
One Particle, when activated,
capable of destroying
all organic life.
Very nice!
Ooh!
(PULSATES)
Did you make that?
The Cyberium created it...
...through me.
So you're the host...
...for all Cyber knowledge
and strategy.
Oh. Interesting.
Now, I hate to point out
the flaw in your plan -
Cybermen are part organic,
but you more than most.
My new Cyberwarriors
are purged
of organic components.
We shall rise towards
full automation,
driven by the intelligence
of the Cyberium.
And when that work is done...
...I shall join my warriors
and make the final ascension
to full mechanisation!
Oh, you mean robots.
You'll be robots.
We shall be dominant.
But robots.
Oof. I'm a bit disappointed.
I see how you got there -
an Al wanting to create
more things in its own image -
but it lacks vision.
Right, what if we, um,
workshop this?
You know, kick it around a bit?
I have notes.
You question the strategy
of the Cyberium?
I do. I mean, it's good,
but it's not great.
There's loads of robots.
Throw a stick in this universe,
you'll hit a robot.
I used to do that.
Any idiot can make themselves
into a robot.
It's not special.
(WHIRRING)
But if you want to be
the dominant force
in the universe...
...I can facilitate that.
(GROANS)
Explain.
How fast are the conversion
processes on your ship?
They have been restored
to optimal efficiency.
(GROANS) Good. Good, good.
Good.
Good!
Cos I burned the Citadel,
but if I have one weakness,
it's that I am...
...a bit of a hoarder.
Let me show you.
(GRUNTS)
She's waking up in that Matrix.
But don't worry,
my consciousness
can deal with her.
I'm that good -
I can be in two places at once.
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
Now, having seen
her adopted child
regenerate her body,
Tecteun,
a scientist and explorer,
had a new landscape to explore.
She dedicated her life
to studying her child.
Detailed every fragment
of genetic material.
It took her years...
...several of the child's
regenerations.
Tecteun grew older.
Her desire to understand
became an obsession.
She worked tirelessly,
endlessly, furiously.
She had to crack this code
to understand regeneration.
And finally...
...she did.
And to prove herself right,
she took the ultimate risk.
Tested the theory on herself.
Put her own life on the line.
(GRUNTS)
(BUZZING)
Spliced into herself
the genetic ability
to regenerate.
I didn't know any of this.
Did you know any of this?
(SIGHS) Nearly there.
The planet of Gallifrey
evolved.
Shobogans grew
in knowledge and ability.
They built themselves
the Citadel.
They discovered the ability
to travel through time
as well as space.
With Tecteun, they became
a self-appointed ruling elite.
And Tecteun proposed
that he gene-splice
the ability to regenerate
into future generations
of Citadel-dwellers.
It would become
the genetic inheritance of them
and their descendants.
But he would restrict
the regenerative process
to a maximum of 12 times.
The timeless child became
the base genetic code
for all Gallifreyans
within the citadel.
The civilisation
which renamed themselves -
with characteristic pomposity -
Time Lords.
The foundling
had become the founder.
The rest, as they say,
is history.
What happened to the child?
(CHUCKLES)
What?
What's so funny?
What happened to the child?!
Oh, Doctor, really?
Haven't you
worked this out yet?
The child is you.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
You are the timeless child.
(BREATH QUICKENS)
No.
No, I'm not.
You always have been.
I can't be.
(BREATH QUICKENS)
(SCREAMS)
KO SHARMUS: Come on, come on!
Hurry, hurry!
- This place is like a maze.
- I made it that way.
In case of an eventuality
like this.
Hey, you never think of doors?
Big, lockable doors.
Indestructible doors.
Dream of them every night!
But I had to work
with what I had.
Now...
Hide well,
take what shots you can.
Kill them before they kill you.
Go!
Three human life forms
detected.
(RATTLING)
- (KNOCKING)
- Hello.
Too many of them.
- One human located.
- No! No...
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
All humans will be executed.
(COCKS BLASTER)
(BLASTER POWERS UP)
- Oh! Oh, my days...
- Oh, my saints...
BOTH: Where's Ethan?
CYBERWARRIOR: Attention,
remaining humans.
We have your friend.
You have ten seconds
to surrender
or he will be executed.
- Don't come for me. Argh!
- Ten...
He's two pathways away.
This way.
Hey! We're coming!
We surrender!
- Stop!
- Five, four...
- I said, "We surrender!"
- ...three...
- We surrender!
- ...two, one...
- No!
- (BLASTS)
(METAL RATTLES)
I don't understand.
How about now?
GRAHAM: Uh, Yaz,
I can't...can't
get this hat off.
MASTER: Wow...
Wow.
Wow, wow, wow, wow!
Ah!
You have got a lot of these!
A whole Cybercarrier worth.
Perfect.
So, what's your plan now?
The Cyberium will process
and dictate the strategy.
The Cyberium?
I've heard a lot about that
over the millennia.
The heart of all your power.
The centre
of all Cyber knowledge.
(EXHALES)
Oh, come on, Cyberium,
show us some leg.
What do you actually
look like, hmm?
It will not leave me...
...while I live.
Oh.
OK.
(GASPS)
Well, aren't you pretty?
And fast.
You made your exit
very swiftly there.
Worried, were you?
I thought if he was compressed,
the Death Particle
would activate...
(SIGHS)
...and all this would be over.
I would've been OK with that.
I thought it was a nice little
gamble, but no. (GROANS)
Here we are.
All still alive.
And one miniaturised
Death Particle still in him,
waiting for its moment...
...for its chamber
to be smashed open.
Prrrksh!
Oh! (SNAPS)
Shoot!
I should've said, "Somebody
needs to cut you down to size",
then zapped you.
(GIGGLES)
I was just trigger-happy.
(SIGHS) I'll use it next time.
Sit there for a mo.
Oh, sorry, were you close?
Candidly,
I think you can do better.
I request an alliance.
I deserve to be
your business partner
because I have performed well
in all the tasks.
I ransacked the Matrix
of the Time Lords,
distilled all the knowledge,
all the experiences,
all the discoveries,
into these brains up here.
All the Cyber knowledge,
all the Time Lord knowledge...
(LAUGHS) Put it together,
what do you get?
Absolute supremacy
in the universe.
Choose me.
Oh, wow!
That was quick! (CACKLES)
Wa-ha-ha! Whoa!
Woohoo!
At least buy me...dinner!
(SHRIEKS)
(ECHOING LAUGHTER)
MASTER: This is no time
to be sleeping.
Is it hurting, Doctor?
I hope it's hurting,
because it really hurt me.
It's all lies.
None of this is the truth.
For the first time in my lives,
I can honestly say
every word is true.
I know my life.
I know...
I know who I am.
No, you don't. You never have.
Your life has been hidden
from you.
Our founding parents
wanted a noble creation myth
for the Time Lords.
"Born To Rule".
I remember my home.
I remember growing up.
I remember you and me
at the Academy together.
That happened.
It just wasn't your first life.
Why would they lie?!
Why would they do that?
I wish it wasn't true,
but it is.
You know what I find
the most infuriating?
You always behaved
like you were different,
like you were... like
you were special.
And you were.
You can see...
You can see why I'm angry.
(STAMMERS)
A little piece of you is in me.
AILT am is somehow
because of you,
and believe me when I say,
I cannot bear that!
Show me the rest.
I'm not sure you can cope
with much...
Show me the rest!
I have a right
to know my own life.
(LAUGHS)
All right.
But I'm not sure
it's going to make you happy.
The policy of the Time Lords
is clear -
strict non-intervention
in other worlds and times.
However...
Policy and reality
sometimes diverge.
There are times when
it is necessary to intervene.
That is the purpose
of The Division.
The tests we set you...
These results are the best
I've ever seen.
Those images.
Island. I've seen them...
...in my head.
What are they?
Sh-sh-sh-sh.
She's talking.
The Division does not exist.
The Division does not
have operatives.
We are not even here.
Do you understand?
I propose...
What have you done?
Not me.
That was done
long before I got here.
Everything from here
is redacted, blocked out,
all but erased.
There was something here.
A lot of stuff, seemingly,
but now it all
just looks like this.
I tried everything,
everything, to decode it,
but it's...it's unrecoverable,
beyond even my brilliance.
And it's not often I say that.
(CHUCKLES)
But it's my life.
Yeah.
How much was lost?
Impossible to tell.
It took up a lot of space
in the Matrix, though.
Yeah.
There is one final trace.
Those glitches of Island
you keep seeing.
Those images, they were buried
deep in the Matrix.
Tecteun put
a visual filter over it
so that no-one who watched it
would find it remarkable.
(YELPS)
I transmitted them
into your mind
as you tracked the Cybermen.
Maybe this is
the last gift of a parent.
A clue.
Or an apology.
You can decide.
Did Tecteun leave these images
for you to decode one day?
We have to get rid
of everything, I'm afraid.
Thank you for your service.
We're sorry
you won't remember it.
(SHRIEKING)
(CLOCK TICKS)
What did they do to you,
Doctor?
How many lives have you had?
Wake up.
(GASPS)
I know you're broken,
but it's all over now.
What do you mean?
When I said
I killed everyone here...
...I did keep the bodies.
Just...just cold enough
in case they'd be useful.
I thought...I thought maybe
some good can come
out of all of this.
Your adopted mother isn't the
only one who can experiment.
I mean, what if...
...a new race could be created?
Huh?
(EXHALES EXCITEDLY)
Time Lord organics
with the ability to regenerate
and self-repair
in Cyber arm our!
(GASPS)
Invincible!
The perfect army, right?
Right?!
(LAUGHS EXUBERANTLY)
Oh, come in, my pretties.
Yeah!
(CLANKING)
Doosh, doosh, doosh!
Line up. Attention!
Yeah, that's it.
(LAUGHS)
Grr!
Well, let's test it out.
Shoot him.
Shoot him!
Good dog.
All dead.
Um...
Wait.
Could it be?
Yes, it could!
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
(LAUGHS)
(YELLS)
Behold your new CyberMasters,
Doctor.
All born from you!
But led by me.
How does that feel?
Huh?
Now, no time to lose.
Don't move.
Oh, that's right, you can't.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS) Can you feel
a new era dawning, Doctor?
- For Gallifrey.
- CYBERGUARDS: For Gallifrey!
For the Time Lords.
CYBERGUARDS:
For the Time Lords!
For the end
of the universe itself!
CYBERGUARDS: For the end
Sweet dreams.
This way, soldiers.
RAVIO: The Boundary, it's real!
RYAN: Yeah. And the Doctor's
on the other side.
So, how do we do this?
The Boundary will absorb us.
But you have to take the step.
Step into the unknown.
Who fancies going first?
Ah!
This is Gallifrey.
This is where
the Doctor's from.
We're never going to find her
in this lot.
Yeah, we are.
We're going to find her
and we're going to rescue her.
She's done it for us enough
times. Now it's our turn.
This is going to be even more
dangerous from here.
You don't have to come.
We owe you.
We're in. Right?
Right.
Great. How am I meant
to contradict that,
if you're going all heroic?
You coming?
I already lived
longer than I expected.
There must be a few last things
I can blow up before I'm done.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Oh, great.
(SIGHS)
What are you doing here?
Or are you the Matrix
playing more games with me?
Don't ask me.
I'm as lost as you are in here.
Maybe...you just summoned me.
Where do you fit into all this?
Were you me all that time ago?
Were all my memories
of you erased?
Did they force me back
into becoming a child?
How many more of me
are out there?
I don't have those answers.
But say I did -
would they even help?
Of course they would.
All this?
It means I'm not
who I thought I was.
Because your memories
aren't compatible
with what you've learnt today?
Yes.
Have you ever been limited
by who you were before?
Ah.
Now, that does sound
like me talking.
I'm so tired!
The Matrix is sapping
all the energy out of me.
No time to be tired.
Still work to do out there.
Lives at stake.
Armies being born.
People need the Doctor.
I don't know
how to stop the Master.
Course you do.
That one question
that's nagging at you,
the one thing he said
that you didn't understand.
The one thing who said?
- The Master?
- No!
Get out of here.
I know this place
has blown your mind.
Maybe you should return
the compliment.
No, wait!
Are you still there?
Of course she's still there.
If you were me,
you're buried within me,
buried within him...
Too many thoughts.
All right, first things first,
what did she say?
Mind blown.
Yes! Of course.
All this history,
all these lies,
it's too much stimulus.
It might work.
I've fought the Matrix before,
denied its reality,
I can do it again.
Maybe.
Well, you know
what they say, Doctor -
nothing ventured,
nothing blown.
Oh!
I'm talking to myself again.
That's a good sign.
Thanks, Doctor. Still here.
No, shut up,
I need to concentrate.
Uh...
All right.
Have a blast of this, Matrix.
YAZ: Doctor!
GRAHAM: Yaz, is she all right?
Doctor?
Doctor, we're here for you.
My fam.
She's not dead, then.
Who are they?
Are we having a party?
Oh.
All those memories.
The Matrix.
The memories blew the Matrix.
Oh, she's clever.
I'm clever.
We're all clever.
All of us.
However many that is.
All right, then.
Off we go. Ugh!
No, there's something
I'm missing.
The Master is creating
a new race of Cybermen
using Time Lord bodies.
An endlessly regenerating army.
I have to stop him.
Fast.
You shouldn't be here.
- No humans on Gallifrey.
- If it helps,
- we have explosives.
- And a plan.
The Cybership's parked up
in the middle of your hometown,
it's ripe for blowing up.
We're going to strategically
place bombs around the ship,
including some close enough
to the core.
Yes. Good.
Do that.
But it won't achieve
everything.
A race of CyberMasters -
can't let them off this planet,
have to be stopped.
And your bombs
aren't going to do that.
We need more!
But there isn't anything more.
The Master's seen to that.
The Master's seen
to everything.
Are you all right, Doctor?
(SIGHS)
That's what's been bugging me.
That's the thing
that he said to me.
What thing? Who said?
The half-converted Cyberman.
The death of everything...
...Is within me.
That's what he said! Argh!
But what did it mean?
There is a myth around him.
The Death Particle.
The legend is -
he, it, whatever
has a Particle
in a tiny chamber
inside its chest.
It will take out
all organic life on a planet.
- That's grim.
- Or it's a solution.
A timer on an explosive
to activate the Particle
- and a clear evacuation plan.
- Only if you've got a way
to get us off this planet
before it hits.
You all good to set
those explosives?
I'll deal with the rest.
Meet in the corridor
below the carrier.
Go on, then!
Now, I need to get
a fix on the Master.
Got him.
(COMMS BEEPS)
Found the activator core.
If this one goes,
it'll set off chain reactions
across the carrier.
(EXPLOSIVES BUZZ)
(BUZZES)
We're set.
Sweet dreams, losers.
(BUZZES)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
DOCTOR: Where's the Master?
He should be here.
(SONIC BUZZES)
The Master?
He did that?
But the Death Particle
is still in place.
Just smaller than before.
If the Master did this...
...what happened
to the Cyberium?
(GASPS)
You think I didn't feel you
connecting to me?
(LAUGHS)
Laid you a false trail.
Left you a gift, though.
You and me - Matrix Chamber.
No-one else. One last time.
Fine.
I need to get you all
off Gallifrey.
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(BUZZES)
- (TICKING)
- Oh, dear.
Sorry for the short notice.
But it seems that
the main trigger device
has a mind of its own
and has set
all the others going.
May I suggest a very fast
getting the hell off this ship?
Run!
Human life form located.
Delete.
Execute all humans.
All humans must be deleted.
Humanity shall be eradicated.
Incendiary devices identified.
(SCREAMING)
- Thanks for the warning.
- You're still alive,
- aren't you?
- Everyone, through here.
Come on.
It's a TARDIS.
It is a TARDIS, right?
Looks like it.
Sorry, what's happening now?
This can take us all home.
Don't touch. Still working.
Any explosives left?
One.
Emergencies only.
- Timer?
- Hand detonation only.
Yeah. Course.
I'll take it.
So, come on, Doc,
what're you thinking?
One option left.
I have to use
the Death Particle
on Gallifrey.
On my home.
On the Master
and his new breed of Cybermen.
You sure you want to do that?
I'm sure
I don't want to do that,
but there's no alternative.
If the Master and the Cybermen
get off this planet,
they'll be unstoppable.
I started this
with Shelley and the Cyberium,
now I have to finish it.
Alone.
What?
The TARDIS will take you
back to Earth.
All of you.
You can settle
in the 21st century.
- You're not serious.
- Deadly.
What about you?
You detonate that thing,
you'll die, too.
That's the way it has to be.
And I would do that
in a heartbeat
for this universe.
For you...
...my fam.
We're not letting you go.
- You're not doing this.
- Get off me, Yaz!
Please.
Yaz.
Come on.
Live great lives.
I definitely said no plus-ones.
Well... Oh!
Where I go, they go now.
Are you going to have them
shoot me?
No, Doctor.
As of now,
I wish my enemies
a long and healthy life,
so they may witness
my many triumphs,
because they will be legion.
You're looking peaky.
Oh, yeah!
The Cyberium lives in me now,
Doctor.
(CHUCKLES) Yes!
See...
(SHIVERS WITH EXCITEMENT)
I've been looking forward
to seeing your face about that.
I can feel it
flowing around in me -
the information, the strategy,
the...the consciousness.
It's a beautiful thing.
I mean, look at us.
I have broken you
and created a new race.
And now...
Well, now I shall conquer...
...everything.
Oh!
You think you've broken me?
You'll have to try
harder than that.
You've given me a gift.
Of myself.
You think
that could destroy me?
that makes me lesser?
It makes me more.
I contain multitudes more
than I ever thought or knew.
You want me to be scared of it
because you're scared
of everything.
But I am so much more than you.
Wow.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
So, why are we here?
(GASPS) Oh, good, very good.
That's why I left it for you.
Wondered if you would...
...take out me.
Take out these life forms.
All those bodies
still in the vaults.
Every organic cellular
life form on this planet...
...forever.
And yourself.
Do that, would you?
Yes.
This time...
...yes.
Go on, then.
You were the start of
all of this, now finish it.
Come on, come on.
Come on!
Come on, come on!
What have you got left anyway?
You don't even know
your own life.
Look how low
I have brought you.
I have won, Doctor.
You may have made me,
but I have destroyed you.
Become death.
Become me.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
For just a moment there,
I thought maybe.
Argh! (EXHALES DISMISSIVELY)
Oh, Doctor.
The universe will suffer
for your weakness,
I'lLl make sure of it.
KO SHARMUS: Not if
I have anything to do with it.
Excuse me?
No gate-crashers.
You can't still be here,
I set the controls!
I followed you out.
They tried to stop me,
but I wanted to be sure
that these things are gone.
- And now I can be.
- No.
(CHUCKLES)
You didn't start this. I did!
I was part of a resistance unit
that sent the Cyberium
back through time and space.
Though, obviously, we didn't
send it back far enough.
So, this is my penance.
Mine to finish.
My journey ends here.
But the universe
still needs you.
So, I suggest you run.
- But...
- Run, Doctor!
MASTER: Don't you dare.
Doctor!
Still feeling confident?
(SONIC BUZZES)
(WHIRRING)
(TARDIS POWERS UP)
Kill him.
Killed you first.
(GROANS)
MASTER: All of you,
through here - now!
(THRUMS)
This is Earth.
(EXHALES)
We're on Earth.
We're home.
She got us home.
But what happens to her?
Oh, yeah, nice.
Good chameleon circuit.
I'm going to have to
leave you there, though.
I can think of worse places
to spend eternity.
(POWERS UP)
Hello, mate.
(TARDIS BEEPS)
Thanks.
Home sweet home.
(TARDIS WARBLES)
We got a lift back another way.
- (TARDIS BEEPS)
- Don't get jealous.
I'll pick them up now.
Maybe just need a moment.
(TARDIS BEEPS)
(ALARM BLARES)
What?
Judoon Cold Case Unit.
Fugitive - the Doctor.
Sentence -
whole of life imprisonment,
maximum security facility.
What?
What?!