(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(PANTING)
(CREAKING)
I'm lost. Please, can you help me?
It's that way.
-Are those trees?
-I need the Doctor.
Are you the Doctor?
Yes. Do you have an appointment?
You need an appointment
to see the Doctor.
Please. Something's chasing me.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GASPING)
When you drink a glass of Coke,
it's only this big
but it's actually got
this much sugar in it.
-Works a bit like that.
-What does?
The Tardis.
It's bigger on the inside
than the outside.
Or did you not notice?
I just thought it was supposed to be
bigger on the inside,
so I didn't say anything.
Well, of course it's supposed
to be bigger.
Most people are confused by that.
I find everything confusing, nearly.
So I don't say anything.
That's how come I'm in the woods.
I thought Miss Oswald told me
to find the Doctor,
but it wasn't her.
-It was just in my head.
-Miss Oswald? Dark hair?
Highly unpredictable?
Surprisingly round face?
Everyone says she's in love
with Mr Pink.
The PE teacher?
Maths. I really like him.
I was in his group.
Mr Pink was looking after you?
Well, that explains why you're lost.
It doesn't surprise you
that I know all about your school?
Everyone seems to know everything
about everything, apart from me.
-(BEEPING)
-That's not quite true.
I, for instance, have no idea why,
when the terrestrial navigation...
...the terrestrial navigation starts up,
it closes down all the other systems.
You should ask somebody who knows.
Hmm. That's another of the drawbacks
of being the last of your species.
No one to ask
when your Tardis won't start.
(WHOOSHING)
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
You have reached your destination.
No, we haven't. We're supposed
to be in the middle of London.
-You have reached your destination.
-Oh, stop saying that!
She's only saying it because it's true.
We are in the middle of London.
We are in the middle of a forest.
Come and see.
Nelson's Column. Do you like it?
Do I... Sorry, what?
Do you like the forest
being in Trafalgar Square?
I think it's lovely.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Bradley! Sir! Tell him, sir!
He's blinding me.
-Give me that, Bradley.
-I'm allowed a torch, sir.
I've got a note. I'm darkness-phobic.
Just 'cause he's scared
of the dark, sir,
does that mean
he's allowed to blind me?
You're allowed a torch, Bradley,
not a pocket supernova.
Okay, listen up.
Just a few things to run through
before we head home.
Put your phone away, Bradley.
Thank you.
Firstly, collect up any rubbish
you may have generated
through midnight feasts or whatever...
DANNY: Hello?
Hello?
GIRL: Look at this.
Why's this one so fat, miss?
Because it was alive so long.
This ring, though.
All the other rings are thin
but this one's fat and red, see?
Must have been a good year
to be a tree.
I should have been relieved, you know.
-Oh, Coal Hill School. Sleepover.
-Shh, shh!
(KEYS JANGLING)
(CHILDREN GROANING)
(BOY YAWNING)
(LOCK BEEPING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Hang on. There's a knack to this.
No, no, no, no, no. It moved. It moved.
It's just jammed, it's not locked.
Come on, team.
What team?
(ALL GRUNTING)
Wow!
-BOY: Sir, where are we?
-What do you mean, where are we?
(CHILDREN GASPING)
We can't have been asleep
for that long, can we?
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
You've heard of leaves on the line.
This is going to be slightly
harder to clear.
In three hours" time,
the Ghana Black Stars are due to play
Sierra Leone
in the African Cup of Nations.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
It does not look
like the pitch will be ready.
You are always showing me
amazing things.
Well, I, Doctor, have finally got
something amazing to show you.
Yes, well, there are some things
that I've never seen
but that's usually because
I've chosen not to see them,
even my incredibly long life
is too short for Les Misérables.
CLARA: Oh, Doctor.
You are going to love this.
DOCTOR: Well, when you come
to collect this child,
you can tell me then.
Huh? What child?
Young female human.
Standard defenceless little girl.
Your friend Mr Pink was supposed
to be looking after her.
-She probably has a name.
-Good point.
You. Have you got a name at all?
Maebh. My name's Maebh.
What? Maebh?
-Where are you?
-Trafalgar Square.
I found her wandering
around the brand new forest.
-Brand new forest?
-Yes.
It's like the New Forest,
except even newer.
Is that the forest
that's covering London?
DOCTOR: Was that the amazing thing
that you were going to show me?
'Tis amazing, but I saw it first.
Look, is she all right?
Will you bring her over?
No, I can't bring her over.
I'm a Time Lord, not a childminder.
You've got a spaceship.
All we've got are Oyster cards.
And I've got a global rapid
afforestation crisis to deal with.
-What did they say?
-Who?
School. Parents.
You were just on the phone.
Oh, yeah. Rang school and parents.
Yes, of course.
Thought that was the priority.
And?
And I couldn't get through.
Left messages. I'll try again.
Oh, you didn't call the school.
You called him.
No, he called me, actually.
I can't stop him calling me, can I?
I thought you weren't in contact.
London has just been taken over
by a gigantic forest.
Who do you want to talk to, Monty Don?
I want to do my job,
which is looking after these kids.
Oh, really? How many kids?
-What?
-Where's Maebh Arden?
She's with the Doctor.
What? No, no, no, no.
Maebh is a vulnerable kid.
She's on medication.
She's had an emotional trauma.
He... Has he even been CRB checked?
He didn't abduct her. She was lost.
He found her.
I thought you said they were in love.
Why are they shouting at each other?
That's what people do
when they're in love.
Don't you know anything?
BOY: Where are we actually going?
Where is he taking us?
(CHILDREN GRUMBLING)
-Who wants to be navigator?
-CHILDREN: Me, me, me!
Good lad. Come on, let's do this.
What's a navigator?
We'll follow the lampposts,
that will keep us on Cromwell Road.
We'll be able to orientate ourselves.
I thought we were getting a coach.
Where's the coach?
Well, Ruby, it seems
there are a lot of trees in the way.
Why can't we just wait here
till they've gone?
Trees don't just disappear, Ruby.
They just came.
Why wouldn't they just go?
You see, the question is
how did it get here?
Can a forest grow overnight
or have we been asleep for years,
like Sleeping Beauty?
No, the question is how are we
going to get these kids home?
Oh, absolutely. Yeah.
That is the big question.
DANNY: Okay, team!
It's crucial we stick together.
If you start to fall behind, don't.
Bradley, we're going to head
northeast first
to collect Maebh from Trafalgar Square,
then we're going south to the river.
Come on, keep up!
-(CHILDREN MURMURING)
-BOY: What's he talking about?
You are enjoying this
just a little bit too much.
Come on, are you not even
a little bit curious about how?
Who? Why? When?
I am curious. I am bewildered.
I am, in fact, enchanted.
But I'm not the priority here.
The kids are.
You see, now, that attitude is...
actually very attractive.
The government emergency committee,
COBRA,
has formulated an action plan.
We will create pathways
through the trees,
using carefully controlled fires.
This will facilitate
the movement of essential services.
We're therefore asking you
to stay in your homes...
- (SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-...Till your baths, sinks
and any buckets with fresh water...
Why would there be no reading?
Because they're actually
made of wood. No circuits.
No mechanism. Wood.
-(GRUNTS)
-What's this for?
This is a sonic screwdriver.
It interacts with any form
of communication you care to mention.
Sadly, trees have no moving parts
and they don't communicate.
They communicate a bit, though.
What?
Otherwise they wouldn't all grow
at the same time, would they?
So, what, do you think
that's how spring begins?
With a group message on Tree Facebook?
Do you think they send
texts to each other?
You don't need a phone
to communicate, do you?
I haven't phoned home and I know
my mum is worried about me.
You said you'd collect Maebh!
It's all right, I'm collecting her.
Soon as I find my car keys.
I can't see a thing!
Next door planted bloody
hydrangeas and they've gone mental!
I've had words with her
about it before. She's...
Oh.
I'll call you back.
Miss, in the museum, right,
I was reading about reproduction...
Oh, Ruby, this really isn't
the right moment...
And that said that trees have blossom
and then that turns into fruit
or seeds or nuts. Right?
Right, Ruby.
This tree has got blossom and nuts.
Oh, yeah.
That is strange.
Nuts. That's unfortunate for you,
isn't it, Bradley?
You have an allergy, don't you?
What if one of them falls on your head?
You'd die, Bradley, yeah?
Or you'd swell up like a massive melon.
Shut it!
I think we should have been consulted.
What's it made of, even?
MAEBH'S MUM: How far does this go?
I need to collect Maebh.
Trafalgar Square! Well done, Bradley.
Excellent navigation skills.
A-ha! There it is.
All sorted now. Come on.
Can we take a picture
with the lion, sir? Please?
Uh, stay together but okay.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
I cannot believe
Bradley just said "please”.
-Really?
-Yeah.
He usually prefers
other means of persuasion.
Give it! Give it!
Miss! He won't lend me his dictionary.
You could try saying "please”, Bradley.
-(BOY GROANING)
-(LOUD CRASH)
(WHIMPERS)
And Ruby...
How do we find X?
Ruby?
It's there, sir. At the top.
No, how do we find...
It's not lost. It's there,
at the top, look!
No, how do we find the value of X?
Why are you asking me
all the questions?
Give someone else a go.
You bring out the best in them.
-(RUMBLING)
-(CHILDREN WHIMPERING)
BOY: Whoa! What was that?
(SHRIEKS)
Look, sir. No rings.
Trees usually have rings,
to tell you how old they are.
This one's got no rings.
Why's that then, sir?
The rings mark the years of growth.
One ring for each year.
This grew up overnight.
That whole tree
is the result
of just one night's growth.
And they're still growing.
Everyone, this is the Doctor
and he's going to sort everything out.
Isn't that right, Doctor?
It's what he does.
Well, having looked at things,
I think probably
the answer to that is no.
He always says that.
He's really clever.
Oh, yes, I am very clever.
But what use is clever against trees?
They don't listen to reason.
You can't plead with them.
You can't lie to them.
They've got no moving parts,
no circuits.
This is a natural event.
How can it be natural for a tree
to grow in one night?
Exactly what they said
about the Ice Age.
How can whole glaciers
just pop up out of nowhere?
Well, they just did.
That's how this planet grows.
A series of catastrophes.
Farewell to the Ice Age.
Welcome to the Tree Age. Possibly.
When the Ice Age was here,
you lot managed to cook mammoth.
Now that there's a forest,
you'll just have to eat nuts.
I can't eat nuts. I've got an allergy.
Don't worry. It's a thing he does.
He pretends he's not interested
and then he has an idea.
He's playing for time.
Time!
Interesting.
See? Clever kicking in.
A tree is a time machine.
You plant a little acorn in 1795
and in the year 2016
there's an oak tree,
there, in the same spot,
with a tiny little bit of 1795
still alive inside of it.
You can't create a whole overnight
forest with extra-special fertilizer.
You have to mess
with the fabric of time.
And communicate with trees.
So you're saying
it's an act of aggression?
-By trees.
-Um, trees clean the air.
Exactly. Well done, Ruby.
Someone or something who's trying
to scrub the atmosphere
before colonising or invading...
Ah, yes, Doctor... (CLEARS THROAT)
This is Coal Hill Year 8
Gifted and Talented group.
What are the round bits for?
Ask your teacher. Come on!
-Down from there! Hey!
-(CHILDREN MURMURING)
Away from the console, come on.
That's an antique. Get away from there!
Don't touch that!
Haven't any of you been
struck by the fact that it's...
Look, it's bigger on the inside!
There wasn't a forest,
then there was a forest.
Nothing surprises us any more.
These trees all appeared at once.
That wasn't a coincidence.
There's no such thing
as an arboreal coincidence.
Something, someone
has coordinated this.
To coordinate, you need to communicate.
Every communication channel
on the Tardis is open
and nothing.
Except...
Let me see that.
Homework books. Why are these here?
Maebh Arden.
Maebh Arden. Which one is Maebh Arden?
Which one is Maebh?
Maebh? Maebh?
Maebh? Maebh? Maebh?
-Maebh? Maebh?
-Oh, my God!
Maebh's gone.
Maebh's lost in the forest.
-Maebh's going to die!
-DOCTOR: Ahhh!
Ruby, that's enough! Doctor?
-We've got to find her!
-Yes, I know that we have to find her.
Doctor, listen to me.
Her sister went missing last year.
She's on medication.
The child is barely functioning.
She hears voices.
-She's very vulnerable.
-What do the voices say?
I don't know.
She takes tablets and they stop.
You people, you never learn.
If a child is speaking, listen to it!
Oh, like you listened to her?
He's right.
She was trying to tell me
something and I ignored her.
Maebh Arden is tuned
to a different channel.
She can lead us to the source,
to the heart of the forest.
We have to listen to her,
we have to find her.
Not everything can be fixed
with a screwdriver.
It's not a magic wand.
-Does she have a phone?
-Well, yeah, she does.
-Have you got the number?
-Um, yep.
Maebh Arden.
500 yards southeast of here.
-I'll go get her.
-I'll go with him.
-Oh, I can go. You can...
-You haven't seen him for months?
Something like that.
You didn't even say hello.
You just sprung straight into action.
Special unit.
-BOY: This is so cool...
-Hey!
Do not touch anything.
-Anything. Okay?
-Okay.
See? Someone needs to go.
Child protection.
(CHILDREN MURMURING)
Gifted and Talented? Really?
Furious, fearful, tongue-tied...
They're all superpowers
if you use them properly.
Are they going to be all right?
They're in the Tardis.
It's the safest place on the planet.
(RUMBLING)
(CLARA GRUNTS)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
-If this is an invasion...
-What?
It's over. They're here. They've won.
What do they want?
(ALL COUGHING)
I'm not just going to stand here
and let her die!
-Who?
-Miss.
You let her go off
with some randomer into the forest.
You're supposed to be
madly in love with her.
I... Who said that?
Everyone.
She's probably dead now, anyway.
Crushed by Nelson.
What if the trees collapse on her
and kill her?
You're worrying too much.
Yeah, but what if the wild animals
come out and eat her?
Ruby, you're letting your
imagination run away with you.
I'm not, though, am I?
Because I haven't got an imagination.
You can ask Miss Oswald.
Okay, then, come on, team.
Let's do this!
We will, if you stop calling us a team.
Maebh!
Doctor? Look behind us.
The path we just walked down,
it's overgrown already.
Clara!
Why would she put her phone down?
Doesn't want to be followed?
Lost a hold of it in a struggle?
Left it as a clue,
so we would know where she was going?
Trail of breadcrumbs.
Hansel and Gretel.
I'm actually frightened.
I never get frightened.
-Why am I frightened?
-You just lost a little girl.
Yes. That is a worry
but I know you'll find her.
No, no, no. This, this is not a worry,
this is a dread. Maebh!
You're pursuing a little lost girl
through a mysterious forest.
The path has disappeared.
You find yourself with a strangely
compelling, masculine figure...
Maebh!
Any minute now, we're going
to find a gingerbread cottage
with a cannibal witch inside. Maebh!
Exactly. The forest.
It's in all the stories
that kept you awake at night.
The forest is mankind's nightmare.
(PANTING)
(PANTING CONTINUES)
DOCTOR: Clara!
Is it hers?
Yes. Clever girl.
Get back! We're burning here.
Stay back.
-CLARA: We're looking for a little girl.
-Stay back.
We're about to burn.
MAN 1: Good job!
MAN 2: What's going on?
MAN 3: Tree's not responding
to flamethrower.
I mean, they don't catch fire.
They just don't catch.
It's like they're flameproof
or something.
Trees control the oxygen on this planet,
they withhold it,
they smother the fire.
What sort of forest is clever?
What sort of forest
has its own in-built fire extinguisher?
-CLARA: What do they want?
-And why now?
What do you mean, why now?
The whole natural order is
turning against this planet.
-But why? Why now?
-Well, what else?
How did she know this?
What is it?
This is a massive solar flare
headed for Earth,
like the one that destroyed
the Bank of Karabraxos.
I've got an entire Tardis
and I didn't notice this.
But she knew. How?
This is Maebh's.
Where did you get this?
You left your marking on the Tardis.
Oh, great, right.
Well, that's just brilliant, isn't it?
You don't think Danny saw this, do you?
I've just informed you
that a solar flare
is going to wipe out your planet.
You're worried about
a row with your boyfriend?
How does she know this?
She even put the date on it!
I always make them date their homework.
It's today's date!
Well, there must be...
a way.
They want something.
They're saying something.
If there is a way,
the way is Maebh Arden.
Okay, you know they're not really
gifted and talented, don't you?
I just tell them that
to make them feel good.
She's lost someone.
People who've lost someone,
they're always listening,
they're always looking,
they're always hoping.
So they notice more. They hear more.
(MOURNFUL HOWLING)
Was that a howl?
-(HOWLING CONTINUES)
-Was that a wolf?
No. That is impossible.
We're in London.
Would that be the London with the zoo?
The zoo with the pack of wolves?
The zoo whose barriers and gates
have probably been
mangled by the trees?
No, wolves are not impossible.
Stick to the path, Red Riding Hood.
There is no path.
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
Then we're lunch.
(PANTING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Maebh!
(WOLVES SNARLING)
(MAEBH PANTING)
(WOLVES BARKING)
Maebh! Doctor, give me a boost
so I can pull her over.
-Maebh? Maebh?
-(WOLVES SNARLING)
Maebh. You came looking for me.
You didn't... Maebh, Maebh,
you didn't just stumble into the Tardis.
-Tell me what you know.
-Doctor...
-This is important.
-Yes,
can we please deal
with the wolves first?
These are zoo wolves,
they're not even used to hunting.
-Doctor!
-(WOLVES SNARLING)
Oh! Right, okay, all right, all right.
We've just got to look as if
we're too much bother to eat.
Right. So stay still. Stay together.
Look big. Look big,
like a big, three-headed,
six-legged scary thing!
(WOLVES WHINING)
DOCTOR: (LAUGHING)
Told you they were rubbish.
Those wolves are terrified.
What are wolves frightened of?
(LOW GROWLING)
(ROARS)
There are very good,
solid, scientific reasons
for being really quite frightened
just now.
(ROARS)
(SNARLING)
(LAUGHING)
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
Mr Pink! Why, thank you very much.
Ah, no problem.
Just decided it was best
not to leave you alone with him.
They've worked well together.
Noticeable increase
in confidence levels and energy.
Well done.
And for saving us from a tiger, too.
Um, has she had her medication yet?
-Um, oh, no, I...
-No, no, not her medication.
We don't want to shut her up.
We want to know what she knows.
Maebh, what's... Maebh, what is...
Maebh, what's this? What is this?
Apart from being
almost savaged by a tiger
and abducted by a Scotsman,
she's allowed
any nervous tics she likes, okay?
This is not a nervous tic.
-This is react...
-RUBY: Please!
Just give her her tablets!
She's been in a state
since her sister went missing.
Maebh! Maebh! Maebh!
RUBY: You won't find
your sister out there.
(MAEBH PANTING)
Miss? What is it, miss?
It's coming. It's coming
for everyone and I can't unthink it.
Maebh. Maebh,
this forest is communicating.
With you. Nobody else.
No technology can hear
what it's saying. But you can.
Tell us what it wants.
Where it came from.
Just tell me who did this.
It was me.
I did this. I did these trees.
No, Maebh.
You didn't make
a global forest appear overnight.
How could you do that?
Thoughts come to me.
Ever since Annabel went missing,
I look for her everywhere.
I don't find her but I find thoughts.
The big forest was one.
I thought everyone would love it.
The thoughts!
(GROANS) The thoughts!
They go so fast.
This is stressing me now.
When I get stressed,
I forget my anger management.
Maebh, can you see
something that we can't see?
Nearly... Too fast... Everywhere...
Everything is subject to gravity.
If I can create a little
local increase...
No. You are not experimenting on...
(GASPING)
They're lovely!
They don't like it
when you're holding them.
They want you to let them go.
Who are they?
(DEEP VOICE JOINING MAEBH)
We are here. Here always,
since the beginning and until the end.
Here? That's it?
We are the green shoots
that grow between the cracks,
the grass that grows over
the mass graves.
After your wars are over,
we will still be here.
We are the life that prevails.
Why now? Why are you here now?
We hear the call and we come,
as we came before
to the great North Forest,
where we lie still in a great circle,
as we came to the vast Southern Forest.
Who's calling you now?
The sun that creates.
The sun that destroys.
You are hurting us. Let us go.
You sent for me.
The girl came looking for me.
Why? Why me?
We did not send...
Pain. ...did not send for you.
We don't know you.
We were here before you
and will be here after you.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER CLICKS)
-Argh!
That was actually quite cool.
(GROANS)
Maebh, you came looking
for the Doctor. Think.
Who sent you for the Doctor?
It was just a thought.
It was just a thought that came.
I think it came from Miss.
They've gone!
Why does everything have to go?
This really is
going to happen, isn't it?
Stars implode. Planets grow cold.
Catastrophe is the metabolism
of the universe.
I can fight monsters.
I can't fight physics.
Why would trees want to kill us?
We love trees.
You've been chopping them down
for furniture for centuries.
If that's love, no wonder they're
calling down fire from the heavens.
But we saw the future.
Lots of futures.
Earth's futures!
They're about to be erased.
If you can't save them all,
save what you can.
The Tardis.
It's a lifeboat, isn't it?
Not everybody has to die.
(RUMBLING)
DANNY: # Everywhere we go-o!
CHILDREN: # Everywhere we go-o!
# People wanna kno-ow!
# Who we a-are
CHILDREN: # Who we a-are
DANNY: # We are the Coal Hill
Gifted and Talented
CHILDREN: # We are the Coal Hill
Gifted and Talented... #
Whoa!
All right. Come on, team.
When they're done,
you need to get in your box and go.
DOCTOR: We're all going.
We're taking the kids.
Taking them where?
What are you going do with them?
Leave them on an asteroid?
Find a space academy
for the gifted and talented?
They just want their mum and dads
and they're never
going to stop wanting them.
(CHILDREN GRUNTING)
I can save you and Danny.
Danny Pink will never leave those kids
so long as he is breathing.
-(CHILDREN CHEERING)
-Hey! Well done, team.
BRADLEY: Can we take
another selfie, sir?
DANNY: Course. Come on, then.
BOYS: Yes!
I can save you.
I don't want you to.
-What, you don't want to live?
-Of course I want to live, I just...
What?
Don't make me say it.
Say what?
I don't want to be the last of my kind.
Then why did you bring us all here?
Because it's the only way
to get you back to the Tardis,
make you think you're saving someone.
Well, you know what, Doctor?
This time, the human race is saving you.
Make it worthwhile.
This is my world, too.
I walk your Earth, I breathe your air.
And on behalf of this world,
you're very welcome.
Now, go.
Save the next one.
Maebh!
I'm sorry that I couldn't help you.
You helped me loads!
I thought it was all my fault.
I feel much better now.
Are you going to get rid of the forest?
Hard to get rid of a flameproof forest,
Maebh, eh? Come on.
SAMSON: Government crews
have been deployed...
-(DOOR CLOSES)
-...with the latest de-fo...
...de-foo...
-(LAUGHTER)
-(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
Defoliant agents, Samson.
They're used to take the leaves off
the trees so they're easier to burn.
That's harsh.
(WHOOSHING)
BOY: Where's he going?
Home.
He's going home.
Which is exactly where we're going.
Flameproof forest...
Flameproof.. forest!
A thousand atom bombs and no one hurt.
I am Doctor Idiot!
DOCTOR: Clara! Come back here!
Come back!
-He's calling you.
-Yes, let him call.
This is more important.
Clara! Mr Pink! Maebh!
All of you! Quick! Quick!
Come back, come back. Come on!
Maebh, quick! Good girl, good girl!
Come on!
It's there on the screen, look!
Big solar flare. Headed this way.
A thousand kilometres a second.
Coronal mass ejection.
Geomagnetic storm. It's huge!
It's brewing up a solar wind
big enough to blow
this whole planet away.
I assumed your teachers
have mentioned this?
I thought it would spoil
an otherwise enjoyable walk.
Okay. Okay.
Well, this is the bad news.
The good news is it's happened before.
And you're still here!
The Tunguska Blast, 1908,
that should have blown
the whole planet off its axis.
But it didn't.
It knocked a few trees over.
Well, a few tens of thousands
of trees over.
Curuca in Brazil. Same story.
Earth should have been smashed!
But it wasn't.
What do these things have in common?
They're really, really scaring us?
Trees!
Whenever there's a planet-threatening,
extra-terrestrial impact, trees!
Massive forest,
filling the atmosphere with oxygen.
Pumping it up, like a massive,
highly inflammable airbag,
so that when trouble hits...
Everyone dies.
No. The impact burns off
the excess oxygen.
You have some fairly hectic weather
for a few days
and some fairly trippy-looking sunsets
but apart from that,
you will be all right.
I was wrong. The trees are not
your enemy. They're your shield.
They've been saving you since forever,
protecting you from everything
that space can throw at you.
The wide ring.
The red ring.
In the museum,
Ruby saw a cross-section of a tree.
One of the rings was
wider than the others and red.
Atmospheric dust,
captured by the trees.
The fingerprint of an asteroid.
Happy Red Ring Day.
RUBY: I don't get it.
If they're good, then why are we
chopping them down?
The Government are sending out
defoliating teams.
They're dropping chemicals on them
right now.
What is it with you people?
You hear voices,
you want to shut them up.
The trees come to save you,
you want to chop them down.
CLARA: Or you think you
need to save the world
when it's already saving itself.
-I did admit that I was wrong.
-(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
Excellent.
Mobile networks are still operative.
Right, we are going to call
everyone on Earth
and tell them to leave the trees alone.
Can I do it?
I started it. I should finish it.
Okay. Okay.
Class project. Save the Earth.
(CHILDREN CONFERRING, INDISTINCT)
Okay. And I think that's it.
(CLICKS)
(MOBILES RINGING)
(RINGING ECHOES)
(MOBILE RINGING)
MAEBH: "Essential services
have been disrupted
-"due to an unexpected forest.”
-Maebh! Where are you?
"We'd like to reassure you
"that the situation
will be rectified very soon.
"Please don't be scared.
"And please don't chop,
spray or harm the trees.
"They're here to help.
Be less scared. Be more trusting.”
Oh, and Annabel Arden,
please come home.
-(POWERING DOWN)
-Okay, who would like to witness
a once-in-a-billion years
solar event at close quarters?
Mum! There's my mum!
I thought I'd lost you, too.
Never. Not ever.
(LAUGHING)
So, trip to space, anyone?
I want my mum.
I slightly want my mum, too.
Tell them, Mr Pink,
what an educational opportunity...
You... You go. This...
This is enough for me.
What?
Coronal ejections, geomagnetic storms.
How often do you get
a playlist like that?
I was a soldier. I put myself at risk.
I didn't try too hard to survive
but somehow, here I am.
And now I can see what I nearly lost.
And it's enough.
I don't want to see more things.
I want to see the things
that are in front of me more clearly.
There are wonders here, Clara Oswald.
Bradley saying "please”,
that's a wonder.
One person is more amazing,
harder to understand,
but more amazing than universes.
Really? What person is that, then?
(KIDS CHEERING)
I told you! I said so, didn't I?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
CLARA: We could have a picnic.
You can't. You've got marking.
Oh.
Well, no, no, no.
That was, um, that was from ages ago.
You see, what happened was...
They always write the date
neatly at the top of the page.
Yeah, they do, don't they?
Yeah, last Friday.
You were on the Tardis last Friday.
Today, you thought the world
was going to end.
-You still didn't tell me the truth.
-No, I tried. He interrupted.
I just want to know the truth.
I don't care what it is.
I just want to know it.
Like Maebh said. Like the forest.
Fear a little bit less,
trust a bit more.
Okay.
-Well...
-No, not now.
Go home, do your marking.
Think about it.
Then tell me.
I saved you from a tiger today.
I deserve at least that.
Yes, you did.
And yes, you do.
I hope I'm right.
It would be slightly awkward
if the world was destroyed
at this point.
What?
(RUMBLING)
DOCTOR: There goes
the planet-sized airbag.
That's the trees,
harvesting the solar fire.
Now, that was surprising.
And I love surprises.
(CHIRPING, FLUTTERING)
CLARA: That is amazing.
How will they explain this tomorrow?
You'll all forget it ever happened.
We are not going to forget
an overnight forest.
You forgot the last time.
You remembered the fear
and you put it into fairy stories.
It's a human superpower, forgetting.
If you remembered how things felt,
you'd have stopped having wars.
And stopped having babies.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Annabel!
My Annabel!
I knew you'd be here.
The thought of you came to me.
DOCTOR: Clara?
CLARA: Do I have your attention?
You will never step inside
your Tardis again.
DOCTOR: Clara, what are you doing?
CLARA: Time can be rewritten.
DOCTOR: Clara, my Clara,
I don't think you will!
You know who I am.
I'm not Clara Oswald.
Clara Oswald has never existed.