(GRUNTING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Kathy?
DOCTOR: Listen, your life
could depend on this.
Don't blink. Don't even blink.
Blink and you're dead.
They are fast.
Faster than you can believe.
Don't turn your back,
don't look away and don't blink.
Good luck.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Hello?
Bit freaked. Need to talk.
Making you a coffee.
Sally Sparrow, it's 1:00 in the morning.
Do you think I'm going out
at 1:00 in the morning?
No.
I'm in the kitchen. What's that
on all those screens in your front room?
(SIGHING) Oh, God.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Oh, God. Sally, you've met
my brother Larry, haven't you?
-No.
-You're about to.
(DOOR OPENING)
Okay.
Not sure, but really, really hoping...
-Pants?
-No.
Put them on! Put them on! I hate you!
What are you thinking?
Sorry. My useless brother.
Sally? What's wrong?
What's happened?
Okay. Let's investigate.
You and me, girl investigators.
Love it. Hey! Sparrow and Nightingale.
-That so works.
-Bit ITV.
I know!
What did you come here for anyway?
I love old things.
They make me feel sad.
-What's good about sad?
-It's happy for deep people.
The weeping angel.
KATHY: Wouldn't have that in my garden.
-It's moved.
-It's what?
Since yesterday.
I'm sure of it. It's closer.
It's got closer to the house.
How can my name be written here?
How is that possible?
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Who'd come here?
-What are you doing?
-It could be a burglar.
A burglar who rings the doorbell?
-Okay. I'll stay here in case of...
-In case of?
-Incidents?
-Okay.
I'm looking for Sally Sparrow.
How did you know I'd be here?
I was told to bring this letter
on this date at this exact time
to Sally Sparrow.
-Looks old.
-It is old.
I'm sorry, do you have anything
with a photograph on it,
like a driving licence?
(RATTLING)
No one knew I was coming here.
I didn't tell anyone.
How could anyone have known?
MAN: It's all a bit complicated.
I'm not sure I understand it myself.
Yes. Sorry, I feel really stupid.
I was told to make absolutely sure.
It's so hard to tell
with these little photographs, isn't it?
Apparently.
Well, here goes, I suppose.
-Funny feeling after all these years.
-Who's it from?
-Well, that's a long story, actually.
-Give me a name.
Katherine Wainwright.
But she specified I should tell you
that, prior to marriage,
she was called Kathy Nightingale.
(BANGING)
Kathy?
Kathy. Yes.
Katherine Costello Nightingale.
-Is this a joke?
-Joke?
Kathy, is this you?
Very funny. Kathy?
-Kathy? Kathy?
-Please.
You need to take this. I promised.
Excuse me. Where am I?
I was in London.
I was in the middle of London.
-You're in Hull.
-No, I'm not.
-This is Hull.
-No, it isn't.
-You're in Hull.
-I'm not in Hull. Stop saying Hull.
Who are you? Why are you here?
-I made a promise.
-Who to?
My grandmother.
Katherine Costello Nightingale.
Don't have that in London.
There's no call for it. It's all Hull.
-Your grandmother?
-Yes.
She died 20 years ago.
Huh.
-So they're related?
-Sorry?
My Kathy, your grandmother.
They're practically identical.
Where you going?
My dearest Sally Sparrow,
if my grandson has done
as he promises he will,
then as you read these words,
it has been mere minutes
since we last spoke.
For you. For me,
it has been over 60 years.
The third of the photographs
is of my children.
The youngest is Sally.
I named her after you, of course.
This is sick.
This is totally sick.
Kathy? Kathy!
Kathy?
(FLUTTERING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
No, wait. Hang on!
I suppose, unless I live
to a really exceptional old age,
I will be long gone as you read this.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I have led a good and full life.
I've loved a good man
and been well loved in return.
You would have liked Ben.
He was the very first person I met
in 71920.
-Are you following me?
-Yeah.
-Are you going to stop following me?
-No, I don't think so.
To take one breath in 2007
and the next in 1920
Is a strange way to start a new life,
but a new life
is exactly what I've always wanted.
1902.
You told him you were 18, you lying cow.
My mum and dad are gone by your time,
so really there's only Lawrence to tell.
He works at the DVD store
on Queen Street.
I don't know
what you're gonna say to him,
but I know you'll think of something.
Just tell him I love him.
Excuse me,
I'm looking for Lawrence Nightingale.
In the back.
Hello?
-Martha!
-Sorry.
Quite possibly.
Afraid so.
Oh. Hello.
-Can I help you?
-Hi.
38.
Just a moment.
Hang on. We've met, haven't we?
It'll come to you.
-Oh, my God.
-There it is.
Sorry. Sorry, again, about the whole...
-Message from your sister.
-Oh, okay.
What? What is it? What's the message?
-She's had to go away for a bit.
-Where?
Just a work thing.
Nothing to worry about.
-Okay.
-And...
-And... And what?
-She loves you.
She what?
She said to say...
She just sort of mentioned it.
She loves you.
There, that's nice, isn't it?
-Is she ill?
-No! No.
-Am I ill?
-No.
-Is this a trick?
-No. She loves you.
People don't understand time.
It's not what you think it is.
-Who is this guy?
-Sorry, the pause thing keeps slipping.
-Stupid thing.
-Last night at Kathy's,
you had him on all those screens,
that same guy.
Talking about, I don't know,
blinking or something.
Yeah, the bit
about the blinking's great.
I was just checking to see
if they were all the same.
What were the same?
-What is this? Who is he?
-An Easter egg.
-Excuse me?
-Like a DVD extra, yeah?
You know how on DVDs they put extras,
you know, documentaries and stuff?
Sometimes they put on hidden ones
and they call them Easter eggs.
You have to go looking for them,
follow a bunch of clues
on the menu screen.
Complicated.
Sorry.
It's interesting, actually.
He is on 17 different DVDs.
There are 17 totally unrelated DVDs
all with him on,
always hidden away, always a secret.
Not even the publishers know.
I've talked to the manufacturers, right?
They don't even know.
He's like... He's a ghost DVD extra.
Just shows up
where he's not supposed to be.
-But only on those. Those 17.
-Well, what does he do?
Just sits there, making random remarks.
It's like we're hearing
half a conversation.
Me and the guys are always trying
to work out the other half.
When you say you and the guys,
you mean the internet, don't you?
-How'd you know?
-Spooky, isn't it?
Very complicated.
-Lawrence, need you.
-Excuse me a sec.
People assume that time is
a strict progression of cause to effect,
but actually, from a non-linear,
non-subjective viewpoint,
it's more like a big ball
of wibbly-wobbly, timey-wimey stuff.
It started well, that sentence.
It got away from me, yeah.
Okay, that was weird.
Like you can hear me.
Well I can hear you.
Okay, that's enough.
I've had enough now. I've had a long day
and I've had bloody enough.
Sorry, bad day.
-Got you the list.
-What?
The 17 DVDs.
I thought you might be interested.
Yeah. Great. Thanks.
Go to the police, you stupid woman.
Why does nobody ever just go
to the police?
Look, I know how mad I'm sounding.
Shall we try it from the beginning
this time?
Okay, there's this house,
a big, old house, been empty for years,
falling apart, Wester Drumlins,
out by the estate.
You've probably seen it.
-Wester Drumlins?
-Yes.
-Could you just wait here for a minute?
-Oh.
Okay. Cracking up now.
Hi. DI Billy Shipton.
Wester Drumlins, that's mine.
Can't talk to you now,
got a thing I can't be late for,
so if you could just...
-Hello.
Er, Marcie, can you tell them
I'm going to be late for that thing?
-All of them?
-Over the last two years, yeah.
They all still have personal items
in them
and a couple still had
the motor running.
So over the last two years,
the owners of all of these vehicles
have driven up
to Wester Drumlins house,
parked outside and just disappeared?
-What's that?
-Ah.
The pride of
the Wester Drumlins collection.
We found that there, too.
Somebody's idea of a joke, I suppose.
But what is it? What's a police box?
Well, it's a special kind of phone box
for policemen.
They used to have them all over,
but this isn't a real one.
The phone is just a dummy
and the windows are the wrong size.
Can't even get in it.
Ordinary Yale lock, but nothing fits.
But that's not the big question.
See, you're missing the big question.
Okay, what's the big question?
-Will you have a drink with me?
-I'm sorry?
Drink? You, me, now?
Aren't you on duty,
Detective Inspector Shipton?
Nope. Knocked off before I left.
-Told them I had a family crisis.
-Why?
Because life is short
and you are hot. Drink?
No.
-Ever?
-Maybe.
-Phone number?
-Moving rather fast, DI Shipton.
-Billy. I'm off duty.
-Aren't you just?
-Is that your phone number?
-Just my phone number.
Not a promise, not a guarantee,
not an IOU, just a phone number.
-And that's Sally...
-Sally Shipton.
Sparrow! Sally Sparrow.
-Ah.
-Okay, going now. Don't look at me.
-I'll phone you.
-Don't look at me.
-Phone you tomorrow.
-Might even phone you tonight.
-Don't look at me.
Definitely gonna phone you,
gorgeous girl.
Definitely better.
SHIPTON: Ordinary Yale lock,
but nothing fits.
DOCTOR: Welcome.
-Where am I?
-1969.
Not bad, as it goes. You've got
the moon landing to look forward to.
Oh, the moon landing's brilliant!
We went four times.
-Back when we had transport.
-Working on it.
-How did I get here?
-Same way we did.
Touch of an angel. Same one, probably,
since you ended up in the same year.
No, no, no. Don't get up.
Time travel without a capsule, nasty.
Catch your breath,
don't go swimming for half an hour.
I don't... I can't...
Fascinating race, the weeping angels.
The only psychopaths in the universe
to kill you nicely.
No mess, no fuss, they just zap you
into the past and let you live to death,
the rest of your life used up
and blown away in the blink of an eye.
You die in the past and in the present
they consume the energy
of all the days you might have had.
All your stolen moments.
They're creatures of the abstract,
they live off potential energy.
What in God's name
are you talking about?
Trust me, just nod
when he stops for breath.
Tracked you down with this.
This is my timey-wimey detector.
Goes "bing" when there's stuff.
Also, it can boil an egg at 30 paces.
Whether you want it to or not, actually,
so I've learnt to stay away from hens.
It's not pretty when they blow.
-I don't understand. Where am I?
-1969, like he said.
Normally, I'd offer you a lift home,
but somebody nicked my motor.
So I need you to take
a message to Sally Sparrow.
And I'm sorry, Billy,
I am very, very sorry.
It's gonna take you a while.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Hello?
Billy, where are you?
Where?
Billy?
It was raining when we met.
It's the same rain.
-She looks nice.
-Her name was Sally, too.
-Sally Shipton.
I often thought about looking for you
before tonight.
But apparently it would have torn
a hole in the fabric of space and time
and destroyed
two thirds of the universe.
Also, I'd lost my hair.
Two thirds of the universe?
Where'd you get that from?
There's a man in 1969.
He sent me with a message for you.
-What man?
-The Doctor.
-And what was the message?
-Just this,
-look at the list.
-What does that mean?
-Is that it? Look at the list?
-He said you'd have it by now.
A list of 17 DVDs.
I didn't stay a policeman back then.
Got into publishing,
then video publishing.
Then DVDs, of course.
You put the Easter egg on.
Have you noticed
what all 17 DVDs have in common yet?
I suppose it's hard for you in a way.
How could the Doctor have even known
I had a list?
-I only just got this.
-I asked him how,
but he said he couldn't tell me.
He said you'd understand it one day,
but that I never would.
Soon as I understand it,
I'll come and tell you.
No, gorgeous girl. You can't.
There's only tonight.
He told me all those years ago,
that we'll only meet again
this one time.
On the night I die.
Oh, Billy.
It's kept me going.
I'm an old, sick man.
But I've had
something to look forward to.
Ah, life is long and you are hot.
Look at my hands.
An old man's hands.
How did that happen?
I'll stay.
I'm gonna stay with you, okay?
Thank you, Sally Sparrow.
I have till the rain stops.
(MOBILE RINGING)
-Bantos.
-SALLY: They're mine.
What?
The DVDs on the list, the 17 DVDs,
what they've got in common is me.
They're all the DVDs I own.
The Easter egg was intended for me.
-You've only got 17 DVDs?
-Do you have a portable DVD player?
-Of course. Why?
-I want you to meet me.
Where?
Wester Drumlins.
I knew you would live
in Scooby Doo's house.
For God's sake, I don't live here.
Okay. This is the one
with the clearest sound.
Slightly better picture quality
on this one,
-but I don't know...
-Doesn't matter.
Okay.
There he is.
-The Doctor.
-Who's a doctor?
-He's the Doctor.
-Yup, that's me.
-Okay, that was scary.
-No, it sounds like he's replying,
-but he always says that.
-Yes, I do.
-And that.
-Yup. And this.
He can hear us.
-Oh, my God. You can really hear us.
-Of course he can't hear us.
Look.
I've got a transcript, see?
Everything he says.
"Yup, that's me." "Yes, I do."”
"Yup, and this." Next, it's...
BOTH: Are you gonna read
out the whole thing?
Sorry.
Who are you?
I'm a time traveller. Or I was.
I'm stuck in 1969.
We're stuck. All of space and time,
he promised me.
Now I've got a job in a shop.
I've gotta support him!
-Martha!
-Sorry.
I've seen this bit before.
Quite possibly.
-1969, that's where you're talking from?
-Afraid so.
But you're replying to me.
You can't know exactly what
I'm gonna say 40 years before I say it.
38.
I'm getting this down.
I'm writing in your bits.
-How? How is this possible? Tell me.
-Not so fast.
People don't understand time.
It's not what you think it is.
Then what is it?
-Complicated.
-Tell me.
-Very complicated.
-I'm clever and I'm listening.
And don't patronise me
because people have died
and I'm not happy. Tell me.
People assume that time is
a strict progression of cause to effect,
but actually, from a non-linear,
non-subjective viewpoint,
it's more like a big ball
of wibbly-wobbly, timey-wimey stuff.
Yeah, I've seen this bit before.
You said that sentence got away
from you.
It got away from me, yeah.
Next thing you're gonna say is,
"Well, I can hear you."
Well I can hear you.
-This is impossible.
-No. It's brilliant!
Well, not hear you, exactly,
but I know everything you're gonna say.
Always gives me the shivers, that bit.
How can you know what I'm gonna say?
-Look to your left.
-What's he mean by "look to your left"?
I've written tons about that
in the forums.
I think it's a political statement.
He means you. What are you doing?
I'm writing in your bits.
That way, I've got a complete transcript
of the whole conversation.
Wait until this hits the Net.
This will explode the egg forums.
I've got a copy of the finished
transcript, it's on my Autocue.
How can you have
a copy of the finished transcript?
It's still being written.
I told you, I'm a time traveller.
I got it in the future.
Okay, let me get my head round this.
You're reading aloud from a transcript
of a conversation you're still having.
Wibbly-wobbly, timey-wimey...
Actually, never mind that.
You can do shorthand?
So?
What matters is we can communicate.
We have got big problems now.
They have taken the blue box,
haven't they?
The angels have the phone box?
"The angels have the phone box",
that's my favourite.
-I've got that on a T-shirt.
-What do you mean, angels?
-You mean those statue things?
-Creatures from another world.
-But they're just statues.
-Only when you see them.
What does that mean?
The Lonely Assassins
they used to be called.
No one quite knows where they came from,
but they're as old as the universe,
or very nearly,
and they have survived this long
because they have the most perfect
defence system ever evolved.
They are quantum locked.
They don't exist
when they're being observed.
The moment they are seen
by any other living creature,
they freeze into rock.
No choice, it's a fact of their biology.
In the sight of any living thing,
they literally turn to stone.
And you can't kill a stone.
Course, a stone can't kill you, either,
but then you turn your head away.
Then you blink.
And, oh, yes, it can.
-Don't take your eyes off that.
-That's why they cover their eyes.
They're not weeping,
they can't risk looking at each other.
Their greatest asset
is their greatest curse.
They can never be seen.
Loneliest creatures in the universe.
Well I'm sorry. I am very, very sorry.
It's up to you now.
-What am I supposed to do?
-The blue box. It's my time machine.
There is a world of time energy in there
they could feast on forever,
but the damage they could do
could switch off the sun.
-You have got to send it back to me.
-How?
How?
And that's it I'm afraid.
There's no more from you
on the transcript,
that's the last I've got.
I don't know what stopped you talking,
but I can guess. They're coming.
The angels are coming for you.
But listen,
your life could depend on this.
Don't blink. Don't even blink.
Blink and you're dead.
They are fast.
Faster than you can believe.
Don't turn your back,
don't look away and don't blink.
Good luck.
No, don't. You can't!
-I'll rewind him.
-What good will that do?
-You're not looking at the statue.
-Neither are you.
Keep looking at it. Keep looking at it.
It's just one, right?
It's just this one.
We're okay if we just keep staring
at this one statue.
-Everything's gonna be fine.
-There's three more.
-Three?
-They were upstairs before,
-but I think I heard them moving.
-Moving? Three of them?
-Moving where?
-I'm gonna look around. I'm gonna check.
You keep looking at this one.
Don't blink.
Remember what he said. Don't even blink.
Who blinked? I'm too scared to blink.
Okay, we're going to the door.
Front door.
Okay, we can't both get
to the front door
without taking our eyes off that thing,
so you stay here.
-What?
-I'll be just round the corner.
You stay here.
They've locked it! They've locked us in.
-Why?
-I've got something they want.
-What?
-The key.
I took it last time I was here.
They followed me to get it back.
I led them to the blue box.
Now they've got that.
Give them the key.
I'm gonna check the back door.
You wait here.
Give them the key!
Give them what they want!
-Sally, no! What if they come behind me?
-Hang on!
(DOOR RATTLING)
God.
-Oh, God.
-It's locked!
Sally! Sally!
It won't open!
Sally, please, I can't do this!
Sally, hurry up!
Where are you?
Larry, they've blocked up the back door,
but there's a cellar.
There might be a way out.
Delivery hatch or something.
I'm coming! I can't stay here.
Okay, boys. We know how this works.
You can't move so long as I can see you.
A whole world in the box,
the Doctor says.
I hope he's not lying 'cause I don't see
how else we're getting out.
Oh, and there's your one.
Why is it pointing at the...
light?
Oh, my God, it's turning out the light!
-Quickly!
-I can't find the lock!
Sally, hurry up!
Get it open!
-They're getting faster, Sally! Come on!
-It won't turn!
-I can't turn it!
-Sally! Oh!
Sally, hurry up! Come on!
DOCTOR: This is Security Protocol 712.
This time capsule has detected the
presence of an authorised control disc,
valid one journey.
Please insert the disc
and prepare for departure.
Looks like a DVD player. There's a slot.
-They're trying to get in!
-Well, hurry up, then!
-What's happening?
-Oh, my God, it's leaving us behind.
Doctor, don't! You can't!
Doctor!
Look at them! Quick, look at them!
I don't think we need to.
He tricked them.
The Doctor tricked them.
They're looking at each other.
They're never gonna move again.
Can you mind the shop? I'm just nipping
next door for some milk.
Yeah, no worries.
-What's this?
-Nothing.
Sally.
-Can't you let it go?
-Of course I can't let it go.
This is over.
How did the Doctor know
where to write those words on the wall?
How could he get
a copy of the transcript?
Where did he get
all that information from?
Look, some things you never find out
and that's okay.
No, it isn't.
Ever think this might be getting
in the way of
other things?
We just run a shop together.
That's all it is, just a shop.
Anyway. Milk.
Back in a mo.
-Right, it's definitely this way.
-Okay.
-Doctor! Doctor! Doctor!
-Hello. Sorry, bit of a rush.
There's a sort of thing happening.
Very important that we stop it.
Oh, my God, it's you. It really is you.
Oh, you don't remember me, do you?
Doctor, we haven't got time for this.
Migration's started.
Look, sorry,
I've got a bit of a complex life.
Things don't always happen to me
in quite the right order.
Gets a bit confusing at times,
especially at weddings.
I'm rubbish at weddings,
especially my own.
Oh, my God, of course!
You're a time traveller.
It hasn't happened to you yet,
none of it. It's still in your future.
-What hasn't happened?
-Doctor, please! 20 minutes to hatching.
It was me! Oh, for God's sake,
it was me all along.
-You got it all from me.
-Got what?
Okay, listen. One day,
you're gonna get stuck in 1969.
Make sure you've got this with you.
You're gonna need it.
-Doctor!
-Yeah! Listen, listen, gotta dash.
Things happening. Well, four things.
Well, four things and a lizard.
Okay, no worries. On you go.
See you around some day.
-What was your name?
-Sally Sparrow.
Good to meet you, Sally Sparrow.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Don't blink.
Blink and you're dead.
Don't turn your back.
Don't look away.
And don't blink.
Good luck.
We're going to the end of the universe.
The call came from across
the stars, over and over again,
"Come to Utopia."”
-Doctor.
-Captain.
(BOTH YELLING)
It's a future time.
Utopia is...
The last of the humans,
scattered across the night.
Humans are coming.
Not even us Time Lords came this far.
We should leave.