Exterminate!
Aaagh!
The Doctor must be destroyed!
Earth is protected by me and my
mates, this year and every other.
Here we go!
Exterminate!
- Now attach the parts.
- Weapon failure.
- The parts are on, Doctor!
- Get clear!
Is everyone all right in there?
We had an accident.
People got hurt.
The issue's been dealt with.
There'll be someone
waiting at Depository 23.
Long time since we opened that one.
Whatever that is, is it safe?
Just get it there quick as you can.
Am I allowed to stop for a cuppa?
Oh, only 'cause it's you.
How's your mum, by the way?
- Yeah, you know...
- Must be hard.
Yeah. Best get on the road.
- Hi.
Can I get a cup of tea in
there, please? Thank you.
- There you go, love.
- Cheers.
- Have a good day.
- Thanks very much. Have a good one.
When you said breakfast meeting,
I presumed it would be somewhere
that served breakfast.
- Jo Patterson.
- Leo Rugazzi.
CEO, Rugazzi Technologies.
I acquired Leo's company 18 months ago.
I see you buying a lot
of companies right now.
They're calling you the
American Mike Ashley.
There's a lot of value
in the market today.
Having your political ambitions ruined
by that little toxic waste scandal
seems to have been
a blessing in disguise.
That's a very sensitive subject for me.
I just wanted to say
that I am super-psyched
about having a proper
Technology Secretary at last.
I was super-psyched too,
until they told me that
my budget was £2.70.
Well, if anybody can make
it work, it's you, Jo.
Show me why we're here.
Leo has something...
...revolutionary to show you.
Just a small role-play.
We all know the problems
facing the world today.
Trust in our leaders
is at an all-time low.
Civil unrest is growing.
Security budgets are falling.
Our police forces are under pressure.
Goodness, I hope no-one's
going to get hurt.
The problem is obvious.
Here's the solution.
Built-in water cannon.
And CS gas.
We're not using actual CS gas.
I still think it would have been fine.
Sonic deterrent!
Entirely robotic with an
AI interface programme
for every eventuality,
thanks to extensive
real-world scenario testing.
Er, solar... solar powered
with A-grade energy rating.
You built this yourself?
Oh, pretty much. Um, once
Mr. Robertson became involved,
he really helped us
turbo-boost the whole project.
Actually, talking about...
Er, she gets the picture,
Leo. That's fine.
This is a game-changer, Jo.
It's the security equivalent
of the iPhone.
Shall we talk in private?
I want them built and beta
tested in my constituency.
Yes, yes, as discussed.
When those car firms deserted
you, I bought up all the plants.
I own them now. So we repurpose
new infrastructure, new jobs.
This is going to be
a big win for you, Jo.
A flagship policy from our dynamic
new Technology Secretary
and it looks like, er, your party's
going to need a new leader soon.
What does he know, young Leo?
Only that I got the parts
from some unknown source.
If it ever gets out
that I tipped you off
about advanced technology
being transported from GCHQ...
It won't.
We trust each other.
This is a good arrangement, Jo.
You're simply facilitating
an acquisition
and I'm cutting you in on the IP.
Nobody knows.
Everybody wins.
How long will it take?
Er, a year, give or take.
Ugh...
Morning, camera 37.
Morning, camera 38.
Morning, Angela.
All right, Bonnie and Clyde?
Tiny!
How many times?
You can't eat the cage.
Believe me, I've tried.
Bedtime story, Doctor?
Yes, please, Doctor.
One of the classics?
Ooh, yes, please.
Settle down, then.
"Mr. and Mrs. Dursley, of number
four Privet Drive, were proud to say
that they were perfectly normal..."
What?
Who's there?
Stay strong.
People are waiting for you.
I keep thinking she was barely
in here for a couple of minutes
and yet she coded the
entry lock to our DNA,
just like on her own TARDIS.
Maybe that's 'cause she wanted
us to be able to follow her,
to find her,
'cause she needed us.
I'm going to work it out.
I must be able to work it out.
Happy New Year, Yaz.
When was it New Year?
You been sleeping in here?
Maybe.
Yaz, you can't keep
being here all the time.
The Doc, you know, she went to do
something she knew might kill her.
- We've just got to assume she didn't make it.
- Why?
Why do we have to assume that?
Mate, we've been back ten months.
We have to get on with our lives.
That's what she told us.
That's what she wanted for us.
But what if she needs us?
How many times has she saved us?
Yaz, face up to it, we
don't know how to find her.
All right?
And there's something else.
- Graham, show her.
- Mm-hm.
The Doc would really want us to
keep an eye on the planet, right?
Look, this is leaked online footage
of what they're calling a
prototype security drone.
Apparently, this was taken
over a year ago. Just watch.
- That's a Dalek.
- Mm-hm.
But how's that possible?
- No idea.
- Watch.
Jack Robertson.
- Spider guy.
- Mm.
He's in league with a Dalek?
That's what we're going to find out.
And that's what the Doc would
do if she was here, so...
...are you with us?
Well, it's an honour
to be summoned by the
Prime Minister in waiting...
...even if it is a bit, er, rural.
How many hours till we get
the results from the ballots?
The numbers are on my side.
That's why I wanted to talk.
You're not having doubts
about our agreement, are you?
Quite the opposite.
I want to expedite our project.
Six of the sweetest words
in the English language.
I want an immediate national
roll-out of security drones.
National?
But we've only just started
regional beta testing.
And I want it at no cost
to the British taxpayer.
Why, Jo, this is starting
to sound like a shakedown.
This country can be your
shop window for global sales.
Unless, of course, you'd like
the Treasury to take a look
at how much tax all your
companies pay over here?
Ah. Well played...
...Prime Minister.
Well played.
Leo? I'm outside.
Three minutes.
Yo. Remember us?
Take the car! Just leave my face.
What?
Oh, no! Not you guys!
Yeah, us, 'cause we know
all about you and that Dalek.
- The what?
- The Dalek.
The most deadly creature in the
universe. We saw you with it.
What is this word that you keep using?
Oh, don't play innocent! Dalek.
Whatever you're doing with
it, we're going to stop you.
Hands in the air!
Step away from the car!
What, you didn't think
I'd increase my security
since the last time we met?
You're lucky you're not
all dead on the ground.
Get rid of 'em, boys.
Well, that didn't go
exactly to plan, did it?
I like that whole
"whatever you're doing,
we're going to stop you"
vibe. Very Doctory.
Doesn't work when I do it.
We didn't get anywhere near
an explanation from him.
If we had the Doctor's psychic paper
or we knew how to work that TARDIS,
we could get into his office
and see what's going on.
Yeah, but we don't, so we're going
to have to try and
figure out another way.
Yeah. This is hard, innit?
Morning, camera 38.
Oh, I forgot you were here.
What about this face?
Remember this?
Jack?
Jack!
I knew you would look better
in these colours than me.
Hello, Doctor.
What are you doing here?
What do you think I'm doing
here? Breaking you out.
Temporal-freezing gateway
disinhibitor bubble. Catchy, right?
If it were me, I'd have
called it a breakout ball.
Freezes time temporarily,
breaks through walls.
Only problem is...
...it doesn't last long.
- Hi!
- Have you had work done?
You can talk!
Now shut up and run.
I heard a rumour you were in here,
so I committed a few crimes.
Well, maybe a lot of crimes.
Maybe more than I should have.
What sort of crimes?
- Left turn.
- Oh!
You're going to take the
moral high ground with me
when I'm breaking you out of prison?
- Be grateful!
- Front door!
- How long has this thing got left?
- 11 seconds till expiry!
Go!
Phew!
Took 19 years to get
to the cell next to you.
- Hope you had enough to occupy your mind.
- Too much.
Here we go. One secretly
stashed vortex manipulator.
Wondered how long that would
take. We need to go now.
How did you manage to
smuggle that in here?
You really want me to answer that?
Oh, I've missed you... very much.
Let's go.
Operation, logistics and
production have all been called in.
Everyone has been told maximum
capacity, maximum speed,
and our beta partners are
working through the night,
training staff, under our supervisors
all under NDAs, of... of course.
I mean, we think we might
have enough in place to...
...well, to make the deadline.
Great.
Great job, Leo. This is
going to be good for us.
I-I can't help but feel a little...
...well, you know, a little worried
about the speed of this.
Everybody's worried, Leo.
We live in uncertain times.
Do you want to win?
Embrace the uncertainty.
Live in the worry.
O-Okay. Um, so...
So... there's-there's just something
I-I needed to share on this project.
When I first started
working on that casing,
I broke it down into
the tiniest components.
I made it my mission to, well, to
understand everything about it.
Yes, and you did a great job.
These machines are going
to change the world.
I'm not talking about the machines.
I'm talking about what was
inside the original artefact.
There's nothing inside, Leo.
It was a burnt-out shell.
Well, that's what I'm
trying to tell you.
This granular investigation
I've been doing, I...
...well, I found something more
organic remnants inside the machine,
tiny cellular traces
scattered across the casing.
Where are you going with this, Leo?
Well...
Look, I'll ju... I'll just show you.
Look.
Just here, see?
I-I took the cellular traces and I...
...and I cloned them.
Grew them.
I grew a creature.
Oh, my God!
- It's beautiful, isn't it?
- No!
Are you insane?!
That's the most disgusting
thing I've ever seen in my life.
What were you thinking?
What? It's intelligent.
I hooked it into the
intra-neural network
and... and there were
flickers of activity.
It understood our systems immediately.
You did what?!
All right. Not another word.
You've overreached, Leo.
- I want this incinerated immediately.
- What?!
No argument!
- Ow!
- I don't want to see a trace of this.
This never happened, you
never showed it to me,
this thing never existed.
Do you understand?
Okay, okay.
You know what your problem is, Leo?
You're too clever.
This is why people don't like experts.
I'm sorry.
Hi, love.
It... It's me.
I-I have to go on an urgent
business trip tonight.
Give the kids a kiss from me.
Er...
...I'll call you when I can.
Love you.
Bye.
Stand.
Good puppet.
We're out.
I'm back.
My own TARDIS.
Captain Jack Harkness,
gold star for rescuing.
Told your friends if you
ever need help, I'd be there.
Wow.
Nice upgrade in here.
Which way's my room?
You don't have a room.
You've never had a room.
I had a suite with its
own cocktail lounge.
They gave you my message,
about the lone Cyberman?
You didn't give it the Cyberium?
- It's a long story. I fixed it. Eventually.
- What?
Just about. Sort of.
Why were you in prison
in the first place?
Evading the Judoon. Twice at once.
Then once I was in,
they took 7,000 other
offences into consideration.
They stopped at seven?
I was in prison for being me...
...right at the point when I
wasn't sure what that meant.
Ah, it's been a tough few decades.
You're okay now, yeah?
Oh, I guess we'll find out.
Wakey-wakey.
Hey!
Nice nap?
Thanks for waiting.
I had a lot to think about in there.
And three very special
people I've missed.
- One of them was me, right?
- You never change.
Wish I could say the same.
Right.
Find me my fam.
This is what I've got so far.
Remnants of the Dalek we fought at GCHQ
were cleared but then stolen.
The driver is missing, presumed dead.
Now Robertson's got his hands on it.
Well, he can't have,
because you sent that creature
thing that was inside it
into a supernova, so...
Maybe there's more
of them here on Earth.
And one's got Robertson
under their control.
Ryan, shh!
Please.
Please be her.
Hi! I was in space jail.
You what?
Guess who got her out?
You all met Jack, right?
Hey, silver fox!
Hello.
We were worried about you!
What? How long's it been?
A week?
Two weeks?
Ten months.
Er, whoops!
No, it can't be. I set identical
temporal coordinates
to when I sent you back.
Yeah, but your time
machine ain't the best
at running to time, is it, Doc?
I'm sorry.
Yeah, well, it's done now, so...
Yeah.
So...
...what's new on planet Earth?
Dalek.
Forward.
Further. Further.
What is this place?
What have you done?
This is my project.
This is what I have built.
So, it looks like a Dalek,
but it can't be a Dalek...
...unless it is a Dalek!
Trust us. We've seen the footage.
If you scan for Dalek DNA
trace across the planet...
- Oh, she's good.
- Yeah, we all are.
So, you've had dealings
with Daleks as well, then?
Yeah, they killed me once.
Long time ago, no big deal.
- You look pretty healthy for a corpse.
- I know, right?
I can be killed but I come
back to life pretty quick.
Partially her fault, partially a friend
of hers on Earth called Rose.
But she's trapped in a
parallel universe now.
She's what?
Dalek DNA trace, Japan.
Osaka. Well, sort of.
Not an exact match.
Oh, it's corrupted.
I can't quite make sense of it.
I can check it out. Anyone want to come?
I will!
- I want a word with Robertson direct.
- Yeah, me too.
Looks like he's recently
opened a facility in Osaka.
We could check it out,
drop you on the way.
Everyone working at maximum capacity.
Er... Let me call you back.
If you're dealing with Daleks,
you are way out of your depth.
What is that thing?
I want to know what
you're doing right now,
and don't try calling security,
'cause I just blocked your phone lines.
What is the matter with you people? Hmm?
Do you want to know what I'm
doing? I'll show you myself.
Welcome to the production line.
You're making Daleks.
We're 3D-printing security drones.
- What about what's inside?
- There's nothing inside.
It's run by artificial intelligence.
- What?
- Watch.
See?
They're machines.
There's the remote signal unit.
- They're empty.
- Mm-hm.
You're messing with things
you don't understand.
The creature these are modelled on
is the most evil killing
machine in the universe.
You're getting much too excited
about a bunch of 3D-printed shapes.
So what are you doing
at your facility in Osaka?
We don't have a facility in Osaka.
- Yeah, you do.
- No, we don't!
I would know.
It says this is an agricultural park.
Guess this is the future.
- Hmm.
- Vertical farms. All inside.
In my time, there are whole
agri-planets that look like this,
shipping food all over galaxies.
- Your time?
- 51st century.
Get lost!
Seriously. Boeshane Peninsula.
Maybe one day I'll take you there.
- Are they all like you there?
- No.
I'm pretty special.
Had a rough time, then?
Without the Doctor?
I don't know what you mean.
I saw the way you shoved her.
You thought she wasn't
coming back, right?
You're guessing a lot from a shove.
I have my own experience
with the Doctor.
I just missed her.
- I never stopped to think...
- Hey.
When I was with the Doctor,
I saw more than I could
have ever dreamed.
And then...
...we lost each other.
I didn't know what happened to him.
If he was alive or...
...if I was ever going
to see him again.
Hard way to live.
Being with the Doctor, you don't
get to choose when it stops...
...whether you leave her or...
...she leaves you.
It felt cruel...
...to be shown something
I couldn't have any more.
Felt like, um, I'd
rather not have known.
I'd rather not have met her,
cos having met her and then...
...being without her, that's worse.
How do you deal with that?
How many people in the
universe get to meet the Doctor,
let alone travel with her?
We're the lucky ones, Yaz.
Enjoy the journey while you're on it.
'Cause the joy...
...is worth the pain.
Locked door.
Thanks.
"Thanks"?
That's it?
Are you feeling insecure?
'Cause you seem to need a lot of praise.
Do I?
Through here.
Those things.
They were what was
inside the Dalek we met.
Inside every Dalek.
This is a clone farm.
They're not growing
food here, they're...
...they're growing Daleks.
As your new Prime Minister,
I can see great opportunities
ahead for this country.
We here in Britain, we've
never been afraid of the future,
but I do understand that what we
all crave right now is security.
Security in our politics,
security in our jobs,
security for our families.
I pledge to bring stability and security
to every aspect of our national life.
Together, we can make
this the age of security.
What's happening here?
What are we actually doing?
Going to Osaka, fast!
What about...?
What about this blue box?
What is it? It's a... It's a doorway?
It can't be.
That was my hallway.
I don't understand.
Should we explain it to him?
No, it's more fun watching him struggle.
As hard as it is for you to
understand, this isn't about you.
This is about Daleks.
Please stop using that
word. It has no meaning.
Yes, it does.
To billions of people, Dalek means hate.
Daleks are creatures
of hate and aggression.
Daleks are insidious,
relentless and clever,
and, like hate, they will
spread if they're not stopped.
Never underestimate a Dalek.
Which is why I am unveiling today
a very exciting, new solution
to an age-old problem.
We will harness the
technological revolution
to enhance your safety.
We will alleviate pressure
on police and security staff
and all without draining
the public purse.
Oi! Can you hurry up
and help me with this?
I need to take a sample of the liquid.
I want to know what it's being fed on.
Might give us a clue on how to stop 'em.
Huh. We're going to blow 'em up, kid.
That's how we stop 'em.
Jack!
Get it off me!
Stand still! Yaz, don't move!
Nice shot.
As of now, you will see
new defence drones at work
on Britain's streets...
...in our institutions, at our borders...
...and national monuments.
These technological innovations are set
to make Britain more secure.
You do love a beanie.
Me too.
One of the first things I noticed
about you that night we met.
I thought, "Not everyone can
carry off a yellow beanie.
There's a lad to rely on".
Four minutes to Osaka.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm sorry...
...about the ten months.
More sorry than I can ever really say.
This thing, innit? You never
really quite got the hang of it.
I missed you all...
...so much.
Yeah?
We missed you too.
But you've been good?
- Yeah, maybe it's what I needed.
- Oh, yeah. Huh.
Maybe it was.
Hmm. I saw me dad.
Oh, good. Well, was it good?
He's all right?
Yeah, he's back at the oil rigs again.
Due back in a couple of weeks.
But, yeah, we're good.
We're getting there.
Time to reconnect with him,
time to see me mates,
see what's happening on the old planet.
Lots of work to be done here on Earth.
Yeah. Always.
Well, it sounds like
you enjoyed being back.
It's home.
Yeah.
What's happening with your home?
You know, what happened
to you on Gallifrey?
All life there destroyed.
Thanks to the death
particle and Ko Sharmus.
And the Master? What
did he want with you?
- It doesn't even matter now.
- No, no, no.
Don't give me that. Right?
I see what you're doing.
You're trying to avoid the subject.
We've known each other long enough now.
I know when something's changed.
Me too.
I'm not who I thought I was, Ryan.
What I always knew to
be the story of my life...
...isn't true.
I wasn't born on Gallifrey.
Where I'm from, all
the lives I've lived,
some of that has been hidden from me,
and I don't even know how much.
Seriously?
And how do you feel about that?
Mostly...
...angry.
While I was locked away,
all I kept thinking was...
"... If I'm not who I thought
I was, then who am I?"
You're the Doctor.
Same as before, same as always.
Right.
Same Doctor, same Ryan.
Nothing's changed.
No. No.
I didn't say that, did I?
Things change all the time, and
they should, cos they have to.
Same with people.
Sometimes we get a bit scared,
'cause new can be a bit scary, right?
New can be very scary.
So, when we're done
with this Dalek problem,
you find out about your own life.
Confront the new, or the old.
And then everything will be all right.
- Will it?
- No doubt.
What?
Thank you, Ryan...
...for being my friend.
Thank you for being mine.
Always.
Osaka.
Oh-ho-ho! I've missed that sound.
Whoa!
Wait, what just happened?
- Still not telling him?
- No.
Where am I?
- Did you really have to bring him?
- Yaz!
Graham.
Oh, what are those things?
The creatures that live inside Daleks.
But who built all this?!
I have.
- Leo?
- Don't get too close!
I warned you about that thing.
What have you done, Leo?
Cloned the smallest
trace of organic material,
not understanding that
Dalek consciousness
can live within the tiniest
fragment of their DNA.
You weren't to know.
You're safe. We're here for you.
We're going to get
you out of here alive.
You give this body false hope.
All right, then, Dalek,
or whatever you are,
tell me how you've built all this.
I connected myself
into the neural network.
I inserted myself into the
organisation, into every network.
I located this place, created it.
Every piece of equipment,
every idea behind it...
...I did that.
Wait a minute. First of
all, that's not possible.
Where did you get the purchase
order numbers in the first place?
Really, that's what's
bugging you most right now?
I used your systems
to buy this building,
to order equipment,
to pay humans to construct
and to continue the clone work.
I used your systems to build
an army all in my image.
But where are the workers?
Where are the people
who did all the cloning?
Once the experiments
were working, they became...
...unnecessary.
We found them another use.
What, you're feeding cloned
Dalek creatures liquidised humans?
Correct.
This is a PR disaster.
But there's something
else that's bugging me.
- What is it?
- Is it the light?
The light's been changing really
slowly ever since we've been here.
Yes, it is. Thanks, Yaz.
I missed you, Yaz.
Right, why is that important?
Oh, there's too much
going on. Where was I?
Yes. How are you going
to get off this planet?
We will not.
I'm sorry?
The planet is ours.
It will be converted.
Converted into what?
We shall use this planet as a base
from which to conquer this
sector of the universe.
There's a long way between
squatting in a Japanese lab
and subjugating humanity.
I mean, you don't even have bodies.
What are you going to do?
Order people from your tanks?
Even if you made it to those shells
down there, which you can't.
You can't.
I mean, you definitely can't. The...
Those shells aren't even weaponised.
They're not proper Daleks.
- He built them.
- Doctor...
...what's the matter?
The light.
The shells were built in his factories.
Do you think I've not
augmented those designs also?
Where's the light? We
have to turn off the light!
Why, Doctor?
Ultraviolet light.
The Recon Dalek used it
to come back together.
Activate!
My project shall be complete.
The New Dalek Army shall
have but one purpose.
Exterminate!
It appears that there
are some teething issues
with the... with the drones,
so I appeal to everybody to keep calm.
The drones are completely
under our control,
so we're working to shut them down...
Territorial leader identified.
Daleks will not be shut
down. Daleks are supreme.
This must be some sort of a joke.
Daleks do not joke.
- And I do not surrender.
- Exterminate!
This territory is the
property of the Daleks.
Daleks are in control.
All humanity will be exterminated.
- How many Daleks did you build?
- Look, I don't know.
- How many?!
- Thousands!
Stop.
You don't have to kill him.
Correct.
I do not have to, and yet...
I'm sorry.
Oh, Leo!
No weapons. No time to think.
All that time in a cell
wondering who I am.
I'm the Doctor.
I'm the one who stops the Daleks.
All of you, to the TARDIS now!
Only one thing I can
think of. Nuclear option.
Nuclear option that might backfire.
If it's what I think you're thinking,
you'd better stop thinking it right now.
Way too big a risk.
- How big a risk?
- Planet-threatening.
Got any better ideas?
'Cause now is your moment.
I'm all ears.
Exactly!
So, what is it you're going to do?
They're built from the
original Reconnaissance Dalek.
I'm going to give them what
they wanted in the first place.
- What's she doing?
- Something you never want to do.
Doc, what have you done?
Sent a message through the
timelines into the vortex,
'cause I know they're in
there, like sharks in water.
Always scoping, always ready.
Incoming reconnaissance signal detected.
Strategise!
Programme destination for Earth.
Resistance must be expected!
Ready attack formation protocols!
Who's in there?
The ship you never want to
see arriving on your planet.
- What's on it?
- Death Squad Daleks.
Think of them like the SAS of Daleks.
- Only way more brutal.
- They're our best hope right now.
But they're going to kill more humans.
They don't care about humans.
They're the enforcers of the Dalek race.
To combat Daleks, you've
brought more Daleks?
Yes, but they don't know that
I'm behind the transmission,
and it's quite important that
they don't realise I'm here.
We've got previous.
We're not best mates.
All right, look, so if your plan works
and this set of Daleks kills his lot...
- It's not my lot.
- Thank you.
...how do we get rid of the new ones?
That's phase two of the
plan. It'll be down to us.
Feeble humans, do not run!
Your bodies are too slow for Daleks!
Daleks are in control of this territory!
Humans shall be exterminated!
The New Dalek Army is in control!
Daleks are reborn!
Nothing shall stop the supremacy
of the New Dalek Army!
Analysis!
Scan determines rogue creatures below!
Mutated Dalek DNA detected!
Prepare for maximum extermination!
Primary rogue impurities located!
Isolate and engage primary
rogue Dalek impurities!
Seek and destroy all
other Dalek impurities!
Engaging primary rogue Dalek impurities!
Halt. Stay where you are!
- Daleks are now in control!
- In control!
In control!
Daleks are already in control.
Identify!
Dalek!
Incorrect. Scan detects anomalies.
Dalek DNA merged with human traces.
We have mutated to survive.
You are impure! The Dalek
race must have purity!
Exterminate!
Exterminate the impurities!
- Exterminate the impurities!
That's the thing about Daleks.
For a race born out of mutation,
they're pretty obsessed with purity.
All that product.
Maybe I can make a claim on insurance.
Get back in the TARDIS.
I don't take my orders from you, Doctor.
Those are powerful,
intelligent creatures.
I'm backing them.
Don't be stupid. They will kill you.
I don't think so.
See you later.
Robertson, get back here!
- Exterminate!
- Wait, wait.
I come in peace.
Who are you?
I speak for humanity.
You are the leader of this planet?
Yes.
And I'm your best ally here.
Daleks do not need allies.
I know how the Earth works.
I have information.
I can guide you.
Daleks have no need of
guidance from humans.
You are unimportant.
I can see how you might think that,
but, er, I'm no ordinary human.
We shall destroy Dalek impurities!
Of course.
But when you're done with that,
you're going to want
the planet too, right?
Don't you think that would go
down well with your fellow Daleks?
You would betray your own race?
You would betray humanity?
Sure.
And I have some other information.
The signal that brought you here...
Explain!
First, I want to meet
who's in charge here.
In other words, take me to your leader.
Phase one of the plan is working.
Daleks destroying other Daleks
in order to save humanity.
Now, phase two.
Jack, how do you feel about
boarding an SAS Dalek ship?
- Can I blow it up?
- Yes, please.
My kind of plan.
- I have Dalek issues.
- No kidding?
You never forget your first death.
Me and Graham are coming with you.
- Are we?
- Big Dalek ship, only one guy.
If we don't help, the
human race is going down.
Yeah, yeah, he's right.
We're coming with you.
Whoa, whoa, are you okay with this?
I couldn't stop them
even if I wanted to.
No detonation until we're sure
that the SAS Daleks have destroyed
all of Robertson's creations.
And before you're all clear
of the Dalek ship, obviously.
Obviously. We didn't come this
far just to get exterminated.
Okay, boys. Hold tight.
'Cause here we go.
Right.
Okay, command centre is down that way.
Do not go that way. That's
where most of the Daleks will be.
- Are you clear on what to do?
- Yeah.
Spread these things out
and don't get killed.
- That's it. Good luck.
- Oh...
That's it, eh? Ryan, see,
this is our area of expertise.
First, the Cyber dudes, now the Daleks
no alien ship is safe
from us two bad boys.
What?
Stop talking weird, Graham.
Sorry.
Alert! Internal ship sensors report
non-Dalek life forms on board!
Seek, locate and exterminate
all non-Dalek life forms!
Okay! Who's in charge here?
I only want to talk to the boss.
Speak!
Well, first of all, you need
to know that I'm on your side.
Now, to prove that, I can tell you this
you're all headed into a trap.
The person who summoned
you, she's called the Doctor.
The Doctor is an enemy
of the Dalek race!
I know. So, here's the deal.
You let me live, I help you find her.
You've got to be kidding me!
Incoming emergency
spatial shift! Exterminate!
Do not exterminate. I am Dalek. Halt!
We have exterminated all impurities!
You are the final remaining impurity!
I am not impure.
I am a survivor
the last remains of a
reconnaissance scout.
I surveyed this planet.
I attempted to alert the fleet.
I have served, given my
life for the Dalek cause.
But you are impure.
I can be purified.
My genetics can be modified.
There is only one purification.
Exterminate!
- Argh!
- Jack, explosives all laid. Good to go.
- Sort of.
- What do you mean?
Doctor, I've got some good
news and some bad news.
The good news is
the last of Robertson's
Daleks has been destroyed.
Can we stop there and
pretend there's no bad news?
The bad news is Robertson is
negotiating with the Daleks
and has sold you out.
The Daleks know it was you
who brought them here, as a trap.
I knew I wouldn't like the bad news.
What do we do?
Right, just running
through the options...
...which hasn't taken long.
Even if we blow up the ship,
there's still SAS Daleks
marauding through Earth's skies,
and now they know I'm here!
So we have to keep you out their way.
Or...
Or what?
- Shh. Working.
- Doctor, tell me.
You're going to have to
trust me on this, Yaz.
When have I ever let you down before?
I won't disappear again.
Yeah, you will.
One day, you will.
Where are we?
Right, come here and monitor this timer.
Jack, I need you to be ready
to get everyone off
that ship and detonate.
Yaz will tell you when.
What about the other Daleks?
I'm dealing with them!
Hey.
I'm a bit lost.
Alert, alert!
Didn't sound good. Do
you want to get that?
Remain here.
All Dalek units, report
to central control.
The Doctor is detected!
Extermination formations, assemble!
TARDIS location identified!
Give us one good reason why
we should save your life.
Money?
- I still say we should leave him here.
- Yeah.
Exterminate!
Go!
The Doctor's TARDIS is located.
Surround the TARDIS!
Hey! Daleks!
- Over here!
- It is the Doctor!
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks!
Yes, it is. And, yes, I am.
I called you here and you
came, like obedient little pets.
Thanks for solving my problem.
Daleks are not pets of the Doctor!
Yes, you are. Why? What are
you going to do about it?
'Cause I'm just standing
here, in my TARDIS.
Attack the TARDIS!
Exterminate the Doctor!
You're sure this is the right way?
- There's Daleks everywhere!
- We've got to get us out of here.
You are intruders!
This is a terrible rescue!
Intruders located!
Life forms identified!
We're surrounded!
- Do not move!
Hey, are we ready? Do I detonate?
Almost. Grab hold.
Now, Jack! Get off the ship!
Intruders, identify!
I'm Captain Jack Harkness.
And I'm immortal. Ha!
Exterminate!
Dalek craft destroyed!
Where is the Doctor?!
Search the TARDIS!
Exterminate the Doctor!
Oh, mate! You fell
for the old switcheroo.
Awkward. That's not my TARDIS.
I had a spare one lying around,
so I used the chameleon circuit
to make it look like mine,
and guess who fell for it?
You guys.
We shall find you!
We have control of a TARDIS!
No. You don't. Sorry.
More bad news. I've programmed
it to fold in on itself
and send itself to
the heart of the Void,
which will of course break it apart
and destroy you in the process.
Thanks for helping today.
Won't be seeing you later.
You will not escape us, Doctor!
Yes, I will. Every time.
- Oh, that was horrible.
- I feel sick.
What just happened to me?
Did we do it?
We did it!
Daleks all exiled.
Now, you have got a
lot of explaining to do.
I was deliberately acting as a decoy.
They're calling him
the saviour of humanity,
the man who stood up to the
invaders on behalf of us all.
Now, as rumours intensify
that he may be in line
for an honorary knighthood,
Jack Robertson spoke to me from
his home in the United States.
Emily, I did what any man
person, human person
would do in those circumstances.
There's even talk of a revived
presidential run for you.
Well, I can't really answer to that.
- Can you believe that?
- Yeah, I can.
We should go and meet the Doc.
Yeah.
Sorry, lost track of time.
Gwen Cooper sends her love, by the way.
Says she took out a Dalek
with a moped and her
son's boxing gloves.
Hoo-hoo! Anyway,
I'm going to stick around on
Earth and catch up with her.
I'll call ya.
Send my love to Gwen. Okay, bye!
Right, fam,
I thought we could try
the Meringue Galaxy.
It's not a place, it's a restaurant
where every course is meringue.
And the furniture.
- Plus the waiters!
- Love it!
- All set?
- Ready.
Yep.
Nah.
I think I'm going to stay here.
Yeah.
Me mates need me.
And I know this sounds stupid, but...
...I feel like my planet needs me.
You've got to fight for it, right?
Look, Doctor, before...
...before I met you, I didn't know
what I wanted to do with me life.
And...
And now... And now, I know.
Ten months.
I made it back too late.
Missed my time with you.
So, are we hugging, or...?
What about you two?
Are you going to...?
Stay? Yeah, definitely.
Yes!
I'm not ready to let you go yet.
That's all right, isn't it?
You've said it now, so...
Of course it's all right. She needs you.
- Yes for Yaz!
- Hey.
You're getting over me
leaving quick enough.
Two hearts.
One happy...
...one sad.
Make sure she doesn't
get in any trouble.
It's going to be difficult.
I'm holding you responsible
for the planet while I'm away.
Yeah. Deal.
Graham?
Look, it's all right, you know.
I'm all grown up now,
so... you can go with them.
Yeah, well...
Yeah, well, you know,
there's lots to explore,
so much more to see.
You know...
But, um...
I don't want to miss out on you,
you know, and being here
without you ain't going to be...
...the same.
You know, I'll always
be looking around, then,
to say stuff to you, you know?
You see, Ryan, you're my family.
And I remember, Doc,
what you said, you know,
that we... we wouldn't come back
the same people, and you're right.
Just not in the way I thought.
I'm ready. I want to...
I want to be at home with my grandson.
What?
I just thought I'd have the
place to myself, you know.
No such luck.
Yaz.
I'm sure I'll see you soon, eh?
Keep doing humanity proud.
I'm going to miss you.
Doc.
Thank you so much.
Right...
Well, come on, son.
Hey...
Bye, fam.
Yeah.
Right...
Wait.
Take these. Might come in handy.
Oh. Ta.
Oh!
And, Doc, I was wrong.
We do get aliens in Sheffield.
I could always use
the TARDIS to go back,
arrive an hour after you guys,
change the timeline.
Then we'd have more time together.
It's okay to be sad.
Okay, three, two,
one, go!
Yes, go on, Ryan!
You're doing it, son!
Go on, son!
Come on!
All right.
Ryan, you okay, son?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah?
Well, look, definitely further.
- Yeah. Maybe.
- No, definitely.
I was looking online earlier...
Some weird stuff going on
in a village in Finland.
Troll invasion, so
the locals are saying.
Yeah, I saw that.
And, you know, there's a quarry
in Korea that's shut down
because the workers are reporting
they saw gravel creatures come to life.
Psychic paper.
Yeah. These will get us in anywhere.
Yeah, Finland, Korea...
- Well, then, what are we waiting for?
- I'm not done here yet.
Yeah, but, look... I mean, this...
You'll be black and blue.
I don't know if you heard
about me, but I'm Ryan Sinclair.
Me and me mates, we saw off everything
from giant spiders to
a conscious universe.
We fought Cybermen,
Skithra, Morax...
...the mighty Pting.
It's going to take more
than a bike to scare me off.
Ain't that right, Grandad?
Yeah.
Right, then. Well, come
on, then. Jump on, then.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, uh, just got the sun in me eyes.
Yeah, me too.
Right, a few more tries and
we'll go and save the world, eh?
- Yeah.
Here we go, get ready.
Three, two, one...
Go! Go on, Ryan.
Yeah! Go on, son!
You're doing it, mate!