NARRATOR: A long time ago,
on the battlefields of Britain,
an army of enemies came together
to face an impossible opponent
beyond their wildest nightmares.
(ALL SHOUTING)
This unlikely army fought and won
the bloodiest of battles.
But only just.
Their opponent had been so remorseless,
the fear it placed in them was absolute.
So they made a pact.
They split their opponent's
vanquished body into three pieces,
to be buried at
opposite ends of the world,
and vowed that the burial sites would be
forever guarded as a precaution.
The three swore an oath of secrecy.
The terrifying opponent
was to be erased from history.
The three Custodians undertook
their long journeys across land and sea,
locating isolated sites and carrying out
their task with monastic dedication.
Passing their duties down
through the generations,
to protect the future,
the Custodians were unyielding.
(YELPS)
All except one,
whose journey was never made.
Felled at the first
by an unwitting assailant
who would never know
the full impact of his arrow.
And time moved on,
obscuring the lost Custodian's body,
leaving the other two Custodians
and their descendants
unaware of their comrade's fate
for eternity.
Almost.
MITCH: Right, let's have a look.
Where were we?
Oh, yeah, here we go.
I'm so glad you suggested
coming in today.
LIN: I hate New Year's day.
Everything's closed,
everyone is hung over,
and there's nothing to do.
Also, what is cooler than this?
Never thought I'd be involved in
a proper find,
even if this isn't Alfred the Great.
Eh, they found Richard III
in a car park in Leicester,
no reason we can't find Alfred the Great
under Sheffield Town Hall.
No reason.
Oh, apart from history and geography.
Yeah, I was never very good at those.
(BOTH LAUGH)
(CLEARS THROAT)
So, uh,
are we gonna talk about it?
Talk about what, Mitch?
The kiss,
that happened.
Yeah. Yeah, okay, let's talk about that.
So, was it for you...
(STAMMERS) I'm just checking.
I don't wanna presume.
Like a, "Happy New Year mates”
kiss or...
...not?
Did it feel like
a "Happy New Year mates" kiss?
No.
-It was more kissy than that, I'd say.
-(LAUGHS)
Oh, good, yeah.
'Cause it was more than that for me.
-Oh, thank God.
-(BOTH LAUGH)
I mean, great... I mean, amazing...
For me too.
Wow. (STAMMERS) I didn't sleep all night
when I got home, 'cause I was wondering.
Me neither.
That's why I texted you to say come in.
-Oh, really?
-Yes, um...
-(SIGHS)
-You idiot.
So, what do we do now?
I mean,
I'm not suggesting that we... Here.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Finish this,
fix a time to go out properly.
How does that sound?
-That sounds awesome.
-(LAUGHS)
It's my favourite year ever.
Already, one day in. (CHUCKLES)
-Look at this.
-Hmm?
Here, just below this side of the hand.
There's something here.
I just can't figure out what it is.
MITCH: Oh, yeah.
Well, let's record it and bag it up.
Contents recorded, coded and bagged.
Whatever it is.
LIN: Thanks.
You do realise, this means
those drawings could be true.
The battle of Hope Valley.
I know you love those documents
and I know you want them to be true,
but this is more significant than that.
A lot more significant.
What if he was part of it, hmm?
He could've fought in it.
He could be the key
to unlocking what it was all about.
Or, he could be
nothing to do with it, whatsoever.
You see, that's the difference
between you and me.
I am glass half full.
-LIN: Oh, is that right?
-Hundred percent.
LIN: Oh, yeah, who was it who doubted...
(CRACKLING)
(RUMBLING)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
DOCTOR: Wait for it, last one.
See? Cosmic fireworks.
Hey, Doc, I've got to hand it to you.
That is the best fireworks display
I've ever seen.
-Didn't I say?
-Yeah.
Nineteen New Year's Eves in a row,
which was your favourite?
-I did love Mesopotamia.
-Ah, the original.
Oh, really. So, Iraq invented New Year.
Sydney, 2000. Watching the fireworks
on top of the Harbour Bridge.
-Until you nearly fell off.
-Yeah.
1801, discovering that dwarf planet
with your Italian man.
Lovely Giuseppe Piazza.
-Hmm.
-(SIGHS)
-Should we do one more?
-Yeah.
Make it a round 20?
I'm thinking Quantifier.
Little settlement on the edge of
the known universe
where it's permanently New Year's Eve,
every day.
They've got the best blooms.
-(BEEPING)
-(SIGHS)
-YASMIN: Is that important?
-No, not really. It's just Earth.
Leave a little alarm on,
as it's your home. Just in case.
-Oh, that's bad.
-What?
Oh, that's worse, that's...
-Worse than worse.
-Wait, what are you getting?
Something or some things,
non-terrestrial,
are attempting a spacial shift.
I'm homing in
on the convergence pattern.
-Anywhere exciting?
-Sheffield.
What was that?
-Did you see anything?
-No.
Could be a rat.
I think there's something missing.
Must've taken one of the bags.
That's one cheeky rat.
I'll take a look.
(WATER SPLASHING)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WATER SLOSHING)
Oh, my God.
Oh, what's your name?
Mitch.
You just appeared out of thin air.
(STAMMERS) How did you do that?
I'm the Doctor. These are
my best friends, Ryan, Yaz and Graham.
-Hello.
-All right?
Right, okay.
Spend a lot of time in sewers,
do you, Mitch?
We're excavating an ancient burial site.
-When you say "we"...
-Uh, Lin's through here.
Lin! Where are you?
Ah, there you are.
Uh, these guys just sort of arrived.
-LIN: Hi.
-Seen anything unusual then?
(STAMMERS) Yeah, there's something
on the wall back there.
What sort of something?
It's moved.
What did it look like?
Like a massive sort of squid thing.
-RYAN: Ew, really?
-Doc, are you sure that's safe?
Can you get me something to store
this in, for analysis, please, Mitch?
Yeah.
So, Doc, if it was there
and it's not there now,
I assume it's roaming around here,
in the water.
-Should we be worried?
-Probably.
It looks like it slid down this wall
and into the water.
Where are we exactly?
Underneath Sheffield Town Hall.
And where do these sewers lead?
LIN: All the way under the city.
It can be anywhere.
I want you out of these tunnels
right now.
I'm putting this site under quarantine.
Yaz will escort you.
And if you see any sort of creature,
don't go near it.
Not until we've worked out what it is.
Assume proximity is a risk.
Come on, let's get you out of here.
What about the site?
Look, there are valuable
historical artefacts down here.
We've been working on this for months.
We'll make sure it's all kept safe.
I've got your details now,
so we'll let you know
when it's okay to come back down.
DOCTOR: Come on, Yaz.
MITCH: That was weird, right?
Yeah.
I'll call the department tomorrow,
let them know what's happened.
Okay.
I guess we could go for that drink now.
Not right now.
No. Right. Of course.
-I didn't mean to...
-I'm a bit freaked out.
I'll call you if I hear anything
from them.
-Maybe we'll be back in tomorrow.
-Yeah.
(SIGHS)
(MOBILE CHIMES)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
DOCTOR: I've got the TARDIS
scanning the sewers
for non-terrestrial life signals.
So, where are we actually going?
-Your house, of course.
-What?
-(GRUNTS)
-Whoa!
Oh.
-Whoops.
-GRAHAM: You've landed on my chair.
-Sorry.
-You broke my chair.
Well, if you will leave chairs
around the place...
-This is my front room.
-DOCTOR: Where's your kitchen?
I just need to get some eggs
to check the protein alignments
-in the goo.
-(SIGHS)
-(DOORBELL RINGS)
-Oh!
Is that your intruder alert or mine?
-It's the doorbell.
-Oh, yeah. Sorry.
No.
-Who was it?
-Wrong number.
-(DOORBELL RINGS)
-Intruder alert again?
-GRAHAM: It's a doorbell.
-I'll go tell him to go away.
Oh, Ryan, uh...
-Is everything all right?
-Not really, Yaz, no.
YASMIN: Ryan, are you okay?
This is Yaz, and the Doctor.
Hi.
This is my dad.
BOTH: Oh.
Graham.
Hi, Ryan's dad.
-Aaron.
-You weren't at Grace's funeral.
-No.
-Ryan waited for you.
You let him down.
Uh, I was thinking maybe
if we could grab a coffee...
Um, yeah, right, sure.
Is it all right if we, um...
We're just gonna...
Is that okay if, um...
If you're needing somewhere to go,
café around the corner is open.
Yeah. Yeah, good shout, good shout.
I'll just get my coat.
Aaron, uh, can I have a word?
(SIGHS) Ryan's dad.
-It's complicated.
-Yeah.
Dads are.
So I've heard.
(SIGHS) So,
why are you here?
New Year's Day. Turning over a new leaf.
Right. Well, um, be gentle.
He's been through a lot.
-I know.
-No, you have no idea.
I just wanted me and him
to be a family again.
Family isn't just about DNA, Aaron,
or a name.
It's about what you do.
And you haven't done enough.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Are we off then?
-See you later, Gramps.
-(CHUCKLES)
"Gramps"?
-See you later, son.
-(DOOR OPENS)
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
WOMAN: Lin, is that you?
(CHOKES) Yep.
WOMAN: I'm making breakfast.
You want some?
I'm just gonna have a shower.
WOMAN: Did you see Mitch? How did it go?
(PANTING)
CREATURE: No!
(PANTING) Who are...
What are you?
CREATURE: I am your pilot now.
Do not fight me.
I have control over your body.
All brain and motor functions
are under my power.
Please, no...
-Silence.
-(GASPS)
See how I control you.
Turn.
Look.
(GROANING)
BOTH: You are my prisoner now.
(PANTING)
You are my puppet.
(LAUGHS)
DOCTOR: Bio-profiling nearly complete.
-(CONSOLE SOUNDS)
-Yes, a match.
Let's see what we've got.
No.
It can't be.
Doctor, I don't like it
when you go quiet.
This is the DNA of the most
dangerous creature in the universe.
Does it have a name?
The Dalek.
DALEK: Cover me.
Sit.
Now, open the machine.
I must know everything
of this planet's capability.
Its systems, its weapons and its armies.
Everything that must be destroyed.
No, I won't do this.
You have no choice.
Do not struggle or your friends will die
at your hands.
(GASPING) What do you want?
To fulfil my purpose at last.
The Dalek is a mutated remnant
of a warring race.
Genetically created
and housed within a metal case,
designed to be
a relentless killing machine.
Lin said she saw a creature
that looked more like a squid.
It sounds as though
the internal creature
has become separated from its casing.
Well, then, it's vulnerable.
Oh, come on, Doc. Look, one squid
versus seven billion humans and you.
Odds have got to be
in our favour, surely.
I always think I'm rid of them.
Never am.
Trust me, Graham,
even if it's just one, it's enough.
It's gonna kill anyone
that gets in its path,
and it's not gonna stop
until it's taken control of this planet.
There's an alien on the loose
in an archaeological dig.
-Is that where it started?
-I don't know.
-LIN: Hi, this...
-(SIGHS) Voicemail.
Lin, hi, it's Yasmin Khan.
We met in the sewers earlier.
Can you give me a call?
Out of its shell. It can't have got far.
But how's it getting about?
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
DALEK: Faster.
Increase speed.
Nothing shall halt the mission.
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
I sense your thoughts.
That sound is no rescue.
It ls combat.
Can you wind your window down
for me, please, love?
Do you know what speed
you were doing, love?
103 miles per hour.
What have you got to say about that?
You are an enemy of the Daleks.
I'm what, sorry?
(POLICEMAN SIGHS)
And how are you spelling that? (SIGHS)
(GASPS)
Flipping hell.
(SCREAMS)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
You are a useful soldier.
AARON: But this one's a combination.
Microwave and full oven.
Both functions are the best quality
you can get.
I swear, this is the best you can have.
Uh, sorry, not for me, mate.
-(EXHALES)
-This is a new thing you're doing?
Only so long a man can work offshore.
Given up being on the rigs?
Let's just say, I've been examining
my life choices lately.
Not sure if this is the answer.
Get them online, can't you?
Yep. Yes.
Yes, except for this one.
It's actually really good.
A mate of mine makes it.
I helped him with some of the specs.
It's the best working oven you can get.
(LAUGHS) But I make it sound like a con.
So, maybe I'm not cut out for that.
Maybe it's back to engineering.
We'll see.
So, how you been doing?
Seriously?
-That's where you start?
-What?
That's all you got?
How do you think I'm doing?
-I know it's been hard for both of us...
-Okay, stop.
I don't care how it's been for you.
This ain't about us
commiserating with each other.
This is about you making things right.
This is how you talk to your dad?
I don't know,
"cause he ain't been around.
So, don't come walking back in,
demanding respect,
"cause that ain't where we are.
What do you need me to say?
Hmm?
'Cause I wanna say it.
Okay.
You say,
"Ryan, I'm sorry,
"I've messed up.
"I haven't been good enough.
"I've let you down a lot.
"And I know this made life hard for you.
"And if it meant
"that over the years,
you've ever felt lonely or abandoned,
"or didn't know where to turn,
or who to talk to,
"or how to be,
"then, I'm sorry.
"'Cause...
"'Cause you mustn't ever think
that you didn't deserve my love."”
-You didn't ever think that.
-(SCOFFS)
Yeah.
Why wouldn't you?
Okay. Listen.
Here's what you find out
when you get older.
There are things you've done
in your life
to others,
the decisions you've made,
maybe when
things were difficult.
You get it wrong.
But by the time you realise
you got it wrong,
it's too late.
You can't fix it
because the damage is done.
And so you run,
'cause you're too ashamed
to make it right.
That's what I did.
No.
You hid when I needed you.
First Mum, then Nan.
I'm not hiding any more.
We reckon ninth or tenth century.
Part of our funding came from a group
who think it could be Alfred the Great.
YASMIN: Mitch? Are you there?
-There you are.
-But I'm on the phone to you.
-We followed your signal.
-DOCTOR: Have you got him? Come on.
How does it do that?
Oh, it's even better than that.
Deep breath, Mitch.
Welcome to the TARDIS.
(RUMBLES)
DOCTOR: Now we've got the DNA,
maybe I can rig up the TARDIS
to scan for any other traces
in this tiny corner of space and time.
MITCH: No way.
The internal dimensions are bigger than
the box's external dimensions.
-No biggie.
-No, that is quite a biggie.
Got time over.
Was there anything alien-looking
that you uncovered?
What? No. They're historical artefacts,
they've been there for centuries.
Wait. You're not from
the Order of the Custodians?
What's the Order of the Custodians?
So, these guys reckon
there was a battle.
This mythic creature was killed
and it was split and buried
all over the world.
The spacial shift we detected,
parts of the creature
coming back together.
Oh, don't tell me.
When you uncover something,
you leave it under
the ultraviolet lights
-you had in the sewers.
-Yeah.
Ultraviolet light activates
the dormant creature,
bringing it back to life.
Did you say ninth century?
Yeah.
There's been a Dalek buried on Earth
since the ninth century,
waiting to revive.
I'm sorry, a what?
Alien psychopath.
-Are you kidding?
-No.
But where is it?
How is it getting about? Come on, think.
Have you told Lin?
I tried. Phone's going to voicemail
and she's not replying to texts.
What? No,
she keeps her phone on all the time.
It's a running joke between us.
She's the instant replier.
In the sewers,
were you together all the time?
No, she went off to look for...
one of the missing artefacts.
That's when she found the squid.
Tell me she's safe.
I can't.
MITCH: Where are you going?
What are you doing?
GRAHAM: Just follow and do
what she says, Mitch.
DOCTOR: Lin's number is in Yaz's phone.
If I can connect it to the TARDIS,
-we can locate her.
-(CONSOLE BEEPS)
Getting something.
No, lost it.
-(CONSOLE WHIRS AND BEEPS)
-Yeah!
Bio-fix on the location
of the Dalek DNA.
Right.
(PANTING) Cross-reference
with the signal triangulation
of Lin's phone.
(BEEPING)
It's the same place.
Lin and that creature, they're together.
You mean he's holding her hostage?
I'm really sorry, Mitch.
I think it's crueller than that.
I think it's using her to move about.
MITCH: How can you be so sure?
I learned to think like a Dalek
a long time ago.
Hello? The door's...
I need to use the... You know.
Dad, you know you can say "toilet,"
you know.
MITCH: Can you get to Lin?
You have to help her.
-How'd it go with your dad?
-Don't ask.
I don't want him here.
Take this, will you?
You can't just leave him outside,
can you?
(BEEPS LOUDLY)
-(SCREAMS)
-YASMIN: What just happened?
DOCTOR: It can't do that.
How did it do that?
It's blown the systems.
Shorted the navigation.
Fold-back blast
from the creature itself.
It can't do that.
Unless,
-it's a reconnaissance scout.
-In English.
Recon scouts have capabilities
beyond the normal Dalek soldier.
Specially advanced from the basic Dalek.
The first to leave Skaro.
Possibly the first to reach Earth.
So, it's even worse
than the really bad thing
you was worried about
in the first place.
-Graham, emergency peanut-butter run.
-What?
I need to grease
the geo-feudal locks, quick.
-Chop-chop, Grandad.
-Oh, I'm just a gofer.
I'm not having this.
Whoa! You gave me a fright.
-I wasn't expecting... It's just...
-Who has access to the archives?
Today, it's just me. Hello.
Most secure digits in Yorkshire.
That's what I tell me
boyfriend, anyway.
I probably shouldn't be
telling you that.
I'm new at this.
Why?
-(PANEL BEEPING)
-(DOOR OPENS)
DALEK:
I will destroy the energy signal...
DOCTOR: Stop. I know you can hear me
right now.
Who are you?
I'm your secret conscience.
Not really.
We both know you don't have one.
How are you communicating?
You might have temporarily disabled
my navigation,
but I still know a trick or two.
Like I know you're a refugee
from the planet Skaro.
What sort of Dalek are you, anyway?
My mission is
reconnaissance and conquest.
Just as I thought. Recon scout.
All humanity is my prisoner now.
In your dreams, mate.
You've got no casing, no weapons
and no chance.
I have weapons.
Right.
Okay, well, whoop-de-doo.
You've got a weapon after all.
Lot of good it's gonna do you.
DALEX: This planet is now
the property of the Daleks.
I know seven billion people who may have
something to say about that.
Now, you might have a weapon,
but you're a long way from conquest.
Release the woman
you're holding prisoner.
(DALEK LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
-What's it doing?
-I think it's laughing.
(WHIRRING)
Now, do that again to my face.
What is this?
These are my serious tech skillz.
And yes, that is with a "Z."
Bio-tracking fuse to hold projection.
Won't last long, but I need you to see
just how serious my face is right now.
But it's not just you I want to talk to.
-(LIN GROANS)
-Lin, I know you can hear me.
I need you to know we're coming for you.
So keep fighting.
-Mitch is here with us.
-I'm not leaving you.
-(GASPING)
-I know you're scared. Keep fighting.
(GROANS)
This feeble vessel will not fight.
The Daleks are supreme.
(TARDIS BEEPS)
Yeah? If you're so supreme,
how come you let me keep you chatting
while I rebooted my systems?
Here's my New Year's resolution,
I'm coming for you, Dalek.
Lin, hold on.
Blocking signal... (GROANS)
Not getting away from me now.
(TYRES SCREECH)
Where'd they go?
AARON: Did they take the cabinet?
They've gone without me.
(MITCH PANTING)
MDZ Research. What was it doing there?
Uh, they're a weapons research company.
The Order of the Custodians
claim that MDZ were buying up
any non-terrestrial weaponry
on the black market.
What do you think it got there?
-DOCTOR: I don't know.
-(CONSOLE WHIRRING)
Oh, it's blocking the bio-fix now.
-(CONSOLE BEEPING)
-I'm going old-school.
Tracking CCTV cameras, GPS
and number plate tracking.
It's shooting out the cameras
to stop us tracking it.
(GRUNTS) It's taken out
the whole junction box.
Right. Switching to
satellite monitoring.
See, it can't get away that easy.
Where's it going? What's it doing?
If I knew that,
I wouldn't be this panicked.
- (CRACKLES)
-We're gonna need some help.
UK security helpline, this is Polly.
How can I help?
-I'm sorry, what?
-UK security helpline.
How can I help?
Get me Kate Stewart at UNIT.
This is a code zero emergency.
I don't know what that is, I'm afraid.
Which organisation did you say?
UNIT. Unified Intelligence Taskforce.
This is incredibly urgent.
The fate of the entire planet
is at stake.
-I'm checking for you.
-(SIGHS)
Oh, I'm so sorry. UNIT operations
have been suspended, pending review.
What? No, it can't have been.
UNIT is a fundamentally vital protection
for planet Earth against alien invasion.
Yes, but when did that last happen?
Now! Right now!
What happened to it?
I'm just checking.
All UNIT operations were put on hold
following financial disputes,
and subsequent funding withdrawal by
the UK's major international partners.
You're kidding.
Other armed forces are available
if you can answer a couple of questions
-to help me best direct your call.
-(MOBILE BEEPS)
We're on our own.
(ALL SIGH)
Since you're here...
-What's this?
-Have a look.
When my mum died,
my dad got rid of all her things
super quick.
He couldn't bear to have it
in the house.
"She's gone now, and that's
the end of it." That's what he said.
Yeah. Funny old bloke, my dad.
Of course, now I realise
that was his way of dealing with it.
When your mum died,
I had to go through all her stuff.
But this is all mine.
Yeah, I know. She kept it all.
She once said to me, um,
"If anyone
"ever asks about me after I'm gone,
"you tell them I was lucky.
"Tell them I gave someone life
and I watched him grow
"and I was proud.”
Why didn't you come, Aaron?
Not for you mum, or for Ryan,
but for yourself?
I don't know.
Maybe I thought if... (INHALES SHARPLY)
I wasn't there, she wasn't gone.
I wish I was better at life, Graham.
Well, there's still time.
Can I help you?
What do you want? 'Cause I'm busy.
The work will commence.
What work?
I shall be reborn.
Humanity will be destroyed.
All right, enough. Go on, off my farm.
I don't care what you've been told,
all that stuff's been paid for,
and I can prove it.
You will be exterminated.
(SCREAMING)
(LIN PANTS)
DALEK: No, do not stop.
Return to the work.
You will obey.
The work must be completed.
You are weakening.
No.
(INHALES SHARPLY) You are.
(GRUNTS)
You will stop this.
You cannot escape me.
I will fight.
-(GROANS)
-Stop!
DOCTOR: Satellite signal's
tracked the car to here.
So, Lin's here, eh?
-Doctor.
-(PANTING)
(BUZZING)
That's all the signs of a Dalek weapon.
That's what was at MDZ.
It went and found it
after all this time.
(THUD IN DISTANCE)
-You don't have to come.
-RYAN: Of course, we do.
We're always with you.
LIN: Help.
Listen. Can you hear that?
-LIN: Help me.
-That's Lin.
-(LIN GROANING)
-DOCTOR: I need to take a look at you.
It's okay. I'm here. We're all here.
Everything's all right, Lin.
Is she gonna be okay?
Whatever that thing secretes acted like
a plug on her neck once it left.
Otherwise she'd be dead.
(GROANING) I'm sorry.
DOCTOR: You have
nothing to be sorry about.
-You fought and you won.
-No, listen.
It's still here.
You three help her stand,
get her back to the TARDIS.
There are supplies there
that'll help with the healing.
What about you?
I'm gonna find that creature.
-You can't do that on your own.
-Always have done.
Me and the Dalek, it's personal.
Go on, get her safe.
-Come on.
-(LIN PANTING)
(GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
(PANTING)
Exterminate.
DOCTOR: I'm blocking
your laser signals, mate.
You're not fully in sync yet.
So that's what you've been doing.
Reconstructing yourself from memory.
And remnants.
And spare parts.
I am rebuilt.
What do you call this look?
Junkyard chic?
Earth is now under the control
of the Daleks.
No, it's not.
You couldn't even control one person.
Humanity will surrender.
They really won't, trust me.
I've seen them in action.
They've fought off so many things,
including the worst of their own people.
They're really stubborn.
Have you not worked that out yet?
Even the recon scout Daleks,
the first ones out of Skaro.
Humanity bands together, vanquishes you,
and buries you for centuries.
Yet I survived.
Yeah.
You're good at that.
It won't be enough.
This planet is annexed.
The fleet will be summoned.
You don't have the ability.
You don't have the strength.
You are weak.
Humanity is weak.
Except I'm not human.
Have a scan.
Who are you? Identify.
Oh, mate, I'm the Doctor.
Ring any bells?
-Sonic device override!
-I'll take that as a yes.
The Doctor is an enemy
of all Daleks. Exterminate.
(PANTING) Yes, I am.
You want this planet,
you have to come through me.
So why don't you make it easy
on yourself and leave now.
Conquest has already started.
-I have all the information I need.
-What information?
Humanity will surrender.
Dalek invasion fleet will be summoned.
Total conquest of Earth
predicted in 9376 rels.
(SIGHS)
Now, I must remember. How long's a rel?
-How'd it go? What happened?
-Did you get rid of it?
-Not quite.
-How much "not quite"?
Not at all. Slightly riled it,
-and let it get away.
-RYAN: What?
And now it's in a tank,
-trying to summon the fleet.
-Doctor!
All right, don't go on about it. I know.
They're really persistent.
Oh.
-How you feeling, Lin?
-Uh, shaky.
I'm not surprised. You will for a while.
But you kept fighting it. Thank you.
(CONSOLE WHIRS)
Take these.
Three a minute for four minutes.
Don't take with alcohol,
you'll grow an extra head.
That was an embarrassing party.
It was ready to kill me.
I... I could feel its hatred
enveloping me. I...
Is that what it's gonna do to the world?
No. Because I'm gonna stop it.
We're gonna stop it.
Somehow. Before humans
start engaging with it.
It's flying
right through their airspace.
Where's it going?
(MOBILE RINGING)
-What?
-Where are you?
-In the TARDIS.
-You better be coming to pick me up.
-Okay, fine.
-Right. Thank you.
Um, Aaron, mate, little thing
we haven't told you.
A tiny thing, so word of warning.
You know that blue cabinet?
That is just about to blow your mind.
-What do you mean?
-(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
GRAHAM: It travels,
in space and time.
Come on, quick.
The Doc said you can come, too,
but Graham will have to explain.
SOLDIER: Go! Go!
Get back!
Intercepted unknown drone.
We have it surrounded.
Surrender!
Did it just talk?
Allocated surrender period has expired.
Consequence, extermination.
Open fire!
Cease fire!
(WHIRRING)
Run.
-What?
-Run! That's an order!
Go, go, go!
The Dalek race is supreme.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Left.
SOLDIER: Out! Out!
DOCTOR: Oh, new heat signal.
And a non-terrestrial form
moving away from it fast.
I'm on its tail. Sorry, the TARDIS
isn't designed for these short hops.
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
Ah, a microwave.
Who brought a microwave with them?
It's actually an oven and a microwave.
Nice.
What is this place?
This is where I've been since Nan died.
Travelling the universe with these guys.
Even if we track this Dalek thing,
how do we stop it?
-I'm still working on that.
-The Custodians managed it.
If we take the same approach
as those drawings...
Those documents aren't reliable, Mitch.
Yeah, except all the rumours
have proved to be true.
It's shown here.
Short version,
alien psychopath in its own tank
trying to bring loads more to Earth.
I guess this is how they attacked it
last time.
-What's it made of?
-Remnants of its original shell.
Patched up with
all sorts of spare parts, mainly metal.
-You can use my oven.
-It's not gonna fit in there.
That's not what I meant.
Help me break it up.
(CONSOLE BEEPING)
DOCTOR: That Dalek's moving fast,
but where's it going?
AARON: Ryan,
help me get the element out.
RYAN: Why?
AARON: It's metal.
Oh, you're good, Ryan's dad.
You're almost making up
for your parenting deficit.
(CONSOLE BEEPING)
I know where it's heading.
The biggest communications resource
in the country.
-(EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE)
-(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
I don't mean you any harm.
Exterminate.
Communication headquarters acquired.
Aligning all signals to Dalek fleet.
All power will be diverted
towards fleet signal transmission.
Earth is annexed.
It's diverting every bit of power
it can take from the whole of the UK
to power the transmission.
It's shutting down the Wi-Fi.
-The phone signals.
-(TARDIS BEEPING)
Whoa! That Dalek just shut down
the whole of Britain's Internet.
What, on New Year's Day?
When everything's shut
and everyone's hung over?
What a monster.
(KEYS CLACKING)
The Wi-Fi's gone off.
Everything's gone off. No Wi-Fi,
no phone signal. It's all down.
Not even Netflix?
(REMOTE KEYS CLICKING)
-Nothing.
-What do we do?
I suppose
we'll have to have a conversation?
BOTH: What?
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-Don't shoot.
-Exterminate!
Do you think I'm daft enough
to stand here without shields?
It's safe, gang.
DALEK: Hide behind your shields, Doctor.
You and your human friends,
you have failed.
Say hello to a Dalek.
Signal activation in nine rels.
-The fleet shall be summoned.
-No, it won't.
No matter how many times you try,
no matter how long you wait,
I will always be in your way.
Backed up by the best of humanity.
Now, final, final, final warning.
'Cause I'm nice.
I really do try my best.
Stop the signal, get off this planet.
You are not my commander.
I tried. You heard me, right?
I tried, I gave it a chance.
-Yep, yep.
-You did, you did.
I'm fast enough, right?
I'm fast enough for this plan?
-Uh, probably.
-Maybe.
-Possibly.
-Well, that one needs work.
Here's a New Year message
for you to send.
Earth is protected by me and my mates.
This year and every other.
Here we go!
DALEK: Exterminate the Doctor.
The Doctor must be exterminated.
DOCTOR: Now, gang!
-GRAHAM: Come on, Doc.
-None of you will survive.
DOCTOR: Aim for one of the servers.
...weaponry malfunctioning.
DOCTOR: No, attach the parts.
-Weapon failure!
The parts are on, Doctor. Get clear!
Working on my casing.
The Custodians burned your shell.
And we've got something
they didn't have.
A nicely-designed, portable
combination oven. Transformers,
primary and secondary coils,
going from high voltage, low am page,
to low voltage, very, very high am page.
(WHIRRING LOUDLY)
-Get down!
-(DALEK SCREAMING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
RYAN: Is it dead?
-(PANTING)
-(BUZZING)
Signal never sent.
I think that was my best skid ever.
I'm so chuffed.
Well done, team.
Gang. Extended fam.
(DALEK LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
RYAN: Dad...
You underestimate me,
Doctor.
Dalek survives.
Doctor, do something.
I'm sorry, Aaron,
I miscalculated.
You'll take me to the Dalek fleet.
-Resist...
-(GROANS)
-...and this body will be destroyed.
-RYAN: Doctor, do something.
Fine.
Doctor, seriously.
My decision.
Whatever you want.
Just promise me you'll let him go.
You are my prisoners now.
The glory of the TARDIS shall be ours.
-Help him.
-Trust me.
We've landed.
Finally, my mission is complete.
The Earth and the Doctor shall submit
before the Dalek fleet.
(SCREAMS)
RYAN: Doctor! What are you doing?
DOCTOR: Sorry, did I not mention?
No fleet. Only a sun going supernova.
And a squid-sized vacuum corridor
-about to pull you out into space.
-Dad!
You're too weak, Dalek.
You can't hold on.
Except it is holding on, Doctor.
All right.
Argh! The vacuum corridor's expanding,
I can't control it.
-GRAHAM: What do you mean?
-It's gonna take Aaron with it.
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMS)
Everybody, hold on!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Dad! Doctor, help him.
(GRUNTING)
No, Dad! Hold on!
Ryan!
(PANTING) Dad.
Dad, I know you can hear me.
(GROWLS)
He is mine now!
No, he's not! He's mine.
(GASPING)
Dad. Dad, I'm here for you.
I forgive you.
I love you, Dad.
Take my hand.
Fight it!
Take my hand!
(RYAN GRUNTS)
Leave my dad alone!
(DALEK SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(PANTING)
(GROANS) I've got you.
Not bad for a kid with dyspraxia, right?
Not bad at all.
DOCTOR: Think that's everything
back in place.
Next time, you go looking for
anything that goes missing.
You're really going in that?
This is what you do?
Yeah. You fancy a trip?
(LAUGHS) No.
Call me when you get back.
-You are coming back?
-Yeah, of course.
-Look after him.
-Always.
DOCTOR: Come on then, you lot.
Places to go.
YASMIN: When you say "places to go,"
what are you thinking?
Where to next?
I was thinking...
Everywhere.
NARRATOR:
On the first day of the year 20189,
across the land and sky of Britain,
an army of unlikely friends
came together
to face an impossible opponent,
and prevailed.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)