POSTMAN: Morning, love.
WOMAN: Morning.
WOMAN: Hiya!
MAN: All right.
Maeve? You okay?
No, love, I'm not.
-You want me to call a doctor?
-Doctor can't help.
Can't you... Can't you feel it, Trish?
Can't feel anything.
Boys! Get indoors! Get inside!
Get 'em inside!
What's up with you?
They ain't done nothing wrong.
MAEVE: It's happening again!
GIRL: # ...sits in the old gum tree
# Merry merry king of the bush is he
# Laugh, kookaburra, laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be #
-They're not safe.
-They're in the garden.
That's what it likes.
It likes it when they're playing.
Get 'em in, I'm begging you!
# Merry merry king of the bush is he
# Laugh, kookaburra, laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be #
Right, I've got my beady eyes on them.
Come on, come on.
MAEVE: No!
MAN: Tom?
-MAEVE: What are you?
-Where's he gone?
MAEVE: What do you want
with our children?
(HUMMING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(WHOOSHING)
Ah.
Ah!
(DRILLING)
So, near future, yeah?
I had a passing fancy.
Only, it didn't pass, it stopped.
-30th Olympiad.
-No way! Why didn't I think of this?
That's great. Aw!
DOCTOR: Only seems like yesterday
a few naked Greek blokes
were tossing a discus about,
wrestling with each other in the sand,
as the crowds stood around baying...
No, wait a minute, that was Club Med.
Just in time
for the opening doodah ceremony tonight.
I thought you'd like that.
Last one they had in London was dynamite.
Wembley, 1948.
I loved it so much I went back
and watched it all over again.
Fella carrying a torch. Lovely chap.
What was his... Mark? John, Mark?
Legs like pipe-cleaners,
-but strong as a whippet...
-Doctor...
And in those days,
everyone had a tea party to go to...
-Doctor!
-You ever have those little cakes
-with the crunchy ball bearings on top?
-You should really look at this!
You know those things?
Nobody else in this entire galaxy
has ever even bothered
to make edible ball bearings. Genius!
DOCTOR: Who's taken them, do you think?
Snatching children
from a thoroughly ordinary street like this.
And why is it so cold?
Someone reducing the temperature?
ROSE: Says here he went missing
this week.
Why would a person
do something like this?
What makes you think it's a person?
(DOOR OPENING)
ROSE: Whatever it is,
it's got the whole street scared to death.
Doctor, what...
(CAR ENGINE FALTERING)
There you go. Fifth today.
That's not natural, is it?
Dunno what happened.
I had it serviced less than a month ago.
Nah, don't even try and explain it, mate.
All the cars are doing it,
and you know what?
It's bonkers. Bonkers.
Come on then, pal, I'll help you shift it.
Quicker you're on your way,
happier you'll be.
(GRUNTING) There we go.
-Do you want a hand?
-No, we're all right, love.
Well, you're not.
I'm tougher than I look. Honest.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
-Does this happen a lot?
-DRIVER: Cheers, mate!
(SIGHING) Been doing it all week.
Since those children started going missing?
Yeah. Suppose so.
Hmm. Tickles.
What's your game?
My... Um...
Snakes and ladders.
Quite good at squash, reasonable...
I'm being facetious, aren't I?
There's no call for it.
Every car cuts out.
Council are going nuts.
I mean, they've given this street the works.
Renamed it.
I've been tarmacking every pothole.
Look at that. Beauty, innit?
Yep.
And all this is because that Olympic torch
comes right by the end of this close.
Just down there.
Everything's gotta be perfect, ain't it?
-KEL: Only it ain't.
-It takes 'em when they're playing.
-What takes them?
-Danny, Jane, Dale,
-snatched in the blink of an eye.
-MAN: Liar! You're a liar!
DOCTOR: I am a... I'm a... Police officer!
That's what I am.
I've got a badge and a police car.
You don't have to get... I can prove it.
Just hold on...
We've had plenty of coppers
poking round here,
and you don't look or sound like any of 'em.
See? Look, I got a colleague! Lewis.
Well, she looks less
like a copper than you do.
Training. New recruit.
It was either that or hairdressing.
So... Voila!
-What are you going to do?
-The police have knocked on every door.
No clues, no leads, nothing!
Look, look, kids run off sometimes,
all right?
-That's what they do.
-I saw it with me own eyes.
Dale Hicks in your garden
playing with your Tommy, and then...
Right in front of me,
like he was never there.
There's no need
to look any further than this street.
It's right here amongst us!
-Why don't we...
-Why don't we start with him!
There's been all sorts like him
in this street, day and night...
Fixing things up for the Olympics!
Yeah, and taking
an awful long time about it!
I'm of the opinion
that all we've gotta do is...
That woman who just said... That's slander!
I don't care what it is!
I think we need to just...
-I want an apology off her!
-Stop picking on him!
-Yeah! Stop picking on me!
-MAEVE: And stop pretending to be blind!
-It's evil!
-I don't believe in evil.
Oh, no! You just believe in tarmackers
with sack-loads of kidnapped kiddies
in their van.
-Hey, hey, that's not what she's saying!
-Would you stop ganging up on me?
Feeling guilty, are we?
Fingers on lips!
In the last six days,
three of your children have been stolen,
snatched out of thin air, right?
Uh... Can I...
Look around you.
This was a safe street till it came.
It's not a person.
I'll say it if no one else will.
Maybe you're coppers, maybe you're not.
I don't care who you are.
Can you please help us?
(DOCTOR SNIFFING)
-Want a hanky?
-You smell it?
What's it remind you of?
Sort of metal?
-Mmm-hmm.
-Oh!
Danny Edwards cycled in one end
but never came out the other.
Whoa! There it goes again.
Look at the hairs on the back
of my manly hairy hand.
And there's that smell.
It's like a burnt fuse plug or something.
There's a residual energy in the spots
where the kids vanished.
Whatever it was,
it used an awful lot of power to do this.
(MEWING)
-You have to come down sometime, Chloe.
-I'm busy, Mum.
Look at it in here.
Must've used up half a rain forest.
That's Dale.
-Why did you draw him so sad?
-I didn't draw him like that.
Dale made himself sad,
so I'm gonna draw him a friend.
That's what he needs, more friends.
Have you seen the TV?
Look, this'll cheer you up.
The torch is getting close.
It'll pass right by our street.
And tonight they'll light the Olympic flame
in the stadium,
and the whole world
will be looking at our city.
MAN ON TV: ...they're lining the street...
I mean, doesn't that make you feel
part of something?
Sweetheart?
We've seen the Prime Minister,
we've seen members of the Royal family...
-Chloe?
-I'm busy, Mum.
-Okay.
-...as young Danny Fairweather
carries the torch past them
on this wonderful summer's day.
Very fitting. We've seen lots
of our sporting royalty, too...
You're tired, Chloe.
I heard you calling out again last night.
-It's fine.
-Nightmares?
I'm drawing.
MAN ON TV: Let me remind you
where the torches come from...
Whatever they are...
...journey from the temple of...
...they're just dreams. You do know that?
-They can't hurt you.
-I'm busy.
Unless you want me to draw you,
Mum.
If you wanna stay cooped up in here, fine.
I'll leave you to it.
-Oh, aren't you a beautiful boy!
-Thanks!
I'm experimenting with backcombing. Oh.
I used to have one like you.
(CAT MEWING)
What?
No, I'm not really a cat person.
Once you've been threatened by one
in a nun's wimple,
kind of takes the joy out of it.
(CAT MEWS)
Come here, puss.
What do you wanna go in there for?
Doctor.
Whoa!
(EXCLAIMING)
Ion residue. Blimey!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMS)
That takes some doing.
Just to snatch
a living organism out of space-time.
This baby is just like,
"I'm having some of that!" I'm impressed.
So the cat's been transported?
It can harness huge reserves
of ionic power.
We need to find the source of that power.
Find the source and you will find
whatever has taken to stealing children
and fluffy animals.
See what you can see.
Keep 'em peeled, Lewis.
I've given you friends, and you still moan.
Moan, moan, moan. You're lucky.
You're all together.
You don't know what it is to be alone.
If you did, you'd be thanking me.
(PENCIL SNAPS)
No!
(DOG BARKING)
(THUDDING)
(METALLIC CLINKING)
That you, puss cat? You trapped?
(CRASHING)
Not gonna open it, not gonna open it.
Not gonna open it...
(BUZZING)
Stay still!
Okey do key?
-Yeah. Cheers.
-No probs.
(EXCLAIMS IN RELIEF)
I'll give you a fiver if you can tell me
what the hell it is.
'Cause I haven't got the foggiest.
-Well, I can tell you you just killed it.
-It was never living.
It's animated by energy.
The same energy that's snatching people.
That is so dinky!
The go-anywhere creature.
Fits in your pocket.
Makes friends, impresses the boss,
breaks the ice at parties.
(LAUGHING)
DOCTOR: Oh. Hi-oh. Here we go.
Let's have a look.
-Get out of here!
-What's it say?
It is.
It's graphite.
Basically, the same material
as an HB pencil.
-I was attacked by a pencil scribble?
-A scribble creature.
Brought into being with ionic energy.
Whatever we're dealing with,
it can create things as well as take them.
But why make a scribble creature?
Maybe it was a mistake.
I mean, you scribble over something
when you wanna get rid of it,
like a drawing. Like a...
child's drawing.
-He said it was in the street.
-Probably.
-The girl.
-Of course! What girl?
Something about her gave me the creeps.
Even her own mum looked scared of her.
-Are you deducting?
-I think I am.
-Copper's hunch?
-Permission to follow it up, Sarge.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hello. I'm the Doctor and this is Rose.
Can we see your daughter?
-No. You can't.
-Okay. Bye.
Why? Why do you want to see Chloe?
Well, there's some interesting stuff
going on in this street,
and I just thought...
Well, we thought that she might like
to give us a hand.
-Sorry to bother you.
-Yeah. Sorry.
We'll let you get on with things.
On your own. Bye again.
Wait.
Can you help her?
Yes, I can.
MAN ON TV: The torchbearer
ls running up towards the Mall...
She stays in her room most of the time.
I try talking to her,
but it's like trying to speak to a brick wall.
She gives me nothing,
just asks to be left alone.
What about Chloe's dad?
-Chloe's dad died a year ago.
-I'm sorry.
You wouldn't be if you'd known him.
Well, let's go and say hi.
I should check on her first,
she might be asleep.
Why are you afraid of her, Trish?
I want you to know, before you see her,
that she's really a great kid.
I'm sure she is.
Yeah.
She's never been in trouble at school.
You should see her report from last year.
A's and B's.
Can I use your loo?
She's in the choir.
She sings in an old folks' home.
Any mum would be proud, you know?
I want you to know these things
before you see her, Doctor,
because right now, she's not herself.
(DOOR RATTLING)
All right there?
I'm the Doctor.
I'm Chloe Webber.
-How you doing, Chloe Webber?
-I'm busy.
I'm making something.
Aren't I, Mum?
And like I said, she's not been sleeping...
But you've been drawing, though.
I'm rubbish. Stickmen about my limit.
I can do this, though.
Can you do that?
-They don't stop moaning.
-TRISH: Chloe...
I try to help them,
but they don't stop moaning.
Who don't?
-We can be together.
-Sweetheart...
Don't touch me, Mum.
(DOOR RATTLING)
SINISTER VOICE: I'm coming...
I'm busy, Doctor.
Come on, Chloe, don't be a spoilsport.
What's the big project?
I'm dying to know.
What you making up there?
ROSE: Doctor!
SINISTER VOICE: I'm coming to hurt you...
-Look at it.
-No, ta.
-What the hell was that?
-ROSE: Drawing. Face of a man...
-What face?
-Best not.
What have you been drawing?
-I drew him yesterday.
-Who?
-Dad.
-TRISH: Your dad?
But he's long gone.
Chloe, with all the lovely things
in the world, why him?
I dream about him staring at me.
I thought we were putting him behind us.
What's the matter with you?
-We need to stay together.
-Yes, we do.
No, not you. Us.
We need to stay together,
and then it'll be all right.
Trish, the drawings,
have you seen
what Chloe's drawings can do?
Who gave you permission
to come into her room?
Get out of my house.
Tell us about the drawings, Chloe.
I don't want to hear any more of this.
But that drawing of her dad...
-I heard a voice, he spoke.
-He's dead.
And these? They're kid's pictures.
Now get out!
Chloe has a power.
And I don't know how,
but she used it to take Danny Edwards,
Dale Hicks.
She's using it to snatch the kids.
-Get out.
-Have you seen those drawings move?
-I haven't seen anything.
-Yes, you have.
-Out of the corner of your eye.
-No.
And you dismissed it,
because what choice do you have?
When you see something
you can't possibly explain,
you dismiss it, right?
And if anyone mentions it, you get angry.
-So it's never spoken of ever again.
-She's a child.
And you're terrified of her.
But there's no one to turn to,
"cause who's gonna believe
the things you see
out of the corner of your eye? No one.
Except me.
Who are you?
I'm help.
(ROSE CLEARS THROAT)
Those pictures, they're alive.
She's drawing people
and they end up in her pictures.
Ionic energy.
Chloe's harnessing it to steal those kids
and place them in some kind of holding pen
made up of ionic power.
And what about the dad from hell
in her wardrobe?
How many times do I have to tell you?
He's dead.
Well, he's got a very loud voice
for a dead bloke.
If living things can become drawings,
then maybe drawings
can become living things.
(EXCLAIMS IN FEAR)
Chloe's real dad is dead,
but not the one who visits her
in her nightmares.
That dad seems very real.
That's the dad she's drawn,
and he's a heartbeat away
from crashing into this world.
She always got the worst of it
when he was alive.
Doctor, how can a 12-year-old girl
be doing any of this?
Let's find out.
(DOOR OPENING)
Nice one.
-There we go.
-I can't let him...
(WHISPERING) Shh, it's okay. Trust him.
Now we can talk.
(IN SINISTER VOICE) I want Chloe!
Wake her up!
-I want Chloe!
-Who are you?
-I want Chloe Webber!
-What have you done to my little girl?
Doctor, what is it?
I'm speaking to you,
the entity that is using this human child.
I request parley in compliance
with The Shadow Proclamation.
I don't care about shadows or parleyses!
So what do you care about?
I want my friends.
You're lonely, I know.
Identify yourself.
I am one of many.
I travel with my brothers and sisters.
We take an endless journey.
A thousand of your lifetimes.
But now I am alone. I hate it.
It's not fair, and I hate it!
Name yourself.
Isolus.
You're Isolus, of course.
Our journey began in the deep realms,
-when we were a family.
-What's that?
The Isolus mother, drifting in deep space.
See? She jettisons millions
of fledgling spores,
her children.
The Isolus are empathic beings
of intense emotion.
When they're cast off
from their mother, their empathic link,
their need for each other,
is what sustains them.
They need to be together.
They cannot be alone.
Our journey is long.
The Isolus children travel,
each inside a pod.
They ride the heat and energy
of solar tides.
And it takes thousands and thousands
of years for them to grow up.
Thousands of years
just floating through space?
Poor things.
Don't they go mad with boredom?
We play.
You...play?
DOCTOR: While they travel,
they play a game.
They use their ionic power
to literally create make-believe worlds
in which to play.
-In-flight entertainment.
-Helps keep them happy.
While they're happy
they can feed off each other's love.
Without it, they're lost.
-Why did you come to Earth?
-We were too close.
That's a solar flare from your sun.
Would have made a tidal wave
of solar energy
that scattered the Isolus pods.
Only I fell to Earth.
My brothers and sisters are left up there,
and I cannot reach them.
-So alone!
-Your pod crashed?
Where is it?
My pod was drawn to heat.
And I was drawn to Chloe Webber.
She was like me. Alone.
She needed me and I her.
DOCTOR: You empathised with her.
You wanted to be with her
because she was alone like you.
I want my family!
It's not fair!
I understand. You wanna make a family.
But you can't stay in this child. It's wrong.
You can't steal any more friends
for yourself.
I am alone.
(THUDDING)
SINISTER VOICE: I'm coming to hurt you.
I'm coming...
-Trish, how do you calm her?
-TRISH: What?
When she has nightmares, what do you do?
-What do you do?
-I sing to her.
Then start singing.
SINISTER VOICE: Chloe, I'm coming...
# Kookaburra sits in the old gum tree
# Merry merry king of the bush is he #
Chloe!
(SINISTER VOICE FADING)
# ...kookaburra, laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be #
It came to her because she was lonely.
(CRYING) Chloe, I'm sorry.
Chloe usually got the brunt of his temper,
when he'd had a drink.
The day he crashed the car,
I thought we were free.
I thought it was over.
-Did you talk to her about it?
-I didn't want to.
But maybe that's why Chloe feels so alone,
'cause she has all these
terrible dreams about her dad,
but she can't talk to you about them.
Her and the Isolus,
two lonely kids who need each other.
And it won't stop, will it, Doctor?
Just keep pulling kids in.
It's desperate to be loved.
-And it's used to a pretty big family.
-How big?
Say around four billion?
MAN ON TV: ...in and out of central London.
It is remarkable.
The queue started a week ago
for those desperate enough to be inside,
and there are lots of them.
We're expecting
a capacity crowd of 80,000
for this evening's opening ceremony.
I have to say there's been...
We need that pod.
It crashed. Won't it be destroyed?
Well, it's been sucking in
all the heat it can.
Hopefully that should keep it
in a fit state to launch.
It must be close.
It should have a weak energy signature
the Tardis can trace.
Once we find it,
then we can stop the Isolus.
She's running a temperature.
I can't go into that now, Kirsty.
Yes, we've got a doctor.
Yeah, he said he can help her.
We can scan for the same trace
that I picked up from the scribble creature.
Just need to widen the field a bit.
(TARDIS DOOR SHUTTING)
You knew the Isolus was lonely
before it told you. How?
I know what it's like to travel a long way
on your own.
Give me the steino-magnetic... Um...
Thing in your left hand.
Sounds like you're on its side.
I sympathise, that's all.
The Isolus has caused a lot of pain
for these people.
It's a child. That's why it went to Chloe.
Two lonely mixed-up kids.
Feels to me like a temper tantrum
'cause it can't get its own way.
It's scared. Come on, you were a kid once.
-Binary dot.
-Yes.
And I know what kids can be like.
Right little...terrors.
-Gum.
-I've got cousins.
Kids can't have it all their own way.
That's part of being a family.
And what about trying to understand them?
-Easy for you to say, you don't have kids.
-I was a dad once.
What did you say?
I think we're there. Fear. Loneliness.
They're the big ones, Rose.
Some of the most terrible acts ever
committed have been inspired by them.
We're not dealing with something
that wants to conquer or destroy.
There's a lot of things you need
to get across this universe,
warp drive, wormhole refractors.
You know the thing you need most of all?
You need a hand to hold.
No, no, I'm pointing.
DOCTOR: It's the pod! It is in the street!
Everything's coming up Doctor.
Okay, it's like, two inches across.
Dull grey, like a gull's egg, very light.
ROSE: So these pods, they travel
from some sun using heat, yeah?
So it's not all about love and stuff.
Doesn't the pod just need heat?
(CRASHING)
Doctor?
Doctor!
It's okay, I've taken all the pencils off her.
Leave me alone!
I want to be with Chloe Webber!
I love Chloe Webber!
-Bring him back now.
-No!
Don't you realise what you've done?
He was the only one who could help you.
Now bring him back!
Leave me alone! I love Chloe Webber!
I know.
Doctor, if you can hear me,
I'm gonna get you out of there.
I'll find the pod.
Don't leave her alone, no matter what.
MAN ON TV: ...the torchbearer getting
even closer to the Olympic Stadium,
heading down the Strand, before
turning east along the Embankment...
Heat. They travel on heat.
Look at this finish.
Smooth as a baby's bottom.
Not a bump or a lump.
Kel, was there anything in this street in
the last few days giving off a lot of heat?
I mean, you could eat your dinner off this.
Beautiful. So, you tell me
why the other one's got a lump in it
when I gave it the same love
and craftsmanship as I did this one.
Well, when you've worked it out,
put it in a big book about tarmacking.
But before you do that, think back six days.
Six days.
When I was laying this the first time round.
What?
Well, that's when I filled in this pothole
for the first time.
-Six days ago.
-Yeah.
Hot, fresh tar.
Blended to a secret council recipe.
No, I don't keep it in the van.
Hey! That's a council van. Out.
Whoa! Wait... Wait a minute!
You've just removed a council axe
from a council van.
Put it back! No, don't, wait.
If it's going in the van, that's my van.
Gimme the axe!
Wait! No! No! You... Stop!
You just took a council axe
from a council van,
and now you're digging up a council road!
I'm reporting you to the council!
It went for the hottest thing
in the street, yeah? Your tar.
-What is it?
-It's a spaceship.
Not a council spaceship, I'm afraid.
MAN ON TV: ...joined us, welcome.
We're live on BBC News 24.
The opening ceremony
of the London Olympics of 2012.
Well underway,
athletes from all over the world,
streaming into the stadium right now.
They all have their dreams.
They've all put in years of hard work...
I found it!
Don't know what to do with it, but maybe
the Isolus will just hop on board.
Hang on, I told you not to leave her.
MAN ON TV: My God!
Uh, what's going on here?
I don't care if you got Snow White
and the Seven Dwarves buried under there,
-you don't go digging...
-Shut up and look!
The crowd has vanished.
Um, they're gone, everyone has gone.
Thousands of people have just gone,
uh, right in front of my eyes.
Um, it's impossible.
Bob, can we join you in the box? Bob?
-Not you too, Bob!
-ROSE: A stadium won't be enough.
The Isolus has
four billion brothers and sisters.
Over 80,000 spectators
and 30,000 athletes...
Not enough.
They're gone, all of those people.
Uh, it's a terrible, terrible turn of events...
We won't be alone, Chloe Webber.
We'll have all of them.
And then we'll never feel alone ever again.
TRISH: Chloe?
ROSE: Chloe, it's Rose! Open the door!
We found your ship!
We can send you home.
-Chloe!
-Open up!
Right, stand back.
SINISTER VOICE: I'm coming to hurt you.
I'm coming. Coming to hurt you, Chloe.
-Chloe!
-I'm coming to hurt you!
-I'm coming.
-I've gotta stop her.
If you stop Chloe Webber, I will let him out.
We will let him out. Together.
I cannot be alone! It's not fair!
(GROWLING)
-Look, I've got your pod!
-The pod is dead!
-No, no. It only needs heat.
-It needs more than heat.
What then?
I'm not being funny or nothing,
but that picture just moved.
And that one!
She didn't draw that, he did.
But it needs more than heat, Doctor.
MAN ON TV: ...still on its way.
I suppose it's much more than a torch now.
It's a beacon. It's a beacon
of hope and fortitude and courage.
-And it's a beacon of love.
-Love.
So let's have a look from the helicopter.
-There we go, the torchbearer...
-I know how to charge up the pod.
...past Dame Kelly Holmes Close...
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
-Sorry, you'll have to watch from here.
-No, I've gotta get closer!
-No way.
-I can stop this from happening!
SINISTER VOICE: Chloe.
-Chloe.
-I'm coming to hurt you.
My baby!
-You're not going to hurt her again!
-Chloe! I'm coming!
(POD BEEPING)
You felt it, didn't you?
(WHISPERING) Feel the love.
(ROSE CHEERING)
I can go home.
Goodbye, Chloe Webber.
I love you.
-Mum?
-I'm here.
Mummy!
Nice one! You did it!
What was it you did?
Yeah!
Mummy!
Oh, Jane!
Doctor?
MAN: He's back now.
I don't know who you are, or what you did,
but thank you, darling.
And thank that man from me, too.
Where is he? He should be here.
All the drawings have come to life.
That means all of them.
(SINISTER VOICE GROWLING)
Oh no...
-Trish, get out!
-I can't. The door's stuck.
-Is the Doctor in there?
-I don't think so.
Mummy!
(THUDDING)
SINISTER VOICE: I'm coming to hurt you!
-Please, Dad, no more.
-Chloe!
Chloe, listen to me.
It isn't real like the others.
It's just energy left over by the Isolus.
-But you can get rid of it, Chloe.
-Help us!
Oh, it's 'cause you're so scared
that he's real.
But you can get shot of him, Chloe.
-Mummy!
-ROSE: You can do it, Chloe!
I can't!
SINISTER VOICE: Chloe! I'm coming!
-I'm coming!
-I can't!
-I'm coming! Chloe!
-Mummy!
I'm with you, Chloe. You're not alone.
You'll never be alone again.
-I'm coming to hurt you.
-ROSE: Sing again. Chloe, sing!
Chloe! Chloe!
# Kookaburra sits...
-Chloe!
-# ...gum tree
-# Merry merry king of the bush #
Chloe, I'm coming to hurt you.
BOTH: # Laugh, kookaburra,
laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be
# Laugh, kookaburra, laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be #
(SINISTER VOICE FADING)
# Kookaburra sits in the old gum tree
# Merry merry king of the bush is he
# Laugh, kookaburra, laugh, kookaburra
# Gay your life must be #
Maybe he's gone somewhere.
Who's gonna hold his hand now?
MAN ON TV: Just look at this. Utterly
incredible scenes at the Olympic Stadium.
80,000 athletes and spectators,
they disappeared, they've come back.
They've returned.
They've re-appeared. It's quite incredible.
But, Bob, this will certainly prompt...
80,000 people. So where's the Doctor?
I need him!
But hang on. The torchbearer seems to be
in a bit of trouble.
We did see a flash of lightning earlier
that seemed to strike him.
Maybe he's injured.
He's definitely in trouble.
This mean that the Olympic dream is dead?
Doctor!
There's a mystery man.
He's picked up the flame,
and we've no idea who he is.
He's carrying the flame,
yes, he's carrying the flame,
and no one wants to stop him.
It's more than a flame now, Bob.
It's more than heat and light.
It's hope, and it's courage, and it's love.
(SPECTATORS CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
Go on. Join your brothers and sisters.
They'll be waiting!
(CHEERING)
Cake?
(LAUGHING)
Top banana!
I can't stress this enough.
Ball bearings you can eat. Masterpiece!
-I thought I'd lost you.
-Nah. Not on a night like this.
This is a night for lost things being found.
Come on.
What now?
I wanna go to the Games,
it's what we came for.
Go on. Give us a clue.
Which events do we do well in?
Well, I will tell you this,
Papua New Guinea surprised everyone
in the shot put.
Really? You're joking, aren't you?
Doctor? Are you serious, or are you joking?
Wait and see.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
You know what?
They keep on trying to split us up,
but they never ever will.
Never say, "Never ever."
Nah, we'll always be okay, you and me.
(FIRECRACKERS BURSTING)
Don't you reckon, Doctor?
Something in the air. Something coming.
What?
A storm's approaching.
ROSE.: This is a story of war on Earth.
DRAMATIC VOICE: The valiant child
who will die in battle so very soon.
ROSE: It said I was gonna die in battle.
DOCTOR: Then it lied.
Welcome to Torchwood.
Woke up one morning,
and there they all were.
Ghosts everywhere.
If I'm the enemy,
does that mean I'm the prisoner?
Oh, yes.
Oi! Where are you taking that?
If it's alien, it's ours.
We've got a problem down here.
MAN: Yvonne, can you hear me?
You send that thing back into hell.
The Doctor, lording it over us, assuming
alien authority over the rights of man.
DOCTOR: They're bleeding through
the fault lines.
Walking from their world, across the void,
and into yours.
You can't stop us, Doctor.
DOCTOR: This world is colliding
with another.
Positions!
What are they?
Cybermen.
(SCREAMING)
ROSE: And that's when it all ended.
This is the last story I'll ever tell.