(YELLS)
It is.
It's you two.
We could say hi to Future Us.
- (AMY SHRIEKS)
- Get away!
Amy, no! No!
- Go! Go!
- Her name's Alaya.
She's one of their warriors.
One of you will kill me.
- If she lives, so do Elliot...
- Mum...
...and Mo...
and Amy, because I will find them.
My death shall ignite a war
and every stinking ape
shall be wiped from the surface
of my beloved planet.
We return their hostage,
they return ours.
Nobody dies today.
ELDANE: This is the story
of our planet, Earth,
of the day 1,000 years past
when we came to share it
with a race known as Humanity.
It is the story of the Doctor who
helped our races find common ground
and the terrible losses he suffered.
It is the story of our past
and must never be forgotten.
This place is enormous and deserted.
The majority of the race
are probably still asleep.
We need to find Amy, looking
for heat signature anomalies.
But, Doctor, how can all this be here?
I mean, these plants.
Must be getting closer
to the centre of the city.
You're sure
this is the best way to enter?
Front door approach!
Definitely. Always the best way...
PA: Hostile life force detected, area 17.
Apart from the back door approach,
that's also good,
sometimes better.
- Hostile life force detected, area 17.
- Doctor?
Hostile life force detected, area 17.
We're not hostile, we're not armed!
We're here in peace!
(THEY COUGH)
(WHIMPERING)
Don't you come near me with that!
(GROANING)
From the clothing,
the human female appears to be
more resistant to the cold
than the male.
I dressed for Rio!
Leave her alone! You've got me/
- (CLUNKING)
- (SHRIEKS)
Decontamination complete.
Commencing dissection.
(WHIMPERS)
PA: Area 17 incursion,
species diagnostic requested.
Area 17 incursion,
Yeah! And stay out!
Ha-ha!
How did you get that?
You never picked a lizard man's
pocket? Come on, before he gets back.
That creature,
do you think it was an alien?
Any more of them, do you think?
Do you think the Earth's been invaded?
Don't know. But I know someone
who could have some answers.
We need to get back to the surface
and find him.
- I wonder where this leads.
- Maybe it's a way out.
- Oh, my God, no.
- What is it?
Oh, God...
It's my son. It's Elliot.
What've they done to him?
No! He's in there!
We have to get him out!
Elliot! Elliot, it's Dad!
PA: Access denied.
Unauthorised genetic imprint.
Stop. Seriously. We can't get in.
That's my boy in there!
These screens, they're monitoring
something. I think they're vital signs -
heartbeats, pulses.
Why else would he be wired up?
- He's still alive.
- All right.
We find weapons,
get that creature from the lab
and force it to release Elliot, yeah?
Yeah, trust me. We'll get him out.
Ambrose.
You lied.
You told us you were the police.
It was a misunderstanding...
Who are you? You and the Doctor?
Why is this happening to us?
What did we ever do?
The Doctor will get your son back,
I promise. In the meantime,
we take turns guarding the creature.
So that's it? We just sit and wait.
And then we exchange her
for your family.
I promise you, Ambrose,
I'd trust the Doctor with my life.
We stick to his plan.
We keep that creature safe.
Argh! Argh!
How can they have escaped?
This proves all prisoners
should remain under military guard.
I'm sure you'd prefer to be in charge
of everything and everyone, Restac,
but we rank the same.
(SCREAMING)
Is there any word from Alaya?
No.
It's fine to show concern, you know.
- She's part of your gene-chain.
- Huh!
I'm decontaminating now.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Decontamination? No, no, no!
(DOCTOR YELLS)
- (BUZZING RISES IN PITCH)
- (DOCTOR SCREAMS)
(SNIFFS)
Why aren't you dead? You're
carrying my venom in your blood.
You should have died.
Why aren't you dead?
Show me.
(HISSES)
- How does it feel, ape?
- Like it's burning in my blood.
Please.
If you help me, I can help you.
If you could cure me,
I could help you escape.
You see? You beg
and offer betrayal so early!
Why would I want to escape
when I can watch you die?
The first ape death of the coming war.
(DOCTOR YELLS)
Its all right. It won't harm you.
I'm only neutralising
all your ape bacteria.
I'm not an ape! Look at the scans!
Two hearts!
Totally different! Totally not ape!
Remove all human germs, you remove
half the things keeping me alive.
No, complete the process.
Oh, that's much better, thanks!
Not got any celery, have you?
No, no, not really the climate.
Tomatoes, though, you'd do
a roaring trade in those. I'm the Doctor.
Oh, and there's Nasreen, good!
Oh, a green man.
Hello, who are you?
Restac. Military commander.
Oh, dear, really?
There's always a military, isn't there?
Your weapon was attacking
the oxygen pockets above our city.
Oxygen pockets! Lovely!
Oooh, but not so good
with an impending drill!
Now it makes sense!
Where is the rest of your invasion force?
Invasion force?
Me and lovely Nasreen? No!
We came for the humans you took.
And...to offer the safe return of Alaya.
Oh, wait, you and she,
what is it, same genetic source?
Of course you're worried,
but don't be, she's safe.
You claim to come in peace,
but you hold one of us hostage.
Wait, wait, we all want
the same thing here.
I don't negotiate with apes.
I'm going to send a clear message
to those on the surface.
What's that?
Your execution.
Yes...
These chambers are all over the city.
Uh! Turn it off quick!
- They're not moving.
- Maybe they're asleep.
Let's have another look.
No, Amy, don't!
Amy, what are you doing?
Get out of there.
(WHISPERS) Some sort
of suspended animation.
I wonder what these are.
The Doctor would know.
The Doctor always knows.
Hey, look.
Wait...
I've got it.
It's how they came up to the surface.
Some sort of powered transport discs.
It's our way out of here.
Even better, weapons.
Come on, now we can fight back.
- Which way now?
- Door at the end.
- Are you sure?
- Nope!
- MO: Wow.
- AMY: Yeah.
We don't stand a chance.
We have to find the Doctor.
Dad, are you all right? Dad!
Ambrose, I'm fine! Leave me alone.
You are not fine. Let me...
Let me look.
Get off!
Oh, my God, Dad.
I don't know what's happening to me.
It's going to be fine.
First thing is bring
this temperature down, get you resting.
These must be the only ones awake.
The others must still be
in hibernation.
So, why did they go into
hibernation in the first place?
Their astronomers predicted
the planet heading to Earth
on a crash course.
They built a life underground
and put themselves to sleep
for millennia in order to avert what
they thought was the apocalypse.
When in reality, it was the moon
coming into alignment
with the Earth.
How can you know that?
Long time ago, I met another
tribe of Homo reptilia,
- similar, but not identical.
- Others of our species have survived?
The humans attacked them.
They died, I'm sorry.
A vermin race.
- What's the cure?
- What?
I saw what you've done to my dad.
What's the cure?
Why would I tell you?
Cos if you don't,
I'm going to have to use this on you.
Now you reveal yourselves.
First you take my son,
now you hurt my dad.
I'm just protecting my family here.
That's all. I don't want to use it.
I want you to put things right.
Use it.
What?
Use it on me.
But you're too afraid.
A woman who can't even protect
her own child must be too weak to...
- (ZAPPING, SHE SHRIEKS)
- I didn't want to do that.
Are you all right? Tell me,
what's the cure for my dad?
He's vermin. He deserves a painful death.
I'm giving you a chance.
I knew it would be you.
The one with the most
to lose, the weakest.
(ZAPPING)
I'm a nurse,
you should've told me.
(SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
(ALAYA GASPS FOR BREATH)
- Ambrose... What have you done?
- She kept taunting me
about Mo and Elliot and you.
(ALAYA GROANS)
We have to be better than this!
She wouldn't tell me anything.
I thought sooner or later,
she'd give in. I would've done.
I just... I just want my family back, Dad.
RORY: I'm sorry.
How do we help you?
Tell us what to do.
I knew this would come.
And soon the war.
You're not dying.
I'm not going to let you,
not today...
(ALAYA GROANS LOUDLY)
You're not authorised to do this!
I'm authorised to protect the safety
of our species while they sleep.
THE DOCTOR: Oh, lovely place,
very gleaming.
This is our court
and our place of execution.
- Let them go!
- Amy Pond, there's a girl to rely on.
You're covered both ways,
so don't try anything clever, buster.
- Mo!
- Now let them go. Or I shoot.
I'm warning you!
- Don't you touch her!
- And you?
All right, Restac.
You've made your point.
This is now a military tribunal.
Go back to your laboratory,
Malohkeh.
This isn't the way.
Prepare them for execution.
OK, sorry, as rescues go,
didn't live up to its potential.
- I'm glad you're OK.
- Me too!
Lizard men, though!
Homo reptilia- they occupied
the planet before humans.
Now they want it back.
After they've wiped out the human race.
Right, preferred it
when I didn't know, to be honest.
NASREEN: Why are they waiting?
What do you think
they're going to do with us?
I didn't know it would go like that, Dad.
Oh, my little girl,
what have you done?
What happens now?
(BUZZING)
Oh, my God.
Who is the ape leader?
It's them. How are they doing that?
How do they know that we're in here?
Who speaks for the apes?
Don't tell them what's happened.
I speak for the...
humans. Some of us, anyway.
Do you understand who we are?
Sort of. A bit. Not really.
We have ape hostages.
- Doctor! Amy!
- Mo! |
Mo, are you OK?
I'm fine, love! I've found Elliot.
I'm bringing him home!
Amy, I thought I'd lost you!
What, cos I was sucked into the ground?
You're so clingy.
- Tony Mack!
- Having fun down there?
Not to interrupt, but
Just a quick reminder to stay calm.
Show me Alaya.
Show me and release her, immediately,
unharmed, or we kill your friends
one by one.
- No!
- Ambrose...
Steady now, everyone.
- Ambrose, stop it/
- Get off me, Dad/!
- We didn't start this!
- Let Rory deal with this, Ambrose, eh?
We are not doing what you say any more.
Now, give me back my family!
No.
Execute the girl.
No! No, wait!
- Rory!
- She's not speaking for us!
- There's no need for this...
- Listen!
- Aim.
- Whatever you want, we'll do it!
- Amy!
- Rory!
- Don't do this.
- No!
- Fire!
- Stop!
You want to start a war
while the rest of us sleep, Restac?
The apes are attacking us!
You're our protector, not our commander,
Restac. Unchain them.
I do not recognise
your authority at this time, Eldane.
Well, then, you must shoot me.
You woke him to undermine me.
We're not monsters
and neither are they.
What is it about apes
you love so much? Mmm?
While you slept, they've evolved.
I've seen it for myself.
We used to hunt apes for sport.
When we came underground,
they bred and polluted this planet.
Shush now, Restac.
Go and play soldiers.
I'll let you know if I need you.
You'll need me,
then we'll see.
Nothing!
I've got to get down there.
- Rory! Hello!
- Where's Amy?
- She's fine, look, here she is.
- Oh, thank God.
- Keeping you on your toes!
- No time to chat.
Listen, you need to get down here.
Go to the drill storeroom.
There's a large patch of earth
in the middle of the floor.
The Silurians are going to send up
transport discs to bring you back down
using geothermal energy
and gravity-bubble technology.
It's how they travel and, frankly,
it's pretty cool. Bring Alaya.
We hand her over, we can land this
after all. All going to work, promise.
Got to dash! Hurry up!
The moment we get down there,
everything will fall apart.
We have to return her.
They deserve at least that.
I'd say you've got
a fair bit to talk about.
- How so?
- You both want the planet.
You both have a genuine claim to it.
Are you authorised to negotiate
on behalf of humanity?
Me? No!
But they are!
- What?!
- No, we're not!
Course you are! Amy Pond and Nasreen
Chaudhry, speaking for the planet!
Humanity couldn't have
better ambassadors.
Come on, who has more fun than us?
Is this what happens, in the future,
the planet gets shared?
- Is that what we need to do?
- What are you talking about?
Oh, Nasreen, sorry,
probably worth mentioning at this stage,
Amy and I travel in time, a bit.
Anything else?
There are fixed points through time,
where things must always
stay the way they are.
This is not one of them.
This is an opportunity,
a temporal tipping point.
Whatever happens today
will change future events,
create its own timeline,
its own reality.
The future pivots around you.
Here. Now.
So do good.
For humanity, and for Earth.
Right.
No pressure there, then(!)
We can't share the planet.
Nobody on the surface
is going to go for this idea.
- It is just too big a leap!
- Come on.
Be extraordinary.
Oh...you...
OK.
Bringing things to order -
the first meeting of representatives
of the human race and Homo reptilia
is now in session.
Ha! Never said that before,
that's fab! Carry on!
Now, Mo, let's go and get your son.
Oh, you know, humans and their
predecessors, shooting the breeze.
Never thought I'd see it.
So we get on those, and they
take us down through the Earth?
Geothermal gravity bubbles,
or something.
They sent four.
She was our only bargaining chip.
We have to hand her back.
Wait...
Before we go down,
there's something I've got to do...
Dad, I need your help.
- No! No way.
- Please, Dad...
- just a precaution.
- I've told you, I won't do it.
- Look at what they did to you!
- This isn't about me or you.
No, it's about your grandson.
If you won't do it for me,
do it for Elliot.
I know I did wrong.
But I can't lose him, Dad.
Elliot, there you are.
- If you've harmed him in any way.
- Of course not!
- I only store the young.
- But why?
I took samples of the young,
slowed their lifecycles
to a millionth of their normal rate,
so I could study how they grew,
what they needed,
how they lived on the surface.
You've been down here,
working by yourself, all alone?
My family, through the millennia...
For the last 300 years, just me.
I never meant to harm your child.
Malohkeh, I rather love you.
It's safe. We can wake him.
(MALOHKEH CHUCKLES)
Come.
- Elliot? ELl, it's Dad.
- What...? Dad.
- You're safe now.
- But where are we?
Well,
I've got to be honest with you, son.
We're in the centre of the Earth...
and there are lizard men.
- Hi.
- Wow.
Elliot, I'm sorry.
I took my eye off you.
It's OK. I forgive you.
You go on, Doctor. I'll catch up.
PA: Storage facility 19 operational.
We lived on the surface of the planet
long before you did.
Our sole purpose has been
to return to our rightful place.
And we've got a planet
that can't already sustain
the people who live there.
And you want to add a whole other
species, to drain resources...
ELDANE: As I sat there that day
across the table from the humans,
the future of both species and of our
beloved planet Earth rested in our hands.
But as the discussions went on,
I began to despair about whether
we would ever find any common ground.
As ambassadors for our species,
we all had too much to lose.
So, erm, what about the areas
that aren't habitable to us?
Australian outback,
Sahara desert, Nevada plains...
- They're all deserted.
- Yes, fine, but what happens
when their population
grows and breeds and spreads?
And anyway,
what benefit does humanity get,
and how will we ever sell this
to people on the surface?
If I could get a word in,
maybe I could tell you.
You give us space,
we can bring new sources of energy,
new methods of water supply,
new medicines, scientific advances.
We were a great civilisation.
You provide a place
for us on the surface,
we'll give you knowledge and
technology beyond humanity's dreams.
We work together,
this planet could achieve greatness.
OK. Now I'm starting to see it.
- Oh, yeah.
- (APPLAUSE)
Not bad for a first session.
More similarities than differences.
(WHOOSHING)
The transport has returned.
Your friends are here.
That's not right.
What are you doing?!
Protecting our race
against the apes.
You can't do this!
You're a good scientist, Malohkeh,
but this is war.
Argh!
Here they are.
Mum!
AMY: Rory!
Something's wrong...
AMY: Doctor, what's he carrying?
No.
Don't do this.
Tell me you didn't do this.
What did you do?
It was me.
- I did it.
- Mum?
I just wanted you back.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
You have to believe me,
they're better than this.
- This is our planet!
- We had a chance here.
Leave us alone.
In future, when you talk about this,
you tell people there was a chance
but you were so much less
than the best of humanity.
My sister.
(SHE WAILS)
And you want us
to trust these apes, Doctor?
One woman.
She was scared for her family.
She's not typical.
I think she is.
One person let us down.
But there's a whole race of dazzling,
peaceful human beings up there.
You were building something here.
Come on, an alliance could work.
It's too late for that, Doctor.
Why?
Our drill
is set to start
burrowing again in...
15 minutes.
- What?
- What choice did I have? They had Elliot.
- Don't do this, don't call their bluff.
- Let us go back.
And you promise to never come
to the surface ever again.
We'll walk away, leave you alone.
- Execute her.
- No!
Everybody, back to the lab! Run!
Execute all the apes!
This is a deadly weapon - stay back.
Take everyone to the lab!
- I'll cover you!
- RORY: Go! Go!
Ah-ah! Stop right there! Or I'll
use my very deadly weapon again.
One warning, that's all you get.
If there can be no deal, you go back
into hibernation. All of you. Now.
This ends here.
No. It only ends with our victory.
Like I said...
one warning.
Elliot, you and your dad
keep your eyes on that screen.
Let me know if we get company.
Amy, keep reminding me
how much time I haven't got.
OK, 12%2 minutes till drill impact.
Tony Mack, sweaty forehead,
dilated pupils, what're you hiding?
Tony! What happened?!
Alaya's sting.
She said there's no cure.
I'm dying, aren't I?
- You're not dying, you're mutating.
- How can I stop it?
Decontamination program!
Might work - don't know.
Eldane, can you run
the program on Tony?
Doctor, shed load of those
creatures coming our way!
We're surrounded in here!
So, question is,
how do we stop the drill,
given that we can't
get there in time? Plus also,
how do we get out,
given that we're surrounded?
How do you feel about
an energy pulse,
channel led up through the tunnels
to the base of the drill?
- To blow up my life's work?
- Yes.
Sorry. No nice way of putting that.
Right, well,
you're going to have to do it
before the drill hits the city, in...
- 11 minutes, 40 seconds...
- Yes!
- Squeaky bum time!
- Yes, but the explosion
is going to cave in
all the surrounding tunnels,
so we have to be on the surface by then.
- But we can't get past Restac's troops.
- I can help with that...
Toxic Fumigation -
an emergency failsafe meant to
protect my species from infection.
A warning signal to occupy cryo-chambers.
After that, citywide fumigation,
by toxic gas. Then the city shuts down.
You could end up killing your own people.
Only those foolish enough
to follow Restac.
Eldane, are you sure about this?
My priority is my race's survival.
The Earth isn't ready
for us to return yet.
- No.
- Ten minutes, Doctor.
But maybe it should be.
So here's a deal.
Everybody listening.
Eldane, you activate shutdown...
I'll amend the system,
set your alarm for 1,000 years' time.
1,000 years, to sort the planet out.
To be ready. Pass it on.
As legend, or prophecy, or religion,
but somehow, make it known.
- This planet is to be shared.
- Yeah. I get you.
- Nine minutes, seven seconds.
- Yes, fluid controls, my favourite!
Energy pulse timed, primed and set.
Before we go, energy barricade,
need to cancel it out - quickly.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINING)
Fumigation pre-launching.
There's not much time for us to get
from here to the surface, Doctor!
Ah-ha, super-squeaky bum time!
Get ready to run for your lives.
Now...
But the decontamination program
on your friend hasn't started yet.
Well, go. All of you! Go.
- No, we're not leaving you here!
- Granddad!
Eight minutes, ten seconds.
Now, you look after your mum.
You mustn't blame her.
She only did what she thought was right.
I'm not going to see you again, am I?
I'll be here.
Always.
I love you, boy.
- You be sure he gets home safe!
- This is my fault.
No, I can't go back up there.
I'd be a freaks how.
The technology down here's my only hope.
I love you, Dad.
- Go. Go!
- Come on.
Go on.
Toxic fumigation initiated.
- Return to cryo-chambers.
- No!
- Toxic fumigation initiated.
- Return to cryo-chambers.
- This is not the order!
- Toxic fumigation initiated.
- They're going! We're clear!
OK. Everyone follow Nasreen.
Look for a blue box. Get ready to run.
I'm sorry.
I thought for a moment,
our race, and the humans...
Yeah. Me too.
Doctor!
We've got less than six minutes.
Go! Go! I'm right behind you!
Let's go.
- I'm not coming either.
- What?
Oh, for goodness' sake!
We're going to hibernate with them,
me and Tony.
Doctor, you must go!
I can be decontaminated
when we're woken.
- All the time in the world.
- But...
Nasreen...you...
No. This is perfect.
I don't want to go.
I've got what I was digging for.
I can't leave when
I've only just found it.
Doctor!
Thank you, Doctor.
The pleasure was all mine.
Come and look for us.
(ALARM BLARES)
ELDANE: So, the Doctor sent our warriors
back to their rest
on the promise
of future harmony with humans.
- Immediate evacuation.
- The other way, idiot!
Toxic fumigation is about to commence.
- Immediate evacuation.
- Come on!
Toxic fumigation
ls about to commence.
No questions, just get in!
And yes, I know it's big!
Ambrose, sickbay up the stairs,
left, then left again...
get yourself fixed up. Come on!
Five minutes and counting...
Not here. Not now.
It's getting wider.
The crack on my bedroom wall.
Two parts of space and time
that should never
have touched right here.
And the Byzantium. All through
the universe - rips in the continuum.
How could it be following me?
Some sort of space-time cataclysm.
An explosion, maybe.
Big enough to put cracks
in the universe. But what?
Four minutes fifty...
We have to go!
The Angels laughed
when I didn't know.
Prisoner Zero knew.
Everybody knows, except me!
- Doctor, just leave it.
- But where there's an explosion,
there's shrapnel.
Doctor, you can't put
your hand in there!
Why not?
Ahhh!
- I've got something!
- What is it?
I don't know.
- Doctor!
- (RESTAC GROANS)
She was there, when the gas started.
- She must've been poisoned.
- You!
- OK, get in the TARDIS, both of you.
- You did this.
Doctor!
- (HE SCREAMS)
- Rory!
(RORY GROANS)
Rory, can you hear me?
I don't understand.
Shh-shh. Don't talk.
Doctor, is he OK?
We have to get him onto the TARDIS!
We were on the hill.
I can't die here.
Don't say that.
You're so beautiful...
I'm sorry.
Doctor, help him.
If the time energy catches up with you,
you'll never have been born.
It will erase every moment
of your existence.
You will never have lived at all.
Amy, move away from the light.
If it touches you,
you'll be wiped from history.
Amy, move away now.
No! I am not leaving him!
We have to help him!
The light's already around him,
- we can't help him.
- I am not leaving him!
- We have to.
- No.
- Sorry!
- Get off me!
No!
No! No! No!
Let me out, please let me out.
I need to get to Rory.
That light - if his body's absorbed
I'll forget him. He'll never have
existed. You can't let that happen.
What are you doing?
- Doctor! No!
- (METALLIC THRUMMING)
No! No! Doctor,
we can't just leave him there.
Keep him in your mind.
Don't forget him. If you forget him,
you'll lose him forever.
On the Byzantium,
I still remembered the Clerics
because I am a time traveller,
now you said.
They weren't part of your world.
This is different...
this is your own history changing.
Don't tell me it's going to be OK.
You have to make it OK.
It's going to be hard,
but you can do it, Amy.
Tell me about Rory.
Fantastic Rory,
funny Rory, gorgeous Rory.
Amy, listen to me.
Do exactly as I say.
Amy, please.
Keep concentrating. You can do this.
- I can't.
- You can.
You can do it.
I can't help you unless you do.
Come on. We can still save his memory.
Come on, Amy. Please...
(INAUDIBLE)
Come on, Amy, come on.
Amy, please.
Don't let anything distract you.
Oh-oh!
Argh!
Remember Rory. Keep remembering,
Rory is only alive in your memory.
You must keep hold of him.
Don't let anything distract you.
Rory still lives in your mind.
(SLAMMING)
What were you saying?
I have seen some things today,
but this is beyond mad.
Doctor!
Five seconds till it all goes up!
All Nasreen's work just erased.
Good thing she's not here to see it.
She's going to give Tony hell
when they wake up.
You could've let
those things shoot me.
- You saved me.
- An eye for an eye.
It's never the way.
Now you show your son
how wrong you were.
How there's another way.
You make him the best of humanity...
...in the way you couldn't be.
You're very quiet.
Oh! Hey! Look! There I am again!
(SHOUTS) Hello, me!
Are you OK?
I thought I saw someone else
there for a second.
I need a holiday.
Didn't we talk about Rio?
You go in.
Just fix this lock, keeps jamming.
You boys and your locksmithery.
ELDANE: Now as my people awaken
from their 1,000-year sleep
ready to rise to the surface,
my thoughts turn back to the Doctor,
the losses he suffered then
and the greater losses
that were still to come.