There's still no word
from inside Downing Street.
Though we are getting
even more new arrivals.
We are the Slitheen.
Reduce the Earth to
molten slag then sell it.
Leave this planet
or I'll stop you.
The world is in your hands.
I've checked the figures.
I've checked them again and again.
Always the same result.
The design is not safe.
It could result in the death of millions.
I beg of you, stop the project right now
before it's too late.
MARGARET: Well, goodness me!
Obviously, Mr Cleaver,
you're the expert.
Then, you'll stop it?
It seems I have no choice.
(RUMBLING)
Oh, do excuse me.
Civic duties leave little time
for a sandwich.
But you promise
you'll stop it today?
Well, of course!
Nothing is more
important than human life.
What do you take me for?
Some sort of maniac?
Why, no.
Am I right in thinking
you've shown your results only to me?
-Just to you, no one else.
-Wise move.
I can't tell you, Mrs Blaine,
this is such a weight off my mind.
I've barely slept.
I couldn't believe my own readings.
The scale of it. Destruction like
the British Isles has never seen before.
If I didn't know better,
I'd almost think that someone
wanted this project to go wrong.
As though they intended this city
should be wiped off the map.
Thank goodness we've got you,
our esteemed leader.
(MR CLEAVER SCREAMING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME MUSIC)
Who the hell are you?
What do you mean, who the hell am I?
Captain Jack Harkness.
Whatever you're selling, we're not buying.
Get out of my way!
Don't tell me,
this must be Mickey.
Here comes trouble.
How you doing, Ricky boy?
-It's Mickey.
-Don't listen to him, he's winding you up.
You look fantastic.
Aw, sweet. Look at these two.
How come I never get any of that?
-Buy me a drink first.
-You're such hard work.
But worth it.
Did you manage to find it?
-There you go.
-I can go anywhere now.
I've told you,
you don't need a passport.
It's all very well
going to Platform One and Justicia
and the Glass Pyramid of San Kaloon,
but what if we end up in Brazil?
I might need it.
You see, I'm prepared for anything.
Sounds like you're staying, then.
So, what are you doing in Cardiff?
And who the hell's Jumping Jack Flash?
I don't mind you hanging out
with Big Ears up there.
-Oi!
-Look in the mirror.
-But this guy, I don't know, he's kind of...
-Handsome?
More like cheesy.
Early 21st century slang.
Is cheesy good or bad?
-It's bad.
-But bad means good, isn't that right?
You saying I'm not handsome?
We've just stopped off,
we need to refuel.
The thing is, Cardiff's got this rift
running through the middle of the city.
It's invisible, but it's like an earthquake fault
between different dimensions.
The rift was healed back in 1869...
Thanks to a girl named Gwyneth
because these creatures called the Gelth
were using the rift as a gateway,
but she saved the world and closed it.
But closing a rift always leaves a scar
and that scar generates energy,
harmless to the human race...
But perfect for the Tardis.
Just park here for a couple of days,
right on top of the scar and...
Open up the engines,
soak up the radiation...
Like filling her up
with petrol and off we go.
-Into time.
-And space.
My God, have you seen yourselves?
You all think you're so clever, don't you?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Should take another 24 hours
which means we've got time to kill.
That old lady's staring.
Probably wondering what four people can do
inside a small wooden box.
What are you captain of?
The Innuendo Squad?
Wait, the Tardis, you can't just leave it.
Doesn't it get noticed?
Yeah, what's with the police box?
Why does it look like that?
-It's a cloaking device.
-It's called a chameleon circuit.
The Tardis is meant to disguise itself
wherever it lands.
Like, if this was ancient Rome,
it'd be a statue on a plinth or something.
But I landed in the 1960s,
It disguised itself as a police box
and the circuit got stuck.
So, it copied a real thing?
There actually was police boxes?
Yeah, on street corners.
You could phone for help
before they had radios and mobiles.
If they arrested somebody,
they could shove them inside till help came.
-Like a little prison cell.
-Why don't you just fix the circuit?
-I like it, don't you?
-I love it.
But that's what I meant,
there's no police boxes anymore
so doesn't it get noticed?
Ricky, let me tell you something
about the human race.
You put a mysterious blue box slap-bang
in the middle of town, what do they do?
Walk past it.
Now, stop your nagging, let's go and explore.
ROSE: What's the plan?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
DOCTOR: Cardiff, early 21st century,
and the wind's coming from the...east.
Trust me.
Safest place in the universe.
This nuclear power station
right in the heart of Cardiff city
will bring jobs for all.
As you can see, as Lord Mayor,
I've had to sanction
some radical redevelopments.
No photographs!
What did I say?
Take pictures of the project,
by all means, but not me, thank you.
So, Cardiff Castle will be demolished,
allowing the Blaidd Drwg project
to rise up, tall and proud.
A monument to Welsh industry.
And, yes,
some of you might shiver.
The words "nuclear power station”
and "major population centre”
aren't exactly
the happiest of bedfellows.
But I give you my personal guarantee
that as long as I walk upon this Earth,
no harm will come to any of my citizens.
Now, drink up!
A toast, to the future.
ALL: To the future.
And believe me...
it will glow.
Mrs Blaine, my name's Cathy Salt.
I represent the Cardiff Gazette.
I'm sorry, I'm not doing interviews.
I can't bear self-publicity.
-But are you aware of the curse?
-Whatever do you mean?
-Cathy, wasn't it?
-Cathy Salt.
That's what some
of your engineers are saying,
that the Blaidd Drwg project is cursed.
Sounds rather silly to me.
That's what I thought,
I was just chasing a bit of local colour.
But the funny thing is,
when you start piecing it all together,
it does begin to look a bit odd.
-In what way?
-The deaths.
The number of deaths associated
with this project.
First of all, there was the entire team
of the European Safety Inspectors.
But they were French.
It's not my fault if "Danger Explosives"
was only written in Welsh.
And there was that accident
with the Cardiff Heritage Committee.
The electrocution of that swimming pool
was put down to natural wear and tear.
And then the architect?
It was raining, visibility was low,
my car simply couldn"t stop.
And then just recently, Mr Cleaver,
the government's nuclear adviser.
Slipped on an icy patch.
-He was decapitated.
-It was a very icy patch.
I'm afraid these stories are nothing more
than typical small-town thinking.
I really haven't got time.
If you'll excuse me.
Except before he died, Mr Cleaver
posted some of his findings online.
-Did he now?
-If you know where to look.
-He was concerned about the reactor.
-All that technical stuff.
Specifically, that the design
of the suppression pool
would cause the hydrogen
recombiners to fail,
precipitating in the collapse
of the containment isolation system
and resulting in a meltdown.
-Who's been doing her homework?
-That's my job.
I think...Cathy Salt...
I think you and I
should have a word in private.
(RUMBLING)
Oh! My little tummy is complaining.
I think we might have to
make a detour to the ladies'.
-I'll wait here.
-Come on. All girls together.
So, you were saying?
These outlandish theories of yours.
(SQUELCHING)
-Sounds like we got here just in time.
-Continue.
Well, I don't know much about
nuclear physics,
but from what I could make out,
Cleaver was saying that the whole project
could go up, worse than Chernobyl.
Is there something wrong with the lights?
They're always on the blink.
I can't tell you how many memos I've sent.
So, Chernobyl?
Apparently,
but a thousand times worse.
I mean, it sounds absurd,
there must be so many safety regulations.
But Cleaver seemed to be talking about
a nuclear holocaust.
He almost made it sound deliberate.
I mean, we're hardly the Sunday Times,
we're only the Cardiff Gazette,
but we still have a duty
to report the facts.
And you're going to
print this information?
Are you all right?
You sound a bit...
Sore throat.
(MARGARET COUGHING)
Just a little tickle.
But tell me, do you intend to make
this information public?
I have to.
So be it.
Mind you,
my boyfriend thinks I'm mad.
We're getting married next month
and he says if I cause a fuss,
I could lose my job,
just when we need the money.
-Boyfriend?
-Jeffrey.
Civil servant.
He's nothing exciting, but he's mine.
-When's the wedding?
-The 19th.
It's really just to stop my mother
from nagging,
but the baby sort of
clinched it, I suppose.
You're with child?
Three months,
it's not showing yet.
Wasn't planned, it was an accident.
Nice accident, though.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-How about you?
-No.
-Is there a Mr Blaine?
-Not anymore.
I'm all on my own.
I had quite a size able family
once upon a time.
Wonderful brothers.
Oh, they were bold.
But all of them gone, now.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I'm cursed.
No, I don't think so, not really.
You're very kind.
If you don't mind,
I might be a while.
You run along.
Perhaps we could do this another day.
-Are you all right?
-Fine.
Okay, I tell you what,
I'll leave my details with your office.
Thanks for talking.
Thank you.
(LOW MOANING)
JACK: I swear!
DOCTOR: You're lying through your teeth!
It turns out the white things are tusks,
and I mean, tusks!
And it's woken and it's not happy.
How could you not know
it was there?
We're standing there,
15 of us, naked.
And I'm like,
"No, it's got nothing to do with me."
And then it roars, and we're running.
My God, we are running.
And Brakovitch falls
so I turn to him and I say...
-I knew we should have turned left!
-That's my line!
I don't believe you, I don't believe a word
you say, ever. That is so brilliant!
Did you ever get
your clothes back?
No, I just picked him up
and went right for the ship.
Full throttle, didn't stop
tilL I hit the space lanes. I was shaking!
It was unbelievable! Freaked me out.
And by the time I got there,
I was 15 light years away
and I realised I'm like this...
And I was having
such a nice day.
According to Intelligence,
the target is the last surviving member
of the Slitheen family.
A criminal sect from the planet
Rexicoricophalvitorius
masquerading as a human being,
zipped inside a skin suit.
Okay, plan of attack.
We assume a basic 57-56 strategy,
covering all available exits
on the ground floor.
Doctor, you go face to face,
that'll designate Exit 1.
I'll cover Exit 2.
Rose, you Exit 3,
Mickey Smith, you take Exit 4.
Have you got that?
Excuse me, who's in charge?
Sorry, awaiting orders, sir.
Right, here's the plan.
Like he said.
Nice plan. Anything else?
-Present arms.
-Ready.
-Speed dial?
-Yeah.
-Ready.
-Check.
See you in hell.
Hello, I've come to
see the Lord Mayor.
Have you got an appointment?
No, just an old friend passing by,
bit of a surprise.
Can't wait to see her face.
Well, she's just
having a cup of tea.
Just go in there and tell her
the Doctor would like to see her.
Doctor who?
Just the Doctor.
Tell her exactly that, the Doctor.
Hang on a tick.
(CUP SHATTERING)
The Lord Mayor says thank you
for popping by.
She'd love to have a chat
but she's up to her eyes in paperwork.
Perhaps if you could make an appointment
for next week?
She's climbing out of
the window, isn't she?
Yes, she is.
-Slitheen heading north.
-On my way.
Over and out.
Oh, my God!
Leave the Mayor alone!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Margaret!
-Who's on Exit 47
-That was Mickey!
-Here I am.
-Mickey the idiot.
Be fair, she's not exactly
gonna outrun us, is she?
She's got a teleport! That's cheating.
Now, we're never gonna get her!
The Doctor's very good at teleports.
I could do this all day.
This is persecution.
Why can't you leave me alone?
What did I ever do to you?
You tried to kill me
and destroy this entire planet.
Apart from that.
So, you're a Slitheen,
you're on Earth, you're trapped.
Your family get killed, but you teleport out,
just in the nick of time.
You have no means of escape,
what do you do?
You build a nuclear power station.
But what for?
A philanthropic gesture.
I've learned the error of my ways.
And it just so happens to be
right on top of the rift.
-What rift would that be?
-A rift in space and time.
If this power station went into meltdown,
the entire planet would go...
This station is designed to explode
the minute it reaches capacity.
Didn't anyone notice?
Isn't there someone in London
checking this sort of stuff?
We're in Cardiff.
London doesn't care.
The South Wales coast could
fall into the sea and they wouldn't notice.
Oh! I sound like a Welshman.
God help me, I've gone native.
But why would she do that?
A great big explosion,
she'd only end up killing herself.
-She's got a name, you know.
-She's not even a she, she's a thing.
Oh, but she's clever.
Fantastic!
Is that a tribophysical waveform
macro-kinetic extrapolator?
Couldn't have put it better myself.
Genius! You didn't build this?
I have my hobbies,
a little tinkering.
No, I mean, you really didn't build this.
Way beyond you.
-I bet she stole it.
-It fell into my hands.
-Is it a weapon?
-It's transport.
You see, if the reactor blows, the rift opens.
Phenomenal cosmic disaster.
But this thing shrouds you in a force-field.
You have this energy bubble...
So you're safe.
Then you feed it coordinates,
stand on top
and ride the concussion
all the way out of the solar system.
-It's a surfboard.
-A pan-dimensional surfboard, yeah.
And it would've worked.
I'd have surfed away from this dead-end dump
and back to civilisation.
You'd blow up a whole planet
just to get a lift?
Like stepping on an ant hill.
How did you think of the name?
What? Blaidd Drwg? It's Welsh.
I know,
but how did you think of it?
I chose it at random, that's all, I don't know.
Just sounded good.
Does it matter?
Blaidd Drwg.
-What's it mean?
-"Bad Wolf."
But I've heard that before. Bad Wolf.
I've heard that lots of times.
Everywhere we go,
two words, following us.
Bad Wolf.
How can they be following us?
No, just a coincidence.
Like hearing a word on the radio
then hearing it all day. Never mind.
Things to do. Margaret,
we're gonna take you home.
Hold on, isn't that the easy option?
Like letting her go?
I don't believe it,
we actually get to go to Rexi...
Wait a minute, Rexicor...
Rexicoricophalvitorius.
-Rexicorico...
-Phalvitorius.
-Rexicoricophalvitorius!
-That's it!
I did it!
They have the death penalty.
The family Slitheen was tried
in its absence many years ago
and found guilty.
With no chance of appeal.
According to the statutes of government,
the moment I return, I'm to be executed.
What do you make of that, Doctor?
Take me home and you
take me to my death.
Not my problem.
MARGARET: This ship is impossible!
It's superb!
How do you get the outside
around the inside?
Like I'd give you the secret, yeah.
I almost feel better
about being defeated.
I never stood a chance.
This is the technology of the gods.
Don't worship me,
I'd make a very bad god.
You wouldn't get
a day off, for starters.
Jack, how we doing, big fella?
This extrapolator's top of the range.
Where did you get it?
I don't know,
some airlock sale.
Must've been a great, big heist.
It's stacked with power.
-But we can use it for fuel?
-It's not compatible.
But it should knock
off about 12 hours.
We'll be ready to go
by morning.
Then we're stuck here, overnight.
I'm in no hurry.
ROSE: We've got a prisoner.
The police box is really a police box.
You're not just police, though.
Since you're taking me to my death,
that makes you my executioners.
Each and every one of you.
You deserve it.
You're very quick to say so.
And you're very quick
to soak your hands in my blood.
Which makes you
better than me how, exactly?
Long night ahead.
Let's see who can
look me in the eye.
It's freezing out here.
Better than in there.
She does deserve it,
she's a Slitheen, I don't care.
It's just weird in that box.
I didn't really need my passport.
I've been thinking, you know,
we could go have a drink.
Have a pizza or something,
just you and me.
That'd be nice.
And, I mean, if the Tardis
can't leave until morning...
We could go to a hotel.
Spend the night.
I mean, if you want to.
I've got some money.
Okay, yeah.
-Is that all right?
-Yeah.
Cool, there's a couple of bars round here,
we should give them a go.
Do you have to go and tell him?
It's none of his business.
So, what's on?
Nothing, just...
I gather it's not always like this.
Having to wait.
I bet you're always
the first to leave, Doctor.
Never mind the consequences,
off you go.
You butchered my family and then
ran for the stars, am I right?
But not this time.
At last, you have consequences.
-How does it feel?
-I didn't butcher them.
Don't answer back,
that's what she wants.
I didn't. What about you?
You had an emergency teleport,
you didn't zap them to safety, did you?
It only carries one.
I had to fly without coordinates.
I ended up in a skip
on the Isle of Dogs.
(DOCTOR LAUGHING)
-It wasn't funny.
-Sorry.
It is a bit funny.
Do I get a last request?
Depends what it is.
I grew quite fond of
my little human life.
All those rituals.
The brushing of the teeth
and the complicated way they cook things.
There's a little restaurant,
just round the Bay.
It became quite a favourite of mine.
-Is that what you want? A last meal?
-Don't I have rights?
Like she's not gonna try to escape.
Except I can never escape the Doctor
so where's the danger?
I wonder if you could do it.
To sit with a creature you're about to kill
and take supper.
-How strong is your stomach?
-Strong enough.
I wonder.
I've seen you fight your enemies.
Now dine with them.
-You won't change my mind.
-Prove it.
There are people out there.
If you slip away just for one second,
they'll be in danger.
Except, I've got these.
You both wear one.
If she moves more
than ten feet away...
She gets zapped
by 10,000 volts.
Margaret, would you like to come out
to dinner? My treat.
Dinner in bondage.
Works for me.
Here we are, out on a date,
and you haven't even asked my proper name.
It's not a date.
-What's your name?
-Blon.
I'm Blon Fel Fotch
Passameer-Day Slitheen.
That's what it'll say
on my death certificate.
-Nice to meet you, Blon.
-I'm sure.
Look, that's where I
was living as Margaret.
Nice little flat,
over there on the top.
Next to the one with the light on.
Two bedrooms, bay side view.
I was rather content.
Don't suppose I'll see it again.
Suppose not.
-Thank you.
-Pleasure.
Tell me, then, Doctor,
what do you know of our species?
Only what I've seen.
Did you know, for example,
in extreme cases,
when her life is in danger,
a female Rexicoricophalvitorian
can manufacture a poison dart
within her own finger.
Yes, I did.
Just checking.
And one more thing.
Between you and me...
WHISPERING: As a final resort, the excess
poison can be exhaled through the lungs.
That's better.
Now then, what do you think?
Steak looks nice.
Steak and chips!
ROSE: The Doctor took me
to this planet a while back.
It was much colder than this.
They called it Woman Wept.
The planet was
actually called Woman Wept
because if you looked at it,
right, from above,
it was like this huge continent,
like, all curved round.
It sort of looked like a woman,
you know, lamenting.
Oh, my God,
and we went to this beach, right.
No people, no buildings,
just this beach,
like, 1,000 miles across.
And something happened,
something to do with the sun, I don't know,
but the sea had just frozen.
In a split second.
In the middle of a storm, right,
waves and foam, just frozen,
all the way out to the horizon.
Midnight, right, we walk
underneath these waves,
100 feet tall and made of ice.
I'm going out
with Trisha Delaney.
Oh, right.
That's nice.
-Trisha from the shop?
-Yeah, Rob Delaney's sister.
Well, she's nice.
-She's a bit big.
-She lost weight.
You've been away.
Well, good for you.
She's nice.
-So, tell us more about this planet, then.
-That was it, really.
Public execution is a slow death.
They prepare a thin acetic acid,
lower me into the cauldron...
and boil me.
The acidity is perfectly gauged
to strip away the skin.
Internal organs fall out into the liquid
and I become soup.
And still alive.
Still screaming.
-I don't make the law.
-But you deliver it.
Will you stay to watch?
What else can I do?
The Slitheen family's huge.
There's a lot more of us,
all scattered off-world. Take me to them.
Take me somewhere safe.
-But then you'll just start again.
-I promise I won't.
You've been in that skin suit too long.
You've forgotten.
There used to be a real Margaret Blaine.
You killed her and stripped her
and used the skin.
You're pleading for mercy
out of a dead woman's lips.
Perhaps I have got used to it.
A human life, an ordinary life.
That's all I'm asking.
Give me a chance, Doctor.
-I can change.
-I don't believe you.
-So, what do you want to do now?
-Don't mind.
We could ask about hotels.
What would Trisha Delaney say?
I suppose.
There's a bar down there
with a Spanish name...
You don't even
like Trisha Delaney!
Is that right?
What the hell do you know?
I know you and I know her
and I know that's
never gonna happen.
-So, who do you think you're kidding?
-At least I know where she is!
There we are, then.
It's got nothing to do with Trisha.
This is all about me, isn't it?
You left me!
We were nice, we were happy.
And then what?
You give me a kiss and run off with him
and you make me feel like nothing, Rose.
I was nothing!
I can't even go out
with a stupid girl from a shop
because you pick up the phone
and I comes running.
I mean, is that what I am, Rose, standby?
Am I just supposed to sit here
for the rest of my life waiting for you?
-Because I will.
-I'm sorry.
I promise you I've changed
since we last met, Doctor.
There was this girl, just today.
Young thing.
And something of a danger.
She was getting too close.
I felt the blood lust rising,
just as the family taught me.
I was going to kill her without a thought.
And then...
I stopped.
She's alive somewhere,
right now.
She's walking round this city
because I can change.
I did change.
-I know I can't prove it.
-I believe you.
Then you know I'm capable of better.
It doesn't mean anything.
I spared her life.
You let one of them go.
But that's nothing new.
Every now and then
a little victim's spared.
Because she smiled.
Because he's got freckles.
Because they begged.
And that's how you live with yourself.
That's how you slaughter millions.
Because once in a while, on a whim,
if the wind's in the right direction...
you happen to be kind.
Only a killer would know that.
Is that right?
From what I've seen,
your funny little happy-go-lucky life
leaves devastation in its wake.
Always moving on
because you dare not go back.
Playing with so many people's lives,
you might as well be a god.
And you're right, Doctor.
You're absolutely right.
Sometimes, you let one go.
Let me go.
I'm not asking you to leave him
because I know that's not fair.
But I just need something,
yeah, some sort of promise
that when you do come back,
you're coming back for me.
(RUMBLING)
-Is that thunder?
-Does it matter?
That's not thunder.
In the family Slitheen,
we had no choice.
I was made to carry out my first kill at 13.
If I'd refused, my father would have fed me
to the Venom Grubs.
If I'm a killer, it's because I was born to kill.
It's all I know.
(RUMBLING)
Doctor, are you even listening to me?
-Can you hear that?
-I'm begging for my life.
No, listen, shush.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Go on, then, run.
It's him again, isn't it? It's the Doctor.
It's always the Doctor.
It's always gonna be the Doctor.
It's never me!
The handcuffs!
-Don't think you're running away.
-I'm sticking with you.
Some date this
turned out to be!
It's the rift.
The rift's opening.
DOCTOR: What the hell are you doing?
JACK: It just went crazy!
It's the rift. Time and
space are ripping apart.
The whole city's
going to disappear.
(CRASHING)
It's the extrapolator.
I've disconnected it,
but it's still feeding off the engine.
It's using the Tardis,
I can't stop it.
Never mind Cardiff,
it's gonna rip open the planet!
What is it? What's happening?
Just little me.
One wrong move
and she snaps like a promise.
I might have known.
I've had you bleating
all night, poor baby.
Now, shut it.
You, fly boy.
Put the extrapolator at my feet.
Thank you.
Just as I planned.
I thought you needed to blow up
the nuclear power station.
Failing that,
if I were to be arrested,
then anyone capable
of tracking me down
would have considerable technology
of their own.
Therefore, they would be
captivated by the extrapolator.
Especially a magpie-mind
like yours, Doctor.
So, the extrapolator was programmed
to go to Plan B.
To lock on to the nearest alien power source
and open the rift.
And what a power source it found.
I'm back on schedule.
Thanks to you.
The rift's gonna convulse,
you'll destroy the whole planet.
And you with it.
While I ride this board
over the crest of the inferno,
all the way to freedom.
Stand back, boys.
Surf's up.
Of course, opening the rift
means you'll pull this ship apart.
So sue me.
It's not just any old power source.
It's the Tardis, my Tardis.
The best ship in the universe.
It'll make wonderful scrap.
-What's that light?
-The heart of the Tardis.
This ship's alive.
You've opened its soul.
It's...so bright.
Look at it, Margaret.
Beautiful.
Look inside, Blon Fel Fotch.
Look at the light.
Thank you.
Don't look,
stay there, close your eyes!
Now, Jack, come on, shut it all down.
Shut down.
Rose, that panel over there,
turn all switches to the right.
DOCTOR: Nicely done.
Thank you, all.
ROSE: What happened to Margaret?
JACK: Must've got burned up.
Carried out her own death sentence.
No, I don't think she's dead.
Then where'd she go?
She looked into the heart of the Tardis.
Even I don't know how strong that is.
And the ship's telepathic,
like I told you, Rose.
Gets inside your head,
translates alien languages.
Maybe the raw energy can translate
all sorts of thoughts.
-Here she is.
-She's an egg?
-Regressed to her childhood.
She can start again.
Live her life from scratch.
If we take her home,
give her to a different family,
tell them to bring her up properly,
she might be all right.
-Or she might be worse.
-That's her choice.
-She's an egg.
Oh, my God, Mickey.
We're all powered up, we can leave.
Opening the rift filled us up with energy.
-We can go. If that's all right.
-Yeah, fine.
-How's Mickey?
-He's okay. He's gone.
Do you want to go and find him? We'll wait.
No need. He deserves better.
Off we go, then.
Always moving on.
Next stop, Rexicoricophalvitorius.
Now, you don't often get to say that.
We'll stop by and pop her in the hatchery.
Margaret the Slitheen can live her life again.
A second chance.
That'd be nice.
(WHOOSHING)
You got chosen, you're a housemate.
You're in the house,
isn't that brilliant?
Welcome to the Weakest Link.
We are giving you
a brand-new image.
Why? Is there something wrong
with what I'm wearing?
-What was that?
-She's been evicted.
This isn't just a game.
I need to find the Doctor,
he's here somewhere, he's always here!
There's something else going on.
MAN: We have contestants
outside the games.
My Masters,
they fear the Doctor.
Tell me, who are they?
That's impossible,
I know those ships, they were destroyed.
Obviously they survived.
Alert. Alert. We are detected.