BOY: Judy!
-Judy, what are you doing? Come on!
-JUDY: I want to hear the music.
You're going to get me in trouble.
Everyone knows
there are ghosts in the hill.
Wait! You'll hear it in a minute.
That's ghosts.
If you stay out here,
listening to ghosts,
they will come out
of the hill and eat you.
-They won't.
-They will.
And I'll get the blame. Now, come on.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I can hear it.
Judy, no!
(VOICE WHISPERING)
Judy!
CROW: (CAWING) Doc-tor.
Doctor. Doctor. Doctor. Doctor.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
NARDOLE: (SIGHS) Where are we now?
BILL: Aberdeen. Scotland.
Second century AD.
THE DOCTOR: You weren't complaining
when it was Mars, were you?
So why is Scotland suddenly
more important than guarding the vault
and keeping your sacred oath?
She thinks she knows
more about Romans than me.
Oh, that's explained everything,
thank you.
You don't know more about
the Ninth Legion than me. You don't!
I read the book. I loved the book.
I read everything...
They disappeared.
Except they didn't.
THE DOCTOR:
They were annihilated in battle.
Then where's the big pile of bodies?
-Oh, I don't know.
-So where's the Ninth Legion?
If they'd left,
they should still be leaving.
Can you see 5,000 Roman soldiers
marching south?
-Mmm.
-BILL: Down there.
By the river.
They'd have followed the river.
That's what they did.
So much that you don't understand
about Roman Britain...
I got an A star.
-Ooh, got an A star!
-I've lived in Roman Britain.
Governed. Farmed. Juggled.
Speaking as a former vestal virgin,
second class, I can assure you...
I bet you there is a Roman legion
down there.
Hang on! What, what, second class?
Fine, you go and check the river,
I'll go and find their last battlefield.
Fine. I'll meet you back here
with a Roman soldier.
Yeah, but seriously, second class?
Yeah, it's a long story. Come on.
WOMAN: We honour you, Mother.
(SOBS) We honour you.
We honour all our dead.
I honour you, Father.
I honour you, Mother.
I honour you, Mother. (KISSES)
I honour all our dead.
(TWIG CRACKS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Oh!
THE DOCTOR: 5,000 Roman soldiers.
Eyes peeled. They must have left
some kind of mark on the landscape.
Burning huts, slaughtered locals,
sweetie wrappers...
CROW: (CAWING) Dark!
Dark! Dark!
Doctor!
-CROW: (CAWING) Doc. Doc-tor.
-Look!
A stone cairn. Pictish civilisation.
NARDOLE: The bird!
-What about it?
-He said, "Dark."
Yes, well, that's why we're hurrying,
because there's not much light
at this time of day.
But it talked.
Well, of course it did.
It's a crow. All crows talk.
-Well, they don't talk in the future.
-Course they do.
Human beings just stopped having
intelligent conversations with them.
-And they all took a bit of a huff.
-Crows in the future are all in a huff?
Course they are. Haven't you noticed
that noise they make?
It's like a mass sulk. Come on!
The sooner we get there,
the sooner we'll know the answer.
-NARDOLE: Yeah. I know, but...
-(CROWS CAWING)
THE DOCTOR:
Picts, early Celts, loved stone cairns.
They built them under the ground,
but close to the sky.
They think they're doors between worlds.
Iron Age churches.
-What do you always find near churches?
-Women in hats.
Exactly! Human settlement.
It's a little bit damp, though,
isn't it?
It's Scotland. It's supposed to be damp.
BILL: Oh! A Roman soldier!
Ah, I wish I'd studied Latin
so you could understand me.
I understand you.
Sorry, what?
But, you're...
But you're speaking English.
What's English?
What you're speaking in.
You're speaking Latin.
(LAUGHS) I'm not.
That's Latin.
You just said that in Latin.
Ha! It's The Doctor.
Or the TARDIS. Or both.
Something telepathic.
Link. Auto-translate.
That's why everyone in this place
speaks English.
What on Earth are you talking about?
Oh, my God. It even does lip-sync.
Who are you?
I'm Bill.
Are you from the Ninth Legion?
Yes.
Yes! Where have you been?
Don't you know?
Know what?
Did you see what happened to us?
It's as if his bones have disintegrated.
Oh!
What could do that?
Complete and total absence
of any kind of sunlight.
Huh. Death by Scotland. (CHUCKLES)
-No.
It should take decades.
This happened a short while ago.
This is alien.
Right.
Good-o!
Question is, where are the rest of them?
(GROANS) Just wanna go back to bed.
THE DOCTOR: There they are.
The Ninth Legion.
They're a big pile of bodies.
Not always fun to be right.
This wasn't long ago.
Whatever did this, is close by.
We need to find Bill.
Don't move! Stay where you are!
(GASPS)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
SOLDIER: The barbarians
dug these traps everywhere.
(GRUNTS)
-(SNARLS)
-BILL: What was that?
SOLDIER: It's what slaughtered
the Ninth.
Can you see it?
Attacked us with a thing. A monster.
There's nothing here.
I've got to get back to the others.
You said they were wiped out.
There were survivors. A handful.
I can't leave them.
Of course not.
We found a hiding place.
We might still be safe there.
BILL: So what was it like, this monster?
SOLDIER: I don't know.
But we deserted.
We were the ones who couldn't face it.
Roman soldiers don't run.
And we did.
What?
(BRANCHES CRACKING)
(ROARING)
SOLDIER: They're underground.
By the river,
there's a carving of a fish.
Was that it? The monster?
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
(PANTING)
(ROARING)
(LOUD ROARING)
Ah!
Block the entrance! Quickly!
Hurry up!
(GRUNTS)
MAN 1: How long will that hold?
MAN 2: Not for long.
Ah!
Now bring her through.
Where we can have a better look at her.
SOLDIER: You do realise the beast
now knows where we are.
-You're not one of the barbarians?
-No.
So...
-You are the Ninth Legion!
-We are what's left.
Simon should be back.
SOLDIER 1: He was looking for the road.
Our route south, did you see him?
-Yeah.
-Well, where is he?
I'm sorry, the creature killed him.
What is it, that thing?
Where did it come from?
Killed him?
Yeah, he was covered
in this like, black slime.
SOLDIER 2: It knows where we are.
We'll all die here in the dark.
No one is going to die.
THE DOCTOR: Oh, for heaven's sake,
how long are you going to keep us here?
Couldn't we have seats?
What about the Wi-Fi code,
how about that?
MAN: Don't move! Don't speak.
Kar will be here soon.
-Who's Kar?
-The keeper of the gate.
My sister.
Well, let's hope
she's the brains of the family.
Because there's a big bad wolf
of a monster out there,
and you live in a house of sticks.
Nice, here, isn't it? Yeah, yeah,
I like what you've done
with the place, yeah.
Yeah, would you like some popcorn?
Won't take me a jiffy to make.
What are you doing?
-I'm ingratiating myself.
-Stop it, it's nauseating.
It's called charm.
I'm against it.
-I'm against charm.
-Yeah, we all know that.
I said don't move!
-I'm rooted.
-Shh!
Does anybody hear that?
Do you know what that sound was?
What?
That was the sound of my patience
shattering into a billion little pieces.
Now, there are only two things
that I need to know.
Where is my friend
and what destroyed the Roman army?
-(DOOR OPENS)
-I destroyed the Roman army.
Really? What, you? Just on your own?
That's quite a trick.
I'm the gatekeeper.
Gatekeeper? What gate?
Didn't you hear the call?
Where were you?
I had to find the gatekeeper's things.
Sorry, wait a minute,
are you the mighty warrior
that we've all been waiting for?
Where are all the grown-ups?
There was a great battle.
A great battle and we beat the Romans!
Kar beat them, that's all that matters.
Yes, but she's not a warrior,
she's an embryo.
What did you do?
Throw your action figures at them?
Listen, Roman.
We're not Roman.
We're not part of the Roman army.
No, we're not even slightly Italian.
I mean, I do a mean Spag Bol...
Let me tell you about the Romans!
They are the robbers of this world.
When they've thieved everything on land,
they'll rob the sea.
If their enemies are rich,
they'll take all they have.
If their enemies are poor,
they'll make slaves of them.
Their work is robbery,
slaughter, plunder.
They do this work
and they call it empire.
They make deserts
and they call it peace.
Yeah, but you gotta love
the indoor toilets, yeah?
They're not conquerors, they're cowards.
They're also all dead.
There's an awful lot
of dead cowards out there.
And I don't believe
that you killed them.
Because the thing is,
you said gate,
you called yourself gatekeeper,
and you mentioned gate weapons,
so I've got to wonder
what kind of a gate is that
and what's on the other side.
-And yes, you're absolutely right.
-Right?
I am extremely quick.
Listen, you are all very, very angry.
But really, you're just very scared.
But for now, would you mind awfully
all just jumping out of your skins,
and allowing Nardole and I
to escape in the confusion?
Who are you?
Let me explain.
-(EXPLODING)
-(SCREAMING)
(LOUD ROARING)
CROW: (CAWING) Monster!
NARDOLE: We're looking for Bill, right?
No, we're looking for the maximum danger
in the immediate area,
and walking right into it.
Yeah, but what about Bill?
Well, if she's there, we're saving her.
If she's not, she's safe already.
Trust me, this is not my first rodeo.
Now, they think these cairns
are gateways between worlds.
Given that they
keep going on about gates.
And possibly, they're right.
(GASPS)
No...
WOMAN: The gate's opening.
-Your friend won't be coming back.
- (EXCLAIMS)
(RUMBLING)
(SNARLS)
NARDOLE: However, the human ship
was called the Mary Celeste.
Something like that. Anyway.
The Enzomadons assumed
that any species they encountered
would communicate as they did,
by digesting each other.
The Enzomadon ambassador got through
the whole crew,
and then very sadly
choked on a lifeboat.
So... You're back!
They said you would
probably never come back.
I was in there for seconds.
Two days.
It's an inter dimensional temporal rift.
A second in there
equates to days of time on this side.
I was in there for two days?
And eight hours, five minutes and...
That's good then, isn't it?
-Good?
-Plenty of time for you to find Bill.
Oh.
I looked. They helped me look.
How hard did you look?
I think we've lost her, Doctor.
No, no, no, no.
We just don't know where she is.
Not the same thing at all. Come on.
NARDOLE: I'll tell you
about the Lusitania later.
Oh, keep an eye out for Bill.
SOLDIER: You have to move again.
Stay in the sunlight.
It burns off the slime.
Here.
-Thanks.
-No problem.
Are you hungry?
Come on, you have to eat.
-How much food have we got left?
-Enough.
Really?
Shut up, Cornelius.
Go on, eat it.
It's two days, you haven't had anything.
I've never been lost this long.
-I need to find him.
-Who?
The Doctor. My friend.
I don't know what I'm going to do
if I can't find him.
Well, we will look after you.
I have to find my way home somehow.
This is the safest place to be.
The beast is still out there.
You came back.
-Did you know what was in there?
-The gate?
A portal between dimensions.
Do you know what's on the other side?
Oh, you don't know anything, do you?
You just stand around making speeches
and waving a TV aerial about.
Shall I tell you what's in there?
No. It's called the eater of light
and we held it back.
Every generation,
a new warrior went into the gate
and fought the eater of light
so it couldn't break through.
But the creature did break through.
It broke through
and it destroyed the whole Ninth Legion.
It's weak, it's nearly dead,
it will die soon.
Well, let's hope so.
Because there are millions more,
just like it, on the other side.
And very soon, all of them
will find their way
through to this dimension.
Then I'll hold them back.
You'll hold them back?
What, with your lollipop
and your kitty face paint?
And your crazy,
novelty monster killing tool?
Are you holding that thing
the right way up by the way?
I don't want your help!
But I'm all you've got.
Believe me, I'm on your side.
(SCREAMING)
Come on, let's go!
SOLDIER: We're all in this together.
You're going to be fine.
Marcus was hurt, like you,
and the sunlight healed him in the end.
-I am feeling better.
-Good.
Yeah, don't worry, Bill.
Lucius will look after you.
Shut up, Cornelius!
Uh...
Lucius...
Right, listen, there's
something I should explain.
What?
This is probably
just a really difficult idea.
I don't like men. That way.
What, not ever?
Nah, not ever.
-Only women.
-Oh.
All right, yeah, I got it.
You're like Vitus, then?
-What?
-He only likes men.
Some men.
Better looking men than you, Lucius.
-(LAUGHS)
-I don't think it's narrow-minded.
I think it's fine.
You know what you like.
And you like both?
I'm just ordinary.
You know, like men and women.
(LAUGHS) Well,
isn't this all very modern?
Hey, not everyone has to be modern.
I think it's really sweet
that you're so restricted.
-Cheers.
-We can be friends, though.
You know, I did save your life,
that means we're friends forever.
(LAUGHS) Yeah, I can deal with that.
(SUDDEN NOISE)
-Why is it going dark?
-The sun is setting.
Nah, it's the beast. It's circling us.
It's looking for a way in.
It's getting stronger again.
Strong enough to feed.
Every hour of sunlight that feeds it
makes the world darker,
and the beast stronger.
We've got very little time.
I have to stop it. This is my fault.
I'm the keeper of the gate.
I have to put this right.
THE DOCTOR:
So, you were supposed to guard the gate
while everyone else went off to war.
But, you had strangers at the door
and a guard dog in the attic,
so you let the beast come through.
It was the only thing
that would defeat them.
So you thought the eater of light
could destroy a whole Roman army?
It did.
And a whole Roman army
could weaken or kill the beast?
-Yes.
-Well, it didn't work.
You got a whole
Roman legion slaughtered,
and you made the deadliest creature
on this planet very, very cross indeed.
To protect a muddy little hillside,
you doomed your whole world.
One man?
You think one man can save us all?
Come and meet him.
He came here to meet you.
He's met loads of people like you,
they're terrified, they're desperate.
And he always helps.
He always makes a difference.
LUCIUS: There are
painted barbarians out there.
They outnumber us.
There is a beast of darkness
that laid waste
to an entire legion
in less than an hour.
No one man
can make a difference to that.
Maybe that's what you don't learn
when you think it takes
5,000 highly trained soldiers
to slaughter
a bunch of Scottish farmers.
Yes, one man can.
And he's here.
If you're calling us cowards, carry on.
We already ran away. We know.
You're not cowards.
You're scared.
Scared is fine.
Scared is human.
I'll tell you what it isn't.
It isn't a plan.
She's right.
Why are you even
listening to her, Grandad?
Because no-one else is saying anything.
We need a plan.
A real commander would have a plan.
Why do they call you Grandad?
They always call me Grandad.
I'm the commander.
I'm the oldest one left.
How old are you?
Eighteen.
Right, listen to me. All of you.
I'm going up there to find my friend.
And if you come with me...
I can't promise that you won't all die.
But I can promise you this.
You won't all die
in a hole in the ground.
THE DOCTOR:
We have to drive it back through
and close the portal behind it.
Now the gate only opens
when the dawn sun hits it. Why is that?
Our ancestors couldn't
close the gate completely.
But they built the cairn to control it.
Ah, like venting an oil gush?
If they let the portal open
a few moments every year,
they stop the whole thing ripping apart.
Yeah, it's quite clever, really.
Are you sulking?
I'm remembering the dead.
Ah, all right.
Well, save that for old age.
They're dead because of me.
You know, every moment you waste
wallowing about in that happy thought,
means more of the living
are going to join them.
When you want to win a war,
remember this.
It's not about you.
Believe me, I know.
Time to grow up.
Time to fight your fight.
How does this work?
It poisons the light
as the beast eats it.
Good.
We'll need more of this.
It has optical cancellation properties.
Now, we have one chance.
Right now, it's weak,
it's injured, it's starving.
But when the sun comes up,
it will feed and grow strong.
We have to lure it back
through the portal
before that happens, before sunrise.
Now, I've got a plan.
But I need your help.
But I'm afraid.
Who isn't?
But you've still got to
face your beast, anyway.
Can you do that?
Aye.
-(WHOOSHING)
-Shh!
LUCIUS: (WHISPERING) It's nothing.
It's the wind in the rocks.
Forward, centurion. Keep going.
There are lots of entrances
the beast could get through.
It's a labyrinth.
(WIND HOWLING)
This is where we hear them.
Barbarians. Right up there.
Up above us.
Are you sure
your friend will be with them?
Yeah.
Basically, he always ends up
being boss of the locals.
-How?
-Usually by knowing them.
(GROWLING)
What was that?
LUCIUS: All right, centurions.
Stay sharp.
-That's the way out, so let's get out.
-Easy, Cornelius.
Let's make sure we know
what we're walking into.
No, let's go.
(PANICKED ARGUING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAM)
Come quickly!
Douse the fire, quickly!
(FIRE HISSES OUT)
Shift your arse, Roman!
Close the trap door.
Block it off. We have to block it off.
Centurions! Defence formation.
It's fallen back. It's waiting.
It's waiting to feed off the sunlight,
to grow to its full strength.
-Hello.
-Hi.
I brought you the Ninth Legion.
THE DOCTOR: Oh, there they are.
The lost legion of the Ninth.
Totally found them.
Yeah, you totally did.
BILL: Nardole!
-What happened to you?
-Oh, I'm blending in.
(SCOTTISH ACCENT) Hmm.
Welcome to our land.
(CHUCKLES) Scotch.
Drop your weapons.
Oh, for goodness sake,
we don't have time for this!
-Stay back!
-Lucius, stop it!
Are you their champion now?
-There is no time for fighting.
-Exactly.
We never wanted to fight!
We lived in peace and then you came.
And laid waste to everything
and everyone we loved.
All you understand is war.
No, he understands.
Don't you?
Now he's wondering why.
You speak Latin?
I don't.
Neither do I. Not a word.
BILL: And I don't speak
whatever they speak either.
It's him.
It's you, isn't it?
Yes, it's me.
Something to do with the TARDIS, maybe?
Telepathic field?
So now that we all understand
each other, how do we all sound?
You sound like children.
-You sound like children, too.
-You all do.
BILL: This is what happens.
You can understand what everyone
in the universe is saying.
Everybody just sounds like children.
There are exceptions.
-Thank you very much.
-THE DOCTOR: Not you.
Okay, kids, pay attention.
She slaughtered your legion,
you slaughtered
everything that she loves.
Now, you all have a choice,
you can carry on
slaughtering each other,
till no one is left standing,
or you grow the hell up!
Because there's a new war now.
I think these creatures
are light-eating locusts,
looking for rents and cracks
between worlds to let themselves
into dimensions of light.
Once they break through,
they eat.
They will eat the sun.
And then, they will eat the stars.
And they will keep eating until...
There are no stars left.
So, whose side are you on, now?
Because as far as I can see,
there is only one side left.
If it helps,
I do have a plan.
THE DOCTOR: It feeds on light,
but it homes in on sound.
BILL: So, what's going to happen?
It's simple. Bit of noise,
lure the beast here,
drive it back through the gate.
But how do we keep it there?
I mean, you said all those things
are going to come through, right?
Well, they can only come through
one at a time.
-I know.
-That's why guarding the gate worked.
One Pict in there,
fighting it off for a few minutes.
That adds up to 60 or 70 years out here.
I get it, yeah,
and then the next one goes in.
But what are we going to do this time?
Or are you going to line up Picts
sacrificing themselves
until the end of the world?
I've got a better idea this time.
Which is the part you never tell me!
-Don't I?
-Uh-uh.
I'll probably just get interrupted.
(LAUGHING AND BAGPIPE MUSIC)
This is worse than jazz.
-Nothing. There's nothing.
-Hmm.
Maybe it won't come.
-Hello.
-(CAWS)
CROW: (CAWING) Hello.
Hello.
CROW: (CAWING) Doctor.
No, no, Nardole.
Yeah, it's probably a bit tricky
for you, that, innit?
(CAWS)
Huh! Lovely! (CHUCKLES) Hello.
-CROW: (CAWING) Monster!
-Sorry?
(CAWS) Monster!
(SNARLING)
There!
(ROARING)
Oh!
-It's coming.
-It's here.
Get ready!
Turn on the light!
(ROARING)
THE DOCTOR: Keep it here.
We've got to hold it here till sunrise.
Ah!
Keep it there!
(GRUNTING)
THE DOCTOR: Turn her! The sun is rising!
Back! Back to the void!
It'll only stay open as long as
the sunlight's on it.
Give me your weapon.
What are you doing?
-THE DOCTOR: This is the clever bit.
-Well, tell me.
The gate has to be guarded.
There's no other way.
The trouble is, human lifespans.
They're tiny.
They're hilarious.
You get used up too quickly.
So what's the answer?
Go on, figure it out.
The answer is me. I go on for ages.
I don't even really die, I regenerate.
I can hold that gate
until the sun goes out.
-No, you can't.
-Of course, I can. I'm going to.
This isn't your job.
No it isn't, Bill. It's who I am.
I've been standing
by the gates of your world,
keeping you all safe
since you crawled out of the slime.
-I'm not stopping now.
-Doctor, please!
Listen, the TARDIS will take you home.
-Return journeys are easy.
-Listen to me.
Leave the instruments
on the current setting.
Just hit them with a spanner.
Weapon, now.
-No.
-Give it to me, come on.
You'll be safe.
Tomorrow, you'll be farming.
And you can name a cow after me.
What about the other gates
that you have to guard?
What about the vault?
The vault will never exist
if I let those things come through!
Well, then somebody else
better stop them!
-Nobody else can.
-I can!
What did you say?
Time to grow up, Doctor.
Time to fight my fight.
(ROARS)
I'm sorry, no. No one else can do this.
Not like I can.
We can. I'm ready.
I'll guard the gate with you.
I'll fight by your side.
Awesome. Brilliant.
You'll be a hero for two seconds.
Then the whole solar system
will be devoured.
Stop him!
This is my destiny, my fight!
Out of my way! Now!
-We'll take it in turns.
-The two of you can't hold the gate.
Two of them? I'm counting more than two.
The Legion of the Ninth
stands ready to serve.
Oh, stop being brave.
I can't bear brave people.
I'll put the story in the stone.
I'll put your name in the air.
They'll see it for hundreds of years
and they'll know your name forever.
Good!
Ready?
No, listen to me. No! Listen...
BILL: You're wrong, Doctor.
It's their destiny.
Not yours.
NARDOLE: Sorry, you're going nowhere.
-THE DOCTOR: Bill! Bill, stop it!
-Quickly. Quickly.
Soldiers of the Ninth! Advance!
Come on!
(SHOUTING)
(BAGPIPES PLAYING)
(LOUD CRASHING)
What's that?
What's happening?
Too many of them going through at once.
This place is unstable.
We need to get out of here! Now!
NARDOLE: Oh! Oh!
(BOTH PANTING)
(CAWING)
NARDOLE: I know you're inclined
to bear a grudge,
so just remember, I know
about 10% of your secrets,
the dark secrets,
and, I'm the only one in the TARDIS
who knows where the teacakes are.
-(CRIES) Kar.
-CROW: (CAWING) Kart!
She's holding the gate.
Remember, her name is Kar.
-CROW: (CAWING) Kar! Kar!
-Kar.
(CAWS)
You were wrong.
The crows aren't sulking.
-The crows are remembering.
-(CROW CAWS)
BILL: I'm sorry, Doctor,
but you have a vault to guard.
You can't take on every fight.
All right, I was wrong.
I didn't know what really happened
to the Ninth Legion.
No, we were both wrong about that.
They were never really missing.
They've always been here.
The Ninth Legion
and the keeper of the gate.
Seizing the day till the sun goes out.
Holding back the dark.
(BAGPIPES PLAYING FAINTLY)
What?
I thought... Did you hear that?
I thought I could hear the music,
but I can't, can I?
They're in another time.
Music's funny like that.
(CAWS)
Right.
Shall we go back home?
Time you were guarding that vault,
we don't want Missy getting any ideas.
MISSY: One should always
try to avoid those.
Hello! Well, you lot were ages,
I was getting ever so worried.
How did you get out of the vault?
Sir, what do we do?
How could this happen?
It's all right, Nardole,
she's been doing some work for me.
Sorry, I'm sorry, I'm so sorry,
I assumed they knew.
Should I have stayed below decks?
No. no, no, no, it's fine.
She's supposed to be in the vault!
How are the engines?
Better than you deserve.
You are naughty.
Do you ever do basic maintenance?
THE DOCTOR: No,
but I've got a plan for that.
-What?
-You.
What, seriously? What, what
she's doing chores for you now?
Sir, I must protest in the strongest,
most upset terms possible.
Don't make me go squeaky-voiced.
Do relax, you two.
I'm bio-locked out of the controls,
I can't even get through those doors.
I'm as much a prisoner here
as I am in the vault.
No, you most certainly are not.
Doctor, seriously.
Why did you let her out?
THE DOCTOR: I think you may be
forgetting how we got home from Mars.
What, so now you trust her?
No, so now he's getting
TARDIS maintenance for free.
Let's not get carried away.
THE DOCTOR: So what have you been up to?
Did you watch us?
-Some of it. A little bit.
-THE DOCTOR: What did you think?
-Oh, is she reviewing us now?
-MISSY: Oh, those little people.
Trapped in a hill fighting forever.
Is that really up to
your bleeding heart standards?
Well, they're not trapped.
And they're more than just fighting.
And there's music.
Always music.
Well, team.
Who's going to help me hide his guitar?
See, that's what I'm trying
to teach you, Missy.
You understand the universe.
You see it, you grasp it.
But you never learn to hear the music.
(BAGPIPES PLAYING FAINTLY)
(CHUCKLES)
Huh.
I don't even know why I'm crying.
Why do I keep doing that now?
I don't know.
Maybe you're trying to impress me.
Yes.
Probably some devious plan.
That sounds about right.
Well, the alternative
would be much worse.
Really?
The alternative
is that this is for real.
And it's time for us
to become friends again.
Do you think so?
I don't know.
That's the trouble with hope.
It's hard to resist.
THE DOCTOR: I pick a scenario.
We drop her down into it
and we see how she does.
Hello.
I am that mysterious adventurer
in all of time and space.
And these are my disposables.
Just promise you won't get me killed.
I said this was a bad idea.
THE DOCTOR: A 400-mile ship
reversing away from
the gravitational pull of a black hole.
I'm so sorry, but you're the reason
that they're coming.
NARDOLE: What are they?
A Mondasian Cyberman.
Give us a kiss.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)