(LIQUID DRIPPING)
BUZZER: Lights.
(CODE BEEPING, DOOR BUZZING)
JIMMY: Lights.
You know the drill, people.
Acid visors down and locked.
Buzzer.
-Reading of 9.7.
-JIMMY: Sounds a bit low for Unrefined.
JIMMY: How's the average?
JENNIFER: The acid potency stats
have definitely dropped below the mean
during the last quarter.
-Prettier than a computer, isn't she?
-Give over, Buzz.
Whoa!
Buzzer! Buzz!
Oh, great. Nice going, twinkle-toes.
I shouldn't have swung at him.
Sorry, Buzz. My bad.
No, you're all right. Jimmy?
Well, no point
carrying you back legless.
Sorry, Buzzer, you're dead.
Oh, this is a right pain in the arm our.
Heart's gone now.
Look, we'd best get off.
Got to write this one up for the boss.
-Those suits cost a bomb.
-(BUZZ GRUNTING)
If I miss my boy's birthday
filling out forms, I'll kill you again.
Lights.
JENNIFER: I'm looking at these readings,
Jimmy,
and the potency stats are way too low.
We may have to take that read again.
This thing is still jamming up on me.
So, uh, I think we'd better talk about
what just happened back there.
I could get compensation.
I've seen the holo-ads.
"Had an accident in the workplace?”
Yeah, I have, as it goes.
-I've melted.
-Let it go.
Look, just remember, when you're doing
your report, it wasn't my fault.
She took a swing at me.
I never touched you.
You've got two left feet, Buzzer.
I haven't got two left feet.
Or any arms, neck, head, the chin.
This body costs money, love.
Not as much as that acid suit.
Oh, lighten up.
It's not like anyone was hurt.
(ACID HISSING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Forty-six.
Rubbishy, rubbishy rubbish.
-Hello! It's a double-top.
-Wrong side of the wire, mister.
-You're on the oche, Red.
-I'm not. Stop trying to put me off.
Who wants fish and chips?
I'll drop you both off.
Take your time. Don't rush.
-Er...and you?
-Uh, things to do.
Things involving other things.
Well, we'll stay with you.
We'll do the other things.
Nope.
Whatever you're up to,
I'd personally like to be a part of it.
What?
(ALARM SOUNDING)
-(AMY SCREAMS)
-Whoa!
Solar tsunami.
Came directly from your sun.
A tidal wave of radiation.
Big, big, big!
-Uh, Doctor, my tummy's going funny.
-Well, the gyrator disconnected.
Target tracking is out.
(DOCTOR GRUNTING, AMY YELLING)
Assume the position!
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Textbook landing.
Behold! A cockerel!
Love a cockerel.
And underneath, a monastery,
uh, 13th century.
Oh, we've gone all medieval.
-I'm not sure about that.
-Really? Medieval expert, are you?
No, it's just that
I can hear Dusty Springfield.
# You don't have to say you love me
Just be close at hand
# You don't have to... #
These fissures are new.
Solar tsunami sent out
a huge wave of gamma particles.
This is caused by a magnetic quake
that occurs just before the wave hits.
-Well, the monastery's standing.
-Yeah, for now.
-Doctor, look.
-Yeah. It's a supply pipe.
Ceramic inner lining.
Something corrosive.
They're pumping something nasty
off this island to the mainland.
My mum's a massive fan
of Dusty Springfield.
Who isn't?
Right, let's go!
Satisfy our rabid curiosity.
# ...loneliness
# There's nothing left to feel
# You don't have to say... #
So, where are these
Dusty Springfield-loving monks, then?
I think we're here. This is it.
Doctor, what are you talking about?
We've never been here before.
-We came here by accident.
-Hmm? Accident?
-Yes, I know. Accident.
-Ah! Ow!
Acid. They're pumping acid
off this island.
That's old stuff.
Fresh acid, you wouldn't have a finger.
Hmm.
GUARD: Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
There are people coming. Well, almost.
-Almost coming?
-Almost people.
-I think we should really be going.
-AMY: Come on!
I am telling you,
when something runs toward you,
it's never for a nice reason. (GRUNTS)
-What are all these harnesses for?
-Uh, the "almost people"?
What are they, prisoners?
Or are they meditating, or what?
Well, at the moment
they fall into the "or what" category.
GUARD: Halt and remain calm.
Well, we've halted.
How are we all doing on the calm front?
Don't move!
Stay back, Jen.
We don't know who they are.
So let's ask them. Who the hell are you?
Well, I'm The Doctor
and this is Amy and Rory
and it's all very nice, isn't it?
Hold up. You're all...
What are you all, like identical twins?
This is an Alpha-grade
industrial facility.
Unless you work for the military
or for Morpeth Jetsan,
you are in big trouble.
Actually, you're in big trouble.
Meteorological Department? Since when?
-Since you were hit by a solar wave.
-Which we survived.
Just, by the look of it.
And there's a bigger one on the way.
Which we'll also survive.
Dicken, scan for bugs.
Backs against the wall. Now.
You're not a monastery,
you're a factory.
22nd century Army-owned factory.
You're Army?
No, love, we're contractors.
And you're trespassers.
It's clear, boss.
All right, weatherman,
your ID checks out.
If there's another solar storm,
what are you going to do about it?
Hand out sunblock?
(LAUGHS)
I need to see your critical systems.
Which one?
You know which one.
(BUBBLING)
And there you are.
Meet the government's
worst kept secret. The Flesh.
It's fully programmable matter.
In fact, it's even learning
to replicate itself
at the cellular level.
Right. Brilliant. Lost.
Okay.
Once a reading's been taken,
we can manipulate
its molecular structure into anything,
replicate a living organism down
to the hairs on its chinny chin chin.
Even clothes.
And everything's identical.
-Eyes, voice...
-Mind, soul.
Don't be fooled, Doctor,
it acts like life but it still needs
to be controlled by us,
from those harnesses you saw.
Wait, whoa, hold it.
So, you're Flesh now?
I'm lying in a harness
back in that chamber.
We all are, except Jennifer here.
Don't be scared. This thing,
just like operating a forklift truck.
You said it could grow.
Only living things grow.
Moss grows. It's no more than that.
This acid is so dangerous,
we were losing a worker every week.
So now we mine the acid
using these doppelgangers, or Gangers.
If these bodies get burnt
or fall in the acid...
Then who the hell cares? Right, Jen?
Nerve endings automatically cut off,
like airbags being discharged.
So we wake up and get a new Ganger.
It's weird but you get used to it.
Jennifer, I want you in your Ganger.
Get back to the harness.
-Hang on.
-What's he up to?
What are you up to, pal?
Stop it. Ah...
Strange, it was like for a moment there
it was scanning me.
(BUBBLING)
Doctor.
-Get back, Doctor, leave it alone!
-(GROANING)
(CRIES OUT) I understand.
Doctor?
-Are you all right?
-Incredible.
You have no idea. No idea.
I mean, I felt it in my mind.
I reached out to it and it to me.
Don't fiddle with the money, Doctor.
How can you be so blinkered?
It's alive. So alive.
You're piling your lives,
your personalities directly into it.
(STORM CRASHING)
It's the solar storm.
The first waves come in pairs.
Pre-shock and fore-shock. It's close.
Buzzer, we got anything
from the mainland yet?
No, the comms are still
too jammed with radiation.
Okay, then we'll keep pumping acid
until the mainland says stop.
Now, why don't you stand back
and let us impress you?
COMPUTER: ID confirmed. Jennifer Lucas.
The meter is running.
Cardio and respiratory, online.
Motor functions, online.
Plumbing in.
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(GROANING)
-(INHALES DEEPLY)
-Oh!
(EXHALES)
Well, I can see
why you keep it in a church.
-Miracle of life.
-No need to get poncy. It's just gunge.
Guys, we need to get to work.
Okay, everybody, let's crack on.
-(STORM CRASHING)
-DOCTOR: Did I mention the solar storm?
-You need to get out of here.
-Where do you want us to go?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
-We're on a tiny island.
-Well, I can get you all off it.
CLEAVES: Don't be ridiculous.
We've got a job to do.
It's coming.
That's the alarm.
-How do you get power?
-We're solar. We use a solar router.
-The weathervane.
-Big problem.
Boss, maybe if the storm's back,
we should get underground.
The factory's seen better days.
The acid pipes might not withstand
another hit.
We have 200 tons of acid to pump out.
We fall behind,
we stay another rotation.
-Anyone want that?
-Please.
You're making a massive mistake here.
You're right at the crossroads of it.
Don't turn the wrong way.
If you don't, if you don't
prepare for this storm,
you are all in terrible danger.
Understand?
My factory, my rules.
I need to check
the progress of the storm.
Monitoring station.
-Mmm.
-Monitoring station.
Three lefts, a right, and a left.
Third door on your left.
Thank you.
(ALARM SOUNDING, THUNDER CRASHING)
(GRUNTS) Waves disturbing
the Earth's magnetic field.
There is going to be the mother
and father of all power surges.
See this weathervane,
the cock-a-doodle-do?
It's a solar router feeding
the whole factory with solar power.
When that wave hits, kaboom!
I've got to get to that cockerel
before all hell breaks loose.
I never thought
I'd get to say that again.
(SIGHS) Amy, breathe.
Yeah. I mean, thanks, I'll try.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
(ACID HISSING)
(GRUNTING)
Er...
(SCREAMING)
Ow!
(GRUNTS)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Oh! For want of a better word, "Ow"!
Cleaves! You're not in your harness.
-I'm sorry, Doctor. You were right.
-You've lost all power to the factory.
-Doctor, I abandoned my team.
-Then let's go get them.
How long would you say
we were unconscious for, Cleaves?
Not long. A minute, two minutes?
I'd hazard we've been out
a teensy bit longer.
-Well, how long?
-An hour.
I've seen whole worlds turned inside-out
in an hour.
A lot can go wrong in an hour.
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTING)
I feel like I've been toasted.
-What the hell happened?
-The tsunami happened. You hurt?
It feels like the National Grid's run
through my bones, but apart from that...
I hope the meter's not bust.
I still want to get paid.
-Why...
-Jennifer!
-(WHIMPERING)
-Jennifer? Hey, all right.
-It hurt so much.
-Hey, it's okay. It's over.
-I couldn't get out of my harness.
-Shh, shh, shh.
I thought I was going to die.
Welcome to my world.
Doctor, these are all real people,
so where are their Gangers?
Don't worry. When the link shuts down,
the Gangers return to pure Flesh.
Now, the storm's left us
with acid leaks all over
so we need to contact the mainland.
They can have a rescue shuttle
out here in no time.
(YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY YOU LOVE ME
PLAYING)
That's my record.
Who's playing my record?
-Your Gangers, they've gone walkabout.
-No, it's impossible.
They're not active.
Cars don't fly themselves,
cranes don't lift themselves
and Gangers don't...
# When I said I needed you... #
-No way.
-I don't...
I... I don't believe this.
They could've escaped
through the service door at the back.
This is just like the Isle of Sheppey.
It would seem the storm
has animated your Gangers.
They've ransacked everything.
-Not ransacked. Searched.
-Through our stuff!
Their stuff.
-Searching for what?
-Confirmation.
They need to know
their memories are real.
Oh, so they've got flaming memories now?
They feel compelled
to connect to their lives.
-Their stolen lives.
-No. Bequeathed. You gave them this.
You poured in your personalities,
emotions, traits, memories,
secrets, everything.
You gave them your lives.
Human lives are amazing.
Are you surprised
they walked off with them?
I'll say it again, Isle of Sheppey.
Ganger got an electric shock,
toddled off, killed his operator
right there in his harness.
I've seen the photos.
-This bloke's ear was all hanging...
-Even if this has actually happened,
they can't remain stable
without us plumbed in to them.
Can they, boss?
Guess we'll find out.
-(GASPS)
-Are you okay?
-Do you need some water?
- I feel funny.
I need the washroom.
I'll come with you.
-(SNEEZES) Sorry.
-Oh. That's okay.
That's me. It's good to have a hobby.
So what?
My Ganger did that all on its own?
Who taught you to do this?
My granddad.
Well, your Ganger's granddad
taught him to do it, too.
You both have the same childhood
memories, just as clear, just as real.
-No.
-Scared, disorientated,
struggling to come to terms
with an entire life in their heads.
The Doctor's always saying,
"Don't wander off."
First rule with him, actually,
don't wander off.
I just need a minute.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Take all the time you need.
I've got your back. You're fine.
(GASPS)
Uh, Jennifer?
(GASPING)
-What, what's up, Jennifer?
-(DOOR CLOSING)
We, uh,
better get going.
Everything okay in there, Jen?
Just let us live! (GRUNTING)
We need to protect ourselves.
-Are you a violent man, Jimmy?
-No.
Then why would the other Jimmy be?
Tell me you can eat
at a time like this, Doctor.
You told me we were out cold
for a few minutes, Cleaves,
when in fact, it was an hour.
Sorry? I just assumed...
Well, it's not your fault.
Like I said, they're disorientated.
Amy, when you got to the alcoves,
who was in harness?
Um, Jimmy and Dicken
were helping Buzzer out.
Jennifer?
She was standing on her own
when we got to her.
-It's hot.
-(SUCKS BREATH IN) Uh.
Trans-matter's still a little rubbery.
Nerve endings not quite fused properly.
-What are you talking about?
-It's okay.
-Why didn't I feel that?
-You will.
You'll stabilise.
No. Stop it.
You're playing stupid games.
Stop it!
You don't have to hide.
Please, trust me, I'm the Doctor.
Where's the real Cleaves, you thing?
What have you done with her?
That's it. Good, you remember.
This is early Flesh. The early stages
of the technology. So much to learn.
-Doctor, what's happened to her?
-She can't stabilise,
she's shifting between half-formed
and full-formed. For now, at least.
We are living!
(SCREAMING)
-Let her go.
-Doctor, Rory.
-Rory?
-Rory!
Oh, Rory. Rory! Always with the Rory.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Explosion must've ruptured
the acid feeds.
We're going to need the acid suits.
No, no, no. We haven't got time.
Back, back, back!
JENNIFER: Rory!
Rory?
Rory!
Rory.
Of course, Jennifer's a Ganger, too.
Doctor, you said
they wouldn't be violent.
But I did say
they were scared and angry.
And early technology is what you said.
You seem to know something
about the Flesh.
Do you? Doctor?
You're no weatherman.
Why are you really here?
I have to talk to them. I can fix this.
Wait! What's going on?
Where's the real Jennifer?
(SHUDDERING)
It is too dangerous out here
with acid leaks.
We have to find Rory.
Yes, I'm going back to the Tardis.
Wait for me in the dining hall.
I want us to keep together, okay?
No more wandering off.
And what about Rory?
Well, it would be safer to look
for Rory and Jennifer with the Tardis.
Here we go.
Distress flares.
-Exit?
-Keep going straight. Can't miss it.
But you're never going to get
your vehicle in here.
I'm a great Parker.
Well, we really need those acid suits.
I've sent Buzzer and Dicken to get them.
Fine and dandy. I'm just going to
find my husband. So, cheers.
-Amy, I wouldn't.
-Nor would I.
What can you do, eh?
At least wait for an acid suit!
When I was a little girl,
I got lost on the moors,
wandered off from the picnic.
I can still feel how sore my toes
got inside my red welly boots.
And I imagined another little girl,
just like me, in red wellies.
And she was Jennifer, too.
Except she was a strong Jennifer,
a tough Jennifer.
She'd lead me home.
My name is Jennifer Lucas.
I'm not a factory part.
I had toast for my breakfast.
I wrote a letter to my mum.
And then you arrived.
I noticed your eyes right off.
Did you?
Nice eyes. Kind.
Where's the real Jennifer?
I am Jennifer Lucas!
I remember everything
that happened in her entire life.
Every birthday, every childhood illness.
I feel everything she has ever felt
and more.
I'm not a monster!
I am me. Me! Me! Me!
Why did they do this to us?
Help me, Rory. Help me.
Shh, shh.
(BUBBLING)
(BUBBLING INCREASES)
Trust me.
Oh... What are you doing down there?
Ooh.
Ah!
Ah! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Ah! Ah!
Clear.
Those damn Gangers
got to the acid suits.
There is acid leaking everywhere.
Did you see the boss' eyes
back there in the hall?
I've never seen a Ganger
look at me like that.
I don't know what they are now
but they ain't us.
(SNEEZES LOUDLY)
(CODE BEEPING, DOOR BUZZING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We have the advantage now.
We have the acid suits.
We can move freely, strike at will.
Are you sure you're feeling better?
No more super-elastic punches?
I'm...different now.
-Stronger.
-The Doctor won't hurt you.
He wants to help, Jennifer. Okay?
You used my name.
You used my name. Thank you.
-Amy's a lucky girl.
-Yeah. She is.
(SIGHS)
Let's go.
Rory. Rory?
(GASPS)
-Amy!
-(GASPS) You're okay.
What happened?
-She needs protecting.
-Jen?
No, it's a Ganger.
-Rory, listen...
-No, you listen! Nobody touches her!
(DOOR BUZZING)
Hello.
-How are you all getting on?
-Why don't you tell us?
Well, we have two choices.
The first is to tear each other apart,
not my favourite. The second is
to knuckle down and work together,
try to work out how
best we can help you.
Now, I know it's hard for you
to hold your fully human form.
That's why you keep shifting
between the Flesh stages. But do try.
It'll make the others
less scared of you.
Where's Jen?
What have you done with her?
I haven't seen her, I swear.
But look, I'm her.
I'm just like her. I'm real.
You're a copy.
You're just pretending to be like her.
Rory, we don't really know anything
about them yet.
-Well...
-And...
I know that she's afraid
and she needs our help.
Rory, would you...
Jimmy, Buzzer, come on, you guys.
We've worked together for two years.
I worked with Jennifer Lucas, not you.
Okay, let's not do anything at all
-until the Doctor gets...
-Until the Doctor gets here. Hello.
-This is...
-You're telling me.
All right, Doctor,
you've brought us together, now what?
Before we do anything,
I have one very important question.
Has anybody got
a pair of shoes I could borrow?
Size 10, although I should
warn you, I have very wide feet.
That's it, Doctor, befriend them,
team up with them, why don't you?
Make a football team. How about that?
You're going to have us all
together singing campfire songs.
The Flesh was never merely moss.
These are not copies.
The storm has hardwired them.
They are becoming people.
-With souls?
-Rubbish! (SNEEZES)
Bless you.
DOCTOR: What? We were all jelly once.
Little jelly eggs sitting in goop.
AMY: Yeah, thanks, too much information.
We are not talking about an accident
that needs to be mopped up.
We are talking about sacred life.
Do you understand?
Good. Now, the Tardis is trapped
in an acid pool.
Once I can reach her,
I can get you all off this island,
humans and Gangers. How does that sound?
Can I make it home for Adam's birthday?
What about me?
He's my son, too.
-You? You really think that?
-I feel it.
Oh, so you were there when he was born,
were you?
Yeah.
I drank about eight pints of tea.
Then they told me I had a wee boy
and I just burst out laughing.
(CHUCKLES)
No idea why.
I miss home,
as much as you.
Look, I'm not going to lie to you,
it's a right old mess, this.
But as you might say up north,
"Oh, well, I'll just go
to t'foot of stairs.” (CHUCKLES)
"Ee by by gum."” Or not. Good. Right.
First step is we get everyone together,
then get everyone safe.
Then get everyone out of here.
But we're still missing
Jennifer and Cleaves.
I'll go and look for them.
I'll give you a hand, if you like.
-Cover more ground.
-Yeah.
-Okay. Thanks.
-This circus has gone on long enough!
Oh, great.
You see, that is just so typically me.
Doctor, tell it to shut up!
-Cleaves, no. No, no.
-Circuit probe.
Fires about, oh, 40,000 volts?
Would kill any one of us.
So I guess she'll work on Gangers
just the same.
It's interesting you refer
to them as "it"
but you call a glorified cattle prod
a "she".
When the real people
are safely off this island
then I'll happily talk philosophy
over a pint with you, Doctor.
What are you going to do to them?
Sorry, they're monsters. Mistakes.
-They have to be destroyed.
-Give me the probe, Cleaves.
We always have to take charge,
don't we, Miranda.
Even when we don't really know
what the hell is going on.
(GRUNTS)
Oh! Agh! Dead!
We call it decommissioned.
-(GASPS)
-You stopped his heart.
He had a heart!
Aorta, valves, a real human heart!
And you stopped it.
-Jen?
-What happened to Buzz
will happen to us all if we trust you!
Wait, wait. Just wait.
-No! (GRUNTS)
-(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS) Idiot!
Wait!
(CLEAVES PANTING)
Look at what you have done, Cleaves!
If it's war, then it's war.
You don't get it, Doctor.
How can you? It's us and them now.
-Us and them.
(SIGHS) Us and them.
(SIGHS)
You tried.
We all tried and look what they did.
-Us and them now.
-Us and them.
Us and them.
-Jennifer.
-Buzzer warned you it was a trick
and now he's dead.
If we want to live,
then it's time to go to war.
I'll take care of the spare one
running around out there.
(DOOR CLANGS SHUT)
(WHIMPERING)
Trust me. Ahhh...
Oh!
-I just wanted to help her.
-Well, we all do, okay?
-Don't be like that. Listen, she's...
-I said I agree with you, so drop it.
(ARGUMENT CONTINUES, INDISTINCT)
The most fortified and defendable room
in the monastery.
Cleaves, the most fortified
and defendable room in the monastery?
-The chapel.
-Thank you.
Only one way in,
stone walls two feet thick.
You've crossed one hell of a line,
Cleaves.
You've killed one of them.
They're coming back.
In a big way.
-Jennifer!
-Rory?
What about the flares?
We'll worry about the flares
when we're locked inside.
-(JENNIFER SCREAMING)
-Rory Pond.
-Rory, come on.
-Jen's out there.
She's out there and she's on her own.
Well, if she's got any sense,
then she's hiding. Rory!
-I can't leave her out there!
-Rory!
-I know you understand that.
-Get in here! Get in here!
There they are!
-Amy.
-Ah!
Rory!
Amy, they are not after him,
they're after us.
Why? Why?
Show yourself. Show yourself!
(GRUNTING)
Jennifer.
Doctor, pass me the barrel.
We need something heavy,
anything you can find.
This is insane! (CHUCKLING)
We're fighting ourselves!
Yes, it's insane. And it's about to get
even more insanerer.
-Is that a word?
-Show yourself, right now!
Doctor, we are trapped in here
and Rory's out there with them.
Hello! We can't get to the Tardis
and we can't leave the island.
DOCTOR GANGER: Correct
in every respect, Pond.
It's frightening, unexpected,
frankly a total,
utter, splattering mess on the carpet.
But I am certain, 100% certain,
that we can work this out.
Trust me.
I'm the Doctor.
I have a plan.
Oh! You're hurting me.
And it'll destroy them all.
(GRUNTS) Ah! Why?
You're one of us, Doctor.
Nooo!
Oh!
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)