RASSMUSSEN:
You must not watch this.
(BREATHING SHAKILY) I'm warning you.
You can never un-see it.
But if you do watch...
Gagan Rassmussen. I'm Gagan Rassmussen.
And this is Le Verrier lab
in orbit around Neptune.
(EERIE MOANING)
I've put things together
into some kind of order,
so that you can understand.
So that you can have some idea.
Uh, there are bits missing.
Sorry about that.
Um, I don't fully understand
what's been going on here.
But uh...
This is what happened.
Stop staring!
RASSMUSSEN: They came from Triton.
This is Chopra.
Bit of an attitude in my opinion.
NAGATA: Calm down, pet.
CHOPRA: Well, it's ridiculous!
That thing's meant to be
a lethal fighting machine
-(POD HISSING)
-and it just moons around
like a lovesick puppy.
I could hear your ranting
from inside the pod, Chopra,
for the God's sake!
Feel better?
RASSMUSSEN: Commander Nagata.
Young for the responsibility.
Quite a baptism of fire, I'm afraid.
DEEP-ANDO: Marvellous, ma'am.
All hail, Morpheus, eh?
RASSMUSSEN: Deep-Ando, conscript.
Likes to think of himself as the joker
of this little group.
Well, he did.
CHOPRA: Morpheus! Morpheus! Morpheus!
Sleep's the one thing left to us.
The one thing they couldn't
get their filthy mitts on
and now they're even grabbing that.
Colonising it!
Spoken like a true Rip.
CHOPRA: Oh, don't call me that.
And don't call me that "ma"am".
Give it a rest, pet.
Give what a rest?
This is a mission, Chopra.
We find out what's
happened on Le Verrier
and then we all go home.
Keep your politics to yourself, okay?
I know someone who'd love to get
Chopra back to Triton, eh?
(DEEP-ANDO LAUGHS)
RASSMUSSEN: This one's
obvious from the markings, isn't it?
We all know a Grunt when we see one.
-NAGATA: Come on, behave.
-Ooh.
(DISTANT THUDDING)
(BEEPING)
Nearly there, kiddies.
RASSMUSSEN: These are the rescue crew.
Don't get too attached.
Everything you're about to see
is from their individual viewpoints,
all taken from the station itself.
The only footage available.
They came to find me.
This is my station, my lab.
I've pieced together
the rescue as best I could.
If you're going to watch,
then pay close attention.
Your lives may depend on it.
NAGATA: Emergency lighting only.
Grav and orbit stable.
There must be power.
NAGATA: Nothing.
No sign of anyone.
There was no crew.
No crew left.
They did find others, though.
Strangers.
NAGATA: What the hell happened here?
474: Hide seek.
Maybe they play hide seek.
CHOPRA: Hide "and" seek.
Why do they miss out words?
It's infuriating.
474: Chopra, don't be anger.
"Don't be angry!"
Is it so hard to breed them
to speak properly?
DEEP-ANDO: Oh, lighten up.
-CHOPRA: What now?
-Talk.
-What?
-People talk.
CLARA: Do you ever get the feeling like
you're being watched?
DOCTOR: Paranoia.
CLARA: Why is it so dark?
DOCTOR: Night-time setting.
Faulty filament. Three day week.
CLARA: So, orbit around Neptune?
DOCTOR: Ah, this close into the planet
they must have some pretty powerful
anti-grav shielding on board.
CLARA: Looks like a Japanese restaurant.
(GASPS) Have you brought me
to a space-restaurant?
DOCTOR: People never do that, you know.
Do what?
They never put the word
"space" in front of something
just because everything's all sort of
hi-tech and futurey.
It's never space-restaurant
or space-champagne
or space, you know, hats.
It's just restaurant, champagne or hats,
even if this was a restaurant.
CLARA: What about space-suit?
DOCTOR: Pedant.
(GUN POWERING UP)
Hello.
NAGATA: Are you crew?
Uh...
Engineering stress assessors?
Yes. Yes, we are.
We're here to, uh...
-To assess stress.
-Assess... Stress...
NAGATA: So what happened?
From the beginning of time?
That's a very long story.
(SOFTLY) Doctor.
Well... (SIGHS)
Well, we just arrived, you know,
and there was nobody about.
Well, what are you doing here?
Twenty-four hours ago
this station fell silent.
No comm signal, nothin'. Dead.
We've come to find out why.
Theories?
NAGATA: Could be anything.
Meteorite strike. Space pirates.
Ah, see!
Not just pirates, space pirates.
So, what, you are a rescue mission?
Yes.
Of four?
Cuts, pet.
Right. You're to consider yourself...
Part of the furniture?
...under my command.
-Okay. Really?
-Yes, really.
-CHOPRA: Come on.
-Oh, okay.
CLARA: We still don't know where we are.
Indo-Japanese.
Thirty-eighth century.
-Tuesday.
-Thirty-eighth century?
Mmm.
After the Great Catastrophe,
there was a tectonic realignment.
India and Japan, they are...
Sort of merged.
We still don't know where the rest
of the crew are though.
I mean, a place this size.
Hey, what?
Great Catastrophe?
What Great Catastrophe?
(CHUCKLES) Well...
You've got all that
to look forward to, haven't you?
Mind you,
this place looks as if it's been
dead for a long while now.
DOCTOR: What is it?
CLARA: I still
can't shake the feeling...
474: Eyes. Watch.
Eyes in sky.
CHOPRA: What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
Chopra not worry.
474 protect Chopra.
Chopra pretty.
Oh, for the gods!
Just back off!
(GRUNTING)
DEEP-ANDO: Oh, come on, now!
-(BOTH GRUNTING)
-NAGATA: Let him go, pet.
474: 474, sorry!
Let him go now!
Not help it!
(CHOPRA WHIMPERING)
He could have killed me!
NAGATA: That's how
they're grown, you know that.
They react to any attack.
"Grown"?
NAGATA: They might not
give 'em much upstairs,
but our friend here
certainly knows how to fight.
You'd be glad of her
in a tight corner, I'll bet.
CLARA: What does she mean "grown"?
DOCTOR: She's a Grunt, Clara.
They're bred in hatcheries.
Cloned muscles.
Low intelligence. Brute force.
Instant army.
That's disgusting.
Well, that's how they roll
in the 38th century.
(DISTANT GROWLING)
DOCTOR: Hold my hand.
CLARA: I'm okay.
DOCTOR: I'm not.
(GUN POWERING UP)
(CREATURE ROARING)
-Run! Run! Run!
-(GUNFIRE)
Run, run!
DEEP-ANDO: Follow me!
DEEP-ANDO: Straight ahead!
NAGATA: No!
-This way! Deep-Ando!
-DEEP-ANDO: Straight ahead!
Push anything in front of it,
we've gotta keep them out!
NAGATA: Deep-Ando. We've lost him.
CLARA: What the hell are they?
DOCTOR: Not pirates.
NAGATA: We've got to get Deep-Ando.
Where's your friend?
CHOPRA: Deep-Ando. I don't know. He's...
NAGATA: He's still out there!
(ROARING)
NAGATA: 474!
(GRUNTING)
NAGATA: What the hell are they?
Where did they go?
-(DEVICE BEEPS)
-Chief Nagata, this is Deep-Ando.
Where did you go?
-(BEEPING)
-(DEEP-ANDO PANTING)
Nagata, this is Deep-Ando.
May the gods look favourably upon you.
(BEEP)
Nagata, are you there?
NAGATA: Deep-Ando, this is Nagata.
May the gods look favourably upon you.
-Deep-Ando, are you there?
-(RADIO CRACKLING)
What are you doing?
DOCTOR: Finding out
what they're made of.
NAGATA: Deep-Ando, are you there?
CHOPRA: Send the Grunt.
-NAGATA: No.
-Why not? That's what it's for.
Look, he's still out there.
You can't just abandon him.
I need proper intel
before I risk anyone else,
including 474.
Keep trying the comms!
CHOPRA: Deep-Ando,
may the gods look favourably upon you...
-CLARA: Well?
-Organic. Definitely, organic.
Blood cells, skin cells, mucus...
CHOPRA: Deep-Ando, may the
gods look favourably upon you.
Deep-Ando?
What are these?
-Morpheus.
-Morpheus?
Named after the god of dreams.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah!
Not just this!
So, what are they then, sleep pods?
-More than that.
-(RADIO CRACKLING)
-Deep-Ando?
-(CRACKLING CONTINUES)
Deep-Ando, can you hear me?
NAGATA: Keep trying.
I could take a look at that, you know.
Triangulate the signal,
help you find your friend.
NAGATA: First, tell me
what those things are.
(RADIO CRACKLING CONTINUES)
Deep-Ando?
Deep-Ando, this is Chopra.
I'm getting a signal.
Deep-Ando, can you hear me?
Deep-Ando?
Deep-Ando, this is Chopra.
Can you hear me?
CLARA: Doctor!
-(ALARM BLARING)
-Clara?
# Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, borm, born
# Mr Sandman, bring me a dream... #
-Clara?
-NAGATA: It's fine, it's just Morpheus.
What do you think you were doing?
Huh?
It dragged me in.
The wires, they were like snakes.
-Like it was alive.
-Are you okay?
Yeah, it just kind of
flicked over my eyes.
CLARA: Did I sleep?
CHOPRA: Yeah, you did.
CLARA: Why did it just grab at me?
DOCTOR: Semi-sentient.
It thinks it knows what's good for you.
You obviously needed 40 winks.
Clever little sleep pod.
You said it was something
more than that though.
NAGATA: Come on, everyone knows.
Well, let's just say,
for the sake of argument, that we don't.
What is Morpheus?
474:; Last pod.
This pod.
Not empty.
(MR SANDMAN PLAYING)
Oh, no. No, no.
Enough of that.
(MUSIC STOPS)
(WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
-(POD WHIRRING)
-(GRUNTS)
It's almost like...
Someone's...
CLARA: Careful.
(GUN POWERING UP)
CLARA: Here. Let me try.
Hello?
It's okay. We're not going to hurt you.
Will you open up now?
Come on.
Let's start with names, shall we?
Um, I'm Clara.
This is the Doctor.
CLARA: It's okay.
RASSMUSSEN: AA, this is where I come in.
Hello.
I wanted to get out of there.
Immediately. Of course I did, but, um...
This man, the Doctor...
He wanted explanations first.
So...
May the gods look
favourably upon us all.
Friends, we live in a time
of unparalleled prosperity.
A golden age of peace,
harmony and industry.
But every shift must come to an end.
Every working day must stop.
Of course we can
take stimulants to make that deadline.
(YAWNS)
To keep us propped up
through that important meeting.
But always, always,
sleep claims us in the end.
Until now.
Sleep deprivation pods?
Not exactly.
PRESENTER: Welcome Morpheus!
(MR SANDMAN PLAYING)
The Morpheus machine concentrates
the whole nocturnal experience
into one five-minute burst.
Now you can go
a whole month without sleep!
-A month?
-All the chemical benefits of rest
but freeing up the nights
to continue working, working, working.
To get the edge on your competitor.
To turn that extra profit.
That's insane. That's horrible.
Finally!
Someone who sees it for what it is!
Leave the Rip Van Winkles behind
and become one of a new
generation of Wide-Awakes!
The future is here.
The future is now.
Let yourself slip into
the arms of Morpheus.
-But sleep is...
-Terms and conditions apply.
Sleep is vital.
Sleep is wonderful. Even I sleep.
When?
Well, when you're not looking.
Morpheus is mine. My invention.
It's changed Triton society forever.
DOCTOR: So how does it work?
The pod sends out
a coded electronic signal
that acts on certain parts of the brain.
Changes the fundamental chemistry.
CHOPRA: It's disgusting.
Making people into bloody drones.
-I've said it before...
-NAGATA: Aye, you have.
Colonising our sleep! Is nothing sacred?
We spend a third of our lives asleep.
And time is money.
He's right, man. It's amazing.
Everyone on Triton's using it.
DOCTOR: Are they now?
"Sleep that knits up
the ravelled sleeve of care.
"The death of each day's life,
sore labour's bath.
"Balm of hurt minds.
"Chief nourisher in life's great feast.”
Congratulations, Professor.
You've revolutionised the lab our market.
You have conquered nature.
RASSMUSSEN: Thank you.
You've also created an abomination.
RASSMUSSEN: The Doctor said that
we had to find the other soldier.
And to find answers.
So we left the lab.
He thought that there
was some connection
between my Morpheus process
and those creatures that attacked us.
Anyway, you'll see, he had a theory.
-Sleep dust?
-DOCTOR: Sleep dust.
NAGATA: You're kidding.
What, do I look like I'm kidding?
Is this a kidding face?
Ask the crew of this station
if they're kidding.
Or what's left of them.
NAGATA: But sleep dust?
Yes.
The stuff in the corner of your eye.
The stuff you wipe away
every morning when you wake up.
That's ridiculous.
This is getting us nowhere.
Okay, how, Doctor?
How can those things
be made of sleep dust?
Well, when we sleep,
the mucus crust builds up in our eyes.
Blood cells. Skin cells.
That's what dust largely is.
Human skin.
But your meddling has evolved it.
Hot-housed it.
What used to be sleep in your eye
has turned into a carnivorous life form!
You can't just throw
accusations like that around!
CLARA: So the longer you're in Morpheus,
the more the dust builds up?
That's slander!
Lying there in those pods,
people are a ready-made food source.
CLARA: Well, where are they then?
Where's the crew?
Digested.
NAGATA: Come on,
we need to find Deep-Ando.
DEEP-ANDO: Come on. Oh, come on!
Must be an exit here somewhere.
(DEEP-ANDO BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RADIO BEEPS)
Listen to me.
These things, they're everywhere.
For the gods' sake come and get me.
(CREATURE GROWLING)
NAGATA: But what about us?
We've all used the pods back on Triton.
Not all of us.
NAGATA: This isn't
a good time to be smug, pet.
DOCTOR: Well, my guess
is that the ones you're using
are pretty primitive
compared to what's going on up here.
These are a sort of Mach 2, yeah?
Obviously, I have tried
to improve the process.
Speed things up.
You succeeded there.
But how does the dust
become those creatures?
You saw what happened.
The dust conglomerates.
It moulds itself into humanoid form.
It's adaptable. It's clever.
-(DISTANT GROWLING)
-(GUN POWERING UP)
And it's coming for us.
Look, you came to rescue the crew.
I'm crew. So rescue me!
CLARA: How come
you're the only one left?
Because I hid.
I hid in the only place I thought those
monsters wouldn't find me.
Look, we've got to get out of here!
No, we can't leave this place
until there's not a trace of the dust
or your machines left.
-Or that's it for your lot.
-NAGATA: Our lot?
What do you mean?
Oh, the human race.
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: Hey.
Haruka Deep-Ando, 6-8-9-7. Let me in.
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: I'd love to.
Well do it then.
My ID must be on the Corporation index.
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
You have to do the song.
What?
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: You have to
do the song, Deep-Ando 6-8-9-7.
I haven't got time for this.
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Do the song, please.
What the hell are you talking about?
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: After the Maha
Shivaratri/Oshogatsu/Christmas party
some of the crew reprogrammed me.
-They did, did they?
-Yes.
In order to enter rooms,
everyone must do the song.
It's very amusing.
But you know who I am!
You just called me by my name!
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: Nevertheless.
(SIGHS)
What song?
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
You know the one.
I don't!
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Now you're just being silly.
Of course you do.
Silly, Deep-Ando 6-8-9-7.
You must know the song.
-Everyone here knows it.
- (CREATURE GROWLING)
I'm not from this station.
I'm on a rescue mission.
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
# Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, bomn... #
Morpheus?
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
That's right. The Morpheus song.
Oh, this is insane!
FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE:
The song, please.
Morpheus.
# Mr Sandman...
# Bring me your dreams
# Make him the cutest... #
Haruka Deep-Ando 6-8-9-7. Let me in!
-FEMALE ELECTRONIC VOICE: More please.
-(DEEP-ANDO SIGHS)
# Give him two lips, like roses in... #
Please, let me in!
Let me in!
(CREATURE ROARING)
(DEEP-ANDO SCREAMING)
(DEEP-ANDO BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BEEPING)
(ROARING)
(SIGHS)
Uh, he was the first of them to die.
We heard the scream but um...
well we... (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
We had our own problems.
(METALLIC CLANKING)
RASSMUSSEN: What's happening?
NAGATA: Engines?
CHOPRA: No, it's the gravity shields!
They're failing!
Nagata, that thing, the schematic.
Give it to me!
Who the hell do you think you are?
-Me? I'm in charge.
-You have no authority.
No. But I'm in charge.
I can bypass the main systems
and reboot the grav-shields.
CLARA: Listen to him for God's sake!
He knows what he's talking about!
(GRUNTING)
CLARA: Doctor!
Doctor, if the grav-shields
are decaying...
RASSMUSSEN: Don't say it.
Please don't say it!
CLARA: We're being pulled
towards Neptune.
RASSMUSSEN: Oh, gods,
oh, gods, oh, gods!
DOCTOR: Hang on!
CLARA: (GRUNTS)
This day couldn't get any worse!
-(GLASS SHATTERING)
-(ROARING)
I can do this! I can fix this!
(RASSMUSSEN SHUDDERING)
RASSMUSSEN: Oh, please!
-(RASSMUSSEN SCREAMING)
-(ROARING)
CLARA: No! No!
DOCTOR: The G-Force is increasing
the closer we get to the planet.
Hold on!
(ROARING)
(BEEPING)
DOCTOR: We're back online!
Grav shields fixed!
We're rising!
Go! Let's get out of here.
Go, go! Out of here, come on!
NAGATA: Chopra, 474, come on!
DOCTOR: Keep going.
Move it, move it, move it!
Nagata!
No, I can't leave them!
NAGATA: Chopra,
474, may the gods... Where are you?
(CHOPRA BREATHING HEAVILY)
CLARA: Oh, God, of all the places.
A cold store.
-Nagata, are you okay?
-No, I'm not.
-What about the others?
-I don't know.
-We have to go after them!
-Don't be ridiculous.
CLARA: Doctor!
They're under my command.
I owe it to them.
To die?
They wouldn't thank you for that.
Nor you, Clara. "To die, to die.
"Glamis hath murdered sleep,
"therefore Cawdor shall sleep no more.
"Macbeth shall sleep no more."
NAGATA: What?
Shakespeare. (CHUCKLES)
He really knew his stuff.
They all did.
The ancients. The poets.
All those sad songs,
all those lullabies.
Sleep is essential
to every sentient being in the universe.
But to humans, greedy, filthy,
stupid humans,
it's an inconvenience,
to be bartered away.
Well, now, we know the truth.
Sleep isn't just a function,
it's blessed.
Every night we dive deep
into that inky pool.
Deep into the arms of Morpheus.
Every morning we wake up
and wipe the sleep from our eyes.
And that keeps us safe.
Safe from the monsters inside.
Well, the bloody monsters
are outside now.
What do we do?
(DISTANT THUDDING)
(GUN POWERING UP)
NAGATA: Dead meat.
(CHOPRA PANTING)
Dear gods, what are we going to do?
Get ship. Go home.
We can't let those things off here.
If they were to get out, to spread,
it's like an infection.
You don't understand, do you?
Sleep men bad.
Kill sleep men.
Yeah. That about sums it up.
Chief Nagata, this is Chopra.
May the gods look favourably upon you.
(RADIO BEEPS)
Chief Nagata, this is Chopra. May the...
We'll head for the rescue ship.
If we don't hear from them soon,
I'm going to have to
assume they're dead.
Then what Chopra do?
I have no choice.
I'll have to destroy this whole station.
(WHIRRING)
NAGATA: What're you doing?
DOCTOR: I've hacked
into your helmet cams.
-NAGATA: What?
-Reviewing the footage.
There's something not right here.
NAGATA: We don't have helmet cams.
Why did it kill Rassmussen like that?
That's what they do, isn't it?
Kill people.
But that's a direct attack.
It's not how they operate.
Dust grows, consumes the host.
They evolve. You said so yourself.
(SIGHS) Maybe.
There's something going on here.
Something we're not getting.
(BEEPING)
POD: Please stand clear of the pod.
Dangerous materials in transit.
What now?
We can't stay in here.
We're gonna freeze to death.
We can't go back out there
because the Sandmen will get us.
(SIGHS)
Sandmen?
Yeah, it's a good name.
It fits. Like in the song.
# Bom, bom, bom... #
No. No, no, no, no.
You don't get to name things.
I'm the Doctor. I do the naming.
CLARA: All right, sorry.
It's like the Silurians all over again.
CLARA: Okay. Well, what would
you prefer then, the Dustmen?
Sandmen.
What did you just say?
-NAGATA: When?
-1.83 minutes ago.
I said we don't have helmet cams.
(LOUD THUDDING)
(SANDMEN ROARING)
(THUDDING)
(SOFTLY) Doctor?
(ROARING)
That door isn't going
to last much longer.
NAGATA: (SOFTLY) So what do we do?
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
We let them in.
CLARA: What?
Mmm. It's clever, that.
Clever strategy.
If they'd stayed in there,
they'd have frozen to death,
so the Doctor had
to let the creatures in.
That was his theory.
Oh, I'm not dead.
You've probably guessed that by now.
(HEARTBEAT POUNDING)
(SANDMAN MOANING)
(SANDMAN CONTINUES MOANING)
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
474: What happen?
Must be damage from
when we fell out of orbit.
(BOTH COUGHING)
We have to go back.
(SANDMEN ROARING)
CHOPRA: I don't know what to do.
I can't save us.
-474 can.
-What?
(SANDMAN HEAVING)
(NAGATA BREATHING SHAKILY)
(MOUTHING)
RASSMUSSEN: The Doctor worked it out.
The creatures can't see.
(SANDMAN HEAVING)
Shh!
DOCTOR: Run! Engine Room!
What happened?
(STRAINING) 474 help.
(474 WHEEZING)
CHOPRA: What?
474 die soon.
No, no, no, don't say that.
You got us through.
You can survive this.
(SANDMEN ROARING)
474: Chopra go.
Get ship.
(WHEEZING) Chopra be safe.
Chopra pretty.
(SANDMEN ROARING)
(ROARING)
(YELLING)
You said you felt like
you were being watched, Clara.
CLARA: Paranoia, you said.
Not this time.
There is a feed. Wireless.
These images are being
stored by someone. Collated.
Nagata, look at this footage.
What's wrong with it?
Don't know.
DOCTOR: Look, there's one
very obvious thing about it.
Do you see it yet?
No?
Okay, I'll tell you what's wrong.
There's footage here of everyone.
But what's missing in all of it?
What can't you see anywhere?
Not in the footage, not on this ship.
Look.
Really look.
There are no cameras here.
No CCTV. No helmet cams.
So how and why does
this footage even exist?
The dust has been watching us.
Each little organic speck,
just a tiny spy,
drifting through the air.
The monsters have
been with us all along.
That's why the Sandmen are blind.
Their visual receptors
are being hijacked!
But by whom and why?
And then, there's this.
That's you, Clara.
That's you looking at me.
Me?
You went into the pod.
The Morpheus process has begun.
(SIGHS)
Pod.
There's nothing here
from Chopra's point of view
because he refuses to use Morpheus.
But everybody else is here,
including you.
You don't have a camera, Clara.
But will have by now, sleep in your eye.
Okay, well, we'll fix this.
You will fix this.
Yes.
I'm sure it'll be fine,
I'm sure you'll be fine.
Sure?
We will sort this, Clara.
We'll sort you, we'll sort Nagata.
And everyone back on Triton.
Then we will destroy Morpheus forever.
Okay, then.
Let's get on with it.
The power's been almost
entirely out since we arrived,
but we've still got emergency lighting.
But the engines are still on.
Well, there was that incident
with the grav-shields, but...
-Ah!
-CLARA: What? What? What? What? What?
The grav-shields didn't fail.
They were deliberately powered down.
NAGATA: By the Sandmen?
Well, that's not their style, is it?
It's like...
It's like something's been kept here.
Near the engines where it's hot.
Like something's been...
Kept alive.
POD: Warning!
Dangerous materials in transit.
Human contact not advised.
Warning! Dangerous materials in transit.
Well, you said someone's watching.
-Collating images.
-DOCTOR: Yeah.
Well, if it's not the Sandmen,
then who is it?
I have an idea who.
A very nasty idea.
(BEEP)
CHOPRA: In the absence
of any further communication
with Chief Nagata and the others,
I must regrettably assume
them to be deceased.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Under the circumstances,
I'm now returning to the ship
and will begin preparations
to destroy Le Verrier station.
(SANDMAN GROWLING)
(GUN POWERING UP)
(DISTANT THUDDING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Who's there?
-(DOORS HISSING)
-Chief?
(CHOPRA PANTING)
-(SANDMAN ROARING)
-(CHOPRA SCREAMS)
NAGATA: Rescue ship?
Why are we going to the rescue ship?
DOCTOR: Because that's where he'll be.
RASSMUSSEN: Gagan Rassmussen.
I'm Gagan Rassmussen.
This is Le Verrier lab
in orbit around Neptune
I've put things together
into some kind of order...
You had that prepared
well in advance, didn't you?
Your statement. Your alibi.
There would inevitably be questions
when you got to Triton.
So you needed to get
your story straight.
RASSMUSSEN: This is what happened.
You can't fight them, Doctor.
There's no point.
They're the future.
A new life form.
A better life form.
It's very clear to me now. They've...
They've made me understand.
And we're to be their food,
and that's only correct.
I just needed to find a way to get them
off this station and back to Triton
and then they'll spread.
Spread everywhere.
And that's what you want?
You're helping them wipe out humanity.
Things have been made very clear to me!
NAGATA: But we saw you die.
The Sandman swallowed...
I think the Professor has
been playing a long game.
Am I right?
They speak to me.
In my mind.
Trust me, I think.
But they're like children. Babies.
So new.
Evolving.
Hungry.
Always so hungry.
I made them understand.
We had to find a way out.
And then there'd be new food sources.
Unlimited.
So they spared me.
And we waited.
You and your cargo?
RASSMUSSEN: I got it in here
while you were all distracted.
(BEEPING)
CLARA: What's in there?
Dust?
It's like smuggling a jam jar
full of germs through customs.
No. No, more than that.
What do you mean?
I've been working on Morpheus
for a very long time, Doctor.
I had to start somewhere.
Morpheus' first client.
Patient Zero.
The ultimate Wide-Awake.
Inside there,
is @ man who hasn't slept in five years.
Or what's left of him.
He's the well-spring.
Once we get to Triton,
he will spread his spores.
CLARA: But you said
it was an encoded signal.
Something electronic
in the Morpheus process
that changed the chemical
reaction in the brain.
Well, that's how it started, yes.
But it's changing all the time.
Evolving new ways to infect.
To flourish.
Whole moons, whole planets,
whole civilizations.
They'll spread everywhere.
You know I can't allow that.
You can't stop them.
None of us can.
(GUN POWERING UP)
I wouldn't bet on that, pet.
(DEVICE BEEPS)
(KING SANDMAN GROWLING)
CLARA: Doctor!
(KING SANDMAN ROARING)
(SOFTLY) What he wants is to
get that thing off this ship.
-We have to stop him.
-Any ideas?
The doors are not a problem.
CLARA: But...
(BEEPS)
DOCTOR: We need a distraction.
When I say run, run.
(KING SANDMAN HEAVING)
Hey! Sandy!
# Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom, borm, born
-2 Borm, borm bormn, born, boron, borr...
-Run!
2~ Bom, borm bormn, born, born, boron, bormrm Z
DOCTOR: Doors!
(MR SANDMAN CONTINUES PLAYING)
Rassmussen! Turn off the engines!
Shut the ship down!
I can't do that I'm afraid, Doctor.
We can't fight the inevitable.
Humanity's day is done.
NAGATA: Yeah? Well, humanity might have
something to say about that, pet.
-CLARA: No!
-(GROANS)
Is that your answer for everything?
Did you have a better one?
DOCTOR: He's not the only one dead.
According to this data, we're the only
ones left alive on this station.
(KING SANDMAN GROWLING)
CLARA: Doctor.
Come on, man! We've got to go!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
-This doesn't make any sense.
-CLARA: What?
A man who hasn't slept for five years.
Well, you heard what he said.
That's the first Morpheus patient.
But the dust consumes the host.
And then they make Sandmen,
they conglomerate.
Well, we escaped from that cold storage
room because they were blind.
And why power down
the grav-shields when he did?
It's like... This is all for effect.
Look, can we maybe
have this conversation
when we get off this thing?
Like a story...
-NAGATA: Come on!
-(LOUD THUDDING)
(KING SANDMAN GROWLING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
NAGATA: How do we get off this crate?
DOCTOR: Alternative transport.
(GROWLING)
We have to get to Triton.
Destroy all the Morpheus machines.
End this.
This is how we get home?
I've never been so pleased to see...
(SANDMEN ROARING)
Nagata.
CLARA: Doctor, quickly.
(DOCTOR MUTTERING INCOHERENTLY)
What did you just do?
Self-destructed the grav-shields.
NAGATA: What?
(ALL GRUNTING)
DOCTOR: It's working!
Neptune's gravity is pulling
them apart, bit by bit!
It doesn't make sense.
None of this makes any sense!
Hello, again!
The thing is, you see,
this message, this testament,
it wasn't just my alibi.
It was my plan.
There are no spores, no infection.
The Morpheus process remains the same.
An electronic signal
that affects the sleep
centres of the brain.
It changes them.
An electronic signal
that's contained in this recording.
There it is.
It tickles, doesn't it?
I've just got time to fit this bit in
and then I can finish the story.
And then I'm going to
transmit this footage
to the whole solar system.
I do hope you've enjoyed the show.
I did try to make it exciting.
All those scary bits.
All those death-defying scrapes.
Monsters.
And a proper climax with
a really big one at the end!
Compulsive viewing.
I did tell you not to watch.
(GROANS)
(IN DEEP VOICE) There's nothing left
of Rassmussen any more.
Only us.
You will show this film
to your family, won't you?
And your friends.
And everyone, really.
And then we can all be together.
Dust to dust.
Excuse me.
You've got something...
There.
Just in the corner of your eye.
(LAUGHING EERILY)
Rigsy! Hey. What's wrong?
So, I have this, uh...
It kind of looks like a tattoo.
There's no nice way
to say you're about to die.
What?
I don't know who did this to you.
But I do almost certainly know...
How to find them.
So, this your life then?
Bouncing around time, saving people?
DOCTOR: There have always been rumours,
mutterings about hidden streets.
Secret pockets of alien life
right here on Earth.
ASHILDR: Peace on this street
depends on one thing,
to break it is to face the raven.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)