(LAUGHING)
I told you it'd work.
It very nearly ate you for dinner.
Oh, admit it. I totally saved your life.
It wasn't going to eat me.
(LAUGHS)
I totally saved you from having to marry
that giant sentient plant thing.
That bit, when I jumped
over the side, that was amazing.
-(CHUCKLES)
-(LAUGHS)
Knew you were impressed.
The second most beautiful
garden in all of time and space
and we can never come back here,
because you, Miss Oswald, decided...
(PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
-Hello.
-RIGSY: Clara, finally.
It's Rigsy.
Oh, Rigsy!
Hey. What's wrong?
So, I have this, uh...
It kind of looks like a tattoo.
CLARA: Seriously, I gave you
this number for emergencies.
It's an emergency. Trust me.
Just, come and take
a look at it, please.
Who said you could give out my number?
Look, look.
No matter how bad it is
we cannot take you
back down your timeline
just to fix a tattoo.
That's just it.
I didn't get a tattoo, and it's...
It's counting down.
Sorry. What?
The tattoo.
It's a number
and it's counting down to zero.
Hang tight. We'll be right there.
Hurry. Please.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: Did you make this human?
Lucy? Yeah, she's mine.
CLARA: Oh!
Hello.
Oh, Rigsy, she's gorgeous.
DOCTOR: She's better than that.
She's brilliant.
What are you doing running around
getting tattoo...
(BOTH SHUSHING)
(SOFTLY) Look, I didn't get anything.
I woke up this morning
and it was just there.
Jen noticed it.
Okay. Show me this tattoo
that you didn't get, then.
(LUCY COOS)
It's a tattoo. It's very boring.
No, wait. Look.
Just... Just keep watching.
What were you doing last night?
That's just it.
Yesterday was a total blank.
Jen said that I left
the house before dawn.
I missed work.
And I didn't get back
till after midnight.
No one saw me all day.
Oh, that's not boring.
That is very not boring.
-(WHIRRING)
-What? What is it?
Okay, local knowledge.
You're coming with us,
and bring the new human.
No. Don't bring the new human.
I'll just get distracted.
DOCTOR: If you want
your extremities to stay attached,
stand absolutely still.
If not, we can provide a small bag.
You can take them home at the end.
CLARA: Rigsy, your phone.
It's like they've wiped it,
but only the last day.
No location data, no texts, nothing.
You sure the screen
wasn't cracked before yesterday?
Uh-huh.
Oh, right. Okay, here we go.
Uh...
Good.
Weird.
Good and weird.
(MUMBLING) Can I move?
Ah. Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes. Of course.
First off,
in the last 24 hours you have
had significant contact
with alien life forms.
Right here, in the centre of London.
Okay, so, why don't I remember anything?
You've been Retconned.
-RIGSY: Huh?
-What conned?
Amnesia drug.
Your prefrontal cortex
is marinating in it.
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
Ooh, there's something else.
Something...
(ALARM SOUNDING)
DOCTOR: Uh...
Not good.
Weird.
RIGSY: What's he doing?
He's making an effort to be nice.
There's no nice way
to say you're about to die.
What?
-Rigsy...
-No, no, no, no, no!
Don't start using my actual name now.
Call me pudding brain. Call me
local knowledge, whatever. Just...
Don't call me Rigsy.
You're gonna save me.
You're a Doctor. That's what you do.
(SIGHS)
(SMACKS LIPS) Okay, okay.
Yes!
Okay, let's do this thing.
First up, stop the countdown.
526 minutes. Right!
Okay.
Yes. You know what?
Local knowledge,
I don't know who did this to you or why.
But I do almost certainly know...
(TARDIS POWERING UP)
How to find them.
(WHOOSHING)
(SIREN WAILING)
There have always been rumours.
Stories passed
from traveller to traveller,
mutterings about hidden streets.
Secret pockets of alien life
right here on Earth.
Like a smuggler's cove.
Only not a cove,
because it's right here,
right in the middle of the capital.
The hidden places are in
the great British Library?
No. The maps are.
DOCTOR: I never put stock in it.
London streets that suddenly
disappear from human view. No.
You lot are always overlooking things.
But whole streets,
that would be excessive even for you.
But if the stories are true, though,
there should be a street
in one of these old maps
that no longer exists in the real world.
Like a trap street, only not.
-What did you say?
-A trap street.
You know, when someone's making a map.
A, um, cartographer.
Uses a fake street,
throws it into the mix,
names it after
one of his kids or whatever.
Then if the fake street,
the trap street,
ever shows up on someone else's map,
they know their work's been stolen.
Clever, right?
My God! A whole London street
just up and disappeared
and you lot assume
it's a copyright infringement.
So, we're looking for a trap street?
We're looking for a trap street.
And we're not going to find it here.
The glasses are tracking
your eye movements.
Just keep looking straight down...
I know!
Focus on the buildings
directly below me!
DOCTOR: Whatever they're using,
it only hides the street itself.
It prevents you from noticing there's
even something missing.
They'll somehow make
our eyes skate right over it.
It's called a misdirection circuit.
(EXCLAIMS)
(CLARA EXCLAIMS)
(CLARA SCREAMS)
Clara!
CLARA: Whoo-hoo! (LAUGHS) Whoo!
Whoo-hoo! (LAUGHING)
Whoo!
(YELLS) Hello, London!
(CLARA LAUGHS)
(CLARA EXCLAIMS)
CLARA: Phew!
(CLARA LAUGHS)
I'm good.
(LAUGHS)
CLARA: I'm good.
She enjoyed that way too much.
Tell me about it.
It's an ongoing problem. Here.
(GRUNTS) Keep it steady.
Just move it slowly over the grid.
When we're done
we'll have a map of the areas
of the grid that Clara
couldn't focus on.
So these are the bits
my eyes skated over.
DOCTOR: Okay, we split up.
Clara, that way.
Local knowledge.
DOCTOR: Forget the way
you usually look at the world.
This street's going to be
hiding in plain sight.
Twenty-two, 23...
DOCTOR: If you see something
unusual or notable, dismiss it.
Just keep walking.
But if there's a bit of London
so unremarkable
that you don't even think about it,
stop.
You could very well
be standing right outside a trap street.
Count everything that you see.
Four, five, six...
Because when you hit
the area around a trap street,
it's very likely you'll lose count.
Seventy-nine.
Eighty.
Eighty-one.
Eighty-two.
-Huh?
-Remember 82.
-WOMAN: Come along.
-Eighty-two.
DOCTOR: You'll lose count
because the misdirection circuit
Is creating confusion in your mind.
Details won't add up.
Reality will have glitches in it.
Like when you try to read the same
simple sentence three times over...
One, two, three...
DOCTOR: ...and the meaning
Just won't sink in.
Got ya.
DOCTOR: Clara. Clara.
Clara.
It's off this street, I am certain.
We're very close.
We need to distract our other senses.
Clara, go back to the Tardis.
Pick up all my most annoying stuff.
(BEEPING)
(GROANS)
(PANTS)
(MOBILE BEEPING)
What happened to all
the stuff that I asked...
Someone called you.
Yesterday, 6:00 a.m. Blocked number.
Oh.
(GASPING)
(SNIFFS)
She's dead. (GROWLS)
What is it?
What are you remembering?
(GASPING)
Rigsy, what is it?
You can't see it?
There.
I see it. You?
Fifty minutes left.
Hoodie up, local knowledge.
They know what you look like in there.
RIGSY: How come I saw it
when you guys couldn't?
Well, you were upset, weren't you?
Something slipped through
the Retcon memory.
Something that
took over your whole mind.
Something juicy.
So the misdirection circuit,
it lost its power over you.
Surely people wander
in here all the time then, distracted,
on their phones or whatever.
Well, perhaps they do.
Oh!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(SNARLS)
Flee at once!
It's you!
Hang about.
(SNIFFS)
Uh, this one don't smell human.
Name, species, and case for asylum.
Quick as you like.
-Asylum?
-The reason you're here.
The reason you need sanctuary.
Why didn't they use the protocol?
I saw through the circuit again.
I saw them.
They're definitely not human.
You do know this is a refugee camp.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, of course.
ASHILDR: Of course he does.
Now that you've told him.
Mayor Me.
CLARA: Ashildr.
Ashildr?
That's your name.
I keep telling you that.
Do you?
Infinite lifespan, finite memory,
it makes for an awkward social life.
You must be Clara Oswald.
You're as beautiful as your photos.
We met.
Yes, I know. It's in my diaries.
Oh, don't look like that.
I enjoyed our conversations.
I've read them many times.
Okay, that's slightly odd but nice.
Um, hang on.
So this is where you've been.
That's why he lost track of you.
Oh, come on, please.
It's really cute.
He thinks I don't know.
He's got this whole
secret room in the Tardis
where he collects mentions of you.
It's not cute.
It's surveillance.
It's professional interest.
Precautionary measure.
Still saving the world from me then?
It's still here, isn't it?
CLARA: He lost track of you,
in the early 1800s.
I wondered if you were...
Oh, no. I let him know I was okay.
I saw you. (CHUCKLES)
No. I got your attention.
Yes, you did and you have.
Now we need your help.
Someone in this place
is in control of a quantum shade.
(GROWLS)
RUMP: I knew I recognised that smell.
-Oh!
-Ashildr.
What's going on?
You.
How do you know this man?
Hang on. You did this to Rigsy?
What have you done?
This man committed a crime.
-ASHILDR: I sentenced him.
-Sentenced him?
I also gave him enough time to return
home and say goodbye to his family.
You flooded his brain with Retcon.
Till we showed up, he didn't even know
that he had to say goodbye.
I'm afraid no intruder
leaves this place without a memory wipe.
With respect, that will include you.
Oh, the hell it will.
Ashildr, given that we're all gonna
forget this conversation anyway,
perhaps you could tell us
what happened here yesterday
to necessitate a death sentence.
Fine.
I'll show you.
Mr Kabel, Mr Rump,
permit them entry.
No.
You've already endangered
one of my friends.
I want your personal guarantee
that you will not endanger another.
Shut up. I can handle myself.
I guarantee the safety of Clara Oswald.
She will be under
my personal protection.
That is absolute.
If that's your wish, Mayor Me.
ASHILDR: This way.
Murderer.
What did you say?
(WHIRRING)
Murderer.
He called me a murderer.
DOCTOR: So, you're still
calling yourself "Me" then?
-ASHILDR: "Me"?
-Mayor Me.
ASHILDR: Mayor is a title.
I give myself a title
for the same reason you do, Doctor.
Something to live up to.
DOCTOR: Difficult, isn't it?
How long have you been here?
ASHILDR: Since Waterloo.
DOCTOR: The battle?
ASHILDR: No, the station.
Really, Doctor!
Tread carefully while you're here.
Some of your greatest enemies
are within a few feet of you.
As far as you're concerned,
this is the most
dangerous street in London.
Fascinating.
Now can we skip to the part where you
want Rigsy dead for some reason?
WOMAN 1: It's him! He's back!
The murderer!
It's best we get him inside first.
MAN 1: Murderer,
you're not welcome here.
They look at me as if they
want to kill me themselves.
MAN 2: We don't want
your kind around here.
MAN 3: Murderer!
(SNARLING)
WOMAN 2: Murderer!
Like I said, it's best we get inside.
(PEOPLE YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
WOMAN 3: Filthy murderer!
Wait, Clara!
Look.
DOCTOR: This misdirection
circuit of yours is remarkable.
(RAVEN CROWS)
The cloaking device
that hides the street
makes everyone look like humans.
It's no device.
It's the lurkworms.
Quite something, aren't they?
The light is a telepathic field.
It normalises everything you see.
Places it within the compass
of your expectations.
Your experiences.
You can bypass them, of course.
(EXCLAIMS)
Don't worry. We're perfectly safe.
Yes.
A phrase I find is usually followed
by a lot of screaming
and running and bleeding.
I brokered a truce.
We have strict rules
against violence here.
Rules every creature must abide by
if they wish to remain on the street.
MAN 1: Get away from us.
MAN 2: Don't want your kind around here.
ASHILDR: What's better,
that they're in here with me,
peaceful and cooperative,
or out there on Earth like the Zygons?
We haven't had an act of violence
on this street for a hundred years
until yesterday when your friend here
attacked one of our most
vulnerable residents.
How did Rigsy even get in?
I mean, we barely managed it.
And we knew what we were looking for.
ASHILDR: She was found
at the entrance to the street.
No weapon on the scene.
But the cause of death
is likely the head wound.
It seems she was knocked
to the cobblestones.
CLARA: Seems?
You've sentenced Rigsy to death.
Yet you don't know
exactly what's going on.
He was found over the body.
My people were angry, frightened.
I had to act.
CLARA: This is ridiculous. This is...
What was her name?
ASHILDR: Anna.
We're keeping her here until someone can
take her home for burial.
She's a Janus?
She escaped slavery.
She fled here with her child.
-The child, a daughter?
-No, a boy.
Is that bad?
No, it's not bad. It's just unhelpful.
A daughter might have
seen who killed her mother.
The female Janus is psychic.
One face sees into the future,
the other looks behind her
into the past.
CLARA: I think we saw her son outside.
RIGSY: Clara.
What if I did do it?
I mean, I wouldn't have
meant to hurt her, but...
What if I wandered in
and saw what she really looked like?
What if I freaked?
DOCTOR: You didn't just wander in here.
You were called here at 6:00 a.m.
By a number from a mystery phone.
There is no way you did this.
ASHILDR: So what then?
You think someone
called him here? Set him up?
Yes. Obviously.
Which means one of your
pet aliens out there
is the real killer.
-(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
-MAN: I just need to talk to her.
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Yes, please, go.
It's not like we've got
a ticking clock or anything.
MAN: Mayor, I'm begging you, please!
DOCTOR: Forty-one minutes.
MAN: Lock me up.
Throw us out.
Anything but this. Please.
I only took it to save her.
How many minutes left?
Two, Madam Mayor.
ASHILDR: This man stole medical rations.
He broke a rule of the street
and he stole from all of you.
And, yes, I can remove the Chronolock.
But I won't.
Our rules keep us safe.
Give it to me.
Please.
Tell me I can have it.
One word, say it.
Say yes.
I did this to save you,
you silly old thing.
You really think I could lose you now?
RIGSY: What's happening?
It's called a quantum shade.
It's kind of a spirit.
Once it's bound to a victim,
you can flee across
all of Time and all of the Universe,
and it would still find you.
(CROWS)
Don't run, stay with her.
(SOBS)
Don't go.
Why do they always run?
(WHIMPERING)
MAN: Help me somebody, please!
At least give him a merciful death.
You think a Cyberman
fears a merciful death?
MAN: Help me! Help me! Please!
Peace on this street
depends on one thing,
to break it in any way
is to face the raven.
MAN: Please, help me!
(CROWING)
(RAVEN CROWS)
(SCREAMING)
(WOMAN GASPS)
(WOMAN SOBS)
(CROWING)
I have no wish to harm your
friend if he is innocent, Doctor.
Question anyone.
Examine the body.
But it's not me you need to
convince of Rigsy's innocence.
It's them.
Okay, we split up, cover more ground.
I'm good cop, you're bad cop.
No, no, no, we don't have to...
Can I not be the good cop?
Doctor, we've discussed this.
Your face...
Oh, yeah.
Well, forget about cops, right.
Forget about finding the real killer.
You heard Ashildr.
All we have to do
is persuade these creatures
that it isn't Rigsy.
And fast!
(RIGSY SHUSHING)
Shh, baby girl, shh.
JEN: She's been like this all day.
Now, listen, you be good
for your mum for me, okay?
And I'm doing my best
to get home to you guys.
-She won't stop crying.
-RIGSY: Yeah. I know.
Yeah, she can probably
tell you're upset.
CLARA: Rump.
It's, um, Rump, isn't it?
That man's wife, she said something.
"Give it to me, tell me I can have it."
What did she mean?
Two ways to survive a quantum shade.
The shade's master
removes the Chronolock...
Or you can give it to someone else.
Give it? You can just...
No, you can't just push it on someone,
it's not that simple.
It must be taken willingly.
The death's already locked in.
You can pass it on, but...
You can't cheat it.
RIGSY: You're serious?
You actually expect me
to give you my death sentence?
Shh! Go on.
I've always wanted a tattoo.
You know, something small, discreet.
Clara, cut it out.
Look, weren't you listening?
I'm under the Mayor's
personal protection,
and it's absolute, apparently.
Look, she controls the Raven.
So I will never have to face it.
This is clever.
But this is putting you in danger.
No, this is us talking the
opposition into their own trap.
This is Doctor 101. We're buying time.
We get all of the aliens on our side,
in the next half an hour...
And then, we reveal
I've got the Chronolock, not you...
And boom!
We buy ourselves more time
to find the real killer.
The Doctor would never let you do this.
Doctor 102. Never tell anyone
your actual plan.
He'll have a tantrum when he finds out.
And then, when we confront Ashildr,
she'll want to take
the Chronolock off just to shut him up.
What happens if you don't go home
tonight, to Jen and Lucy, hey?
If you never go home?
You really want your little girl
growing up without a father
just because he wouldn't take a risk?
You trusted us to save you...
So trust us, come on!
Okay. All right.
All right, how do we do this, then?
Well, I was kind of hoping
that would be it.
I say I want it, you say can
have it, you know, done deal.
-(CHUCKLES)
-Hey, turn around, let me see.
(GASPS)
(CROWING)
(RIGSY CHUCKLES)
So, this your life then?
Just bouncing around time
saving people, right?
No, not every day.
(CHUCKLES) You know, sometimes,
Jane Austen and I prank each other.
Oh, she is the worst. I love her.
(SIGHS)
Take that how you like.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
DOCTOR: Are you sure it wasn't
someone from the street?
I told you already, there wasn't
anyone up that end of the street
except Anna and the human.
I've identified 27 different
species on the street so far.
Fifteen of whom
are known for aggression.
Why is it so hard to believe
that one of them is capable of murder?
Capable of murder, yeah.
Capable of killing Anna...
No.
Why not? What's so special about her?
It was the way she looked at you.
Like she understood.
One glance into your past
and she felt it all.
Every battle, every loss.
So you just want the human
dead, is that it?
You don't get it, do you?
If the human didn't do it
that means one of us did it.
Which means folks start pointing
fingers, turning on each other.
And once we turn
on each other in here, that's it.
I might as well be back in a war zone.
So you'll just let Rigsy die?
To keep the peace? Yeah, I will.
Your friend, acting like
he was all scared of us,
calling for a doctor.
-A what?
-I know.
The cheek of him.
Humans can survive losing entire limbs
and I'm supposed to believe that he...
Shut up! Shut up!
The other thing he said,
the second thing...
(STUTTERING)
You said he was scared and...
And he asked the Mayor
to call him a doctor.
-Poor Anna, dead at his feet...
-Shh.
Did he say a doctor or the Doctor?
This is very, very important.
The Doctor.
There was nothing wrong with him, mind.
It was all just your
standard human lies.
Clara gave you my number
for emergencies.
So when you wake up with
a weird tattoo on your neck
and no memory of the last 24 hours,
the first thing you do
is call the Doctor.
Call the Doctor?
But you find yourself accused of murder
on a strange alien street
in the middle of London...
Only they've taken your phone,
so you beg the woman in charge
to call me instead.
She knew you and I were friends.
So why'd she lie?
Unless she had something to hide.
ALIEN: Murderer!
DOCTOR: There's something
very wrong here.
And we're running out of time.
(CLEARS THROAT) There's 12 minutes left.
I'm not giving up yet.
Look, Clara.
Even if one of them knows something,
they're not gonna come forward.
The way they look at me.
The way they look at you?
RIGSY: What?
(KNOCKING)
CLARA: (WHISPERING) Hey, wait!
Everyone here is weird around us,
because of Rigsy, but not you.
You look at me and the Doctor
like you're confused.
Like you're curious.
-I don't know what you mean.
-You do.
You know Rigsy is innocent
because you can
look into his past and you can see it.
CLARA: Can't you?
She dressed you as a boy to protect you.
But, really, you're a girl.
You have the gift.
It is no gift.
I'm safe as a boy.
This is the first place
I have ever been safe
and you want me to throw it away?
To admit what I am?
The Mayor, what is she up to?
It's nothing good, is it?
I can't see everything.
But she thinks
she's doing the right thing.
They usually do.
If what Ashildr is doing is harmless,
then we will just walk out of that door.
No one will know of your abilities.
-But if it's not...
-I don't know what she means to do.
Now, I'm trying but I can't see it.
I can't see it because it involves you.
When I look at you,
I can't tell your past from your future
and there's so very much of both.
This isn't about Rigsy. It's about me!
She couldn't just ask you here.
She needed a mystery.
You can never resist a mystery.
-She's afraid.
-Afraid of what?
Of whom?
I can't see.
I'm sorry.
(CROWS)
You hold your tongue,
we've got 10 minutes left!
(CONTINUES CROWING)
Ashildr said Anna was being
taken home for burial.
But the Janus burn their dead.
RIGSY: Is that true?
So, look, Ashildr got it wrong.
What does it matter?
-Come on!
-There's something about this text.
Look, Doctor, we don't have time.
-What is it?
-DOCTOR: It looks like medical data.
But it can't be, she's dead.
She isn't breathing.
This thing is a stasis pod.
If you're dead,
it's a kind of fancy refrigerator.
-But if you're alive...
-(POD WHIRRING)
(SOFTLY) It simply keeps you that way.
She's alive?
-She's alive.
-Well, get her out...
Get her out of there!
There must be a way to unlock it.
Something basic, something simple...
A keyhole!
A keyhole would be very handy, yes.
But I haven't got...
No, no, no, no! A keyhole. Look!
-Look.
-I'll find her. I'll get the key.
No, Anahson, stay here.
There's a reason
that the Mayor has gone AWOL.
She means for us to release your mother.
But she doesn't want us to use her key.
She wants to use mine.
The Tardis.
That's what this is all about?
Doctor, wait!
DOCTOR: This girl needs her mother.
-(LOCK CLICKS)
-(GASPS)
-Doctor!
-(DOCTOR MUTTERING)
-(GROANS)
-What's it doing?
(CLATTERING)
(GASPING)
Mum!
ANAHSON: Mum, are you okay?
ASHILDR: She'll be perfectly
fine in a few moments.
I assure you.
There are easier ways
to steal a key, you know?
I don't want your Tardis.
That's not what this is about.
Rigsy, come here,
I'll remove your Chronolock.
What is this, Ashildr?
You can't possibly think
this is gonna keep me here?
It's not a restraint.
-It's a teleport bracelet.
-What?
I'll give you time
to say goodbye, don't worry.
No one will be hurt.
Where are you sending me?
I made a deal to protect this street.
They take you,
I take the keys, you can't be traced.
I do as they tell me
and the street is safe.
"They"? Who are they?
One more thing...
Your confession dial.
They have other means of procuring it
but I understand it's likely
to be on your person.
Please, no resistance.
You've already lost.
What is it?
In your terms,
my last will and testament.
How does it work?
I've no idea.
Well, thank you, anyway.
ASHILDR: Rigsy, your neck.
Clara, what are you playing at?
The Chronolock?
Take the teleport off him first.
Look, I don't have it,
I'm telling you. Clara does.
No.
No, you didn't.
Go on, then. Take it off.
Clara, you didn't!
(GASPS)
I had no idea
she'd do something so stupid.
(GASPING)
I swear!
I never meant for anyone to get hurt.
Look, what were you thinking?
Sacrificing yourself...
I wasn't sacrificing anything.
Strategy. Back-up plan
to buy us more time.
Who told you to go to her?
Nobody did. I did. Rump said.
What exactly did Rump say?
He said that death is locked in.
You can pass it on but you...
(SOFTLY) But what?
But...
ASHILDR: But you can't
cheat it altogether.
(CROWING)
Clara, you didn't tell me that.
Give it back to me, now!
She can't.
Clara, I made a contract with the shade
when I put the Chronolock on Rigsy.
I promised it a soul
and only I can break that contract.
When you took it from him,
you changed the terms.
You cut me out of the deal.
(CROWING)
We can fix this, can't we?
We always fix it.
No.
But you can. Fix this, fix it now!
It... It's not possible. I... I can't.
Yes, it is. You can.
And you will,
or this street will be over.
I'll show you and all your
funny little friends
to the whole laughing world.
I'll bring UNIT, I'll bring Zygons.
Give a minute,
I'll bring the Daleks and the Cybermen.
You will save Clara.
And you will do it now.
Or I will rain hell on you
for the rest of time.
Doctor, stop talking like that.
You can't.
I can do whatever the hell I like.
You've read the stories.
You know who I am.
And in all that time,
did you ever hear anything
about anyone who stopped me?
I know the Doctor. The Doctor...
The Doctor is no longer here.
You are stuck with me.
And I will end you
and everything you love.
Doctor, for God's sake will you stop?
-Now!
-I did this.
Do you hear me?
I did this. This is my fault.
-I don't care!
-Liar.
You always care. Always have.
Your reign of terror will end
with the sight of the first
crying child and you know it.
(SOFTLY) No, I don't.
I do.
Listen,
if this is the last
I ever see of you, please...
Not like this.
(RAVEN CROWING)
Is there anything you can do?
Sorry.
I'm truly sorry. I...
Time's short. Yes or no?
(SOFTLY) No.
Well, if Danny Pink can do it, so can I.
Do what?
Die right, die like I mean it.
Face the Raven.
No, this... This is...
This can't be happening.
Maybe this is what I wanted.
Maybe this is it.
Maybe this is why I kept running.
Maybe this is why
I kept taking all those stupid risks.
Kept pushing it.
This is my fault.
-This is my choice.
-I let you get reckless.
Why... Why shouldn't I be so reckless?
You're reckless all the bloody time.
Why can't I be like you?
Clara, there's nothing special about me.
I am nothing, but I am less
breakable than you.
I should've taken care of you.
-I never asked you to.
-You shouldn't have to ask.
-(CROWING)
-(CROWD GASPING)
-Clara, if I'd known...
-Don't! Shut up!
-But, I...
-Really, Rigsy, shut up!
If you feel guilty about this
even for one minute...
(RAVEN CROWING)
You...
Now, you listen to me,
you're gonna be alone now.
And you're very bad at that.
You're gonna be furious,
and you're gonna be sad.
But listen to me,
-don't let this change you.
-(MUTTERS)
No, listen, whatever happens next...
Wherever she is sending you...
I know what you're capable of.
You don't be a warrior.
Promise me.
Be a Doctor.
What's the point of being
a Doctor if I can't cure...
-Heal yourself.
-(EXHALES)
You have to.
You can't let this
turn you into a monster. So...
I'm not asking you for a promise,
I'm giving you an order.
You will not insult my memory.
There will be no revenge.
I will die,
and no one else here
or anywhere will suffer.
What about me?
If there was something I could
do about that, I would.
I guess we're both just
gonna have to be brave.
-Clara...
-(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
Everything you're about to say,
I already know.
Don't do it now.
We've already had enough bad timing.
(RAVEN CROWS)
Don't run.
Stay with me.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Nah.
You stay here.
In the end, everyone does this alone.
-Clara...
-This is as brave
as I know how to be.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
I know it's gonna hurt you
but, please...
Be a little proud of me.
(SIGHS)
Goodbye, Doctor.
(RAVEN CROWING)
(SIGHS)
(CROWS)
(WHISPERS) Let me be brave.
Let me be brave.
(CROWING)
(INAUDIBLY) Let me be brave.
(GASPS)
(INAUDIBLE SCREAMING)
ASHILDR: I'm sorry, Doctor.
I truly am.
(BEEPING)
What Clara said,
about not taking revenge,
do you know why she said that?
She was saving you.
I was lost a long time ago,
she was saving you.
I'll do my best.
But I strongly advise you
to keep out of my way.
You'll find that it's a very small
universe when I'm angry with you.
(BRACELET BEEPS)
(WHOOSHING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
DOCTOR: This whole place
is designed to terrify me.
(WHISPERS) I know you.
I've seen you before.
If you were any part
of killing her and you're not afraid,
then you understand nothing at all.
I am the Doctor.
I'm coming to find you
and I will never, ever stop.