(WIND HOWLING)
Ah!
(EXCLAIMS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
No.
(SCREAMING) No!
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENGINE HUMMING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Hello.
I'm Doctor Who.
And these are my plucky assistants.
Thing One and the Other One.
Bill, Nardole.
We picked up your distress call
and here we are to help,
like awesome heroes.
Yeah, we're not assistants. That's...
Okay, right.
So what does he call you? Companions?
Pets?
-Snacks?
-(ALARM BLARING)
Oh!
Someone's watching!
Well, it's
quite a good beat, really, isn't it?
Yeah. Maybe we should be moving on?
Yeah. And he calls us friends.
Ew, Doctor! Think of the age gap!
DOCTOR: (OVER RADIO)
Stop mucking about and concentrate.
Nardole, do something non-irritating.
NARDOLE: On it sir.
MISSY: Time Lords
are friends with each other, dear.
Everything else is cradle-snatching.
NARDOLE: Oh, it's a big one.
Ship reads as 400 miles long
and 100 miles wide.
It's big. Even for a colony ship.
Anything else?
Uh...
Hmm!
Ooh, look at that.
Finally. It's like watching plants grow.
It's heading towards a black hole!
-No.
-No, it isn't!
It was heading towards a black hole
until somebody noticed.
MISSY: Now they're trying
to reverse away from it.
Engines are on reverse thrust, see?
NARDOLE: Hmm.
Well, it's succeeding.
Very, very slowly.
It explains the distress call, I guess.
So. A 400-mile ship
reversing away
from the gravitational pull
of a black hole.
Are we having fun yet?
Mmm.
-(STATIC CRACKLING)
-Hello?
MAN: Who's there?
Hello? Please report status.
Oh! Hello.
What have we got here?
You're probably handsome, aren't you?
Well, congratulations
on your relative symmetry.
Who are you?
Well, I am that mysterious adventurer
in all of time and space
known only as Doctor Who.
And these are my disposables.
Exposition and Comic Relief.
We're not functions!
Darling, those were genders.
Please, stay exactly where you are
for your own safety.
He likes me! So exciting.
-I'm coming through.
-(STATIC CRACKLING)
Hurry, my stallion!
And if I'm in the shower,
just bring me some beans on toast!
-That's...
-Ugh.
That's roughly human flirting, isn't it?
So, why do you keep calling yourself
Doctor Who?
Because I'm pretending to be him,
because that's the whole point
of this ridiculous exercise.
It's not an exercise, it's a test.
Are you eating?
-No.
-MISSY: Yeah, well, don't test me
eating crisps!
Yeah, but he's called
"The Doctor", so...
But he says, "I'm the Doctor”,
and they say, "Doctor Who?"
See, I'm cutting to the chase, baby.
I'm streamlining.
-(SNAPPING FINGERS)
-I'm saving us actual minutes.
Yeah, okay, whatever. (SCOFFS)
-Also, it's his real name.
-It's what?
Look at the screens.
Slow today, Missy.
MISSY: All those screens have been
angled to a single view-point.
But not originally.
They've all been moved.
-Which means?
-Giant ship, single pilot.
But not designed that way.
Something's happened to the others.
Yes! And now it's time for you
to figure out what.
Uh-oh! Someone else has noticed us.
Sorry. What do you mean,
it's his real name?
Nobody knows the Doctor's real name.
I do. Because I grew up with him.
And his real name is Doctor Who!
Bill, she's just trying to wind you up.
He chose it himself. You know,
trying to sound mysterious.
And then he dropped the Who
when he realised
it was a tiny bit on the nose.
Stop teasing her and focus.
Is she serious, though, Doctor?
Is your real name Doctor Who?
Oh, you're blue! Nice.
I should go back to blue.
Stay where you are!
DOCTOR:
Stay calm! He's very frightened.
Dearie me, I thought you were handsome!
Now you've gone all cross
and you're pointing a gun at me.
Is this the emotion
you humans call spanking?
Are there only three of you?
-Are any of you human?
-MISSY: What has happened to this ship
and how long have you been here alone?
You're looking very sickly.
Two days. Are you human?
-Oh, don't be a bitch.
-How did you get on board?
-MAN: Is that your capsule?
-Yep!
-No!
-There. Look!
MAN: Three lifts. They're coming!
What's in this ship?
Super-fast inertia lifts.
Well, what's inside?
What's coming up here?
Things! Uh...
I don't even know where they came from.
One of you must be human.
They only come up
if they detect human life signs!
-What for?
-MAN: They take them away.
So those are the lift doors, yeah?
That's where they come out?
I'll be right with you.
Which of you is human?
Me! (STAMMERING) Me, I'm human.
I'm the only one. Just... Just me.
Please, stop this.
Stop right there. Now.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry,
but you're the reason
that they're coming.
Put it down. Put that down now.
They won't come if she's dead.
You don't need to do this.
I can get her off the ship.
I can shield her life signs.
You know what, Doctor?
I said this was a bad idea.
Please, listen to me. Look at me!
DOCTOR: Come on, look at me!
That's good.
That's very, very good.
Now, do you see this madwoman
sitting in this chair?
-Her name isn't Doctor Who.
-(SMACKS LIPS)
My name is Doctor Who.
-It's not, is it?
-I like it.
You don't know it yet,
but in a short time,
you will trust me with your life.
And when I save you
and everyone on your ship,
one day you will look back
and wonder who I was,
-or why I...
-(GRUNTS)
(SIZZLING)
(GRUNTING)
BILL: Doctor, this is a bad idea.
DOCTOR: No, it's a good idea.
A test run. She thinks she could be me.
Let's try her out.
-Why?
-She got us home from Mars.
She's a murderer!
Enjoying your bacon sandwich?
-Why?
-Because it had a mummy and a daddy.
Go tell a pig
about your moral high ground.
I pick a scenario,
we drop her down into it,
and we see how she does.
How does that work?
Ah. We're just
take the TARDIS for a spin,
and we graze for distress calls.
We'll pick a good one.
Our usual Saturday.
And, uh... What if she just walks out
and slaughters everyone,
just for a laugh?
Well, I will be monitoring you
the whole time.
-Me?
-Yes.
You and Nardole.
You can be her companions. Hey!
(LAUGHING) Nah, forget it.
Absolutely no way.
Nardole agreed.
No, I didn't!
You did in my head,
which is good enough for me.
Why do you want to do this?
She's my friend!
She's my oldest friend in the Universe.
Well, you've got lots of friends!
Better ones.
-What's so special about her?
-She's different.
Different how?
I don't know.
Yes, you do.
She's the only person I've ever met
who's even remotely like me.
Uh...
So, more than anything,
you want her to be good?
Are you having an emotion?
I know I can help her.
Yeah! Look at that face.
He's having an emotion.
Yeah. Yes, look at that bit.
Yeah, he's doing emotion.
-Oh, leave him alone.
-Can I take a selfie with you?
-(SHUTTER CLICKS)
-DOCTOR: She was my first friend.
Always so brilliant.
From the first day at the Academy.
So fast. So funny!
-She was my man-crush.
-What, I'm sorry?
Yeah.
I think she was a man back then.
I'm fairly sure that I was, too.
It was a long time ago, though.
So, Time Lords...
A bit flexible on the whole
man-woman thing then, yeah?
We're the most civilised civilisation
in the Universe.
We're billions of years beyond
your petty human obsession with gender
and its associated stereotypes.
But you still
call yourselves Time "Lords"?
-Yeah, shut up.
-(CHUCKLES)
Okay.
We had a pact, me and him.
Every star in the Universe,
we were going to see them all.
But he was too busy burning them.
I don't think she ever saw anything.
And you think that if she did,
she'd change?
I know she would.
I know it.
(SCOFFS) You're a bloody idiot,
you know that, yeah?
Of course.
She scares me.
Like, she really scares me.
Okay. So promise me one thing.
Yeah?
Just promise you won't get me killed.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
I'm sorry.
-I can't promise you that!
-(CHUCKLING) Thanks.
I mean, look.
You're human!
-And humans are so mortal.
-Cheers!
I mean, you pop like balloons.
I mean, one heart?
It's your most important organ
and you have no back-up!
It's like a budget cut.
Or you could try and keep me alive.
DOCTOR: Within reason.
BILL: Thanks, mate.
-(LIFT BELL DINGS)
-(DOOR OPENING)
What are they?
NARDOLE: What are those things?
You're too late. She's dead.
Don't you touch her.
Don't you lay a finger on her.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Stand. Away. Stand. Away.
She will be repaired.
-Repaired?
-Stand. Away.
You can help her, is that what you mean?
Where are you going?
What are you gonna do with her?
Repair.
Don't try to stop them.
They'll snap you in half.
When do you bring her back?
We will not.
Wait for me.
DOCTOR: (ECHOING) Wait for me.
-What are you doing?
-Leaving a message in her subconscious.
How? She's dead.
Those things are going to repair her,
so clearly, she isn't.
-Assumption.
-Deduction.
-Hope.
-Faith.
-Idiot.
-Always.
Sir, step away from those doors.
You'll bring them back.
What do you care, Smurf?
They're not even interested in you.
Sir, I swear to you.
Step away from that lift
or I will kill you.
Don't. You will only make me angry.
-Honey, listen to him.
-Why?
Because if somebody kills you
and it's not me,
we'll both be disappointed.
Now, you! What were those things?
I don't know.
How can you not know?
They're on your ship.
MAN: The ship is supposed to be empty.
-But it's a colony ship.
-Because it's brand-new.
The colonies haven't arrived yet.
MAN: We were on our way to pick them up.
A skeleton crew.
Fifty of us, that's all.
-(MACHINE BEEPING)
-Well, it's not empty now, is it? Look!
Thousands of life readings.
Two days ago, there was nothing.
Those readings came out of nowhere.
-Well, obviously you were boarded.
-No!
MISSY: Your ship was taken over.
It happens.
-DOCTOR: No.
-Doctor?
This is worse than I thought.
Much worse.
Fifty of you taking your brand new ship,
fresh from the factory,
to pick up some colonists?
-Yes.
-Two days ago,
you almost bump into a black hole.
What did you do then?
We tried to reverse out of it.
And you sent a team down
to the other end of the ship
to reverse the rear thrusters, yes?
-MAN: Yes.
-How many people in the team?
About 20.
And you never heard from them again.
And then the whole ship just lit up
with all these new life forms, correct?
-Exactly!
-What happened then?
Those creatures arrived.
Took the rest of the humans away.
They weren't interested in me.
I tried to fight them
but they were too strong.
Well, maybe something came out
of the black hole?
Nothing comes out of a black hole.
Nothing boarded this ship.
I'm afraid you will never
see your crew again.
Black hole, 400-mile spaceship...
It's a matter of time.
Pay attention.
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Hello.
Back with us?
-(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
-No, don't try to speak. Just relax.
You'll be fine.
Full conversion wasn't necessary.
Though it will be in time.
Sleep now.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
Oh, awake, is it? Awake now. Good.
Settle.
(BILL GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(GASPING)
Wait for me.
(GASPING) Doctor!
DISTANT AUTOMATED VOICE: Pain.
Pain.
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPING)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
Pain.
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
(AUTOMATED VOICE GROWING LOUDER) Pain.
Pain.
-(BUTTON CLICKING REPEATEDLY)
-Pain.
Pain.
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Who's making all that noise?
Who is it?
(GRUNTING)
Pain.
-All right. What's the matter with you?
-Pain.
-Hmm?
-Making all that fuss.
-Pain.
Pain.
See now...
-Pain.
-WOMAN: Hmm.
-Huh.
-Pain. Pain.
That's better, isn't it?
All right, then, Mr Razor.
I'll just go do the rounds.
-Now I'm here.
-Rounds. Yes, it is.
Rounds. Good. Yes.
(METAL CLANKING)
-(VOLUME INCREASES)
-Pain.
Pain.
Sorry, mate.
-Pain.
-I'm really sorry.
AUTOMATED VOICE: (GROWING LOUDER)
Kill me. Kill me.
Kill me.
-Kill me.
-Sorry! Sorry.
Sorry.
WOMAN: This way, Mr Razor!
Look sharp.
(RUSTLING)
(GASPING)
Would you like some tea?
This way. This way!
What about him?
He's all right. They don't feel pain.
I think they do.
Yes, they do.
So why did you say they don't?
It was a clever lie.
But you see straight through me.
Come. Tea! This way.
What are those things?
People, people, people, people, people!
People, they are people.
Then what are you doing to them?
Curing them.
Come on.
Psst!
In here.
You want the good tea, or the bad tea?
What's the difference?
I call one "good”, one "bad".
Ah, I'll take the good one...
Excellent. Positive attitude,
will help with the horror to come.
What horror?
Mainly the tea.
(CHUCKLES)
(TEA POURING)
Where am I?
Hospital.
Uh, yeah, but where?
The ship. You are on the ship.
I was on a ship, yeah, but it...
Wasn't like this.
You were at top of the ship,
and now you are at bottom.
Ship.
Top. Bottom.
See?
Yes.
How did I get here?
You were sick, very sick.
Broken. Heart broken.
New heart, good, is it?
Ah, I haven't dared look yet...
Is good. Is very good.
Shiny.
You can... Carry it off.
Not everybody can.
For some people,
it all goes a bit... You know.
What?
Vending machine.
-(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
-(LAUGHS)
Drink it while it is very hot,
the pain will disguise the taste.
Thanks.
How long have I been here?
Oh, weeks.
Many weeks, maybe months.
God.
Is good! You get strong.
Yeah, well, I came here with people,
my friends.
Oh, well...
They don't look so bad.
That's them? That's my friends?
I know, I make picture for you.
-You like?
-Where are they now? Are they okay?
Oh, they're fine, look at them.
Yeah, but are they okay now?
That is now.
Is right now. That is them, is live.
Yeah, but they're...
The picture is frozen.
No.
Yeah, it is.
They're not moving, look at them.
They are at top of ship.
Top of ship very slow.
We are at bottom. Bottom much faster.
Very fast bottom.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I don't understand.
Ah...
So, you don't know.
About what?
Short version.
DOCTOR: Because of the black hole,
time is moving faster
at this end of the ship than the other.
It's all about gravity.
(SIGHS)
Gravity slows down time.
The closer you are
to the source of gravity,
the slower time will move.
If you're standing in your garden
your head is travelling faster
through time than your feet.
Don't they teach you this stuff
at space school?
See, he's raising the eyebrow.
That's his sarcasm face.
He's making a joke.
He's been raising
that eyebrow for a week.
So, when are you gonna tell me?
-Tell you what?
-How I can get back up there.
I already told you,
you can't leave here, I'm sorry.
What are you doing in here?
She works for me now, we agreed.
Everyone here works for me.
There's a floor out there.
Needs cleaning.
Running all the way.
I know you dream of leaving.
No... Me?
Never.
-(METAL CLANKING)
-This is your heart now,
but outside this hospital,
it will stop working.
Well, it's a good thing
you've got all those locks then.
In case I accidentally wander off.
Yeah, better get mopping.
Don't change the channel.
A week raising his eyebrow,
why would I change?
Space school? (CLEARS THROAT)
Um, I'm basically the janitor.
-(MISSY CLEARS THROAT)
-Well, that's a good job.
But you gotta concentrate, Paul.
Now, listen.
BILL: He's gonna do an explanation.
That always takes a while.
The months will fly by.
(LAUGHS)
A black hole isn't just any old gravity.
DOCTOR: It's Superman gravity.
If you really want to slow down time,
park next to one of these guys.
Trouble is...
One end of the ship is closer
to the Superman gravity than the other.
(BEEPING)
-(WIND HOWLING)
-(WINDOW CREAKS OPENS)
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GASPS)
(BEEPING STOPS)
(SIGHS)
-(GASPS)
-Wait for me.
(CLOCK TICKING)
How much longer, Doctor?
How many more years?
What about these lifeforms?
What are they? Where did they come from?
MAN: How can there be so many?
Those are the descendants
of your crew mates.
DOCTOR: Two days for you,
generations for them.
-What are these...
-Look!
(EXCLAIMS)
BILL: What kind of treatment is that?
Why won't you ever explain?
I do explain.
They are the special patients.
When do those bag things
come off their heads?
They don't.
They don't?
Conversion is permanent.
Why?
We are dying.
All of us on this ship, dying.
(DOOR OPENING)
They are the cure.
They are the future.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Tie me.
Tie me.
To survive,
they are what we must all become.
I will show you.
-Where are we going?
-Outside.
You always want to go outside,
we go outside.
DOCTOR: Wait for me.
Wait for me.
Psst!
(BABY CRYING)
Everyone looks so sick.
This was a good place once.
Hundreds of years ago,
when the settlers first came here.
But this ship is old.
Everything is dying.
Our world is rust.
Our air is engine fumes.
So, we must evolve to survive.
But, evolution is not fast enough.
The special patients, they are strong.
Soon, we will all be upgraded like them.
-BILL: They're in pain.
-The pain will be cured.
And the exodus will begin.
Exodus?
Operation Exodus.
We will leave this city.
We will climb up, through the ship,
and we will take command.
Well, you could just go up right now.
We have to be strong.
There are lifts.
There are many dangers.
I've been up there.
There's a friend of mine, he could help.
You do not understand
the dangers.
Many years ago, there was
an expedition, to floor 507.
The largest of the solar farms.
And?
Silence.
They never came back.
There is something up there.
And we must be strong.
-(BUZZING)
-(GASPS)
-WOMAN: Return to the hospital.
-I don't...
You see, my dear?
You must be strong,
to leave the hospital.
And you will be. Soon, very soon.
-(BILL GROANING)
-WOMAN: Return to the hospital.
-(GRUNTS)
-Sorry.
Pressed for time.
NARDOLE: That was good!
Venusian Aikido.
I thought you needed
four arms for Venusian.
I've got hidden talents,
as well as hidden arms.
(YAWNS)
NARDOLE: But it's been 10 minutes,
so, she must have been down there
-for years.
-Yeah.
NARDOLE: We could take the TARDIS,
go back, and get it right.
This close to a black hole, we'll never
be able to pilot her accurately.
BILL: Do you think
they're coming down here?
Because if they are,
where does that lift arrive?
Just asking.
You are dear to me.
You are my dearest person.
-You are like...
-I know.
A mother to me.
Definitely not a mother.
Or an aunt.
No.
But this question you must not ask.
(EXHALES) Why not?
Because if you do,
I think I might tell you.
Aw, sorry, mate.
-Guess what I'm about to do.
-Do not. Do not do this.
I'm gonna ask you again.
(SIGHS)
When you hug me...
It hurts my heart.
Aw.
Sweet.
No, your chest unit, it digs right in.
BILL: You sure about the mask?
-MR RAZOR: Is burgling mask.
-Why?
-Just in case.
-In case of what?
Shh!
BILL: But it's locked.
-Where did you get that?
-I have burglary skills.
They don't let just anyone
wear a mask like this, you know.
It's got your name on the label.
I also have key to operating theatre.
I clean up on Wednesdays.
(BILL GASPS)
-(PANTING)
-It's all right, it's all right.
It's just, you know, work in progress.
So, these lifts, where do we find them?
It's through there, somewhere.
Oh! I like the hat.
I'm going to ask for a hat
when it's my turn.
BILL: Your turn?
No, actually,
I'm afraid, Miss Potts, it's your turn.
Thank you for bringing her, Mr Razor.
Ah, you see through my clever disguise.
Stupid thing.
You... You didn't?
Please, tell me you didn't.
Is for your own good.
Make you strong.
Ready for the Exodus.
I'm sorry about the deception.
It's best to get people in here
without them knowing why.
You don't want screaming
in the main part of the hospital.
Don't you touch me!
Don't you lay a finger on me.
This unit of yours won't last forever,
you know.
You need the full upgrade.
You're not gonna turn me
into one of those things.
I'm rebuilding you, to survive
in a world not made for flesh.
But, look at them.
They're screaming in pain
every second they're alive!
But, we've got something for that now.
This won't stop you
feeling pain, but, uh...
It will stop you caring about it.
It fits over your head.
Okay, you two,
welcome to a new time-zone.
Not knowing the differential,
I don't know how much time
has passed here.
(CLOCK TICKING)
Right, we have to find out
more about this ship.
On it.
No, Missy, you do it.
Nardole, you come with me.
But, I'm the computer guy.
That's always me!
Sorry, she's cleverer.
-She's more evil.
-Same thing.
-It really isn't.
-No, it is a little bit.
Little bit the same.
-Anyway...
-Yes, thank you.
DOCTOR: Nardole!
Hello.
Hello, ordinary person.
Please maintain
a minimum separation of three feet.
I'm really trying
not to kill anyone today.
It would be tremendously helpful
if your major arteries
were out of reach.
(LAUGHS)
I have been so looking forward
to meeting you.
Right, well...
I'm very happy for you.
MR RAZOR: I was watching you
on the screen.
It took me a while
to work out who you were.
(YELPS)
(EXHALES)
There's always a scary thing with you,
isn't there?
You're only getting that now?
Oh, this is super interesting.
I assumed this ship was from Earth,
full of squishable,
little humans, but...
-It's not from Earth at all, is it?
-You don't remember me, do you?
MISSY: Looks like an Earth-like planet,
but not Earth itself.
Very Earth-like! If planets had twins...
You don't remember being here before,
do you?
I've never been here before.
Will you please stop whittering on,
or I'll have to splat your brains
for finger paint.
Oh, you have been here before,
you really can trust me on that.
(MUMBLING) Planet... Which planet...
NARDOLE: Hmm,
there's a lot of genetics...
Bio-engineering...
There's a lot of stuff
about something called Exodus.
Operation Exodus.
(MACHINES BEEPING)
Look at that. This ship is from Mondas.
(ROBOTIC WHIRRING)
It's a Cyberman!
A Mondasian Cyberman!
-Doctor!
-Doctor Who! Doctor, Doctor!
(LAUGHING)
Okay, listen to me.
I may be about to take
that silly, little gun from you...
He'll never forgive you, you know.
He'll never set you free.
Not when he discovers
what you did to his little friend.
I haven't done anything
to his silly, little friend.
Oh, but I'm afraid you did.
A long time ago.
DOCTOR: You're brand new.
Fresh out of the factory,
you're not ready for a fight yet.
He does look a little bit ready.
Bill Potts, do you know where she is?
Where is Bill Potts?
(IN ROBOTIC VOICE) Doctor.
You know me?
You are Doctor.
Am I supposed to know
what you're talking about?
Would it help you focus
if I extracted some of your vital organs
and made a lovely soup?
You would never be so...
Self-destructive.
So what?
But then again...
Neither would I.
Listen, we mean you no harm.
We're just passing through.
We're looking for Bill Potts,
friend of mine.
-Bill Potts?
-Yes!
Bill Potts, you're a Cyberman.
You're part of a neural net,
can you find her?
I love disguises.
Do you still like disguises?
Of course, they are rather necessary
when you happen to be
-someone's former prime minister.
-(GASPS)
-Accessing Bill Potts.
-Get back from it.
Locating Bill Potts.
I am Bill Potts.
Hello, Missy.
I'm The Master.
I'm very worried about my future.
Give us a kiss.
Bill?
Bill, talk to me.
DOCTOR: What've they done to you?
Operation Exodus.
NARDOLE: Whatever that is.
MISSY: Oh, wrong name, for a start.
I waited.
MISSY: This is not an exodus, is it?
More of a beginning, really.
Isn't it?
I waited.
THE MASTER: In fact,
do you know what I'd call it?
(GASPS)
I'd call it a genesis.
You've met the ex.
Specifically, the genesis
of the Cybermen.
I waited for you.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
MISSY: The whole city is a machine
to turn people into Cybermen.
What do you think?
It's exciting, isn't it?
DOCTOR: You know the stories.
There's only ever been one way
to stop that many Cybermen.
Me!
Stand with me.