(BELL TOLLING)
NARRATOR: In London,
in the time of Queen Victoria,
there were many tales
of a remarkable personage
known as the Great Detective.
I refer, of course, to Madame Vastra,
the lizard woman of Paternoster Row
and her extraordinary adventures,
her beautiful assistant Jenny Flint
and their mysterious henchman Strax,
whose countenance was too abominable
to be photographed.
What?
There are also accounts of a fourth
member of the Paternoster Gang,
a shadowy figure whose assistance was
only sought in the direst emergencies.
I'm so glad you came.
We have news, I think,
of particular interest to you.
There was a meteor shower
in the southwest,
unexpected timing and density.
I have calculated there is a 34% chance
it is the result of alien intervention.
Twenty-four percent.
Well, they could just be meteors
but it's worth looking into.
There is a very pleasant tea room
in the area.
Also, there's a Professor Erasmus Pink,
who's claiming he's going to
split the world open with a giant drill
through the thinnest part
of the Earth's crust.
I think we should investigate.
I mean,
he doesn't actually have a giant drill
and he's not really a professor
and he was a bit drunk at the time
and singing a bit
but, you know, it's never too early
to investigate a drill.
I've declared war on the moon!
-Do be quiet, Strax.
-(SIGHS)
Too long the moon has hung unmonitored
and unsuspected in the sky.
It has gained
an enormous tactical advantage.
There's no one living there.
Then it is clearly time to act.
They won't suspect a thing.
Who won't suspect a thing?
Moonites.
Why do you keep doing this?
What is the point?
I have told you,
I keep telling you,
I don't do this any more.
I've retired.
There's a man on Praed Street
with an invisible wife.
Maybe he just doesn't have a wife.
You're wasting your time.
Merry Christmas!
I think he means it.
Yes, my dear. I rather think he does.
Damn moon.