(PHONE RINGING)
-DANNY: Clara?
-CLARA: Shut up.
-Is that how we communicate now?
-Shut up, shut up! Shut up!
I need to talk to you!
All right, well I'll be there
in a couple of minutes, so...
-No, not while you're in the room!
-Stupid me. The very idea!
-Shut up!
-Okay.
-Stay, shut up!
-(LAUGHS) Okay.
Things to say. Not all of them good.
Wouldn't it be better if
I was actually there?
Oh, Danny, everything is better when
you're here, but maybe...
Maybe not this.
Okay.
Um...
Okay, before all of that.
Before all of the stuff
that I did wrong.
I love you.
No, not like that. Not like
it's automatic. Not like it's
how you end the phone call,
the sign off, the pat on the back.
-Clara?
-Danny, I'll never say
those words again.
Not to anybody else, ever.
Those words, from me, are yours now.
So, erm...
That's a thing.
Okay? Danny?
Erm... There's more,
but that's kind of the headline.
Okay, Danny? Please speak
to me, this is killing me.
Danny, I love you,
and you are the last person
who is ever going to hear me say that.
WOMAN: Hello?
Hello, is someone there?
Hello, er... Yeah, who is this?
WOMAN: I just picked up the phone,
I'm sorry.
-I found it.
-Oh, okay, uh...
Could you please just put me back on
the phone to Danny,
I was talking to Danny.
Sorry. I'm so sorry!
Okay, what are you sorry about?
Could you please just
pass phone back to...
WOMAN: He was crossing the road,
I found the phone.
It must have just got thrown...
The car, it just came out of nowhere.
I'm so sorry.
(SIRENS BLARING)
(PANTING)
MAN: By now, I'm sure that you've
heard the rumours,
and it is with great sadness that
I must confirm them to be true.
I have gathered you all
here today to say that Mr Pink,
Danny Pink, has sadly passed away.
I'm sure you'll all join me in wishing
his family and friends
our sincerest condolences.
Mr Pink was an inspiration
to all of those who knew him.
A soldier, a teacher, a friend. It was
no secret that he had a close
relationship with Miss Oswald, and our
thoughts and prayers are with her too.
(PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Hello, love. You all right?
Of course you're not.
Sorry, of course you're not all right.
You know what you should do?
You should cry. Let go.
Of what?
It's a terrible thing.
Just a terrible, terrible thing.
-It wasn't terrible.
-Clara?
It was boring.
Boring?
It was ordinary.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
People just kept walking,
with their iPods
and their shopping bags.
He was alive, and then he was dead,
and it was nothing.
Like stepping off a bus.
He deserved better. And so did you.
I don't deserve anything.
Nobody deserves anything.
But I am owed better.
I am owed.
Who owes you?
DOCTOR: Clara! Clara?
Hey!
Sorry, I was busy. What's happening?
Oh, nothing. You know,
same old, same old.
Well, you're only human.
So what I can do for you, Clara?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(GASPS)
Clara?
-Start her up!
-Where are we going?
-Away.
-From?
-Just away.
-Normally you say work, or kids,
or dishes,
or dullness. What's happened?
-A volcano.
-I'm sorry?
I've never seen an active volcano,
do you know one?
What's so good about seeing a volcano?
It's just a sort of leaky mountain.
I've never seen lava.
It's rubbish.
Prove it.
It's on your neck.
Do you still have those
sleep patch things?
You can't have one.
-I'm having trouble sleeping.
-You still can't have one.
-Can I have one?
-No, you can't have one.
So, volcano.
What's so good about lava?
(EXPLODING)
(GASPS)
You told me once what it would take to
destroy a Tardis key.
That's what's so good about lava.
All seven.
From all of your hiding places.
Clara? What are you doing?
Don't! Be very, very careful,
with that. Those are very, very...
Do I have your attention?
-Yes.
-Good.
No. Not good, Clara.
Danny Pink.
Yes?
CLARA: Is dead.
And?
-Seriously?
-And.
And fix it.
Change it. Change what happened.
Save him. Bring him back.
No.
Five left. Every time you say no to me,
I will throw another key down there.
Do we understand each other?
Well. I understand you. Let's not get
carried away.
Time can be rewritten.
With precision. With great care.
And not today.
But you know that of course,
otherwise you wouldn't
be threatening me.
Did you just say no?
If I change the events
that brought you here,
you will never come here and ask
me to change those events.
Paradox loop, the time
line disintegrates,
your time line. And yes.
-Yes?
-Yes.
I did just said no.
Throw away the key.
I have seen you change time.
I have seen you break
any rule you want.
I know when I can, and I know when
I can't. Throw the key.
I know what you're doing.
You're trying to take control.
I am in control. Throw away the key.
Do as you are told.
No!
Well, either you do as you're told,
or stop threatening me.
There really isn't a third option here.
Do you know what, Doctor?
When it comes to taking control,
you really are out of your depth.
One last chance, and I don't
care about the rules.
I don't give a damn about paradoxes.
Save Danny, bring him back, or I swear
you will never step inside
your Tardis again.
-No.
-Do as you are told.
-Say it again so I know you mean it.
No.
-I'm not kidding, Doctor.
-Neither am I.
I will do it.
No, Clara. My Clara.
I don't think you will.
I'd say I'm sorry, but I'd do it again.
(CLARA SOBBING)
CLARA: I'd do it again.
Well. What are you doing, why are you
just going to stand there?
Do you understand
what I have just done?
-Look in your hand.
-There's nothing in my hand.
-Clara, look in your hand.
-The keys, they're gone.
They're down there.
Clara, Clara, look in your hand.
-There's nothing in my hand.
-Yes. Yes, there is, look.
Did you seriously think that
that was gonna work on me?
They're not sleep patches,
they induce a dream state.
Makes you very suggestible.
I allowed the whole scenario
to play out just as you planned.
I was curious about how
far you would go.
-Well. Now you know.
-Yeah, now I know.
I love him.
Yes, you're quite the mess
of chemicals, aren't you?
So, what now?
What do we do now? You and me,
what happens now?
Doctor?
Go to hell.
Fair enough.
Absolutely, fair enough.
Clara?
You asked me what we're going to do.
I told you. We're going to hell.
Or wherever it is people go
when they die.
If there is anywhere. Wherever it
is, we're going there,
and we're going to find Danny.
And if it is in any way possible,
we are going to bring him home.
Almost every culture in the universe
has some concept of an afterlife.
I always meant to have a
look around, see if I can find one.
-You're going to help me?
-Well, why wouldn't I help you?
-Because of what I did. I just tried...
-You betrayed me.
You betrayed my trust,
you betrayed our friendship,
you betrayed everything
that I've ever stood for.
You let me down!
Then why are you helping me?
Why?
Do you think I care for you so
little, that betraying me
would make a difference?
Stop it with the eyes.
Don't do that with the eyes.
How do you do that anyway,
it's like they inflate!
And cut out the whining
while you're at it.
We've got work to do. This is
it, Clara, one of those moments.
-What moments?
-The darkest day, the blackest hour.
Chin up, shoulders back, let's see what
we're made of, you and I.
Switching off the safeguards.
Turning off the nav-com.
Remember we did this before?
We plugged you into the
Tardis telepathic interface.
We ended up all over
Danny's time stream.
Because you and he are linked,
strongly linked.
Your time streams are intertwined.
So if he's anywhere at all, that
link will hold. Give me your hands.
-Doctor...
-We're in a hurry.
I don't deserve a friend like you.
Clara, I'm terribly sorry, but I am
exactly what you deserve.
Think about Danny.
Think about the man you lost.
Let it hurt. Let it burn.
But don't bleat.
Don't ask, why him? Why me?
Forget all that. Ask one question.
Just one.
Ask, where is Danny Pink now?
Where is he now?
(MACHINE CLANGING)
Well! The Tardis thinks he's somewhere.
Has anyone offered you a coffee?
Um...
Well, no...
Could we have some coffee along here
please? The good kind,
we've got a new one.
Five minutes, tops.
Best to wait for the good coffee.
Where am I?
Because sometimes, it's just the
instant, and oh...
-Where am I?
-Well. Big question.
We try to take that one slowly.
We have been trying to
contact family members,
but really, there's so much admin...
I wasn't here, I was...
Yeah. That last thing
that happened to you.
It really happened, I'm afraid.
But that's life.
Well! Not life, I suppose.
There are some forms to fill in.
They might help you relax.
Well, they won't,
but we do need them filled in.
Right, important thing. Need to know.
Are you being cremated?
Sorry, it's a fairly urgent question.
I don't know. Never really
thought about it.
I'm going to put you down as a 'yes',
that's pretty much
the default these days.
-God, if people only knew...
-Only knew what?
We've got a burner in No. 12,
tell them to prep please.
-A burner?
-Yeah, it's fine, we'll come to that.
I don't understand where I am.
(GASPS)
Oh! Look at that!
You can see my house from here!
Yeah, sorry, probably not helping.
Where am I?
Um. You sort of know, don't you?
Most people kind of know, it's just hard
to get traction on the concept.
Where am I?
Okay. You're dead.
And this is what's next.
I'm not dead! How can I be dead?
Our sincere condolences.
-I'm standing right here!
-Yes, you are.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Otherwise known as the Nethersphere,
or the Promised Land.
It's where you go when you die.
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Would you like to breathe into a bag?
Where are we?
Nav-com's offline, we'll have to do
this old school.
But this is where Danny is?
Almost certainly not. It's where
there's a connection with Danny.
According to the Tardis, this is
where it's most likely
that your timeline will re-intersect
with his, and that won't do.
-What won't?
-You won't, look at you.
I need sceptical, clever,
critical. I don't need mopy.
It puts years on your face.
What if people see us together?
-You look like you've been melted.
-Are you forgetting why we're here?
We're here to get your boyfriend back
from the dead,
so buck up and give me some attitude.
CLARA: Fish tanks?
In a mausoleum?
-What does that mean?
-It means those are
definitely not fish tanks.
-Why?
-I don't know.
Okay. I'm assuming they didn't
actually drown in there.
No. They were placed, after death.
These are tombs.
Water tombs, some sort of fluid, anyway.
-With chairs?
-With chairs, yes.
Extra comfort for the deceased.
It pays to die rich.
Oh, God.
Am I going to find Danny now?
Is that why the Tardis brought us here?
-I don't want to see him like that.
-Good point.
Tombs with windows!
Who wants to watch their loved ones rot?
Why would anyone go to so much trouble
just to keep watch on the dead?
(CRACKING)
(WHOOSHING)
WOMAN: 3.
Death is not an end.
But we can we help with that.
Ever since 3W encountered the truth
about the death experience,
we have been working hard to
find a better life for the deceased.
At 3W, afterlife means after-care.
Okay. Bit strange?
Very.
Why have the scrolling
and a voice?
-Is it difficult?
-Is what difficult?
Reading all those words back to front?
Come on. We've come a long way.
Hello. I hope you are well.
How may I assist you with your death?
Well, there is er... No immediate hurry.
We're just, er... We're just...
(STUTTERING)
-Browsing.
-Yeah, yeah, browsing.
Please take all the time you need.
At 3W, you always have the rest
of your life.
Oh, good. That's good to know,
isn't that good, Clara?
Yeah. Great.
-Exactly what is 3W?
-Apologies.
Clearly you have not received
the official 3W greetings package.
Well, no, it's just an unexpected...
(EXHALES)
(GASPS)
Welcome to the 3W Institute.
Clara, is it over now?
I think it's over, yeah.
You also have not received the official
welcome package...
Oh, I'm good, thanks, no worries!
-Who are you?
-I am Missy.
-Missy?
-Mobile Intelligent Systems Interface.
I am a multi-function, interactive,
welcome-droid,
helping you, to help me, to help you.
You're very...
...realistic.
-Tongues?
-Shut up.
I am fully programmed
with social interaction norms
appropriate to a range of visitors.
Please indicate if you'd like me
to adjust my intimacy settings.
Oh, yes, please, please, do that,
do that now right now, yes.
Maybe just a tad, yeah.
I need to speak to
whoever's in charge here.
I am in charge.
Well, who's in charge of you?
I am in charge of me.
Well, who repairs you?
Who... Who... Who maintains you?
I am programmed for self-repair.
I am maintained by my heart.
(GASPS)
MISSY: Is everything in order?
Who maintains your heart?
My heart is maintained by the Doctor.
Doctor who?
Dr Chang!
CHANG: Who's there?
-Hello?
-Hello.
DOCTOR: Hello.
You can probably take your hand
down now, Doctor.
So. Hey. Condolences.
Condolences?
CHANG: It's a mausoleum. It's our hello.
Is there a particular dead person
you want to talk to?
-(VOICES WHISPERING)
-Yes.
Yes, there is.
This way then?
Are you okay?
No.
Good. There would be
something very wrong if you were.
(LAUGHS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(HORNS HONKING)
A bit of fresh air will do you good.
DANNY: Why's it so cold here?
SEB: And the Wi-Fi's better out here.
Don't know why.
-Wi-Fi?
-Still a bit spotty, but basically...
You have Wi-Fi here? You...
You have iPads in the afterlife?
iPads? We have Steve Jobs!
Listen, erm, another big question,
for you.
Have you ever killed anybody?
This is surreal.
Imagine embryos had telephones.
-Really not helping.
-Go with me. Go with me.
Imagine babies in wombs could talk to
other babies
in other wombs. What would they say?
What would they think life was like,
if they could talk among themselves.
I really... I really have no idea.
They'd think that life
was nine months long.
And then boom, a trapdoor opens,
out you fall, gone forever.
Never hear from those guys again.
Nothing at the end of the cord.
Okay.
This isn't really an afterlife.
It's just more life
than you were expecting.
Why did you ask me if I'd killed anyone?
Before you were a teacher, you spent
some time as a soldier.
Yes. So?
Any regrets? Bad memories?
Is that any of your business?
Yes.
(GUNS FIRING)
SOLDIER: Take cover, take cover...
Now!
Sorry if I triggered something.
Memory flashes can be very
impactful in the early stages...
Why?
Why what?
(GUNS FIRING)
DANNY: Why is it any of your business?
We've had a request to meet you.
Any idea who that would be from?
It's been given a priority,
that usually means...
Means what?
Well, anyway...
Erm, we've arranged a meet-up.
-When?
-Come in.
SOLDIER: Seize target!
Repeat, seize target!
SOLDIER: Danny...
Repeat, is the building secure?
SEB: So I guess you remember him, yeah?
SOLDIER: Danny, Danny?
Come in, come in.
Going to need to take a reading off you.
A reading?
It won't hurt.
What won't?
How does the body keep its integrity?
Why isn't it just a bunch of bones,
floating about?
Each body is encased
in a support exoskeleton.
CLARA: An invisible exoskeleton?
CHANG: It's only invisible in the water,
there's a specially engineered
refraction index in the fluid,
so we can see the tank resident,
unimpeded by the support mechanisms.
DOCTOR: So each skeleton
is inside something.
(LAUGHS)
(RUMBLING)
Are you serious? X-Ray water?
It's so cool! Look at this!
We call it dark water.
Only organic matter
can be seen through it.
I keep saying they should
use this stuff in swimming pools.
-Why?
-Think about it.
I am thinking about it. Why?
Doesn't matter.
3W. What kind of name is that?
What does it mean?
Well. You know, don't you?
You're here on business,
or they wouldn't have let you in.
Sorry. Should have checked. Who are you?
I thought that you would never ask.
Sort out your security protocols,
they're a disgrace.
Another government inspection? So soon?
Why is there all this swearing?
Oh, I've got a lot of, erm,
internalised anger.
What does 3W stand for?
Well. The three words.
What three words?
Seriously? You don't know?
Never mind what we know, and what we
don't know, just answer our question.
Because people who don't know,
when they hear about this,
they can freak out.
We're not going to freak out.
If you've had a recent loss.
This might be...
This will be disturbing.
She'll be fine.
Speak for me again,
I'll detach something from you.
I'll be fine.
You know how people are scared of dying.
Like, everybody.
DOCTOR: Of course, it's the most
fundamental fear in the universe.
They'd be a lot more scared
if they knew what it was really like...
(HORNS HONKING)
So...
You okay?
I'm sorry.
I just...
Hey, hey, hey...
Hey... Hey, listen, listen.
Hey!
Probably best not, eh?
-(DOOR CLOSING)
-Doesn't speak much.
Why would he want to see me?
(MAN SCREAMING)
What the hell is that?
Sounds like somebody
left their body to science.
Okay. Erm...
It's probably time to explain why
you're always feeling cold...
-(STATIC)
-White noise off the telly.
We've all heard it.
A few years ago, Dr Skarosa,
our founder...
...did something unexpected.
He played that noise through a
translation matrix of his own devising.
This is a recording of what he heard.
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
-Okay. People, voices.
-So what?
Over time, Dr Skarosa became convinced
these were the voices of
the recently departed.
He believed it was a
telepathic communication from the dead.
Why? Was he an idiot?
He was able to isolate some of
the voices, hear what they were saying.
So. An idiot then.
Shut up, Doctor.
What I'm about to play you, will change
your life, and not for the better.
These are the three words which
caused Dr Skarosa to set up institutes,
like this one, all over the world,
to protect the dead.
If you'd rather not hear these words,
there's still time.
Can you just hurry up, please,
or I'll hit you with my shoe.
(SIGHS)
-(BEEPS)
-MAN: Don't cremate me...
Don't cremate me...
There is one simple,
horrible possibility
that has never occurred to anyone,
throughout human history.
Don't cremate me... Don't cremate me...
Don't say it!
The dead remain conscious.
The dead are fully aware of everything
that is happening to them.
You see your mind is here, your soul,
whatever you want to call it,
and you're in your new body,
in your new world.
But you're still connected to your
old body in your old world.
You're still going to feel
what it feels.
That's why I'm cold.
They're keeping you
in a cold place, yeah.
You did say you were being cremated?
-(BEEPING)
-Sorry, let me get this.
Sorry. Sorry, are you telling me...
Wow! Oh, that's rare.
-This never happens.
-Wow, what now? What never happens?
-You've got a call.
-A call?
-From the other side.
-Meaning?
Do you know somebody
called Clara Oswald?
Fakery. All of it.
-(BEEPING)
-It's a con, it's a racket.
I promise you, this is not a con.
-(BEEPING CONTINUES)
-What's that beeping?
DOCTOR: Never mind about beeping,
who cares about beeping?
The dead are dead!
They're not talking to you out of
your television sets, they're just gone.
And all these poor souls, down there
in these tanks,
I'm sorry, but they're just dead
and they're not coming back!
DANNY: Clara? Clara, are you there?
Danny?
I can hear you. Is that you,
oh, please say it's you...
That's her! That's Clara!
Yeah, you're really lucky,
it hardly ever happens.
(BEEPING)
Where did she go?
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Ah! Just lost the signal,
but I can track it back,
I'm pretty sure...
I don't understand. What is happening?
We've been scanning you telepathically
since you came in,
you said you wanted to speak
to someone who'd passed.
And we've found you a match
in the Nethersphere.
This isn't possible.
The dead don't come back.
-Come on, get her back!
-Da, da, da! I'm trying!
It was him, it was his voice.
If they scanned you telepathically
they could have lifted a voice,
it could still be a fake.
Getting him back... Very nearly!
Clara? Can you hear me?
Yes, Danny, I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, yeah, I can hear you.
Clara! Oh, my God, Clara!
What do I do?
-Who are you talking to?
-Hang on, just a moment.
Question him. Ask him questions
only he'd know the answer to. Be sure.
You, with me.
Where are you going?
I've got to check out those tanks,
there's something that I'm missing.
-DANNY: Clara?
-Sceptical and critical, remember?
Be strong, even if it breaks your heart.
Connection's stabilised, should be okay.
Who would harvest dead bodies?
I feel like I'm
missing something obvious.
Danny?
Yeah. I'm here.
Danny, I'm so sorry, but I'm going to
have to ask you some questions.
Questions? I swear on anything it's me.
Humankind! Bring out your dead!
(RUMBLING)
Oh, my God!
The tanks...
The tanks are activating.
They're not supposed to do that.
All your dead people are standing,
don't you think you
skipped the headline?
Now, now, children.
Naughty, naughty!
Dr Chang,
your welcome droid
has developed a fault.
That's not a droid. That's my boss.
You know, I might have been guilty
of just a teensy, little fibette.
Dr Chang,
I really liked working with you.
I've enjoyed every day of it.
-I'm sorry?
-You know,
I've even got a little photograph
of you looking so sweet,
I'm always going to keep it, always.
-Are you going to kill me?
-Now come on.
Let's not dwell on horrid things.
This is going to be
our last conversation,
and I'm the one who's going
to have to live with that.
CHANG: Please don't kill me.
Say something nice.
Please, please, please. I...
I don't want to die.
Mmm...
You're going to kill me, aren't you?
Say something nice!
Please...
Dr Chang,
I've got all day,
and I'm not going to kill you
until you say something nice!
It has been an absolute pleasure
working with you
and I truly believe that you will never
be able to find it in your heart
to murder me.
Now, I'll be with you in a moment,
just feeling a bit
emotional at the moment.
Cybermen!
It's me. I swear.
I swear on anything it's me.
The very first restaurant you took me
to, that first date. What was it called?
Clara, it's me!
Then what was the name of
the restaurant?
What was it?
I can't remember.
They're Cybermen, all of them!
We've got to stop them getting out!
Now who's missing the headline?
The Nethersphere.
You know it's ever so funny,
the people that live inside that
think they've gone to heaven.
CLARA: My birthday. When is it?
November 23rd.
That's right, isn't it?
I got that one right.
That's pretty basic information.
Anyone could know that.
Say something only you could say.
Tell me something only Danny would know.
(EXHALES)
DOCTOR: That's a matrix data-slice.
A Gallifreyan hard drive.
Time Lord technology.
Imagine you could upload
dying minds to that? Edit them.
Rearrange them. Get rid of
all those boring emotions.
Ready to be re-downloaded.
Meanwhile, you upgrade the bodies.
Upload the mind, upgrade the body.
Cybermen from cyberspace,
now why has no-one
ever thought of that before?
How did you get hold of
Time Lord technology?
-Who are you?
-You know who I am.
I told you.
You felt it.
(GASPS)
Surely you did.
Two hearts.
And both of them yours.
You're a Time Lord.
Time Lady, please,
I'm old fashioned.
Which Time Lady?
The one you abandoned, Doctor.
The one you left for dead.
Didn't you ever think
I'd find my way back?
Clara! Clara! Clara!
I've got to get Clara!
Oh, Clara, Clara, Clara!
I should shoot you in a jealous rage,
now, wouldn't that be sexy?
I've turned the lift off, though.
-I presume you have stairs.
-Well, I'm not a Dalek!
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Oh, dear, Doctor.
Didn't you realise where you were?
(BELLS CASCADING)
-DANNY: I love you.
-No.
No, no, no. I'm sorry, but no.
Anybody could say that.
Anybody would know to say that.
Say something only you could tell me.
Prove to me you are really Danny.
-How?
-"I love you" means nothing right now.
Not till I know who's talking.
Say something only Danny could say...
-Clara...
-CLARA: Danny,
if that is you,
wherever you are, whatever it takes,
I will be with you again, I swear.
No, you won't. You're not coming here.
Nothing will stop me, nothing in
the world. As soon as I know it's you.
There's only one way to come here,
and you are not doing that.
I'll do anything, Danny,
anything, just...
...say something
only you could say.
Clara, you have your life!
You have your whole life to live.
You have to stay there.
No. I have to be with Danny Pink.
-I love you.
-Stop saying that!
Don't say that! If you say that again,
I swear, I will switch this thing off.
(SIGHS)
Clara?
Yes?
I love you.
(SOBBING)
These emotions,
they're terribly difficult.
But, you know,
we've got a thing for that.
We can help with all these
difficult feelings.
Just press this.
I'll leave you to make a decision.
Doctor!
DOCTOR: Get away from here!
All of you, run!
Go, go, get away from here. Run away.
Run, run! Get away from here,
all of you, now! Now!
I'm sorry everyone,
another ranting Scotsman in the street.
I had no idea there was a match on.
Get away, go!
Stop shouting, love.
Stop making a fuss, it's too late.
All the graves of planet earth
are about to give birth!
Do you know the key strategic weakness
of the human race?
The dead outnumber the living!
Who are you?
Oh, you know who I am.
I'm Missy.
Who's Missy?
Oh, please, try to keep up.
Short for Mistress.
Well!
I couldn't very well keep calling myself
the Master, now could I?
(GASPS)
-(SOBBING)
-(BEEPING)