(WHOOSHING)
-DOCTOR: Cardiff!
-Cardiff?
Ah, but the thing about Cardiff,
it's built on a rift in time and space.
Just like California on the San Andreas
Fault, but the rift bleeds energy.
Every now and then I need to open up
the engines, soak up the energy,
-and use it as fuel.
-So it's a pit stop?
Exactly! Should only take 20 seconds.
The rift's been active.
Wait a minute. They had an earthquake
in Cardiff a couple of years ago.
-Was that you?
-Bit of trouble with the Slitheen.
A long time ago. Lifetimes.
I was a different man back then.
Doctor!
Finito. All powered up.
What's that?
We're accelerating into the future.
The year one billion. Five billion.
Five trillion. Fifty trillion? What?
The year 100 trillion?
That's impossible.
Why? What happens then?
We're going to the end of the universe.
Doctor!
Humans. Humans are coming.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
I just want to go. Please let me go.
Human!
-Human!
A hunt!
Hunt!
(ALL CHANTING)
Hunt. Hunt.
(BEEPING)
There's movement on the surface.
Another human hunt. God help him.
Chan, should I alert the guards, tho?
No, no, we can't spare them.
Poor beggar's on his own.
One more lost soul dreaming of Utopia.
Chan, you mustn't talk as though
you've given up, tho.
No, no, indeed. Here's to it. Utopia.
Well, it is to be hoped the coffee
is a little less sour. Will you join me?
Chan, I am happy drinking
my own internal milk, tho.
Yes, well. That's quite enough
information, thank you.
OVER PA: Professor Yana. Don't want
to rush you, but how are we doing?
(STUTTERING) Yes, yes, working.
Yes, almost there.
How's it looking on the Footprint?
It's good. Yes, fine, excellent.
Chan, there's no problem as such.
We've accelerated
the calculation matrix,
but it's going to take time
to harmonise, tho.
Chan, we're trying
a new reversal process.
We'll have a definite result
in approximately two hours, tho.
(DRUMS BEATING)
(DISTANT) Chan, Professor, tho?
Chan, Professor Yana, tho?
Chan, Professor, tho.
Yes, yes, yes, working.
Chan, it's the surface scanner,
Professor.
It seems to be detecting
a different signal, tho.
Well, that's not a standard reading.
I can't make it out.
It would seem something new has arrived.
Well, we've landed.
-So what's out there?
-I don't know.
-Say that again. That's rare.
-Not even the Time Lords came this far.
We should leave. We should go.
We should really, really go.
Oh, my God.
Can't get a pulse. Hold on,
you've got that medical kit thing.
Hello again. Oh, I'm sorry.
Here we go. Get out of the way.
It's a bit odd, though,
not very 100 trillion.
That coat's more like World War II.
-I think he came with us.
-How do you mean? From Earth?
Must've been clinging
to the outside of the Tardis.
All the way through the vortex.
Well, that's very him.
-What, do you know him?
-Friend of mine.
Used to travel with me.
Back in the old days.
But he's... I'm sorry, there's no
heartbeat. There's nothing. He's dead.
Oh, so much for me. It's all right,
just breathe deep. I've got you.
Captain Jack Harkness. And who are you?
-Martha Jones.
-Nice to meet you, Martha Jones.
-Oh, don't start.
-I was only saying hello.
I don't mind.
-Doctor.
-Captain.
-Good to see you.
-And you.
Same as ever.
Although, have you had work done?
-You can talk.
-Oh, yes, the face. Regeneration.
-How did you know this was me?
-The police box kind of gives it away.
I've been following you
for a long time. You abandoned me.
Did I? Busy life. Moving on.
Just got to ask.
The Battle of Canary Wharf.
I saw the list of the dead.
It said Rose Tyler.
-Oh, no, sorry. She's alive.
-You're kidding!
Parallel world, safe and sound.
And Mickey. And her mother.
Oh, yes!
Good old Rose.
So there I was,
stranded in the year 200100,
ankle-deep in Dalek dust, and he goes
off without me, but I had this.
I used to be a Time Agent.
It's called a vortex manipulator.
He's not the only one
who can time travel.
Excuse me, that is not time travel.
It's like, I've got a sports car,
you've got a space hopper.
-Oh, boys and their toys!
-All right, so I bounced.
I thought, "21st century,
the best place to find the Doctor.”
Except I got it a little wrong,
arrived in 1869,
this thing burnt out, so it was useless.
Told you.
I had to live through
the entire 20th century
waiting for a version of you
that would coincide with me.
But that makes you
more than 100 years old.
And looking good, don't you think?
So, I went to the time rift,
based myself there,
'cause I knew you'd come back
to refuel, until finally,
I get a signal on this detecting you
and here we are.
But the thing is,
how come you left him behind, Doctor?
I was busy.
Is that what happens, though, seriously?
Do you just get bored of us
one day and disappear?
-Not if you're blonde.
-Oh, she was blonde! What a surprise!
You two,
we're at the end of the universe, right?
Right at the edge of knowledge itself
and you're busy...
blogging!
Come on.
Is that a city?
City or a hive or a nest.
Or a conglomeration.
Like it was grown.
But look, there, that's like
pathways or roads.
There must've been some sort of life.
-Long ago.
-What killed it?
Time. Just time. Everything's dying now.
All the great civilisations have gone.
This isn't just night. All the stars
have burnt up and faded away
into nothing.
They must have an atmospheric shell.
We should be frozen to death.
Well, Martha and I, maybe.
Not so sure about you, Jack.
But what about the people?
Does no one survive?
I suppose we have to hope
life will find a way.
Well, he's not doing too bad.
(ALL YELLING)
Is it me or does that look like a hunt?
Come on!
Oh, I've missed this!
-I've got you. I've got you...
-We've got to run. They're coming!
Jack, don't you dare!
What the hell are they?
There's more of them.
We've got to keep going.
I've got a ship nearby. It's safe.
It's not far. It's over there.
-Or maybe not.
-We're close to the silo.
-If we get to the silo, then we're safe.
-Silo?
-Silo.
-Silo for me.
It's the Futurekind, they're coming!
Open the gate!
Show me your teeth!
Show me your teeth! Show me your teeth!
Show him your teeth!
Human! Let them in! Let them in!
-Close!
Close!
Humans. Humani.
-Make feast.
-Go back to where you came from.
I said go back! Back!
-Oh, don't tell him to put his gun down.
-He's not my responsibility.
And I am? That makes a change.
Kind want you.
(GRUNTS)
Kind hungry.
(SHOUTS)
-Thanks for that.
-Right, let's get you inside.
My name is Padra Fet Shafe Cane.
Tell me, just tell me.
-Can you take me to Utopia?
-Oh, yes, sir. Yes, I can.
Professor,
we've got four new humans inside.
One of them is calling himself a doctor.
-Of medicine?
-He says of everything.
What? A scientist! Oh, my word!
(STUTTERING) Chantho, just...
I don't know. I'm coming!
DOCTOR: It's like a box, a big blue box.
I'm sorry, but I really need it back.
It's stuck out there.
I'm sorry, but my family were heading
for the silo. Did they get here?
My mother is Kistane Shafe Cane.
My brother's name is Beltone.
Computers are down, but you can
check the paperwork. Creet!
-Passenger needs help.
-Right, what do you need?
A blue box, you said?
Big, tall, wooden, says "Police".
We're driving out for the last water
collection. I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
Come on.
-Sorry, but how old are you?
-Old enough to work. This way.
CREET: Kistane Shafe Cane.
Kistane and Beltone Shafe Cane.
I'm looking for a Kistane
and Beltone Shafe Cane.
PADRA: The Shafe Canes, anyone?
CREET: Anyone?
Kistane and Beltone Shafe Cane.
Anyone know the Shafe Cane family?
Anyone called Shafe Cane?
It's like a refugee camp.
It's stinking.
Sorry. No offence. Not you.
Don't you see, though? The ripe old
smell of humans. You survived.
Oh, you might've spent a million years
evolving into clouds of gas
and another million as downloads,
but you always revert
to the same basic shape.
The fundamental human.
CREET: Kistane Shafe Cane.
End of the universe and here you are.
Indomitable, that's the word!
Indomitable!
Is there a Kistane Shafe Cane?
-That's me.
-Mother!
KISTANE: Oh, my God. Padra!
It's not all bad news.
-Captain Jack Harkness. And who are you?
-Stop it. Give us a hand with this.
It's half-deadlocked.
See if you can overwrite the code.
Let's find out where we are.
JACK: I've got you.
DOCTOR: Thanks.
How did you cope without me?
Now that is what I call a rocket.
DOCTOR: They're not refugees,
they're passengers.
He said they were going to Utopia.
The perfect place. 100 trillion years
and it's the same old dream.
DOCTOR: Do you recognise those engines?
Nope, whatever it is, it's not rocket
science. But it's hot, though.
Boiling.
But if the universe is falling apart,
what does Utopia mean?
-The Doctor?
-That's me.
Good! Good! Good!
Good, good, good. Good!
It's good, apparently.
Chan, welcome, tho.
This is the gravitissimal accelerator.
It's past its best,
-but it works.
-Chan, welcome, tho.
And over here is
the Footprint Impeller System.
Do you know anything
about end-time gravity mechanics?
-Hello. Who are you?
-Chan, Chantho, tho.
But we can't get it to harmonise.
-Captain Jack Harkness.
-Stop it.
-Can't I say hello to anyone?
-Chan, I do not protest, tho.
Maybe later, blue.
So what have we got here?
-And all this feeds into the rocket?
-Yes, except without a stable Footprint,
we'll never achieve escape velocity.
If only we could harmonise
the five impact patterns
and unify them,
well, we might yet make it.
What do you think, Doctor? Any ideas?
Well, basically, sort of, not a clue.
Nothing?
I'm not from round these parts.
I've never seen a system like it.
-Sorry.
-No, no, I'm sorry. It's my fault.
There's been so little help...
Oh, my God.
You've got a hand.
A hand in a jar.
A hand, in a jar, in your bag.
(STUTTERING) That's my hand.
I said I had a Doctor detector.
Chan, is this is a tradition
amongst your people, tho?
Not on my street!
What do you mean, that's your hand?
You've got both your hands,
I can see them.
Long story. I lost my hand,
Christmas Day in a sword fight.
What, and you grew another hand?
Yeah, yeah I did, yeah. Hello.
Might I ask, what species are you?
Time Lord. Last of.
Heard of them? Legend or anything?
Not even a myth? Blimey,
end of the universe is a bit humbling.
Chan, it is said that I am
the last of my species too, tho.
-Sorry. What was your name?
-My assistant and good friend, Chantho.
A survivor of the Malmooth.
This was their planet, Malcassairo,
before we took refuge.
-The city outside. That was yours?
-Chan, the conglomeration died, tho.
Conglomeration! That's what I said!
-You're supposed to say sorry.
-Oh, yes.
-Sorry.
-Chan, most grateful, tho.
You grew another hand?
Hello again. It's fine.
Look, really, it's me.
All this time
and you're still full of surprises.
-Chan, you are most unusual, tho.
-Well...
So what about those things outside,
the Beastie Boys? What are they?
We call them the Futurekind,
which is a myth in itself,
but it's feared
they are what we will become.
-Unless we reach Utopia.
-And Utopia is...?
Every human knows of Utopia.
Where have you been?
Bit of a hermit.
-A hermit with friends?
-Hermits United.
We meet up every 10 years, swap
stories about caves. It's good fun.
For a hermit. So, Utopia?
The call came from across the stars.
Over and over again.
"Come to Utopia."”
Originating from that point.
Where is that?
Oh, it's far beyond
the Condensate Wilderness.
Out towards the Wildlands
and the Dark Matter Reefs.
Calling us in,
the last of the humans
scattered across the night.
DOCTOR: What do you think is out there?
YANA: We can't know.
A colony, a city, some sort of haven.
The Science Foundation created the
Utopia Project thousands of years ago
to preserve mankind,
to find a way of surviving
beyond the collapse of reality itself.
Now, perhaps they found it.
Perhaps not.
But it's worth a look, don't you think?
Oh, yes.
(DRUMS BEATING)
And the signal keeps modulating
so it's not on automatic.
That's a good sign. Someone's out there.
(DISTANT) And that's
a navigation matrix, isn't it?
So you can fly without the stars
to guide you, Professor?
Professor? Professor?
Professor!
I... Right, that's enough talk.
There's work to do.
Now if you could leave, thank you.
-Are you all right?
-Yes, I'm fine. And busy.
Except that rocket's
not going to fly, is it?
This Footprint mechanism thing,
it's not working.
-We'll find a way!
-You're stuck on this planet.
And you haven't told them, have you?
That lot out there,
they still think they're gonna fly.
Well, it's better
to let them live in hope.
Quite right, too. And I must say,
Professor... What was it?
-Yana.
-Professor Yana,
this new science is well beyond me.
But all the same, a boost
reversal circuit, in any time frame,
must be a circuit
which reverses the boost.
So I wonder what would happen
if I did...this.
Chan, it's working, tho!
But how did you do that?
Oh, we've been chatting away.
I forgot to tell you, I'm brilliant.
All passengers, prepare for boarding.
Repeat, all passengers
prepare for immediate boarding.
Destination, Utopia.
In there.
Inside! Everyone, inside!
Come on, move, move, move!
All passengers
prepare for immediate boarding.
Excuse me.
-Hey, what was your name? Creet?
-That's right, miss.
Who are you with, Creet? You got family?
No, miss. There's just me.
Well, good luck. What do you think
it's gonna be like in Utopia?
My mum used to say
the skies were made of diamonds.
Good for her.
Go on, off you go, get your seat.
(SNARLING)
-Is that...
-Gluten extract.
It binds the neutralino map together.
But that's food.
You've built this system out of food
and string and staples?
-Professor Yana, you're a genius.
-Says the man who made it work.
Oh, it's easy coming in at the end.
But you're stellar.
This is magnificent.
And I don't often say that 'cause...
Well, 'cause of me.
Well, even my title is an affectation.
There hasn't been such a thing
as a university for over 1,000 years.
I've spent my life going
from one refugee ship to another.
If you'd been born in a different time,
you'd be revered. I mean it.
Throughout the galaxies.
Oh, those damn galaxies,
they had to go and collapse.
Some admiration would have been nice.
Yes, just a little. Just once.
Well, you've got it now.
But that Footprint engine thing...
You can't activate it from on-board.
It's got to be done from here.
You're staying behind.
With Chantho. She won't leave
without me. Simply refuses.
You'd give your life so they could fly.
Oh, I think I'm a little too old
for Utopia. Time I had some sleep.
Professor, tell the Doctor
we've found his blue box.
-Ah.
-Doctor?
Professor, it's a wild stab in the dark,
but I might just have found you
a way out.
Extra power.
Little bit of a cheat,
but who's counting?
Jack, you're in charge
of the retro feeds.
Oh, am I glad to see that thing.
Chan, Professor, are you all right, tho?
Yeah, I'm fine, I'm fine.
I'm fine. Just get on with it.
Connect those circuits into the spar,
same as the last lot.
-But quicker.
-MARTHA: Yes, sir.
You don't have to keep working.
We can handle it.
It's just a headache,
just noise inside my head, Doctor.
-Constant noise inside my head.
-What sort of noise?
The sound of drums.
More and more,
as though it's getting closer.
-When did it start?
-I've had it all my life.
Every waking hour.
Still, no rest for the wicked.
So how long have you been
with the Professor?
Chan, 17 years, tho.
-Blimey. Long time.
-Chan, I adore him, tho.
Oh, right. And he...
Chan, I don't think
he even notices, tho.
-Tell me about it.
-Chan, but I am happy to serve, tho.
Do you mind if I ask? Do you have
to start every sentence with "Chan"?
-Chan, yes, tho.
-And end every sentence with...
-Chan, tho, tho.
-What would happen if you didn't?
Chan, that would be rude, tho.
-What, like swearing?
-Chan, indeed, tho.
-Go on. Just once.
-Chan, I can't, tho.
-Do it for me.
-No.
(GIGGLING)
Professor. Systems are down.
Professor, are you getting me?
I'm here! We're ready.
Now all you need to do
is connect the couplings,
then we can launch.
Save us, this equipment!
-Needs rebooting all the time.
-Anything I can do?
-I've finished that lot.
-Yes, if you could.
Just press the reboot key
every time the picture goes.
Certainly, sir.
Just don't ask me to do shorthand.
-Are you still there?
-Present and correct.
Send your man inside.
We'll keep the levels down from here.
He's inside.
Captain, keep the dials below the red.
-Where is that room?
-It's underneath the rocket.
Fix the couplings
and the Footprint can work.
But the entire chamber
is flooded with stet radiation.
Stet? Never heard of it.
You wouldn't want to.
But it's safe enough
if we can hold the radiation
back from here.
(ALARM BEEPING)
It's rising. 0.2.
-Keep it level.
-Yes, sir.
(ALARM BUZZING)
We're losing power, tho.
-DOCTOR: Radiation's rising.
-We've lost control!
-The chamber's going to flood!
-Jack! Override the vents!
Get out! Get out of there!
Jate!
GUARD: Hey, you!
Stop!
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
-We can jump-start the override.
-Don't. It's gonna flare!
(SCREAMING)
Jate, get out of there! Get out!
No!
-I've got him.
-Chan, don't touch the cables, tho.
I'm so sorry.
The chamber's flooded
with radiation, yes?
Without the couplings,
the engines will never start.
-It was all for nothing.
-Oh, I don't know.
-Martha, leave him.
-You've got to let me try.
Come on, come on, just listen to me.
Now leave him alone.
Strikes me, Professor, you've got a room
which no man can enter without dying.
-Is that correct?
-Yes.
Well...
(GASPING)
I think I've got just the man.
Was someone kissing me?
Lieutenant, get on-board the rocket.
I promise you're going to fly.
-The chamber's flooded.
-Trust me, we found a way
of tripping the system. Run!
What are you taking
your clothes off for?
-I'm going in.
-By the looks of it,
I'd say that stet radiation
doesn't affect clothing, only flesh.
Well, I look good, though.
How long have you known?
Ever since I ran away from you.
Good luck.
MARTHA: We lost picture
when that thing flared up.
Doctor, are you there?
Receiving, yeah. He's inside.
-And still alive?
-Oh, yes.
But he should evaporate.
What sort of a man is he?
I've only just met him.
The Doctor sort of travels through time
and space and picks people up.
God, I make us sound like stray dogs.
Maybe we are.
-He travels in time?
-Don't ask me to explain it.
That's a Tardis, that box thing.
The sports car of time travel, he says.
(DRUMS BEATING)
VOICE: Inside the box, inside the box...
When did you realise?
Earth, 1892.
Got in a fight on Ellis Island,
a man shot me through the heart.
And then I woke up.
Thought it was kind of strange.
But then it never stopped.
Fell off a cliff, trampled by horses,
World War I, World War II.
Poison, starvation, a stray javelin.
Ooh!
In the end, I got the message.
I'm the man who can never die.
-And all that time you knew.
-That's why I left you behind.
It's not easy,
even just looking at you, Jack,
-'cause you're wrong.
-Thanks.
You are. I can't help it.
I'm a Time Lord.
It's instinct. It's in my guts.
You're a fixed point in time and space.
You're a fact.
That's never meant to happen.
Even the Tardis reacted against you,
tried to shake you off.
Flew all the way to the end
of the universe just to get rid of you.
So what you're saying is
you're prejudiced?
I never thought of it like that.
-Shame on you.
-Yeah.
JACK: Last thing I remember,
back when I was mortal,
I was facing three Daleks,
death by extermination.
VOICE: Daleks... Daleks...
JACK: Then I came back to life.
-What happened?
-Rose.
JACK: I thought
you'd sent her back home.
DOCTOR: She came back.
Opened the heart of the Tardis
and absorbed the time vortex itself.
JACK: What does that mean exactly?
DOCTOR: No one's ever meant
to have that power.
If a Time Lord did that,
he'd become a god, a vengeful god.
But she was human.
I bring life.
Everything she did was so human.
She brought you back to life.
But she couldn't control it.
She brought you back forever.
That's something, I suppose.
The final act of the Time War was life.
JACK: Do you think
she could change me back?
DOCTOR: I took the power out of her.
She's gone, Jack.
She's not just living on
a parallel world, she's trapped there.
The walls have closed.
-I'm sorry.
-Yeah.
I went back to her estate
in the '90s, just once or twice.
Watched her growing up.
Never said hello,
timelines and all that.
-Do you want to die?
-This one's a little stuck.
Jack?
I thought I did. I don't know.
But this lot, you see them out here
surviving and that's fantastic.
-You might be out there somewhere.
-I could go meet myself.
Well, it's the only man
you're ever gonna be happy with.
This new regeneration,
it's kinda cheeky.
VOICE: Regeneration. Regeneration.
I never understand
half the things he's saying.
-What's wrong?
-Chan, Professor, what is it, tho?
Time travel.
They say there was time travel
back in the old days.
I never believed.
But what would I know? Stupid old man.
Never could keep time.
Always late, always lost.
Even this thing never worked.
Martha, this watch is me.
I'm gonna become human.
Time and time and time again,
always running out on me.
-Can I have a look at that?
-It's only an old relic. Like me!
-Where did you get it?
-Hmm?
-I was found with it.
-What do you mean?
An orphan in the storm.
I was a naked child found
on the coast of the Silver Devastation.
Abandoned. With only this.
-Have you ever opened it?
-Why would I? It's broken.
How do you know it's broken
if you've never opened it?
It's stuck, it's old,
it's not meant to be.
I don't know.
Does it matter?
No, it's nothing. It's...
Listen, everything's fine up here.
I'm gonna see if the Doctor needs me.
-Yes!
-Now, get out of there, come on!
-Lieutenant, everyone on board?
-Ready and waiting.
Stand by! Two minutes to ignition.
ATILLO: Ready to launch.
Outer doors sealed.
Launching in T minus 99, 98...
Ah, nearly there.
The Footprint, it's a gravity pulse.
It stamps down, the rocket shoots up.
Bit primitive. Gonna take
the both of us to keep it stable.
(BEEPING)
Doctor, it's the Professor. He's got
this watch, he's got a fob watch.
It's the same as yours,
same writing on it, same everything.
-Don't be ridiculous.
-I asked him.
-He said he's had it his whole life.
-So he's got the same watch.
Yeah, but it's not a watch.
It's this chameleon thing.
No, no, no, it's this thing...
This device, it rewrites biology.
Changes a Time Lord into a human.
-And it's the same watch!
-It can't be.
That means he could be a Time Lord.
-You might not be the last one!
-Jack, keep it level!
-But that's brilliant, isn't it?
-Yes, it is. Of course it is.
Depends which one. Brilliant, fantastic,
yeah. But they died, the Time Lords.
-All of them, they died.
-Not if he was human.
What did he say, Martha?
What did he say?
He looked at the watch
like he could hardly see it.
Like that perception filter thing.
What about now? Can he see it now?
DOCTOR: The Tardis. The time vortex.
VOICE: Regeneration.
It's the drums, the drums, the drums,
the never-ending drumbeat.
Open me, you human fool. Open the light
and summon me and receive my majesty.
Destroy him.
Then you will give your power to me.
Chan, Yana, won't you please
take some rest, tho?
ATILLO: 77, 70, 9...
If he escaped the Time War,
then it's a perfect place to hide.
The end of the universe.
Think what the Face of Boe said.
His dying words.
He said...
(RUMBLING)
You
are
not
alone.
Chan, Professor Yana, tho?
Lieutenant, have you done it?
Did you get velocity?
Have you done it?
Lieutenant, have you done it?
ATILLO: Affirmative.
We'll see you in Utopia.
Good luck.
-Chan, but you've locked them in, tho.
-Door open.
Door open!
Not to worry, my dear.
As one door closes, another must open.
(SNARLING)
Chan, you must stop, tho.
Chan, but you've lowered the defences.
The Futurekind will get in, tho.
Chan, Professor, I'm so sorry,
but I must stop you.
You are destroying all our work, tho.
Oh! Now I can say I was provoked.
Did you never think,
all those years standing beside me,
to ask about that watch? Never?
Did you never once think, not ever,
that you could set me free?
Chan, I'm sorry, tho.
Chan, I'm so sorry.
And you, with your
"Chan" and your "tho",
driving me insane.
-Chan, Professor, please.
-That is not my name!
The professor was an invention.
So perfect a disguise
that I forgot who I am.
Chan, then who are you, tho?
I am
the Master.
This way!
Professor!
Professor, let me in! Let me in!
Jack, get the door open, now!
Professor, Professor, where are you?
Chantho, Chantho, are you there?
Please, I need to explain.
Whatever you do, don't open that watch.
Utopia.
Hurry!
Open the door! Open the door, please.
I am begging you, Professor.
Please listen to me.
Just open the door, please.
And locked.
Let me in. Let me in!
-She's dead.
-I broke the lock. Give me a hand.
I'm begging you. Everything's changed.
It's only the two of us.
We're the only ones left.
Just let me in!
Killed by an insect.
A girl.
How inappropriate.
But still, if the Doctor
can be young and strong,
then so can I.
The Master,
reborn.
(SCREAMING)
Doctor, you'd better think of something!
(LAUGHING)
Now then, Doctor.
Oh, new voice.
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Anyway, why don't we stop
and have a nice little chat
while I tell you all my plans
and you can work out a way to stop me?
I don't think!
Hold on, I know that voice.
(SCREAMING)
I'm asking you, really properly,
just stop, just think.
-Use my name.
-Master.
-I'm sorry.
-Tough!
JACK: I can't hold them
much longer, Doctor!
No, you don't.
End of the universe. Have fun. Bye-bye.
Doctor, stop him!
(WHOOSHING)
Hurry up, they're getting in!
Let the work of Government begin.
Diplomatic relations with a new species.
And these are my friends.
-Take aim. Fire!
-Run for your life.
I said run!
REPORTER: Air Force One
has landed on British soil.
Mr President, sir!
From now on,
UNIT has control of this operation.
And what this country
really needs right now
ls a Doctor.