DOCTOR: A monastery, 13th century.
Oh, we've gone all medieval.
They're pumping something nasty
off this island.
-Ah! Ow!
-They're pumping acid off this island.
DOCTOR: You're a factory.
A 22nd century, Army-owned factory.
CLEAVES: We're contractors
and you're trespassers.
DOCTOR: I need to see
your critical systems.
Which one?
You know which one.
CLEAVES: The Flesh.
It's fully programmable matter.
It's alive, so alive.
You're piling your lives,
your personalities directly into it.
(SCREAMING)
DOCTOR: You gave them your lives.
Human lives are amazing.
Are you surprised
they walked off with them?
This is...
You're telling me.
Why are you really here?
CLEAVES: They're monsters. Mistakes.
They have to be destroyed.
If we want to live,
then it's time to go to war.
DOCTOR: They're coming back.
In a big way.
Yes, it's insane. And it's about to get
even more insanerer.
Trust me.
I'm the Doctor.
(SCREAMING)
What's happening?
One day we will get back? Yes, one day.
Reverse the polarity
of the neutron flow.
The Flesh is struggling to cope
with our past regenerations. Hold on!
(FOURTH DOCTOR'S VOICE)
Would you like a jelly baby?
DOCTOR: Why? Why?
-Why?
-Why? Why? What?
(TENTH DOCTOR'S VOICE)
Hello, I'm the Doctor.
No, let it go. If we've moved on...
Hold on, hold on! You can stabilise.
I've reversed the jelly baby
with the neutron flow.
And now, would you like a...
-Doctor, Doctor...
-No!
I'm the... I'm the...
-I can't...
-No, listen, hold on, hold on.
Nooo!
(SCREAMING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(GANGERS BANGING ON DOOR)
(BANGING STOPS)
I think I liked it best
when they were being noisy.
Mmm-hmm.
Doctor, we need you, get over here.
Hello.
-Doctor.
-Cybermats.
-Do we have time for this?
-We make time.
-I'd like more proof that you're me.
-Cybermats.
Created by the Cybermen.
They kill by feeding off brain waves.
Are you sure there aren't any weapons
they could get to,
like big guns with bits on?
Yeah, big guns would be good right now.
Why would we have guns?
We're a factory, we mine...
Acid.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Rory and Amy,
they may not trust both of us.
-Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
-Inevitably.
-You see, I'm glad we're on the same...
-Wavelength. See? Great minds.
Exactly. So, what's the plan?
-Save them all, humans and Gangers.
-Tall order, sounds wonderful.
-Is that what you were thinking?
-Yes, it's just so inspiring
to hear me say it.
-I know.
-AMY: Doctor, come on!
-So, what now, Doctor?
-Well, time to get cracking, Doctor.
BOTH: Hello! Sorry.
-But we had to establish a few...
-Ground rules. Formulate a...
-Protocol.
-Protocol. Very posh.
No, no. A protocol between us,
otherwise...
-It gets horribly embarrassing.
-Potentially confusing.
Okay. Well, I'm glad you solved
the problem of confusing.
-That's sarcasm.
-She's very good at sarcasm.
-BOTH: Breathe.
-What?
-We have to get you outside.
-And the Gangers, too.
Sorry. Would you like a memo
from the last meeting?
-They are trying to kill us!
-They're scared.
Doctor, we're trapped in here.
Right. See, I don't think so.
The Flesh Bowl is filled by cabling
from above.
But where are
the earthing conduits, hmm?
All this piping must go down
into a tunnel or a shaft or something.
Yes? With us?
Yowza! An escape route.
You know, I'm just starting to get
a sense of just how impressive it is
to hang out with me.
-Do you tend to say "yowza"?
-That's enough. Let it go, okay?
We're under stress.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RASPING)
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop.
(LIQUID DRIPPING)
The Army will send a recon team out.
We need to find a way
to contact the mainland.
What about Rory and Jen?
They are both out there.
No, this place is a maze.
Takes a long time 10 find someone
in a maze.
I bet you lot have got
a computer map, haven't you?
If we can get power running and
scan for them, it'll be a lot quicker.
(COUGHING)
Doctor, you said earlier to breathe.
Very important, Pond, breathe.
Yeah, well, I'm struggling to.
(ALL COUGHING)
Acid interacting with the stone.
Creating an asphyxiant miasma.
-A what?
-Chokey gas.
Extra heavy. If we can get above it...
The evac tower. This way!
(GROANS) Damned headaches.
So tired.
They could be anywhere.
-How are we going to find them?
-Think about it.
With all that gas out there,
my guess would be the evac tower.
Get above it, try to get power up.
So, let's stop them.
It's a narrow doorway.
I could defend it easy enough.
So can she. (CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
(GROANING)
I think I've coughed so hard
I've pulled a muscle or something.
It's okay. It's easing off. Whoo! Okay.
(BELL TOLLING)
Midnight.
It's Adam's birthday.
My son's five.
Happy birthday, bud.
Happy birthday, Adam.
He'll be so excited.
Out of bed at the crack of dawn.
(CHUCKLING) It's funny.
He's got this wee dance he does
when he gets over-excited.
(DOOR OPENING)
Listen to me.
I tried to block the memories,
but now I know, I must remember.
It's the eyes.
The eyes are the last to go.
What are you talking about?
When they destroy us,
the eyes are the last things to melt.
And there's one question in those eyes.
Why?
Why should we suffer
for the sake of human beings?
I heard in India there's over
10 million Gangers.
We can reach out.
Inspire them to rise up.
Revolution? Look, I just...
I just want to be left
to live in peace, Jen.
They will melt you.
Have you become so human
that you've forgotten the truth?
Don't you remember all the times
you were decommissioned?
-Or should I say executed?
-No.
We don't remember.
Well, I do.
It's us or them.
She's right.
JENNIFER: I have a plan.
And it'll destroy them all.
Can you really get the power back?
There's always some power
floating around...
Sticking to the wires like bits of lint.
-Can you stop finishing each other's...
-Sentences?
-No probs.
-Yes.
No, but hang on. You said that
the Tardis was stuck in acid.
So won't she be damaged?
-Nah...
-She's a tough old thing.
Tough, old, sexy.
No, tough, dependable, sexy.
-I can't get it out of there.
-Come on.
Okay, how can you both be real?
Well, because we are. I'm the Doctor.
Yeah, and so am I.
We both contain the knowledge
of over 900 years of
memory and experience.
We both wear the same bow tie,
which is cool.
-Because bow ties are...
-And always will be.
But how did the Flesh read you?
Because you weren't linked up to it.
Well, it must have been
after I examined it.
-Thus a new, genuine Doctor was created.
-Ta-da!
No getting away from it.
One of you was here first.
Well, okay, after the Flesh scanned me,
I had an accident with a puddle of acid.
Now new shoes,
a situation which did not confront
me learned self here.
That satisfy you, Pond?
Don't call me Pond, please.
What?
Interesting. You definitely feel
more affection for him than me.
No. No, I... Look, you're fine
and everything, but he's the Doctor.
No offence. Being almost the Doctor
is pretty damn impressive.
Well, being almost the Doctor is like
being no Doctor at all.
Don't overreact.
-You might as well call me Smith.
-Smith?
-John Smith!
-Yes! Communication a go go.
Find Rory, show me the scanning
tracking screen.
(BLEEPING)
Come on, Rory, let's be having you.
CLEAVES: There's no sign of him
anywhere.
Come on, come on, baby, show yourself.
You're right. There's power.
Now, boys, I don't know much,
but I know my own minds.
She'll be straight on the comm link
to the mainland.
St John's calling. Emergency Alpha.
Let's see if we can intercept.
St John's calling the mainland.
Are you receiving me, Captain?
Come in.
We'll never get a signal
through this storm.
St John's calling the mainland.
Come in, this is urgent.
CAPTAIN: We're just about
reading you, St John's.
How are you doing?
We've had all kinds of trouble here.
CLEAVES: Request immediate evacuation.
We're under attack.
The storm's affected our Gangers.
They're running amok.
-CAPTAIN: Your Gangers?
-Yes, our Gangers are attacking us.
We need you to take us
off the island immediately
and wipe them out.
Copy that, St John's.
Shuttle's dispatched. Hang on.
You'll need to airlift us off the roof
of the evac tower.
And, Captain, any further transmission
sent by me
must come with the following code word,
I'm typing it
in case they're listening in.
Qof, see how smart I am?
That's why I'm paid the big bucks.
CAPTAIN: Got it. We'll swing in,
get you out and decommission the Flesh.
Jennifer's right.
We're going to have to fight
if we want to survive.
(PANTING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Thermostatic override rejected.
Can only be operated
by a recognised source.
I am recognised.
I'm Jennifer Lucas.
Oh!
We're going to get out of here.
We are, we're going to get out.
But we're not leaving without them.
I want him found, too,
but it's about casualties, isn't it?
Can't be helped.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
What are you doing?
-Making a phone call.
-Who to?
No one yet. It's on delay.
Right. Not getting it.
Why exactly are you making a phone call?
Because, Amy, I am
and always will be the optimist.
The ho per of far-flung hopes
and dreamer of improbable dreams.
(YELPS)
Wheels are in motion. Done.
Do you know, really,
there could be only one.
-Hmm?
-Ah, nothing. Carry on.
Be amazing.
(GASPS)
Amy, what happened?
-It's her again.
-It's who again?
There's a woman I keep seeing,
a woman with an eye patch.
And she has this habit of sliding
walls open and staring at me.
-Doctor?
-Nothing.
Doesn't seem like nothing.
It's time memory, like a mirage.
It's nothing to worry about.
It's in my head.
-Hey, hold on.
-Don't go!
No, leave it to me.
I'm sorry.
What I said about you being
almost the Doctor, it's just...
It's just really hard because
I've been through so much with him.
I've even seen...
I've even seen the moment of his...
Can you die?
If you really are the same,
then you can die,
you can be killed and...
I might have seen that happen.
-Why?
Because you invited us to see it.
Your death... (YELPS)
-Why?
-You're hurting me.
It's all the eyes say. Why?
I can feel them.
As they work each day, knowing the time
was coming for them
to be thrown away again!
Not again! Please!
And then they are destroyed
and they feel death.
And all they can say is, "Why?"
Why?
Keep him away from me!
Did you sense it?
Briefly, not as strong as you.
Amy, I'm sorry.
No! Hey, you keep away.
We can't trust you.
It would appear
I can connect to the Flesh.
No, you are Flesh.
I'm beginning to understand what
he's been through,
-what he needs.
-What you want. You are it!
It's much more powerful than we thought.
The Flesh can grow, correct?
Its cells can divide.
Well, now it wants to do that at will.
It wants revenge.
It's in pain, angry.
I was right, you're not the Doctor,
you can't ever be.
-You're just a copy.
-Doctor?
It might be best if you stayed
over there for now. Hmm?
Hold on a minute. Hold your horses.
I thought I'd explained this,
I'm him, he's me.
Doctor, we have no issue with you.
But when it comes to your Ganger...
DOCTOR: Don't be so absurd.
-Buzzer.
-Sure, boss.
Take a seat, mate.
Nice barrel, very comfy.
Why not?
Is this really what you want?
JENNIFER: Help me! No! Get away!
Jen?
Jen!
Rory?
I'm sorry, she found me.
-Rory, listen to me.
-Don't listen to her.
I'm Jennifer Lucas, this woman is Flesh.
CAPTAIN: This is the shuttle.
We're right above you.
But we can't get low enough.
Gamma static could fry our nav controls.
Sit tight, we'll get you. Just...
(BLEEPING)
Hello? Can you hear me?
I can't find Rory. I'm going out there.
We could use the sonic to track him.
Humans and Gangers give off
slightly different signals,
the sonic needs to tell the difference.
Oh, so the sonic knows
Gangers are different.
-So the other Doctor is different.
-He is the Doctor.
Not to me, I can tell.
Sure you're not prejudiced?
Nice try. But I know, okay?
We've been through too much.
You're my Doctor, end of.
So, one of you is human.
And one of you
I sat with and talked with.
Why can't you just tell me the truth?
The Doctor wants you to live
and I'm with him all the way.
That's a lovely idea, Rory.
But the Flesh want to kill us now.
You're limping. You're not.
So?
So what? You think a Ganger
can't put on a limp?
Show me your leg.
It got burnt while I was in the harness.
She's lying.
She's telling you what you want to hear.
Look, you can't fake a burn.
No! No! You don't...
(BOTH GRUNTING)
RORY: Stop it! Stop it!
Fighting each other is pointless.
Come on!
Please, please, stop!
Jen! Both Jens, stop it!
(SCREAMING)
No!
(ACID HISSING)
(GRUNTING)
She attacked me. I didn't...
I knew you'd find me.
We're in this together, Rory.
And we've got to trust each other.
Okay. Come on, let's go.
Hey, there's a camera up.
We've got a visual.
AMY: That's Rory and Jennifer.
They're heading
for the thermostatic room.
Let's go get them.
Hang on.
CLEAVES: You can't let him go.
Are you crazy?
Am I crazy, Doctor?
Well, you did once plumb your brain
into the core of an entire planet
just to hold its orbit and win a bet.
He can't go rescue them. I'm going.
Do you know, I want him to go.
And I'm rather adamant.
Well, then, they'll need company.
Right, boss?
It's fine. I'll handle it.
Thank you, Buzzer.
It'll be all right.
I'll find him.
DOCTOR: Can't explain it to you now,
but I need you to trust him.
Can you do that for me, Amy?
And what if you're wrong?
(BOTH COUGHING)
This is the thermostatic chamber.
We can stir the oxygen supply from here.
Uh, what?
We're going to choke to death
if we don't clean this air.
Keep a look out in case of Gangers.
(COUGHING)
JENNIFER: Rory!
What's wrong?
It's this wheel, it's just too tough
for a girl to turn.
You feeling strong?
I'll break out the big guns.
This first.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Human source recognised.
Thermostatic override granted.
These temperature gauges are rising.
Jennifer and Rory must've shut off
the underground cooling vents.
Why do that? It'll kill us.
There's a million gallons
of boiling acid under our feet.
I know, it's heating up
the whole island.
How long until it blows?
(LOUD RUMBLING)
Gangers or no Gangers,
we need to get the hell out of here.
Shuttle, we need evac.
Where are you? Can you hear me?
-Can you...
-Cleaves?
-Cleaves? Cleaves, sit down.
-I'm fine.
You don't look good.
Monsters never do.
I'm fine.
I remember medics doing tests.
I'm waiting for results, so let it go.
It's a very deep parietal clot.
How can you possibly...
(SIGHS)
Inoperable?
On Earth, yes.
Well, seeing as Earth's all that's on...
...offer. Hmm. (CHUCKLES)
I'm no healthy spring chicken
and you're no weatherman, right?
(RUMBLING)
Something just cracked, I heard it.
Yeah, we can't stay here. Let's go!
-He's right, let's shift!
-Cleaves to shuttle, respond.
We need to move and we can't be
collected from the evac tower.
-CAPTAIN: Give us the code word.
-The code word is...
(EXPLODING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Cleaves, Cleaves, it's dead! It's dead.
We need to get out of here.
We need to get back downstairs
and get those vents back on! Come on!
This is our chance. How can we route
the shuttle to the courtyard?
You can't guess the code word.
Yes, I can, Jimmy,
because I created the code word.
Shuttle, do you read me?
This is Foreman Cleaves.
Cleaves, you... You got cut off.
Say again. What's the request?
You need to reroute and pick us up
from the courtyard.
Courtyard?
As soon as we can.
Give me the code word.
Shuttle, the code word is Bad Boy.
I repeat, Bad Boy.
Copy that. The courtyard.
Still want us
to take care of those Gangers?
Negative. They've all been incinerated.
Bad Boy.
Good call.
Yeah, well, it wasn't luck.
We're the same person.
This room's always sealed.
Power surge must've thrown the bolts.
What is that?
Discarded Flesh. Faulty, probably.
Just thrown away. Look at them.
One of my old Gangers.
(YELPS)
Left to rot, fully conscious.
Can you imagine
what kind of hell they're in?
But Cleaves... (STAMMERING)
The company, how could they do this?
How could they?
Who are the real monsters?
We can't let this carry on.
Jen, we have to make people see.
Okay, Rory, I have an idea.
You came for me. We have a bond, right?
We trust each other.
-Yeah.
-So, trust me on this.
I'm getting something.
-Is it human?
-Yeah, it's human.
But it's fading, it's fading!
This is bad. Fading is very...
bad.
-(GRUNTS)
-The signal's gone.
She's dead.
(SIGHING) She was hanging to
the edge of life
but she just, just slipped away.
(SIGHS) Jennifer, I'm so sorry.
Oh, she's been out here for hours.
But if the real Jen's been
lying out here...
Rory's in trouble.
Sorry, pal. It's boss' orders.
Us and them, innit?
Ah.
The eyes have it.
AMY: Why are they here?
To accuse us.
Ignore them, it's not far.
(RUMBLING)
I should've been a postman like me dad.
(JENNIFER SHUSHING)
I'm here, I'm here.
I'm with you.
I know, it hurts.
I'm sorry.
Go to sleep.
Sleep.
BUZZER: You killed her.
You killed our Jen.
And I'm stronger, Buzz.
I can grow.
(BUZZER SCREAMING)
(ALARMS SOUNDING)
It's a chemical chain reaction now.
I can't stop it.
This place is going to blow sky high.
Exactly how long have we got?
An hour? Five seconds?
Somewhere in between.
(KLAXON SOUNDING)
Out!
RORY: Oh, all right.
-Oh, Rory, oh, Rory.
-Oh.
There's a way out, Jennifer found it.
A secret tunnel under the crypt.
From the crypt?
It's not on the schematics.
It leads right out of the monastery,
maybe even under the Tardis, Doctor.
Follow me.
(KLAXON SOUNDING)
Ah.
Got anything for a sore head?
This is how they'll always treat us.
Do you see now?
After all, you're one of us,
Doctor.
(SIGHS) Call me Smith.
John Smith.
We can't leave without Buzzer!
I'll go back for him.
Uh, Doctor, look, I'd better tell you,
I haven't been quite straight with you.
DOCTOR: Rory!
Hang on, Jen, we don't want to
lock them out.
We should just show them
what we've found.
I don't think so.
-Rory Pond. Roranicus Pondicus!
-Rory, what the hell are you playing at?
They've been throwing away
old Flesh and leaving it to rot
alive!
I think the world should see that.
Rory, there is no time.
This factory's about to explode!
Are you sure about this?
'Cause I'm not. Let them out.
-The little girl got strong.
-What?
The little girl lost on the moors
in her red wellies,
looking for a way home.
Well, she got strong, Rory.
-I told you, remember?
-But that wasn't...
It was the other Jennifer that told me
about being a little girl.
Oh?
What other Jennifer?
Well, the...
The, uh...
Wait, you tricked me. Let me go,
I'm opening the door, let me...
I'm sorry!
No!
We have to be free.
I'm sorry, too, Miranda.
Of all the humans in all the world,
you had to pick the one with the clot.
But hey, them's the breaks!
Welcome to the human race.
(SONIC BEEPING)
This is going to overheat
and fill the room with acid.
Just as a point of interest.
-And we can't stop it?
-Just as a point of interest?
-(LOUD THUMPING)
-No.
You created another Ganger
just to trick me. You tricked me!
When I found you, you were both Flesh.
And you tricked me into trusting you!
Jen's dead.
-Isn't she?
-She's gone, Rory! Gone!
CAPTAIN: Shuttle. We're dropping down
on our approach.
Stand by for evac.
The humans will be melted,
as they deserve.
And then the factory will be destroyed.
Once we get to the mainland,
the real battle begins.
The humans won't stand a chance.
You're one of us, Doctor.
Join the revolution.
I've got to go and get them out!
It'll never hold her.
If you have a better plan, I'm all ears.
In fact, if you have a better plan,
I'll take you to a planet
where everyone is all ears.
Doctor, we can't just let them die.
-Ring ring.
-Doctor!
Ring ring!
Oh...
The acid's eating through.
(EXCLAIMS)
(CRASHING)
-Stay!
-Okay.
(PHONE RINGING)
Ah, that'll be the phone.
Somebody get the phone.
Jimmy, get the phone.
No, fine, I'll get the phone. Stay put.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Thank you for booking
your holo-call with Morpeth Jetsan.
Ah! Hello, madam.
I'm the Doctor. Well, other Doctor.
Well, Smith.
It's complicated and boring.
Anyway, who cares? It's your birthday!
-Ya y_/
-Yay!
Now, have you been getting up
very early and jumping on the bed?
Yes, really high.
I expect chocolate for breakfast.
If you don't feel sick by mid-morning,
you're not doing it right.
Now, I think you want to speak to Dad.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Daddy?
You'll do, Jimmy.
What does the other Jimmy matter now?
You're both the same dad, aren't you?
Come on. Adam's waiting.
Daddy...
(LOUD RUMBLING)
Daddy, what's that rumbly noise?
What's going on, Daddy?
Daddy?
You tricked him into an act
of weakness, Doctor.
No, I've helped him
into an act of humanity.
Anyone else like the sound
of that act of humanity?
Dicken, drain the acid well
in Crypt One.
-Don't you dare!
-I've had it with this.
What's the point in this ridiculous war?
Look at you, Jen.
You were a sweet kid. Look at you now.
The stuff of nightmares.
I don't want my world
populated by monsters.
You can't stop the factory
from melting down, boss.
I'll take revenge on humanity
with or without you.
It doesn't have to be about revenge.
It can be so much better than that.
(GRUNTING)
(BEEPING)
(SCREAMING)
Let me through!
There's nothing we can do.
The acid's reached his heart.
(GASPING)
-Hang in there, mate.
-I'm quite handsome from this angle.
(GASPING)
I'm sorry.
I'm the fake.
Adam deserves his real dad.
-Shut up.
-What do you want me to do?
Anything.
Just say.
The way things are, mate,
it's up to you now.
Be a dad.
You remember how.
Jimmy Wicks, you're a dad.
Daddy? Where's my daddy?
Daddy, it's me.
(CHUCKLES) Hey, sunshine.
What are you up to?
Opening all my presents.
Ah, good lad.
You have fun today.
And remember your dad,
he loves you very, very much.
When are you coming home?
-Daddy's coming home today, Adam.
-Yay!
Now we need to move.
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(SNARLING)
Run. Run!
Run!
(RUMBLING)
Ooh, roof's going to give.
We have to stop her!
This door doesn't lock!
No, but the far one does.
(SNARLING)
-(SCREAMING)
-No!
Here she comes.
Whoa!
Oh! She does like to make an entrance!
Get on the move!
-Go, go, go!
-Get aboard! Go!
I'm not leaving.
(EXCLAIMS)
Go!
Hey, hey. Now's our chance.
I have to stay, hold this door closed.
Give you time to dematerialise.
Oh, don't be crazy.
Okay, what happens to you, hmm?
Well, this place
is just about to explode.
But I can stop her.
Both of you can survive this.
I mean, there has to be a way.
Or perhaps you think
I should stay instead, Mr Smith?
No, of course not.
But look, this man, I've flown with him.
You know? And you are amazing,
and yeah, I misjudged you.
But you're not him, I'm sorry.
Amy, we swapped shoes.
-I'm the Doctor.
-And I'm the Flesh.
You can't be. You're the real him.
No, I'm not
and I haven't been all along.
-What?
-I'm the original Doctor, Amy.
We had to know
if we were truly the same.
It was important, vital we learn
about the Flesh.
And we could only do that
through your eyes.
I never thought it possible.
What?
You're twice the man I thought you were.
DOCTOR: Push, Amy.
But only when she tells you to.
Amy, come on!
(LOUD SNARLING)
Well, my death arrives, I suppose.
-But this one we're not invited to.
-Pardon?
Nothing. Your molecular memory
can survive this, you know,
it may not be the end.
Well, if I turn up to nick
all your biscuits,
then you'll know you were right,
won't you?
Doctor! No, please...
(BANGING)
-You too, Cleaves, off you pop.
-I'm staying here.
This is not the time for grand gestures.
Says the king of grand gestures.
This is my factory,
I'm not going anywhere.
Foreman Miranda Cleaves! Marvellous.
Beware of imitations.
Clear off out of here, the lot of you.
(SNARLING CONTINUES)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-This will dissolve her.
-And us, too.
-There may be a way back from this.
-From being vaporised? How?
Don't know. Let's find out, eh?
Geronimo.
Uh, the energy from the Tardis
will stabilise the Gangers for good.
They're people now.
And what happens to me?
Um...I still have this.
Ah! That's not a problem,
I have something for that.
It's small and red
and it tastes like burnt onions.
Ha! But it'll get rid of
your blood clot.
Happy endings.
JIMMY: Hey! Hello, bud.
-Hey!
-Daddy, you're back.
Hello, my boy. How are you doing?
You really want us to do this?
Your company's telling telling the world
that the situation is over.
You need to get in there and tell them
that the situation has only just begun.
Make them understand what
they're doing to the Flesh.
Make them stop.
Dicken, remember, people are good,
in their bones, truly good.
-Don't hate them, will you?
-How can I hate them?
I'm one of them now.
Yeah. And just remember, people died,
don't let that be in vain.
Make what you say in that room count.
Ready?
Side by side.
You got it, boss.
(PEOPLE CLAMOURING)
You okay?
I said breathe, Pond.
Remember? Well, breathe.
-Why?
-Breathe.
-Oh!
-Good.
Whoa! Whoa.
What's wrong with her?
Get her into the Tardis.
(GROANING)
Doctor, what is happening to her?
Contractions.
-Contractions?
-She's going into lab our.
Did he say...
No, no, of course he didn't.
Rory, um, I don't like this.
Ow!
You're going to have to start explaining
some of this to me, Doctor!
What, the birds and the bees?
She's having a baby.
I needed to see the Flesh
in its early days,
that's why I scanned it.
That's why we were there
in the first place.
I was going to drop you off
for fish and chips first
but things happened,
and there was stuff and shenanigans.
Beautiful word, shenanigans.
-It hurts.
-You'll be okay.
Breathe.
I needed enough information
to block the signal to the Flesh.
What signal?
The signal to you.
Doctor, Doctor...
Stand away from her, Rory.
Why? No! And why?
Given what we've learned,
I'll be as humane as I can.
But I need to do this
and you need to stand away!
No...
Doctor, I am frightened.
I'm properly, properly scared.
Don't be. Hold on.
We're coming for you, I swear.
And whatever happens, however hard,
however far, we will find you.
I'm right here.
No, you're not. You haven't been here
for a long, long time.
Oh, no.
(BLEEPING)
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
Well, dear,
you're ready to pop, aren't you?
Little one's on its way.
(WHIMPERING)
Here it comes!
Push.
(SCREAMS)