Doctor, it says in 7he Intrepid
Universe Traveller Handbook
that if you want to properly call
yourself a space traveller
you're supposed to have
an adventure at least once a week.
-Well!
-Well,
-we haven't had an adventure in ages.
-You're absolutely right.
Adventure it is!
(YELPS)
-What was that? what did you just do?
-Exactly what you asked me to.
I set the Tardis to Adventure setting.
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
Are you sure you didn't set it to
Kill Amy And The Doctor setting?
Now, now, now, now,
hang on, that was meant to happen!
-So was that.
-I'm sure it was.
Perhaps I should take it down
just a smidge.
-0h!
-What? What is it?
Systems malfunctioning, Tardis crashing.
Oh, great!
Okay, Tardis going down in
three, two, one... Landing!
(AMY SCREAMS)
-Ha!
-(GROANS)
-Now...
-Ah, so,
where are we, Einstein?
I'm not quite sure. It appears
as though we've landed in the middle
of an Olympic running track.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Where am I?
And what the heck's happened
to your hair?
Yes, yes, yes. From the look of you,
you're an Olympic torch bearer,
London 2012, if I'm not mistaken.
I'm the Doctor, this is Amy, and welcome
to my spaceship, the Tardis. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, and my hair, well, that's a story
for another time.
Wait, there was something chasing me.
That's why I didn't see your.. box.
(AMY YELPS)
BOTH: Don't blink!
Hey!
-How did it do that?
-Oh my God, Doctor, what's it doing?
It's trying to steal the Olympic flame
and destroy the very spirit
of respect, excellence and friendship
it represents.
Well, at least it's trying to.
Ah!
Wow! Thanks, Doctor.
I'd better get going, though,
I've got to light the Olympic flame.
Here, you deserve this.
Oh, thank you very much.
Good as gold you are, Doctor. Bye.
BOTH: Bye!
Ah, cool!
Right, where were we? Ah, yes.
Adventure!