The Tardis is still in the same place
but the Earth has gone.
Exterminate!
Welcome to my new empire.
Ladies and gentlemen, we are at war.
Exterminate Torchwood!
I surrender! I'm sorry!
The Doctor is coming!
He's dying, and you know
what happens next.
-But he can't.
-What do you mean? What happens next?
I'm regenerating.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Ah!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Now then, where were we?
-Exterminate!
-Mickey?
-Us Smiths gotta stick together.
Jackie Tyler. Rose's mum.
Now, where the hell is my daughter?
What the hell?
There now.
You see?
Used the regeneration energy
to heal myself,
but as soon as that was done,
I didn't need to change.
I didn't want to, why would I?
Look at me.
So to stop the energy going all the way,
I siphoned off the rest into
a handy bio-matching receptacle,
namely, my hand, my hand there.
My handy spare hand!
Remember? Christmas Day, Sycorax?
Lost my hand in a sword fight?
That's my hand!
What do you think?
You're still you?
I'm still me.
You can hug me if you want.
No, really, you can hug me.
IANTO: It's a time lock.
The ultimate defence programme.
Tosh was working on it.
I never thought she finished it,
but she did!
The Hub's sealed in a time bubble,
nothing can get in.
-But that means we can get out.
-Nope.
Not without unlocking that Dalek.
We're trapped inside.
It's all up to Jack now.
DALEK: Report! Tardis has been located.
DALEK SUPREME: Bring it here!
Bring the Doctor to me!
Initiate temporal prison!
DALEX. Temporal prison initiated!
DOCTOR: They've got us! Power's gone!
Some kind of chronon loop.
DALEX:. Transferring Tardis
to the crucible.
Those teleport things, can we use them?
If they've taken the Doctor
to the Dalek spaceship,
then that's where we need to be.
It's not just a teleport,
it's a Dimension Jump.
This thing rips a hole
in the fabric of space.
SARAH JANE: But can we use it?
Not yet, it burns up energy.
Needs half an hour between jumps.
-Then put down your guns.
-Do what?
If you're carrying a gun,
they'll shoot you dead.
Daleks! I surrender!
DALEK: All humans in this sector
will be taken to the crucible!
She's bloody mad!
Yeah, but, Mickey, if they've got
the Doctor then they've got Rose.
And us. We surrender.
Now Jack's explained the base code,
I know how this teleport works.
I think. But you just stay indoors,
there's no Daleks on this street,
you should be all right,
just keep quiet.
But where are you going?
I'm a member of UNIT. And
they gave me the Osterhagen Key.
I've got to do my job. I'm sorry.
Martha, what's an Osterhagen Key?
Tell me. What does it do?
Love you.
(DALEKS SPEAKING GERMAN)
JACK: There's a massive Dalek ship
at the centre of the planets.
They're calling it the Crucible.
Guess that's our destination.
You said these planets
were like an engine. But what for?
Rose? You've been in a parallel world,
that world's running ahead
of this universe.
You've seen the future. What was it?
-It's the darkness.
-The stars were going out.
One by one. We looked up
at the sky and they were just dying.
Basically, we've been building
this travel machine,
this... This Dimension Cannon
so I could...
Well, so I could...
-What?
-So I could come back.
Shut up. Anyway, suddenly
it started to work
and the dimensions started to collapse.
Not just in our world, not just
in yours, but the whole of reality.
Even the Void was dead.
Something is destroying everything.
In that parallel world,
you said something about me.
The Dimension Cannon could
measure time lines and it's...
It's weird, Donna, but they
all seem to converge on you.
But why me?
I mean, what have I ever done?
I'm a temp from Chiswick!
(BEEPING)
The Dalek Crucible. All aboard!
DALEX. The Tardis is secured.
Doctor, you will step forth or die.
We'll have to go out.
'Cause if we don't, they'll get in.
You told me nothing could
get through those doors.
You've got extrapolator shielding.
Last time we fought the Daleks,
they were scavengers
and hybrids and mad.
But this is a fully-fledged Dalek Empire
at the height of its power,
experts at fighting Tardises,
they can do anything.
Right now, that wooden door
is just wood.
(HEART BEATING)
JACK: What about your Dimension Jump?
ROSE: It needs another 20 minutes.
And anyway, I'm not leaving.
DOCTOR: What about your teleport?
JACK: Went down with the power loss.
DOCTOR: Right then,
all of us together. Yeah.
Donna?
Donna.
Yeah.
I'm sorry,
there's nothing else we can do.
I know.
Surrender, Doctor,
and face your Dalek masters.
DALEK: Crucible on maximum alert!
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY) Daleks!
Oh, God!
It's been good, though, hasn't it?
All of us, all of it. Everything we did.
You were brilliant.
And you were brilliant.
Blimey.
DALEK: Daleks reign supreme.
All hail the Daleks!
ALL: Daleks reign supreme.
(HEART BEATING)
Daleks reign supreme.
All hail the Daleks!
SUPREME DALEK: Behold, Doctor!
Behold the might of the true Dalek race!
(HEART BEATING)
Donna! You're no safer in there.
Donna?
Doctor?
-What have you done?
-It wasn't me, I didn't do anything!
Oi! Oi, I'm not staying behind!
-What did you do?
-This is not of Dalek origin.
Doctor!
Stop it, she's my friend.
Now, open the door and let her out.
-This is Time Lord treachery.
-Hey, the door just closed on its own!
Nevertheless, the Tardis is a weapon.
And it will be destroyed!
What are you doing? Bring it back!
-Doctor!
-What've you done? Where's it going?
The Crucible has a heart of
Z-Neutrino energy.
The Tardis will be deposited
into the core.
You can't.
You've taken the defences down.
It'll be torn apart!
-But Donna's still in there!
-Let her go!
The female and the Tardis
will perish together. Observe!
The last child of Gallifrey
ls powerless.
Please, I'm begging you,
I'll do anything!
Put me in her place.
You can do anything to me, I don't care,
just get her out of there!
(HEART BEATING)
You are connected to the Tardis.
Now feel it die!
-It's you.
-Oh, yes!
-You're naked.
DALEX:. Total Tardis destruction
in 10 rels.
Nine, eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three two, one.
The Tardis has been destroyed.
Now, tell me, Doctor,
what do you feel?
Anger? Sorrow?
Despair?
Yeah.
Then if emotions are so important,
surely we have enhanced you?
Yeah? Feel this!
Exterminate!
Jack! Oh, my God! Oh, no...
-Rose, come here, leave him.
-They killed him.
I know. I'm sorry.
-Escort them to the Vault.
-There's nothing we can do.
They are the playthings of Davros now.
All repaired. Lovely. Shh!
No one knows we're here.
Gotta keep quiet.
Silent running, like on submarines
when they can't even drop a spanner.
Don't drop a spanner. I like blue.
What do you think?
You are bonkers.
-Why, what's wrong with blue?
-Is that what Time Lords do?
Lop a bit off, grow another one?
You're like worms!
No, no, no, no, no. I'm unique.
Never been another like me.
'Cause all that regeneration energy
went into the hand.
Look at my hand! I love that hand!
But then you touched it, wham!
Shh!
Instantaneous biological met a crisis.
I grew out of you.
Still, could be worse.
-0i! Watch it, spaceman!
-0i! Watch it, Earth girl! Ooh.
I sound like you.
I sound all... All sort of rough.
-Oi!
-0i!
-Spanners! Shh!
I must've picked up a bit of your voice,
that's all. Is it? Did I? No!
Ooh, you are kidding me! No way!
One heart. I've got one heart!
This body has got only one heart!
-Like you're human?
-Oh, that's disgusting.
-Oi!
-0i!
Stop it!
No, wait, I'm part Time Lord,
part human.
Well, isn't that wizard?
I kept hearing that noise,
that heartbeat.
Oh, that was me. My single heart.
I'm a complicated event
in time and space,
it must have rippled back,
converging on you.
But why me?
-'Cause you're special.
-I keep telling you, I'm not!
No, but you are.
Oh, you really don't believe that,
do you?
I can see, Donna, what you're thinking.
All that attitude, all that lip,
"cause all this time
-you think you're not worth it.
-Stop it.
Shouting at the world
"cause no one's listening.
-Well, why should they?
-Doctor, stop it.
But look at what you did.
No, it's more than that, it's like
we were always heading for this.
You came to the Tardis.
Then you found me again.
Your granddad! Your car.
Donna, your car. You parked your car
right where the Tardis was
going to land, that's not coincidence.
Oh, we've been blind.
Something's been drawing us together
for such a long time.
But you're talking like destiny.
There's no such thing, is there?
It's still not finished.
Like the pattern's not complete,
the strands are still drawing together.
But heading for what?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(WITH GERMAN ACCENT)
That accent, that is London, ja?
I went to London. Long time ago.
I thought this place
was supposed to be guarded.
They were soldiers. Boys.
I brought them food, every day.
But when the Albtraume came
from the sky, they went home, to die.
-But not you?
-I've got a job to do.
London, in those days, to see it!
So much glamour. I was so young.
I heard the soldiers talking.
Many times.
They would speak of the Osterhagen Key.
I think London must be changed now, yes?
But still, the glamour.
(GUN CLICKING)
You will not go.
I've got no choice.
I know the Key. What it does.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Then do it.
I know.
Commence disposal. Incinerate!
Disposal completed.
This is Osterhagen Station One.
My name is Martha Jones.
Is there anyone there? Over.
DALEK: Prisoners now
on board the Crucible.
They will be taken for testing!
One step closer to the Doctor.
Activate the holding cells.
Excellent.
Even when powerless,
a Time Lord is best contained.
Still scared of me, then?
It is time we talked, Doctor,
after so very long.
No, no, no, we're not doing
the nostalgia tour.
I want to know what's happening
right here, right now.
'Cause the Supreme Dalek
said Vault, yeah?
As in dungeon. Cellar. Prison.
You're not in charge of
the Daleks, are you?
They've got you locked away down here in
the basement like, what, a servant?
A slave? Court jester?
We have...an arrangement.
No, no, no, no, no. I've got the word.
You're the Dalek's pet.
So very full of fire, is he not?
And to think you crossed
entire universes,
striding parallel to parallel
to find him again.
-Leave her alone.
-She is mine, to do as I please.
Then why am I still alive?
You must be here. It was foretold.
Even the Supreme Dalek
would not dare to contradict
the prophecies of Dalek Caan.
DALEK CAAN: So cold and dark,
fire is coming,
the endless flames.
What is that thing?
You've met before.
The last of the Cult of Skaro.
But it flew into the Time War,
unprotected.
Caan did more than that he saw Time.
Its infinite complexity and
majesty raging through his mind.
And he saw you. Both of you.
This I have foreseen
in the wild, in the wind.
The Doctor will be here as witness
at the end of everything.
The Doctor and his precious
children of time.
(EVIL LAUGH)
And one of them will die!
Was it you, Caan? Did you kill Donna?
Why did the Tardis door close? Tell me!
Oh, that's it! The anger! The fire!
The rage of a Time Lord
who butchered millions.
There he is.
Why so shy?
Show your companion.
Show her your true self.
Dalek Caan has promised me that, too.
I have seen at the time of ending
the Doctor's soul will be revealed.
What does that mean?
We will discover it together.
Our final journey.
Because the ending approaches,
the testing begins.
Testing of what?
The Reality Bomb.
DALEK: Prisoners will stand in
the designated area!
Move! Move!
You will stand!
-I can't.
-You will stand!
I can't. Please.
On your feet. On your feet!
Mickey, Mickey.
Jackie.
Prisoners will stand
in the designated area!
-We can't just leave her!
-No, Mickey, wait!
...in 30 rels.
What does it mean?
What are they testing?
What are they gonna do?
I reckon it's that thing there.
SUPREME DALEK:
Testing calibration of Reality Bomb.
Firing in 10 rels.
Nine, eight, seven, six...
Behold the apotheosis of my genius!
...one, Zero.
Activate planetary alignment field!
It's the planets. The 27 planets!
But that's Z-Neutrino energy.
Flattened by the alignment of
the planets into a single string.
No! Davros! Davros, you can't!
You can't! No!
Single string Z-Neutrinos
compressed into...
No. No way!
(BEEPING)
Thirty minutes. It's recharged!
(INAUDIBLE)
Use it!
I'm so sorry.
Test completed.
What was it?
Doctor, what did it do?
Doctor, what happened?
Electrical energy, Miss Tyler.
Every atom in existence is
bound by an electrical field.
The Reality Bomb cancels it out.
Structure falls apart.
That test was focused
on the prisoners alone,
full transmission will dissolve
every form of matter.
-The stars are going out.
-The 27 planets.
They become one vast transmitter.
-Blasting that wavelength...
-Across the entire universe.
Never stopping, never faltering,
never fading.
People and planets and stars
will become dust,
and the dust will become atoms,
and the atoms will become nothing.
And the wavelength will continue
breaking through the rift
at the heart of the Medusa Cascade
into every dimension, every parallel.
Every single corner of creation!
This is my ultimate victory, Doctor!
The destruction of reality itself!
Prepare for universal detonation!
The fleet will gather at the Crucible!
All Daleks will return to shelter
from the cataclysm!
We will become the only life forms
in existence!
But they're leaving! Dad, they're going,
the Daleks are going.
Going where, though?
And Donna's still out there.
It's not over yet, sweetheart.
Just my luck. I climb through
two miles of ventilation shafts
chasing life signs on this thing,
and who do I find?
-Mickey Mouse.
-You can talk, Captain Cheesecake.
-Good to see you.
-And that's "beefcake".
And that's enough hugging.
We meet at last, Miss Smith.
There is something we can do.
You've got to understand,
I have a son down there on Earth.
He's only 14 years old.
I brought this.
It was given to me by
a Verron soothsayer.
He said, "This is for the end of days."
Is that a Warp Star?
Gonna tell me what a Warp Star is?
A warpfold conjugation
trapped in a carbonised shell.
It's an explosion, Mickey.
An explosion waiting to happen.
This is Osterhagen Station Five.
Are you receiving, Station One?
I've got you. That makes three
of us. And three is all we need.
My name is Anna Zhou, what's yours?
Martha Jones. What about you,
Station Four? You never said.
I don't want my name on this.
Given what we're about to do.
So what happens now? Do we do it?
No. Not yet.
UNIT instructions say once
three Osterhagen Stations are online...
Yeah, well, I've got a higher authority,
way above UNIT.
And there's one more thing
the Doctor would do.
-So, what is this thing?
-It's our only hope.
A Z-Neutrino biological
inversion catalyser.
Yeah. Earth girl, remember?
Davros said he built those Daleks
out of himself.
His genetic code
runs through the entire race.
If I can use this to lock
the Crucible's transmission
-onto Davros himself...
-It destroys the Daleks!
Biggest backfire in history!
Incoming transmission!
Origin planet Earth.
Display.
This is Martha Jones representing
the Unified Intelligence Taskforce
on behalf of the human race.
SUPREME DALEK: Send transmission
to the Vault. Continue to monitor.
...for the Dalek Crucible.
Repeat, can you hear me?
Put me through.
It begins, as Dalek Caan foretold.
DALEK CAAN: The children of time
will gather.
And one of them will die!
Stop saying that! Put me through!
Doctor. I'm sorry, I had to.
Oh, but the Doctor is powerless.
My prisoner.
State your intent.
I've got the Osterhagen Key.
Leave this planet and its people alone
or I'll use it.
Osterhagen what?
What's an Osterhagen Key?
There's a chain of 25 nuclear warheads
placed in strategic points
beneath the Earth's crust.
If I use the key, they detonate
and the Earth gets ripped apart.
What? Who invented that?
Well, someone called Osterhagen,
I suppose. Martha, are you insane?
The Osterhagen Key is to be used
if the suffering of the human race
is so great,
so without hope,
that this becomes the final option.
That's never an option!
Don't argue with me, Doctor!
'Cause it's more than that.
Now, I reckon the Daleks need
these 27 planets for something,
but what if it becomes 267
What happens then?
Daleks? Would you risk it?
She's good.
-MARTHA: Who's that?
-My name's Rose. Rose Tyler.
Oh, my God. He found you.
Second transmission, internal!
Display.
Captain Jack Harkness
calling all Dalek boys and girls.
Are you receiving me?
Don't send in your goons
or I'll set this thing off!
He's still alive!
Oh, my God, that's my mum!
DOCTOR: Mickey, Captain,
what are you doing?
I've got a Warp Star wired
into the mainframe.
I break this shell,
the entire Crucible goes up.
You can't!
Where did you get a Warp Star?
From me. We had no choice.
We saw what happened to the prisoners.
Impossible.
That face. After all these years.
Davros.
It's been quite a while.
Sarah Jane Smith, remember?
Oh, this is meant to be!
The circle of time is closing.
You were there on Skaro
at the very beginning of my creation.
And I've learnt how to fight since then.
You let the Doctor go
or this Warp Star, it gets opened.
I'll do it. Don't imagine I wouldn't.
Now that's what I call a ransom!
Doctor?
And the prophecy unfolds.
DALEK CAAN:
The Doctor's soul is revealed!
(EVIL LAUGH)
See him! See the heart of him!
The man who abhors violence.
Never carrying a gun.
But this is the truth, Doctor!
You take ordinary people and
you fashion them into weapons.
Behold your children of time
transformed into murderers.
I made the Daleks, Doctor.
You made this.
They're trying to help.
Already I have seen them
sacrificed today
for their beloved Doctor.
The Earth woman who fell
opening the Subwave Network.
-Who was that?
-Harriet Jones.
She gave her life to get you here.
How many more? Just think.
How many have died in your name?
The Doctor. The man who keeps running,
never looking back
because he dare not out of shame.
This is my final victory, Doctor.
I have shown you yourself.
Enough.
Engage defence zero five.
It's the Crucible or the Earth.
Transmat engaged!
-JACK: I've got you.
-Don't move, all of you. Stay still!
Guard them! On your knees,
all of you! Surrender!
Do as he says.
Mum. I told you not to.
Yeah, well, I couldn't leave you.
The final prophecy is in place.
The Doctor and his children
all gathered as witnesses!
Supreme Dalek, the time has come. Now!
Detonate the Reality Bomb!
Activate planetary alignment field.
Universal Reality Detonation
in 200 rels.
You can't, Davros, just listen to me!
Just stop!
(LAUGHING)
Nothing can stop the detonation!
Nothing and no one!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Ready! Maximum power!
But that's...
(WHOOSHING)
Impossible!
Brilliant!
Don't!
Activate holding cell.
Doctor!
I've got it!
But I don't know what to do!
Donna!
Donna! Are you all right, Donna?
DAVROS: Destroy the weapon.
I was wrong about your warriors, Doctor.
They are pathetic!
-How come there's two of you?
-Human biological met a crisis.
Never mind that. Now we've got
no way of stopping the Reality Bomb.
Detonation in 20 rels. Nineteen...
Stand witness, Time Lord.
Stand witness, humans.
Your strategies have failed.
Your weapons are useless.
And, oh,
the end of the universe has come!
SUPREME DALEK: ...nine, eight, seven,
six, five four,
three, two, one.
(BEEPING)
And closing all Z-Neutrino relay loops
using an internalised synchronous
back-feed reversal loop.
That button there.
-System in shutdown!
-Detonation negative! Explain!
Explain! Explain!
-Donna, you can't even change a plug!
-Do you wanna bet, Time Boy?
You'll suffer for this!
(SCREAMING)
Ooh, bio-electric dampening field
with a retrogressive arc inversion.
Exterminate her!
Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate!
Weapons non-functional!
Whor! Macrotransmission of a K-filter
wavelength blocking Dalek weaponry
in a self-replicating
energy blindfold matrix.
How did you work that out? You're...
Time Lord, part Time Lord.
Part human! Oh, yes!
That was a two-way
biological met a crisis.
Half Doctor, half Donna.
Doctor Donna.
Just like the Ood said, remember?
They saw it coming!
The Doctor Donna!
Holding cells deactivated.
Unseal the Vault.
Well, don't just stand there,
you skinny boys in suits!
Get to work!
Stop them!
Get her away from the controls.
And spin.
Help me! Help me!
DONNA: And the other way.
-What did you do?
-A trip stitch circuit breaker
in the psycho-kinetic
threshold manipulator!
-But that's brilliant!
-Why did we never think of that?
Because you two were
just Time Lords, you dumbos!
Lacking that little
bit of human, that gut instinct,
that comes hand in hand
with planet Earth.
I can think of ideas you two
wouldn't dream of in a million years!
Oh, the universe
has been waiting for me!
Now, let's send that trip stitch
all over the ship!
Did I ever tell you? Best temp in
Chiswick, 100 words per minute!
Ha!
System malfunctioning!
Motor casing interference!
What is happening? Explain!
Come on then, boys,
we've got 27 planets to send home.
Activate Magnatron!
Stop this at once!
Mickey!
You will desist!
Just stay where you are, mister.
Out of the way!
-Good to see you again!
-Yeah, you, too!
Ready? And reverse!
Off you go, Clom.
Back home, Adipose III!
Shallacatop, Pyrovillia
and the Lost Moon of Poosh, sorted! Ha!
Ha!
DOCTOR: We need more power.
Is anyone gonna tell us what's going on?
He poured all his regeneration energy
into his spare hand.
I touched the hand, he grew out of that
but that fed back into me.
But it just stayed dormant
in my head till the synapses
got that extra little spark,
kicking them into life.
Thank you, Davros!
Part human, part Time Lord.
And I got the best bit of the Doctor.
I got his mind.
-SARAH JANE: So there's three of you?
-Three Doctors?
I can't tell you
what I'm thinking right now.
You are so unique,
the time lines were converging on you.
A human being with a Time Lord brain!
But you promised me, Dalek Caan!
Why did you not foresee this?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, I think he did. Something's been
manipulating the time lines for ages.
Getting Donna Noble to
the right place at the right time.
This would always have happened.
I only helped, Doctor.
You betrayed the Daleks!
I saw the Daleks,
what we have done
throughout time and space.
I saw the truth of us, Creator,
and I decreed no more!
I will descend to the Vault!
Heads up!
Davros, you have betrayed us!
It was Dalek Caan!
The Vault will be purged!
You will all be exterminated!
Like I was saying. Feel this!
Oh, we've lost the Magnatron!
And there's only one planet left.
Guess which one?
But we can use the Tardis.
Holding Earth stability,
maintaining atmospheric shell.
-The prophecy must complete.
-Don't listen to him!
I have seen the end of everything Dalek
and you must make it happen, Doctor.
He's right. 'Cause with
or without a Reality Bomb,
this Dalek Empire's big enough
to slaughter the cosmos.
-They've got to be stopped.
-Just wait for the Doctor.
I am the Doctor!
Maximising Dalekenium power feeds.
Blasting them back!
(EXPLOSION)
-What have you done?
-Fulfilling the prophecy.
There goes the time lock.
Do you know what you've done?
Now, get in the Tardis!
Everyone!
All of you inside! Run!
In! In! In! In! In!
Sarah Jane! Rose! Jackie! Jack! Mickey!
Davros, come with me!
I promise I can save you.
Never forget, Doctor, you did this!
I name you forever!
You are the Destroyer of Worlds!
(SCREAMING)
One will still die.
And off we go!
But what about the Earth?
It's stuck in the wrong part of space.
I'm on it! Torchwood Hub, this is
the Doctor. Are you receiving me?
Loud and clear.
-Is Jack there?
-Can't get rid of him.
-Jack, what's her name?
-Gwen Cooper.
Tell me, Gwen Cooper,
are you from an old Cardiff family?
Yes, all the way back to the 1800s.
Ah, thought so.
Spatial genetic multiplicity.
Ah, yeah, it's a funny old world.
Now, Torchwood, I want you to open up
that Rift Manipulator
-and send all the power to me.
-Doing it now, sir.
-What's that for?
-It's a tow rope.
-Sarah, what was your son's name?
-Luke! He's called Luke!
-And the computer's called Mr Smith.
-Calling Luke and Mr Smith.
This is the Doctor.
Come on, Luke, shake a leg.
-Is Mum there?
-Oh, she's fine and dandy.
Now, Mr Smith, I want you
to harness the rift power
and loop it around the Tardis,
you got that?
MR SMITH: I regret, I will need remote
access to Tardis base code numerals.
Oh, blimey, that's gonna take a while.
SARAH JANE: No, no, no, let me!
K9, out you come.
K9: Affirmative, mistress.
Oh, good dog!
K9, give Mr Smith the base code.
Master. Tardis base code
now being transferred.
K9: The process is simple.
Now then, you lot. Sarah,
hold that down, Mickey, you hold that.
Do you know why this Tardis
is always rattling about the place?
Rose, that, there.
It's designed to have six pilots
and I have to do it single-handed!
Martha, keep that level.
But not any more.
Jack, there you go, steady that.
Now we can fly this thing...
No, Jackie, no, no, not you.
Don't touch anything, just stand back.
Like it's meant to be flown!
We've got the Torchwood rift
looped around the Tardis by Mr Smith
and we're gonna
fly planet Earth back home!
Right, then! Off we go.
(CHEERING)
(WHOOPING)
That's really good, Jack,
I think you're the best.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
You know, you act like
such a lonely man.
But look at you.
You've got the biggest family on Earth!
Gotta go! He's only 14.
It's a long story.
And thank you!
DONNA: Yeah, I'm fine.
Are you all right? Yeah, I know.
I'm gonna miss you. More than anyone.
What do you mean? The Doctor's going to
take us home, isn't he?
Well, that's the point.
I told you. No teleport!
And, Martha, get rid
of that Osterhagen thing, eh?
-Save the world one more time.
-Consider it done.
You know, I'm not sure
about UNIT these days.
Maybe there's something else
you could be doing.
Oi, where are you going?
Well, I'm not stupid.
I can work out what happens next.
And, hey, I had a good time
in that parallel world
but my gran passed away,
nice and peaceful.
She spent her last years
Living in a mansion.
There's nothing there for me now,
certainly not Rose.
What will you do?
Anything. Brand new life.
Just you watch.
See you, boss. Hey, you two!
JACK: Oh. I thought I'd got rid of you.
Just time for one last trip.
Darlig Ulv Stranden. Better known as...
Oh! Fat lot of good this is!
Back of beyond. Bloody Norway!
I'm going to have to phone your father.
He's on the nursery run.
I was pregnant, do you remember?
Had a baby boy.
Ah, brilliant, what did you call him?
Doctor.
-Really?
-No, you plum. He's called Tony.
Hold on.
This is the parallel universe, right?
You're back home.
And the walls of the world
are closing again,
now that the Reality Bomb
never happened.
It's dimensional retroclosure.
See, I really get that stuff now!
No, but I spent all that time
trying to find you.
-I'm not going back now.
-But you've got to.
'Cause we saved the universe,
but at a cost.
And the cost is him.
He destroyed the Daleks.
He committed genocide.
He's too dangerous
to be left on his own.
You made me.
Exactly. You were born in battle.
Full of blood and anger and revenge.
Remind you of someone?
That's me when we first met.
And you made me better.
Now you can do the same for him.
But he's not you.
He needs you. That's very me.
But it's better than that, though.
Don't you see what
he's trying to give you?
Tell her, go on.
I look like him, I think like him.
Same memories, same thoughts,
same everything.
Except I've only got one heart.
-Which means?
-I'm part human.
Specifically, the ageing part.
I'll grow old and never regenerate.
I've only got one life, Rose Tyler.
I could spend it with you if you want.
You'll grow old at the same time as me?
Together.
(HEART BEATING)
(TARDIS HUMS)
We got to go, this reality
is sealing itself off forever.
But it's still not right,
'cause the Doctor's still you.
And I'm him.
All right. Both of you, answer me this.
When I last stood on this beach
on the worst day of my life,
what was the last thing you said to me?
Go on, say it.
I said, "Rose Tyler."
Yeah, and how was
that sentence gonna end?
Does it need saying?
And you, Doctor?
What was the end of that sentence?
I thought we could try
the planet Felspoon.
Just 'cause what a good name, Felspoon.
Apparently it's got mountains
that sway in the breeze.
Mountains that move, can you imagine?
And how do you know that?
Because it's in your head.
And if it's in your head, it's in mine.
-And how does that feel?
-Brilliant! Fantastic! Motto bene!
Great big universe packed into my brain!
You know you could fix
that chameleon circuit
if you just tried hot binding
the fragment links and superseding
the binary, binary, binary, binary,
binary, binary, binary, binary...
(GASPS) I'm fine!
Nah, never mind Felspoon. You know
who I'd like to meet? Charlie Chaplin.
I bet he's great, Charlie Chaplin.
Shall we do that?
Shall we go and see Charlie Chaplin?
Shall we? Charlie Chaplin?
Charlie Chester? Charlie Brown.
No, he's fiction, friction, fixing,
mixing, Rickston, Brixton.
(GASPS)
Oh, my God.
Do you know what's happening?
Yeah.
There's never been
a human Time Lord met a crisis before now.
-And you know why?
-Because there can't be.
I want to stay.
Look at me. Donna, look at me.
I was gonna be with you. Forever.
I know.
Rest of my life.
Travelling in the Tardis.
The Doctor Donna.
Oh! Oh, but I can't go back.
Don't make me go back.
Doctor, please,
please don't make me go back.
Donna.
Oh, Donna Noble. I am so sorry.
But we had the best of times.
The best.
-Goodbye.
-No, no, no, please.
Please! No, no, no!
No!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
That must be her! Donna!
-Help me.
-Donna?
Donna.
She took my mind into her own head.
But that's a Time Lord consciousness.
All that knowledge, it was killing her.
But she'll get better now?
I had to wipe her mind completely.
Every trace of me or the Tardis,
anything we did together,
anywhere we went, had to go.
-All those wonderful things she did.
-I know.
But that version of Donna is dead.
'Cause if she remembers,
just for a second, she'll burn up.
You can never tell her.
You can't mention me, or any of it,
-for the rest of her life.
-But the whole world's talking about it.
We travelled across space.
It'll just be a story.
One of those Donna Noble stories
where she missed it all again.
-But she was better with you.
-Don't say that.
No, she was!
I just want you to know
that there are worlds out there
safe in the sky because of her.
That there are people
living in the light
and singing songs of Donna Noble
a thousand million light years away.
They will never forget her,
while she can never remember.
And for one moment,
one shining moment,
she was the most important woman
in the whole wide universe.
She still is. She's my daughter.
Then maybe you should tell her that
once in a while.
I was asleep! On my bed,
in my clothes like a flipping kid.
What did you let me do that for?
Don't mind me. Donna.
-John Smith.
-Mr Smith was just leaving.
My phone's gone mad! 32 texts!
Veena's gone barmy.
She's saying "planets in the sky!"
What have I missed now?
Nice to meet you.
As I said, I think you should go.
How thick do you think I am? Planets!
I'll tell you what that was, dumbo,
that's those two-for-one lagers
you get down the offy
"cause you fancy that little man
in there with the goatee!
Yes, you do. I've seen you!
Donna, I was just going.
Yeah, see you.
I'll tell you what, though,
you're wasting your time with that one,
because Susie Mair, she went on
that dating site, and she saw him.
No, no... Listen, this is important!
Susie Mair wouldn't lie!
Not unless it was about calories!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Ah! You'll have quite a bit of this.
Atmospheric disturbance.
Still, it'll pass. Everything does.
Bye then, Wilfred.
Oh, and, Doctor.
What about you now? Who have you got?
I mean, all those friends of yours...
They've all got someone else.
Still, that's fine. I'm fine.
I'll watch out for you, sir.
-You can't ever tell her.
-No, no.
But every night, Doctor,
when it gets dark
and the stars come out,
I'll look up.
On her behalf, I'll look up at the sky
and think of you.
Thank you.