(ALL GROANING)
Oh, my head!
Time travel without a capsule,
that's a killer.
Still, at least we made it.
Earth, 21st century by the looks of it.
-JACK: Talk about lucky.
-That wasn't luck. That was me.
Hold it still!
Don't move, hold it still...
I'm telling you, it's broken,
it hasn't worked for years...
That's because you didn't have me!
Martha, grab hold.
Now!
The moral is, if you're gonna
get stuck at the end of the universe,
get stuck with an ex-Time Agent
and his vortex manipulator.
But this Master bloke,
he's got the Tardis.
-He could be anywhere in time and space.
-No. He's here. Trust me.
Who is he anyway?
And that voice at the end,
that wasn't the Professor.
If the Master's a Time Lord,
then he must've regenerated.
-What does that mean?
-It means he's changed his face.
Voice, body, everything, new man.
(TAPPING)
Then how are we gonna find him?
I'll know him. The moment I see him.
Time Lords always do.
But hold on, if he could be anyone...
We missed the election.
But it can't be...
NEWSCASTER:
Mr Saxon has returned from the Palace,
and is greeting the crowds
inside Saxon Headquarters.
MARTHA: I said I knew that voice.
When he spoke, inside the Tardis,
I've heard that voice hundreds of times.
I've seen him, we all have.
That was the voice of Harold Saxon.
That's him. He's Prime Minister.
The Master is Prime Minister
of Great Britain.
The Master and his wife?
This country has been sick.
This country needs healing.
This country needs medicine.
In fact, I'd go so far as to say,
that what this country
really needs right now
ls a Doctor.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
-Finance report, sir.
-Military protocol, sir.
-EC directive, sir.
-Annual budget, sir.
Policy recommendations.
I'm so proud of you, Harry.
Bless.
Sir, if you don't mind me asking.
I'm sorry, but it's all a bit new,
what exactly do you want me to do?
-Oh, yes, what was it...
-Tish, Letitia Jones.
Tish.
Well then, Tish.
You just stand there and look gorgeous.
A glorious day. Downing Street rebuilt.
The Cabinet in session.
Let the work of government begin.
Oh, go on, crack a smile.
It's funny, isn't it?
Albert? Funny? No? Little bit?
Very funny, sir.
But if we could get down to business,
there is the matter of policy,
-of which we have very little...
-No, no, no, no.
Before we start all that,
I just want to say...
Thank you. Thank you one and all.
You ugly fat-faced
bunch of wet, snivelling traitors.
Yes, quite, very funny, but I...
No, no, that wasn't funny.
You see, I'm not making
myself very clear,
funny is like this...
Not funny is like this...
And right now, I'm not like...
I'm like...
Because you are traitors. Yes, you are!
As soon as you saw the vote
swinging my way,
you abandoned your parties and you
jumped on the Saxon bandwagon. So...
This is your reward.
Excuse me, Prime Minister, do you
mind my asking, what is that?
-(MUFFLED) A gas mask.
-I beg your pardon?
It's a gas mask.
Yes, but why are you wearing it?
-(MUFFLED) Oh, because of the gas.
-I'm sorry?
-Because of the gas.
-What gas?
(MUFFLED) This gas.
You're insane.
Home!
What you got?
Computer, laptop, anything.
Who are you phoning?
You can't tell anyone we're here!
Just some friends of mine
but there's no reply.
Here you go. Any good?
I'll show you the Saxon websites,
he's been around for ages.
That's so weird,
"cause the day after the election,
that's only four days after I met you.
We went flying all round the universe
while he was here all the time.
-You gonna tell us who he is?
-He's a Time Lord.
What about the rest of it?
I mean, who'd call himself "the Master"?
That's all you need to know.
Come on, show me Harold Saxon.
TISH: Martha, where are you?
I've got this new job!
You won't believe it it's weird.
They phoned me up out of the blue...
Oh, like it matters!
-I'm sorry, but you're not allowed in...
-"Harold Saxon, a modern Churchill.”
It's the definitive think-piece
on the great man himself.
Come on, sweetheart,
you must've read it!
Um, not really. Sorry, I'm new.
Mr Saxon does like a pretty face.
But I'm here to see Mrs Saxon.
You can't just go barging in...
Mrs Saxon, Vivien Rook, Sunday Mirror.
You've heard of me.
Can't I just have an hour to myself?
It's been a hell of a day.
Strike while the iron's hot,
that's what I say, Lucy...
I can call you Lucy, can't I?
Now, everyone's talking
about Harold Saxon,
but I thought, what about the wife?
AW I need is 20 minutes.
Oh, I think maybe we should wait...
The headline's waiting to print,
"The Power Behind The Throne".
-Really?
-Britain's First Lady.
-Gosh.
-Front page.
Oh! Well...
I suppose... Oh, go on then, 20 minutes.
Excellent!
Thank you. Go, go...
What was it... Tish?
Now you can leave us alone.
-No, but I'm supposed to sit in.
-No, no. It's only a profile piece.
You know, hair and clothes and nonsense.
There's a good girl, out you go.
That's it.
Mrs Saxon, I have reason to believe
that you're in very great danger.
All of us, in fact.
Not just the country,
but the whole world.
No, I beg of you. Hear me out.
-What are you talking about?
-Your husband is not who he says he is.
I'm sorry, but it's a lie.
Everything's a lie.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm voting Saxon.
He can tick my box any day!
ALL: Vote Saxon! Go Harry!
I think Mr Saxon is exactly what
this country needs.
He's a very fine man.
And he's handsome, too.
Former Minister of Defence,
first came to prominence
when he shot down
the Racnoss on Christmas Eve.
-Nice work by the way.
-Oh, thanks.
But he goes back years, he's famous,
everyone knows the story. Look.
Cambridge University, rugby Blue,
won the athletics thing, wrote a novel,
went into business,
marriage, everything.
He's got a whole life.
All of it, the school days, his degree,
even his mother and father,
it's all invented.
Look, Harold Saxon
never went to Cambridge,
there was no Harold Saxon!
The thing is, it's obvious.
The forgery is screaming out
and yet no one can see it!
It's as if he's mesmerised
the entire world.
I think perhaps you should leave now.
Eighteen months ago he became real.
This is his first
honest-to-God appearance,
just after the downfall
of Harriet Jones.
And at the exact same time,
they launched the Archangel Network.
Mrs Rook, now stop it!
Even now, they've said that
the Cabinet's gone into seclusion.
What does that mean, seclusion?
-How should I know?
-But I've got plenty of research on you.
Yes, good family, Roedean,
not especially bright,
but essentially harmless,
and that's why I'm asking you.
Lucy, I am begging you,
if you have seen anything,
heard anything,
even the slightest thing that
would give you cause to doubt him...
-I think...
-Yes?
There was a time, when we first met,
I wondered...
But he was so good
to my father, and he said...
-What? Just tell me, sweetheart.
-The thing is...
-I made my choice.
-I'm sorry?
For better or for worse.
Isn't that right, Harry?
-My faithful companion.
-Mr Saxon.
Prime Minister.
I was just having a little joke with...
-Poor little Lucy, I didn't mean...
-Oh, but you're absolutely right.
Harold Saxon doesn't exist.
Then tell me...
-who are you?
-I am the Master.
And these are my friends.
I'm sorry.
Can't you hear it, Mrs Rook?
-What do you mean?
-The drumbeat.
The drums are coming closer and closer.
SPHERE 1: 7he lady doesn't like us.
-No...
-SPHERE 2: Silly lady.
-SPHERE 2: Dead lady.
(SCREAMING)
But she knew!
Harry, she knew everything.
You promised.
You said Archangel
was one hundred per cent.
Um. Ninety nine. Ninety eight?
But if she's asking questions,
then who else?
How much time have we got?
Tomorrow morning, I promise.
That's when everything ends.
But he's got the Tardis.
Maybe the Master went back in time,
and has been living here for decades.
-No.
-Why not? Worked for me.
When he was stealing the Tardis
the only thing I could do
was fuse the coordinates.
I locked them permanently.
He can only travel between
the year one hundred trillion
and the last place the Tardis landed.
Which is right here, right now.
Yeah, but a little leeway?
Well, 18 months, tops. The most
he could have been here is 18 months.
So how's he managed all this?
The Master was always sort of hypnotic,
but this is on a massive scale.
-I was gonna vote for him.
-Really?
Well, it was before I even met you.
And I liked him.
-Me, too.
-Why do you say that?
What was his policy,
what did he stand for?
I don't know, he always sounded good.
Like you could trust him.
Just nice. He spoke about...
I can't really remember,
but it was good.
-Just the sound of his voice.
-What's that?
-What?
-That! That tapping, that rhythm.
-What are you doing?
-I don't know, it's nothing...
I don't know!
Our Lord and Master
is speaking to his kingdom.
Britain, Britain, Britain.
What extraordinary times we've had.
Just a few years ago,
this world was so small.
And then they came.
Out of the unknown.
Falling from the skies.
You've seen it happen.
Big Ben destroyed.
A spaceship over London.
All those ghosts and metal men,
the Christmas Star that came to kill.
Time and time again and
the government told you nothing.
Well not me. Not Harold Saxon.
Because my purpose here today
is to tell you this.
Citizens of Great Britain...
I have been contacted.
A message for humanity
from beyond the stars.
SPHERE: People of the Earth.
We come in peace.
We bring you great gifts.
We bring technology and
wisdom and protection.
And all we ask in return
Is your friendship.
Oh, sweet.
And this species has identified itself.
-They're called the Toclafane.
-What?
And tomorrow morning they will appear,
not in secret, but to all of you.
Diplomatic relations
with a new species will begin.
Tomorrow, we take our place
in the universe.
Every man, woman and child,
every teacher and chemist
and lorry driver
and farmer and,
oh, I don't know, every...
medical student?
DOCTOR: Out!
(BEEPING)
-All right? Martha?
-Fine, yeah, I'm fine.
-What are you doing?
-He knows about me,
-what about my family?
-Don't tell them anything.
I'll do what I like!
-Mum! Oh, my God, you're there.
-Course I'm here, sweetheart.
-You all right?
-I'm fine, no, I'm fine.
Mum, has there been anyone
asking about me?
Martha, I think perhaps
you should come round.
-I can't, not now.
-No, but it's your father.
We've been talking, and we thought
we might give it another go.
-Don't be so daft! Since when?
-Just come round.
Come to the house. We can celebrate.
You'd never get back with him
in a million years.
Ask him yourself.
-Martha, it's me.
-Dad? What are you doing there?
Like your mother said.
Come round, we can explain everything.
Dad, just say yes or no.
Is there someone else there?
-Yes. Just run! Listen to me, just run!
-Clive, stop it!
-I don't know who they are!
-You stupid man!
-We're trying to help her!
-Dad, what's going?
-We've got to get Martha away from him!
-I've gotta help them.
That's exactly what they want,
it's a trap!
I don't care!
Get off!
It is your fault! All of you!
You voted Saxon! You did this!
Corner!
Mr Saxon, we have Condition Red on
the Jones Plan, we're taking them in.
-All of them.
-But I was helping you!
(PHONE RINGING)
Come on, Tish, pick up.
(RINGING)
Martha, can't talk now! We've just made
First Contact, did you see?
What are you doing! Get off!
-Linda, tell them!
-What's happening? Tish?
It's your fault! It's all your fault!
I was helping you! Get off me!
Martha! Get out of here, get out!
Target identified!
Martha, reverse!
-Take aim!
-Get out now!
Fire!
Move it!
Take them away!
The only place he can go
was planet Earth!
Careful!
Martha, listen to me, do as I say.
We gotta ditch this car.
Pull over. Right now!
-Martha, come on.
-Leo!
Oh, thank God, Leo, you've gotta listen
to me. Where are you?
I'm in Brighton.
Yeah, we came down with Boxer.
Did you see that Saxon thing on telly?
Leo, just listen to me, don't go home.
I'm telling you, don't phone Mum or Dad
or Tish, you've gotta hide.
-Shut up.
-On my life, you've gotta trust me.
Go to Boxer's, stay with him,
don't tell anyone, just hide.
Ooh, nice little game
of hide and seek, I love that!
But I'll find you, Martha Jones.
Been a long time since
we saw each other.
Must be, what, a hundred trillion years?
Let them go, Saxon!
Do you hear me? Let them go!
I'm here.
-Doctor.
-Master.
(SIGHS)
I like it when you use my name.
You chose it. Psychiatrist's field day.
As you chose yours.
The man who makes people better.
How sanctimonious is that?
So, Prime Minister, then?
I know! It's good, isn't it?
Who are those creatures?
There's no such thing as the Toclafane.
That's just a made-up name,
like the bogeyman.
Do you remember all those fairy tales
about the Toclafane when we were kids?
Back home?
Where is it, Doctor?
-Gone.
-How can Gallifrey be gone?
It burnt.
And the Time Lords?
Dead.
And the Daleks. More or less.
What happened to you?
The Time Lords only resurrected me
because they knew I'd be
the perfect warrior for a Time War.
I was there when the Dalek Emperor
took control of the Cruciform.
I saw it.
I ran.
I ran so far.
Made myself human
so they would never find me,
because...
I was so scared.
I know.
All of them? But not you.
Which must mean...
I was the only one who could end it.
And I tried, I did, I tried everything.
What did it feel like, though?
Two almighty civilisations burning.
Oh, tell me, how did that feel?
-Stop it.
-You must have been like God.
I've been alone ever since.
But not any more. Don't you see,
all we've got is each other?
Are you asking me out on a date?
You could stop this right now,
we could leave this planet.
We can fight across the constellations
if that's what you want.
But not on Earth.
Too late.
-Why do you say that?
-The drumming.
Can't you hear it?
I thought it would stop,
but it never does.
It never, ever stops. Inside my head.
The drumming, Doctor,
the constant drumming.
I can help you. Please let me help.
It's everywhere. Listen, listen, listen.
(TAPPING)
Here come the drums.
What have you done?
Tell me how you've done this.
What are those creatures? Tell me!
Ooh, look, you're on TV!
-Stop it. Answer me.
-No, really, you're on telly!
You and your little band.
Which, by the way, is ticking
every demographic box.
So congratulations on that.
Look, there you are!
NEWSCASTER: They are known to be armed
and extremely dangerous.
You're public enemies
number one, two and three!
Oh, and you can tell handsome Jack
that I've sent his little gang off on
a wild goose chase to the Himalayas
so he won't be getting
any help from them.
Now go on, off you go.
Why not start by turning to the...right?
He can see us.
Ooh, you public menace.
Better start running! Go on, run!
He's got control of everything.
-What do we do?
-We've got nowhere to go.
-Doctor, what do we do?
-Run, Doctor!
-Run for your life!
-We run.
I said, run!
Tomorrow morning, Britain will be
welcoming an extraterrestrial species...
The President is said to be furious that
Great Britain's
taken unilateral action...
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Have you seen these things?
This planet's amazing.
Television in their stomach.
Now that is evolution!
-Is the machine ready?
-Tomorrow morning.
It reaches critical at 8:02 precisely.
We have to escape
because it's coming, sir, the darkness.
The never-ending darkness,
and the terrible, terrible cold.
We have to run and run and run.
8:00, tomorrow morning.
Tell your people the world is waiting.
JACK: How was it?
I don't think anyone saw me.
Anything new?
I got this tuned into
the government wavelength
-so we can follow what Saxon's doing.
-I meant about my family.
Still says the Jones family
taken in for questioning.
Tell you what, though,
no mention of Leo.
He's not as daft as he looks.
I'm talking about my brother,
on the run, how did this happen?
-Nice chips.
-Actually, they're not bad.
So, Doctor, who is he?
How come the ancient society of
Time Lords created a psychopath?
And what is he to you?
-Like a colleague, or...
-A friend at first.
Thought you were gonna say he was
your secret brother or something.
You've been watching too much TV.
But all the legends of Gallifrey
made it sound so perfect.
Well, perfect to look at, maybe.
And it was, it was beautiful.
They used to call it
the Shining World of the Seven Systems.
And on the continent of Wild Endeavour,
in the mountains of Solace and Solitude,
there stood the Citadel
of the Time Lords.
The oldest and most mighty
race in the universe,
looking down on the galaxies below,
sworn never to interfere.
Only to watch.
Children of Gallifrey,
taken from their families
at the age of eight
to enter the Academy.
And some say that's where it all began.
When he was a child.
That's when the Master saw eternity.
As a novice,
he was taken for initiation.
He stood in front of
the Untempered Schism,
it's a gap in the fabric of reality
through which could be seen
the whole of the Vortex.
You stand there,
eight years old,
staring at the raw power of
time and space. Just a child.
Some would be inspired.
Some would run away.
And some would go mad.
-I don't know.
-MARTHA: What about you?
Oh, the ones that ran away.
I never stopped.
(BEEPING)
Encrypted channel with files attached.
-Don't recognise it.
-Hmm, patch it through to the laptop.
Since we're telling stories,
there's something I haven't told you.
You work for Torchwood?
I swear to you, it's different,
it's changed.
There's only half a dozen of us now.
Everything Torchwood did
and you're part of it?
The old regime was destroyed
at Canary Wharf.
I rebuilt it, I changed it,
and when I did that, I did it for you.
In your honour.
If I haven't returned to my desk by 2200
this file will be emailed to Torchwood.
Which means if you're watching this,
then I'm...
Anyway, the Saxon files are attached,
but take a look
at the Archangel document.
That's when it all started,
when Harry Saxon became Minister
in charge of launching
the Archangel Network.
-DOCTOR: What's the Archangel Network?
-I've got Archangel, everyone's got it.
It's the mobile phone network.
'Cause look, it's gone worldwide.
They've got 15 satellites in orbit.
Even the other networks,
they're all carried by Archangel.
It's in the phones!
Oh, I said he was a hypnotist.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
(BEEPING)
There it is! That rhythm.
It's everywhere.
Ticking away in the subconscious.
-What is it, mind control?
-No, no, no, no. Subtler than that.
Any strong-willed people
would question it.
But contained in that rhythm,
in layers of code,
"Vote Saxon. Believe in me."
Whispering to the world.
Oh! Yes!
That's how he hid himself from me!
'Cause I should've sensed
there was another Time Lord on Earth.
I should've known way back,
but the signal cancelled him out.
Any way you can stop it?
Not from down here.
But now we know how he's doing it.
-And we can fight back?
-Oh, yes!
Three Tardis keys,
three pieces of the Tardis,
all with low-level perception properties
because the Tardis
is designed to blend in.
Well, sort of, but now,
the Archangel Network's got
a second low-level signal.
Weld the key to the network,
and Martha...
Look at me, you can see me, yes?
-Yep!
-What about now?
No, I'm here, look at me.
It's like I know you're there,
but I don't want to know.
And back again!
See? It just shifts your perception,
a tiny little bit.
Doesn't make us invisible.
Just unnoticed.
Oh! I know what it's like! It's like...
It's like when you fancy someone,
and they don't even know you exist.
That's what it's like. Come on!
You too, huh?
DOCTOR: Don't run.
Don't shout, just keep your voice down.
Draw attention to yourself
and the spell is broken.
Just keep to the shadows.
-Like ghosts.
-Yeah.
That's what we are. Ghosts.
And as the eyes of the world
turn towards Great Britain
sources indicate that Air Force One
has landed on British soil tonight.
Mr President, sir!
Mr Saxon, the British Army
will stand down.
From now on, UNIT has control
of this operation.
You make it sound like an invasion.
The First Contact Policy was decided by
the Security Council in 1968
and you've just gone and ignored it.
Well, you know what it's like,
new job, all that paperwork.
I think it's down
the back of the settee.
I did have a quick look,
I found a pen, a sweet,
a bus ticket, and...
Have you met the wife?
Mr Saxon,
I'm not sure what your game is,
but there are provisions at the UN
to have you removed from office
unless you are very, very careful.
Is that understood?
Are you taking this seriously?
To business.
We've accessed your files
on these Toclafane.
But First Contact cannot take
place on any sovereign soil.
To that purpose, the aircraft carrier
Valiant is en route.
The rendezvous
will take place there at 8:00 am.
(MUMBLING)
You're trying my patience, sir.
-So America is completely in charge?
-Since Britain elected an ass, yes.
I'll see you on board the Valiant.
It still will be televised, though,
won't it?
Because I promised,
and the whole world is watching.
Since it's too late to pull out,
the world will be watching.
Me.
The last President of America.
We have a private plane
ready and waiting.
We should reach the Valiant
within the hour.
My darling...
(SIREN WAILING)
(LAUGHING)
Hi, guys!
What are you doing!
-All! All will be revealed.
-Saxon!
Oh, my God!
-Don't move.
-But...
Don't!
I'm gonna kill him.
What say I use this perception filter
to walk up behind him
and break his neck?
Now that sounds like Torchwood.
Still a good plan.
He's a Time Lord.
Which makes him my responsibility.
I'm not here to kill him.
I'm here to save him.
Aircraft carrier Valiant
that's a UNIT ship,
at 58.2 North, 10.02 East.
How do we get on board?
-Does that thing work as a teleport?
-Since you revamped it, yeah.
Coordinates set.
-MARTHA: Oh, that thing is rough!
-I've had worse nights.
(SCREAMS)
-Welcome to the Valiant.
-It's dawn.
Hold on, I thought this was a ship,
where's the sea?
A ship for the 21st century.
Protecting the skies of planet Earth.
OVER PA: Europe now online.
Awaiting confirmation from South America
and keep tracking Japan.
I want the whole thing branded with
my Seal of Office, not the UN,
have you got that?
Anything I can do?
I could make the tea?
Or isn't that American enough?
I don't know, I could make grits.
What are grits anyway?
If you could just sit.
Misery guts.
What do you think? It's good, isn't it?
It's beautiful.
Some of my best work.
Ministry of Defence,
I helped design this place.
Every detail.
-We've no time for sight-seeing!
-No, wait, shh, shh.
-Can't you hear it?
-Hear what?
-Doctor, my family's on board...
-Brilliant!
This way!
-Oh, at last!
-Oh, yes!
What's it doing on the Valiant?
-What the hell's he done?
-DOCTOR: Don't touch it!
I'm not going to!
MARTHA: What's he done, though?
Sounds like it's sick.
DOCTOR: It can't be.
No, no, no, no, no, no, it can't be.
-Doctor, what is it?
-He's cannibalised the Tardis.
Is this what I think it is?
It's a paradox machine.
Two minutes, everyone.
According to the treaty,
all armed personnel
are requested to leave the flight deck
immediately, thank you.
Jelly baby?
PRESIDENT: Broadcasting at 7:58,
with the arrival timed for
0800 hours exactly.
And good luck to all of us.
As soon as this hits red, it activates.
At this speed, it'll trigger at 8:02.
First Contact is at 8:00,
then two minutes later...
But what's it for?
What does a paradox machine do?
-More important, can you stop it?
-Not till I know what it's doing.
Touch the wrong bit,
blow up the solar system.
Then we've gotta get to the Master!
-Yeah, how we gonna stop him?
-Oh, I've got a way.
Sorry, didn't I mention it?
And in just 30 seconds' time,
we'll be going live to First Contact.
It's been announced that Harold Saxon
has invited President Winters
to take the address.
It's 3:00 am in the morning
on the Eastern Seaboard
and President Winters has been chosen
to lead the world into a new age.
My fellow Americans, patriots,
people of the world.
I stand before you today
as ambassador for humanity.
A role I will undertake
with the utmost solemnity.
Perhaps our Toclafane cousins
can offer us much.
But what is important is not
that we gain material benefits,
but that we learn to see ourselves anew.
For as long as man
has looked to the stars
he has wondered what
mysteries they hold.
Now we know we are not alone.
This plan, you gonna tell us?
If I can get this around
the Master's neck,
cancel out his perception,
they'll see him for real.
It's just hard to go unnoticed
when everyone is on red alert.
If they stop me, you've got a key.
-Yes, sir.
-I'll get him.
And I ask you now,
I ask of the human race,
to join with me
in welcoming our friends.
I give you the Toclafane.
My name is Arthur Coleman Winters,
President Elect of
the United States of America,
and Designated Representative
of the United Nations.
I welcome you to the planet Earth
and its associated moon.
SPHERE 2: You're not the Master.
SPHERE 1: We like the Mr Master.
-SPHERE 3: We don't like you.
-I can be master if you so wish.
I will accept mastery over you
if that is God's will.
SPHERE 2: Man is stupid.
SPHERE 3: Master is our friend.
SPHERE 1:
Where's my Master, pretty please?
Oh, all right, then. It's me!
Ta-da! Sorry!
Sorry, I have this effect,
people just get obsessed.
Is it the smile, is it the aftershave,
is it the capacity to laugh at myself?
I don't know! It's crazy!
Saxon, what are you talking about?
I'm taking control, Uncle Sam.
Starting with you.
Kill him!
Guards, nobody move! Nobody move!
Now then!
Peoples of the Earth,
please attend carefully.
MASTER: Stop him!
We meet at last, Doctor.
Oh! I love saying that!
Stop this! Stop it now!
As if a perception filter is gonna
work on me.
And look, it's the girlie and the freak.
Although I'm not sure which one's which.
Laser screwdriver. Who'd have sonic?
And the good thing is, he's not dead
for long. I get to kill him again!
Master, just calm down.
Just look at what you're doing,
just stop.
If you could see yourself.
Do excuse me, little bit of personal
business. Back in a minute.
Let him go.
It's that sound, the sound in your head.
What if I can help?
Oh! How to shut him up?
I know! Memory lane!
Professor Lazarus, remember him?
And his genetic manipulation device!
What, did you think little Tish
got that job merely by coincidence?
I've been laying traps for you
all this time!
And if I can concentrate all that
Lazarus technology into
one little screwdriver...
But, ooh, if only I had
the Doctor's biological code.
Oh! Wait a minute! I do!
I've got his hand!
And if Lazarus made himself younger,
what if I reverse it?
Another 100 years?
-Teleport.
-I can't.
We can't stop him.
Get out of here.
Get out.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
Doctor, I've got you.
MASTER: Ah, she's a would-be doctor.
But tonight, Martha Jones,
we've flown them in,
all the way from prison.
-Mum.
-I'm sorry.
The Toclafane. What are they?
Who are they?
Doctor, if I told you the truth,
your hearts would break.
SPHERE 2: Is it time?
SPHERE 3: Is it ready?
SPHERE 1: Is the machine singing?
Two minutes past!
So, Earthlings!
Basically, um...
End of the world.
Here come the drums!
(VOODOO CHILD PLAYING)
-How many do you think?
-I don't know!
MASTER: Six billion!
Down you go, kids!
Shall we decimate them?
That sounds good, nice word, decimate.
Remove one tenth of the population!
WOMAN: This is Geneva!
We're getting slaughtered down here!
Valiant, report! Help us!
For God"s sake help us!
MAN: This is London, Valiant.
This is London. What do we do?
They're killing us! The Toclafane...
They're killing us!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
I'm coming back.
And so it came to pass
that the human race fell
and the Earth was no more.
And I looked down upon my new dominion
as master of all.
And I thought it good.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
MASTER: Ever since I was a child,
I looked into the Vortex,
that's when it chose me.
The drumming, the call to war.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
MASTER: Can't you hear it?