(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Gentlemen, good news.
My agents have procured the exact
security software that you requested,
the very latest upgrade.
I extracted it from the memory
of a Judoon trooper.
Well, I say extracted.
It was quicker to take the whole brain.
And to be honest,
I don't think he's going to miss it.
Uh, uh, uh.
A small matter of payment, I think.
Delightful. (LAUGHS)
Oh, I do enjoy sentient money.
The way it wriggles.
You'll find it in the frontal lobe.
Should be quite easy,
there's not a lot in there.
But all this to imprison one child?
Oh, I know what you're up to.
I hear everything in this place.
I even hear rumours about
whose child you've taken.
Are you mad?
You know the stories about the Doctor?
The things that man has done?
God help us if you've made him angry!