Danny Pink.
Is dead.
We're here to get your boyfriend back
from the dead.
These are tombs. Water tombs.
Why would anyone go to so much trouble?
You're dead.
And this is what's next.
A Galyfreyan hard drive.
Time Lord technology.
Do you know the key strategic weakness
of the human race?
The dead outnumber the living
Who are you?
Oh, you know who I am. I'm Missy.
I couldn't very well keep calling myself
the Master, now could I?
Stop! You can't kill me!
Incorrect.
I'm a target of strategic value.
Alive, I'm a tactical advantage.
Dead, I'm your biggest mistake.
You don't know who I am!
You are Clara Oswald. You are human.
You are unimportant.
Incorrect.
You see, that is what
you're supposed to think.
That is what everybody thinks.
You are Clara Oswald.
Clara Oswald is a cover story,
a disguise.
There is no Clara Oswald.
-Identify.
-Oh, don't be so slow,
it's embarrassing.
Who could fool you like this?
Who could hide right under your nose?
Who can change their face
any time they want?
(CHUCKLES)
You see, I'm not Clara Oswald.
Clara Oswald has never existed.
Identify.
I'm the Doctor.
Look at them...
My boys!
Cybermen, in broad daylight?
You think people won't notice?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING AND LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Photos with the big
metal men, one pound!
Oh, honey!
There you go!
New York, Paris, Rome,
Marrakech, Brisbane, Glasgow.
Everywhere. Anywhere. Me and my boys.
We're going viral.
Would you like me to take a picture?
Sorry, selfies are never
as good, are they,
and you're having
a lovely moment, hang on!
(INDISTINCT)
-Nice bow tie.
-Bow ties are cool.
Big smiles, and... Now!
Move, move, move!
Surround target! Hold fast!
Afternoon!
You've picked a lovely day for it.
My, don't you look shiny.
Haircut?
-Bit of a trim.
-Might want to do your roots.
-The woman!
-SOLDIER: Yes, ma'am.
Kate Stewart. Divorcee, mother of two,
keen gardener,
outstanding bridge player.
Also chief scientific officer,
Unified Intelligence Task Force,
who currently have you surrounded.
Human weaponry is not effective
against Cyber technology.
Sorry, you left this behind
on one of your previous attempts.
So, now that I have your attention,
welcome to the only planet
in the universe
where we get to say this.
-He's on the payroll.
-Am I?
Well, technically.
-How much?
-Shh!
Any questions?
Back, back, everyone, back!
Oh, my God!
-Is it supposed to do that?
-Is that new?
DOCTOR: The sun roof on St Paul's?
Yeah, I'd say that was new!
There's going to be mass panic,
everyone in London can see that.
Everyone in London
just clapped and went whee!
Hush, I'm trying to count.
Eighty-seven, I think.
OCD.
Ninety-one. Queen of Evil.
How could St Paul's be full of
91 Cybermen and nobody noticed?
Dimensional engineering
one space folded inside another,
bigger on the inside.
Easy if you're a Time Lord.
Mostly deploying south,
a smaller number east.
-Yep, but one straight up.
-So, 91 isn't a coincidence?
Of course, it isn't.
KATE: Osgood, 91, explain.
Ninety-one areas of significant
population density in the British Isles.
That's one Cyberman
for every city and major town.
It's happening everywhere,
all over the world, right now!
Sweet planet, this.
I think I might keep it.
One Cyberman per city,
what can they hope to accomplish?
Doctor!
(EXPLOSION)
-Has it exploded?
-MISSY: More than that.
Cybermen don't just blow themselves up
for no good reason, dear.
They're not human.
If it isn't exploding, what's it doing?
Pollinating.
Falling like rain
into the cracks of the earth.
SEB: Well, this is a bit exciting!
What's happening?
Well, to cut a long story short,
looks like we might all be going home.
Home?
From the afterlife?
Well, when I said afterlife,
I was being a tiny bit poetic.
And Nethersphere is just a cool name
we came up with during a spit-ball.
What is this place?
Well, you've to think of it
as a data cloud.
You know, for storing data.
In this case, storage of recently
deceased minds.
-We're in a cloud?
-A sort of cloud, yeah.
And what's happening to it?
What happens to any cloud
when it starts to rain.
Are you telling me we're going back?
What, back to our bodies?
And the extra good news is,
there's been a bit of an upgrade!
MISSY: The dead are coming home, Doctor.
All shiny and new.
In 24 hours, the human race,
as you know it, will cease to exist.
What are you doing? Explain!
-Tell me, now!
-Ooh! That was nice.
Let's do it again.
No, no, no, no, I need to talk to her,
I need her awake.
Ahh! No!
No, stupid!
Stupid, no, no!
First protocol is implemented,
we're good to go.
You just have to let it take you...
What did he say?
He said, guard the graveyards.
That's weird. Look at that!
How come it's only raining
inside the graveyard?
TV REPORTER: We are being told that
these metal men
are known as 'Cybermen,'
but unlike the accounts
we have on file,
they now have the ability to fly.
Similar reports are coming in
from all over the world.
Flying Cybermen are here
on a global scale.
Ministers are telling us
to remain calm.
These Cybermen don't seem
to be attacking us,
at least not in any
conventional fashion.
Eye witnesses have reported seeing...
(WATER SLOSHING)
(BANGING)
Hello?
(GROWLING)
(HYDRAULICS WHIRRING)
Whoa!
MAN: Put it in position.
Right.
Careful with it.
Kate? What's with the hand cuffs?
I'm sorry. In the event of
an alien incursion on this scale,
protocols are in place.
Your co-operation is to be ensured
and your unreliability assumed.
-You have a history.
-You don't have a future without me.
Do you think your father
would have done this?
We both know he absolutely would.
Who is she?
Long story. Where's Clara?
-Clara Oswald, your assistant?
-My friend.
-She was with me in St Paul's.
-The team's still on site.
But they've been unable to gain
access to the building.
I want her found and brought here.
I need her with me.
Then give the order.
As soon as you're on board Boat One,
your word is law. Quite literally.
You got the Tardis out though?
Yes. And St Paul's locked down.
Where are we going? Cloudbase?
-You mean the Valiant.
-Cloudbase was Thunderbirds'.
Too conspicuous. We need your location
concealed, not advertised.
From now on you're a moving target.
Ah, so you're bringing Daddy along too,
that's very sweet.
Sir!
Don't do that, you look like
you're self-concussing,
which would explain all
of military history,
now I think about it.
Colonel Ahmed, sir.
Privilege to meet you.
Love your outfit, Colonel Ahmed,
are you in the Scouts?
Are you a Man Scout?
I didn't know they had those.
-It was Captain Scarlet.
-Sorry?
-Not Thunderbirds.
-Oh, God, so it was.
My confidence is growing every minute.
The President is on board.
Mind you, me and Sylvia Anderson,
you've never seen a foxtrot like it.
Hang on a second. The President?
We don't want Americans
bobbing around the place.
They'll only start praying.
Not the President of America, sir.
The President of Earth.
-There isn't one.
-There is now.
The incursion protocols have been
agreed internationally.
In the event of full-scale invasion,
an Earth president
is inducted immediately, with complete
authority over every nation state.
Well, there was only one
practical candidate.
Oh, that's your answer for everything,
isn't it? Vote for an idiot.
If you say so, Mr President.
So long as you're on this plane,
you are the Commander in Chief
of every army on Earth.
Every world leader
is currently awaiting your instructions.
You are the Chief Executive Officer
of the human race.
Any questions?
CAPTAIN: This is your Captain speaking,
please prepare for take-off.
Well, gentlemen. Where to start?
I was born on the planet Gallifrey,
in the constellation of Kasterborous.
I am a Time Lord,
but my Prydonian privileges were revoked
when I stole a time
capsule and ran away.
Currently piloting a Type 40 Tardis.
I have been married four times,
all deceased.
My children and grandchildren
are missing, and I assume, dead.
I have a non-Gallifreyan daughter,
created via genetic transfer.
How much more do you need?
I'm the Doctor!
This information is not proof.
We require proof.
-How about my name?
-Explain.
Well, my name isn't Doctor, is it?
I don't even really have a doctorate.
Well, Glasgow University,
but then I accidentally graduated
in the wrong century, so technically...
This information cannot be confirmed.
-You are Clara Oswald.
-Ah! No, I'm not.
Your deception is intended
to prolong your life.
Your presence has not been ordered.
Correct.
-You are Clara Oswald.
-Oh, seriously, this is getting old.
Look, there is no Clara Oswald.
I invented her. I made her up.
Born 23rd November, 71986.
Yeah, I chose that date.
I always liked it.
Father, David James Oswald.
Mother, Elena Alison Oswald.
Stories. Stories. Stories.
I made them up.
Look, ask anybody who knows me.
I'm an incredible liar.
Correct.
-No order was given.
-Correct.
You are not under Cyber control.
Correct.
(GASPS)
Why are you still alive?
-You saved me.
-I saved Gallifrey.
Yes, Gallifrey, too, I suppose.
There's always collateral damage,
with you and me. It's our Paris.
Gallifrey is lost in another dimension.
Yes and no.
-Meaning?
-Yes, it's in another dimension.
No, it's not lost.
You know where it is?
Yep. You know the best part
about knowing?
Not telling you.
(BEEPING)
MAN ON PA: Mr President. sir,
we're ready for you up here.
Remember all those years, when all you
wanted to do was to rule the world?
-On my way.
-Thank you, Mr President.
Piece of cake.
Oh, erm. It's her little device thingy.
I thought there might be
useful information on it.
Who is she?
You'd never believe me if I told you.
Because I thought she might be
the Master regenerated into female form.
Your childhood friend, responsible
for a number of previous incursions.
That was fairly quick.
We do have files on
all our ex-prime ministers.
Oh, she wasn't even the worst.
Doctor, there's something
nobody's talking about.
Which is?
The clouds, caused by
the exploding Cybermen...
They haven't dispersed,
they're still there.
In fact they have expanded and
are covering almost all the land masses.
We're all looking at the graveyards.
Maybe we should be looking up.
What do you think?
-All of time and space.
-I'm sorry.
Just something for your bucket list.
MAN ON TV: Localised rain in
the cemeteries has resulted in
what can only be described as
disturbances to the soil.
Extraordinary eye witnesses accounts
are claiming that silver creatures
are climbing from the graves.
These scenes are being
repeated everywhere.
Every cemetery. Every mortuary,
every funeral home. Every hospital.
The dead are returning to life
as Cybermen.
The public are being advised to
stay away from all cemeteries,
(GASPING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Hello?
We've done heat scans
of some of the cemeteries
and in each case, only a handful
of Cybermen have so far emerged
but every individual burial site
is active.
Active? Hatching.
More are coming. Potentially millions.
So the rain caused all that
in just a few hours?
It wasn't rain, Man Scout!
It was pollen. Cyber-pollen.
Every tiny particle of a Cyberman
contains the plans
to make another Cyberman.
All it has to do is make a contact
with compatible,
living organic matter,
and bang, full conversion.
But if they've learned
how to convert the dead...
That's what she was doing!
That's what 3W was for!
She creates an all new paranoia
among the super-rich about dying,
she exploits the wealth
and the mortal remains
of selected idiots, so she can create
a whole new race of Cybermen.
Cybermen who can recruit corpses.
Throw away your guns, Man Scout,
it's all over.
How can you win a war against an enemy
that can weaponise the dead?
AHMED: They're not attacking apart from
isolated incidents,
they're just wandering about.
DOCTOR: They're new-borns.
Give them time.
Why were you there this morning,
why were you already attacking?
Been investigating 3W for a while.
Then we got a tip off.
From a woman with a Scottish accent.
Can't play to the gallery,
unless there's a gallery. And here I am.
Dead bodies don't have minds,
of course.
But she's been upgrading dying minds
to a hard drive for a long time.
So, she upgrades the hardware,
then she updates the software.
What do you mean,
a long time? How long?
She must have a Tardis somewhere.
So, as long as she likes,
-the past and future...
-How long, Doctor?
How long has the human race
had a concept of an afterlife?
Turns out the afterlife is real.
And it's emptying.
Every graveyard on planet Earth
is about to burst its banks.
(MISSY SINGING)
Hey, Missy, you're so fine,
you're so fine,
you blow my mind.
Hey, Missy!
Hey... (LAUGHS)
Excuse me.
Hi.
Can I tell you something
really important?
What?
I have to whisper it.
It's, like, so important
to everyone on this plane,
that you'll get in trouble
if you don't listen.
If it was that important,
why would you tell us?
Well, look at me, I'm bananas.
Come on, just a wee bit closer.
Just a little closer, you know,
the Doctor will be really impressed
if you learn my secrets.
Well, you can come a bit closer
than that. Stop mucking about.
Don't be shy.
You don't smell half as bad
as you think you do.
There are two armed men
directly behind you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
If you've got something to say,
just say it.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(WHISPERS) I'm going to kill you
in a minute.
I'm not even kidding,
you're gonna be as dead
as a fish on a slab any second now,
all floppy and making smells.
But don't tell the boys,
this is our secret girl plan.
Why would you bother killing me?
I'm not even important.
Oh, silly! Why does one pop a balloon?
Because you're pretty.
You should have a bit
more confidence in yourself.
Okay.
Sorry, I've got work to do.
All right fine, you get on.
You get that finished.
Would a countdown help you
focus at all?
-No, that's okay.
-Ten.
Don't be scared yet, 'cause I'm still
- in double figures.
-I'm not scared.
Nine. Of course you're not,
because you know you're dying anyway.
Eight. Human beings are born dying.
Your life spans are hilarious.
Please be quiet.
Seven. You know,
from the minute you slop out
you're rotting, decaying.
The stench of you. Oof!
I'm never going to get
this place clean.
-Three!
-Three?
I'm accelerating for dramatic effect.
(GASPS) Oh!
What's that in your pocket?
There's nothing in my...
Oh, my giddy aunt.
The quiet ones are the worst.
Well, those aren't mine!
Then they must be mine!
(GRUNTS)
Say something nice.
Missy! The Master!
Whatever you call yourself. I promise,
I'm much more useful to you alive.
Oh, yeah, that's true.
That's definitely true,
that is a good point, well made...
I'm proud of you, sister.
But did I mention?
Bananas!
Pop!
Ah!
Thanks for being yummy.
Mr President, you need
to get back in your seat.
I don't like being President,
people keep saluting.
I'm never going to salute back.
You know, that was always
my Dad's big ambition,
to get you to salute him, just once.
He should've asked.
-Doctor, what are you looking at?
-The clouds.
Still there, so what else
have they got?
Oh, dear Lord!
There's a Cyberman
out there on the fuselage.
On the plus side, it's not turbulence.
She's out!
Who let her out?
What's it doing? Where did it go?
What can one Cyberman do to a plane?
Oh, she was really scared,
it was classic!
Have you got any more friends
I can play with?
(CYBERMAN MUMBLING)
Are you the one that brought me here?
Affirmative.
-So you know who I am, right?
-You are not the Doctor.
Of course, I'm not the Doctor,
I was lying to stay alive.
But how do I know so much about him?
-You are his associate.
-I'm not.
I'm not his associate,
I'm his best friend.
Right now, his best friend,
anywhere in the universe.
Have you got any sort of
Cyber-Internet in there,
because really, you should look it up.
Look up what happens to you
if you harm me.
-Where is the Doctor?
-(CHUCKLES)
What, you think I'd give up the Doctor?
Don't be daft.
I would never, ever,
give up the Doctor.
Because he is my best friend, too.
He is closest person to me
in this whole world.
He's the man I will always forgive,
always trust, the one man
I would never, ever lie to...
Danny?
Danny Pink is dead.
Help me.
Oh, my God!
Danny!
-Help me.
-Danny!
I'm so sorry.
Help me! I need you
to do something for me.
I can't do it myself.
What is that?
It's an inhibitor.
It's not activated.
I need you to switch it on.
What does it inhibit?
Emotion. It deletes emotions.
Please, I don't want to feel like this.
-There's more than one.
-KATE: What?
They're all over the plane,
they're pulling it apart!
Whoa!
-Ask me.
-Shut up!
Ask me! Go on, you know you want to.
You want to know what my plan is.
You'll be surprised.
I got a gift for you.
You know, I've been
up and down your time line,
meeting all those silly people
who die to keep you alive.
You know what I worked out?
-What you really need?
-For what?
To know that you're just like me.
-(PHONE RINGING)
-Oh!
And now it begins.
Doctor, I do believe you're on call.
Miss Oswald expects.
Who else? But the girl
who's got your number.
Whoops!
It was you!
-Ah! Hello!
-Where did you get this number?
The woman in the shop wrote it down,
it's a helpline, isn't it?
Computer helpline, love!
That's the one.
Best helpline in the universe.
You put us together.
I kept you together.
-Who put that advert in the paper?
-Who gave you my number?
The woman, the woman in the shop.
And there's a woman out there
who is very keen that we stay together.
-Why?
-Because she's perfect, innt?
The control freak and the man
who should never be controlled.
You'd go to hell, if she asked.
And she would.
The phone's ringing, Doctor.
Can't you hear that?
Now, that is the sound
of your chain being yanked.
Heel, Doctor!
Help me Doctor!
Help me, help me, Doctor!
-Clara?
-Doctor?
-With Danny.
-Danny's dead, Clara.
Not yet. Not quite.
But he wants to be.
Clara?
He's a Cyberman.
Doctor, Danny's a Cyberman.
And he's crying.
Doctor, he feels it, he's crying.
Message to Geneva.
Tell them Boat One is going down,
we don't anticipate survivors.
Clara, don't do it, just don't do it!
It's in his chest,
he says it's an inhibitor.
It can delete emotion, or something...
I know what it does.
If you turn it on,
he'll become a Cyberman.
-He's already a Cyberman.
-Not yet, he isn't.
He's hurting because I hurt him.
And he wants it to stop.
Stop the pain, and he'll kill you!
Look, are you going to help me
because I can't do this alone?
I am not going to help
you commit suicide.
Look the Tardis can home in
on this call, right?
Either you help me,
or you leave me alone.
Clara, no!
There's a lot of switches
round the edge.
I'm just going to try pressing them all.
Okay.
I am so sorry.
Yeah.
Doctor! The Cybermen are in,
the plane's going down.
Oh, great. It's the daughter one.
Do you like her? I like her.
Why did you do that?
You didn't have to do that!
Oh, don't be so selfish.
I'm going to miss her, too.
In fact, you know what,
just for that, I'm leaving.
Boys, blow up this plane
and, I don't know, Belgium, yeah?
(PANTING)
Kill some Belgians, might as well,
they're not even French. Bye.
(SCREAMING)
Well, that's very boring!
He's just going to squish.
What kind of a way is that to die?
That man has no finesse, none.
It's quite dramatic.
You're an Al interface,
kindly delete your opinions. Thank you.
What's he doing? Is he...
Oh, no! No, no, now that's...
Oh! Permission to squee!
Two more to go.
Does it feel any different?
-(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
-No.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
Clara, don't.
Help me.
If you do what you're trying to do,
if you succeed, he will snap you.
-No.
-And then he will step
over your broken body, and break
another and another and another.
-He will never stop.
-I will not harm her.
P.E PE.
Sir.
I had a friend once.
We ran together, when I was little.
And I thought we were the same.
But when we grew up, we weren't.
Now, she is trying
to tear the world apart,
and I can't run fast enough
to hold it together. The difference...
...is this. Pain is a gift.
Without the capacity for pain,
we can't feel the hurt we inflict.
Are you telling me seriously,
for real that you can?
-Of course I can.
-Then, shame on you, Doctor.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
Danny. Danny, I need you to tell me,
what are the clouds going to do,
what is the plan?
-How would I know?
-You're part of a hive mind now,
presumably that's how you found Clara.
Just look.
-Can't see much.
-Look harder.
Clara, watch this.
This is who the Doctor is.
Watch the blood-soaked
old general in action.
I can't see properly, sir,
because this needs activating.
If you want to know what's coming,
you have to switch it on.
And didn't all of those beautiful
speeches just disappear
in the face of a tactical advantage?
Sir?
Ahh. I need to know.
I need to know.
Yes. Yes, you do.
Give me the screwdriver.
-No.
-Just do it, Doctor.
Do as you are told.
Typical officer.
Got to keep those hands clean.
-Just point and think, yeah?
-Yes.
Okay.
I wasn't very good at it.
But I did love you.
I loved you, too.
I'm never going to say that again.
Me neither.
-Ready?
-Yeah.
It feels like I'm killing you.
I'm already dead.
You're here this time at least.
Goodbye, Danny.
Goodbye, Clara.
(BUZZING)
Oh...
Ah, no, no, no. Wait, he's activating.
Clara, step away! No, don't!
Danny, if you can hear me,
if you're still there...
What are the clouds going to do?
The rain will fall again.
All humanity will die.
-And rise again as Cybermen?
-Correct.
-How do we stop it?
-We cannot be stopped.
Oh, that was brilliant!
Well, love the telly here,
but did you see that?
Oh, Clara, you poor thing,
you must feel like death.
Let me pop away the pain.
Don't you dare! Don't you
even think about it!
I'm sorry, hon. I'm just getting
a bit carried away.
It's your friends, they're so moreish.
Hmm. Oh, stop looking all cross-pants.
I'm here to give you your gift.
Could you at least try and be excited?
What gift?
Cyberdears!
Look at mummy! Raise your arms.
Lower your arms. Raise your right.
Lower your right. Turn on the spot.
There are exits at the front
and rear of the aircraft.
Please follow the lights up the aisle.
You see, Doctor? The power
to slaughter whole worlds at a time,
then make them do a safety briefing.
Everyone who ever lived, man, woman,
and child is now at my command.
An indestructible army
to rage across the universe.
The more they kill,
the more they recruit.
Happy birthday.
Oh, you didn't know, did you?
It's lucky one of us
remembers these things.
Happy birthday,
# Mr President.
Doctor.
MISSY: Tiny bit pleased?
Oh, go on, crack a smile.
I want to see if your eyebrows drop off.
All of this...
All of it, just to give me an army?
MISSY: Well, I don't need one, do I?
Armies are for people
who think they're right.
Nobody thinks they're righter than you.
Give a good man fire-power,
and he'll never run out
of people to kill.
I don't want an army!
Well, that's the trouble! Yes, you do!
You've always wanted one!
All those people suffering
in the Dalek camps?
Now you can save them. All those bad
guys winning all the wars?
Go and get the good guys back.
-Nobody can have that power.
-You will,
because you don't have a choice.
There's only
one way you can stop these clouds
from opening up
and killing all your
little pets down here.
Conquer the universe, Mr President.
Show a bad girl how it's done.
Why are you doing this?
I need you to know
we're not so different.
I need my friend back.
Every battle, every war, every invasion,
from now on, you decide the outcome.
What's the matter, Mr President?
Don't you trust yourself?
DOCTOR: T7ell me.
Am I good man?
Sir!
DALEK: I see into your soul, Doctor.
I see hatred!
I'm not a hero!
DALEK: You are a good Dalek!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Thank you. Thank you, so much.
I really didn't know. I wasn't sure.
You lose sight sometimes.
Thank you.
I am not a good man.
And I'm not a bad man.
I'm not a hero.
I'm definitely not a president.
And, no, I'm not an officer.
You know what I am?
I am an idiot,
with a box and a screwdriver.
Passing through, helping out. Learning.
I don't need an army, I never have.
'Cause I've got them.
Always them.
Because, love, it's not an emotion.
Love is a promise,
and he will never hurt her.
P.E., catch!
You didn't notice, did you?
While you were doing
all your silly orders,
while you were showing off,
the one soldier not obeying.
No, that's wrong. That's impossible.
The rain will not fall.
Oh? Why won't it?
The clouds will burn.
-And who'll burn them?
-I will burn them.
How?
I will burn.
One burning Cyberman is hardly
going to save the planet.
Correct.
Attention!
This is not a good day.
This is Earth's darkest hour.
And look at you miserable lot.
We are the fallen.
But today we shall rise.
The army of the dead,
will save the land of the living.
This is not the order of a general.
-Nor the whim of a lunatic...
-Excuse me!
This is a promise!
The promise of a soldier!
You will sleep safe tonight.
-(BEEPING)
-(STEAM HISSING)
(EXPLOSION)
Well.
-The clouds have all gone.
-Yes.
Burned up, totally burned.
Burned to nothing.
Sorry.
10-0-11-0-0 by 0-2.
DOCTOR: What did you say?
The current co-ordinates of Gallifrey.
It's returned to its original location.
Didn't you ever think to look?
You are lying.
We can go together. Just you and me,
just like the old days.
You'll be clapped in irons.
If you like.
Doctor, I'm assuming you'll
remember those co-ordinates?
No. Don't you dare, I won't let you.
Old friend, is she?
If you've ever let this creature live,
everything that happened today
is on you.
All of it, on you.
And you are not
gonna let her live again.
Clara,
all I'm doing,
is not letting you kill her.
I never said I was letting her live.
Really?
If it's the only thing
that will stop you, yes.
Seriously?
Oh, Doctor.
To save her soul?
(CHUCKLES)
But who, my dear, will save yours?
Say something nice.
(SIGHING)
Please.
You win.
I know.
-(BEEPING)
-(ZAPPING)
Doctor!
DOCTOR: Kate!
She's breathing.
She's alive! She can't be here!
She is.
She fell out of a plane.
The Cyberman...
Must have caught her.
Doctor. She's talking about her dad!
Of course!
The Earth's darkest hour, and mine.
Where else would you be?
Thank you.
(SIRENS BLARING IN DISTANCE)
DANNY: Clara.
Clara.
Danny.
Danny?
Is that you?
Please say it's you.
DANNY: Clara.
The Doctor told me about the bracelet.
How it can let Missy travel
from one world to the other.
DANNY: This place is dying now.
Yes, but the bracelet
can bring you home.
There's only enough power for one trip.
Then come on, hurry up!
Just one trip.
One trip, one person.
CLARA: Danny!
You need to find his parents.
He died a long time ago.
(GASPING)
I'm sorry, Clara.
(VOICE BREAKING) I truly am.
I had... I had promises to keep.
(CRACKLING)
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(DOOR CHIMES JANGLING)
-Hey. I got your message.
-Hey.
-Two weeks late.
-Not bad.
Improving.
- I see you've got news for me.
-News?
He figured it out then.
P.E., figured out there was a way home.
Yeah. Yeah, he did.
Oh, good old P.E.
He'll make a maths teacher yet.
Listen, Doctor. There's...
There's something that
I have to tell you. And, um,
it's not a good news, so...
-So just listen, okay?
-I know.
Sorry?
I know exactly
what you've got to tell me.
-You... You do?
-You and Danny are together now.
That's great, that's how it should be.
But the old man and the blue box,
that's never gonna fit in.
So no more flying around,
no more lying.
No, that's not exactly...
-It's fine.
-No, it's not fine.
It really isn't fine.
I found Gallifrey!
Wow!
Oh, my God!
(RUMBLING)
DOCTOR: I entered the co-ordinates,
Just like she said.
And I found Gallifrey.
For once, she wasn't lying.
(GRUNTING)
So what are you gonna do now?
-Go home.
-Okay.
Gallifrey can be a good place.
I can help make it that.
-What, you?
-Shut up!
(LAUGHING) You won't just steal
the Tardis and run away?
No, not this time. Never again.
Never again.
It's a long commute,
so, you know, I thought,
-with you and Danny...
-Yeah.
Me and Danny.
Me and Danny, we are gonna be fine.
Don't you worry. You go home.
(LAUGHING) Go home.
Go be a king, or something.
Yeah, I might do that.
(CHUCKLES) Or queen, you know. Whatever.
Yeah, queen, that would be good, too.
(SIGHING)
Tell you what. Seeing as it's goodbye,
shall we break a habit?
What, what habit?
Hug?
Why not.
Within reason.
Come on, you're on the clock.
Fair enough. (CLEARS THROAT)
Why don't you like hugging, Doctor?
Never trust a hug.
It's just a way to hide your face.
(SOFTLY) Yeah.
Doctor?
Travelling with you
made me feel really special.
Thank you for that.
Thank you for making me feel special.
Thank you, for exactly the same.
(WHOOSHING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN: Coo-wee.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Hello!
Doctor, you know it can't end like that!
Hmm>
We need to get this sorted and quickly.
She's not all right, you know.
And neither are you!
-I'm coming in.
-(DOOR OPENS)
Ah! There you are!
I knew I'd get round to you eventually.
Now, stop gawping, and tell me.
What do you want for Christmas?