Sorry.
(WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Where did she go?
-What?
-Who are you?
-But...
-Where am I?
-What?
-What the hell is this place?
What?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
You can't do that, I wasn't...
We're in flight! That is physically impossible.
How did...
Tell me where I am.
I demand you tell me right now, where am I?
-Inside the Tardis.
-What?
-The Tardis.
-The Tardis!
-The what?
-It's called the Tardis.
-That's not even a proper word!
-You're just saying things.
-How did you get in here?
Well, obviously, when you kidnapped me.
Who was it? Who's paying you? Was it Nerys?
Oh, my God, she's finally got me back.
-This has got Nerys written all over it.
-Who the hell is Nerys?
-Your best friend.
-Hold on, wait a minute.
-What are you dressed like that for?
-I'm going ten-pin bowling.
Why do you think, dumbo?
I was halfway up the aisle!
I've waited all my life for this.
I was just seconds away and then you,
I don't know, you drugged me or something.
-I haven't done anything.
-I'm having the police on you.
Me and my husband,
as soon as he is my husband,
we're gonna sue the living backside off you.
No! Wait a minute, wait a minute, don't!
You're in space.
Outer space. This is my...spaceship.
It's called the Tardis.
-How am I breathing?
-The Tardis is protecting us.
-Who are you?
-I'm the Doctor. You?
Donna.
-Human?
-Yeah.
-Is that optional?
-Well, it is for me.
-You're an alien?
-Yeah.
It's freezing with these doors open.
I don't understand it and I understand
everything. This can't happen.
There is no way a human being
can lock itself onto the Tardis
and transport itself inside. It must be...
There's some sort of subatomic connection,
something like a temporal field.
Maybe something pulling you into alignment
with the chronon shell.
Maybe it's something macrobudding your DNA
with the interior matrix.
Maybe a genetic...
-What was that for?
-(SHOUTING) Get me to the church!
Right, fine. I don't want you here anyway.
Where is this wedding?
St Mary's, Haven Road, Chiswick, London,
England, Earth, the solar system.
I knew it, acting all innocent.
I'm not the first, am I?
How many women have you abducted?
-That's my friend's.
-Where is she, then?
-Popped out for a spacewalk?
-She's gone.
Gone where?
-I lost her.
-Well, you can hurry up and lose me.
How do you mean, lost?
Right. Chiswick.
No, she didn't run away.
We're not talking jitters, she literally vanished.
Now go and check the house
and she if she's there.
Oh, Angelica, that's not helping, is it?
Now smarten up.
-Lance, any sign?
-I've looked all around, I can't find her.
-Where the hell did she go?
-Showing off, that's what she is.
-First day at school,
she was sent home for biting.
-It's a bit more serious than that.
-She's never disappeared before.
-She didn't disappear, it's a trick.
It's one of her silly little look-at-me party pieces.
-What if she's dead?
-Oh, don't say that.
I said St Mary's. What sort of Martian are you?
-Where's this?
-Something's wrong with her.
It's like she's recalibrating.
She's digesting. What is it?
What have you eaten? What's wrong?
Donna, you've really got to think.
Is there anything that might have caused this?
Anything you might have done?
Any sort of alien contact? I can't let you go
wandering off. What if you're dangerous?
I mean, have you seen lights in the sky
or did you touch something,
like, something different?
Something strange
or something made out of a piece of metal?
Who are you getting married to?
Sure he's human?
He's not a bit overweight
with a zip round his forehead, is he?
Donna!
-Donna.
-Leave me alone, I just want to get married.
-Come back to the Tardis.
-No way, that box is too weird.
-It's bigger on the inside, that's all.
-Oh, that's all?
3:10. I'm gonna miss it.
Why don't you phone them?
Tell them where you are.
-How do I do that?
-Haven't you got a mobile?
I'm in my wedding dress, it doesn't have pockets.
Who has pockets?
Have you ever seen a bride with pockets?
When I went to my fitting at Chez Alison,
the one thing I forgot to say was,
"Give me pockets."
-This man you're marrying, what's his name?
-Lance.
-Good luck, Lance.
-0i.
No stupid Martian is going to stop me
from getting married, to hell with you.
I'm not... I'm not... I'm not from Mars.
Taxi!
-He had his light on!
-There's another one.
Taxi.
Oi!
There's one.
Do you have this effect on everyone?
Why aren't they stopping?
They think I'm in fancy dress.
-Get off the sauce, darling!
-They think I'm drunk.
You're fooling no one, mate.
They think I'm in drag.
Hold on, hold on.
St Mary's in Chiswick, just off Haven Road.
It's an emergency.
I'm getting married, just hurry up.
That'll cost you, sweetheart. Double rates today.
Oh, my God! Have you got any money?
Erm...no. Haven't you?
Pockets?
And that goes double for your mother!
I'll have him. I've got his number, I'll have him.
Talk about the Christmas spirit.
-Is it Christmas?
-Well, duh!
Maybe not on Mars but here it's Christmas Eve.
Phone box! We can reverse the charges.
How come you're getting married
on Christmas Eve?
Can't bear it, I hate Christmas.
Honeymoon, Morocco. Sunshine, lovely.
What's the operator? I've not done this in years.
What do you dial? 1007
Just call direct.
-What did you do?
-Something...Martian. Now phone, I'll get money.
Oh, answer the phone!
Hello?
Oh, no! The battery's gone dead.
Has anyone got a charger?
Did you try the hotel? Hello? Hello?
Vicar, is your phone working? Mine's run out.
I've got one wedding about to arrive
and another wedding refusing to leave
so, yes, I do think it's a police matter.
Mum, get off the phone and listen, I'm in...
Oh, my God, I don't know where I am,
it's a street.
And there's WHSmith. But it's definitely Earth.
(BEEPING)
Excuse me, I'm begging you.
I'm getting married, I really am,
and I'm late and I just need to borrow a tenner
and I'll pay you back, I promise,
and it's Christmas.
DONNA: Taxi!
I want to go to Chiswick.
Thanks for nothing, Spaceman,
I'll see you in court.
Donna!
I promise you, mate,
I'll give you the rest when we get there.
Oh, I look a mess.
Hurry up.
Hold on a minute, I said Chiswick.
You've missed the turning.
Excuse me, we should have turned off back there.
We're going the wrong way.
(HORN BLARING)
What the hell are you doing?
I'm late for the wedding!
My own wedding, do you get that?
Turn around! Turn this cab around right now!
Are you deaf or what?
Oh, my God!
Help me! Help me!
Help me! Help me! Help me!
Help me! Get me out. Help me!
Help me, I'm being driven by a robot!
Behave!
You are kidding me.
-Open the door!
-Do what?
-I can't, it's locked.
-Santa's a robot.
-Donna, open the door.
-What for?
-You've got to jump.
I'm a blinking bit jumpy!
I'm supposed to be getting married.
Listen to me, you've got to jump.
I'm not jumping on a motorway.
Whatever that thing is, it needs you
and whatever it needs you for, it's not good.
-Now, come on.
-I'm in my wedding dress!
Yes, you look lovely. Come on.
Oh!
I can't do it.
Trust me.
Is that what you said to her?
Your friend, the one you lost.
-Did she trust you?
-Yes, she did.
And she is not dead, she is so alive. Now jump!
(DOCTOR COUGHING)
Funny thing is, for a spaceship,
she doesn't do that much flying.
We'd better give her a couple of hours.
You all right?
It doesn't matter.
-Did we miss it?
-Yeah.
-Well, you can book another date.
-Of course we can.
-Still got the honeymoon.
-It's just a holiday now.
Yeah, yeah, sorry.
-It's not your fault.
-Oh, that's a change.
Wish you had a time machine
then we could go back and get it right.
Yeah, yeah.
But even if I did, I couldn't go back
on someone's personal timeline.
Apparently.
God, you're skinny. This wouldn't fit a rat.
-Oh, and you'd better put this on.
-Oh, do you have to rub it in?
Those creatures can trace you.
This is a bio-damper, it should keep you hidden.
-With this ring, I thee bio-damp.
-For better or for worse.
Come on then, robot Santas, what are they for?
Oh, your basic robo-scavenger.
The Father Christmas stuff is just a disguise.
They're trying to blend in.
I met them last Christmas.
Why, what happened then?
Great big spaceship hovering over London,
you didn't notice?
I had a bit of a hangover.
I spent Christmas day just over there,
the Powell Estate, with this...
Family. My friend, she had this family, well...
Still.
Gone now.
Your friend, who was she?
Question is, what do camouflage
robot mercenaries want with you?
And how did you get inside the Tardis?
I don't know.
What's your job?
I'm a secretary.
Weird. I mean, you're not special,
you're not powerful,
you're not connected, you're not clever,
you're not important.
This friend of yours, just before she left,
did she punch you in the face?
Stop bleeping me!
What kind of secretary?
I'm at HC Clements. It's where I met Lance.
I was temping.
I mean, it was all a bit posh really.
I'd spent the last two years
at a double glazing firm.
Well, I thought I'm never going to fit in here
and then he made me a cup of coffee.
I mean, that just doesn't happen,
nobody gets the secretaries a coffee.
And Lance, he's the head of HR.
He don't need to bother with me.
But he was nice, he was funny.
-She didn't know about that!
-She didn't...
And it turns out he thought
everyone else was really snotty, too.
That's how it started, me and him.
One cup of coffee.
-That was it.
-When was this?
-Six months ago.
-Bit quick to get married.
Well, he insisted.
Will you marry me?
And he nagged and he nagged me.
Oh, just think about it. We'd make a great couple
and I'll get rid of the dog.
And we could do up that back bedroom.
And he just wore me down
and then finally I just gave in.
Please. Oh, please.
Please, please, please, please, please, please.
-What does HC Clements do?
-Oh, security systems, you know.
Entry codes, ID cards, that sort of thing.
-If you ask me, it's a posh name for locksmiths.
-Keys...
Anyway, enough of my CV.
Come on, it's time to face the consequences.
Oh, this is going to be so shaming.
You can do the explaining, Martian boy.
Yeah, I'm not from Mars.
Oh, I had this great big reception all planned.
Everyone's gonna be heartbroken.
(MERRY CHRISTMAS EVERYBODY
BY SLADE PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
You had the reception without me?
Donna, what happened to you?
Hello, I'm the Doctor.
-They had the reception without me.
-Yes, I gathered.
-Well, it was all paid for, why not?
-Thank you, Nerys.
Well, what were we supposed to do?
I got your silly little message in the end.
I'm on Earth? Very funny.
But what the hell happened? How did you do it?
(EVERYONE TALKING AT ONCE)
(WHIMPERING)
-Oh.
(LOVE DON'T ROAM PLAYING)
Well, I taped the whole thing,
they've all had a look.
They said sell it to You've Been Framed,
I said, more like the news.
Here we are.
Can't be, play it again.
Clever, mind. Good trick, I'll give her that.
I was clapping.
That looks like Huon particles.
What's that, then?
That's impossible, that's ancient.
Huon energy doesn't exist any more,
not for billions of years.
It's so old that...
It can't be hidden by a bio-damper.
-Donna! Donna, they've found you.
-But you said I was safe.
The bio-damper doesn't work.
We've got to get everyone out.
-Oh, my God, it's all my family.
-Out the back door.
Maybe not.
We're trapped.
-Christmas trees.
-What about them?
They kill. Get away from the tree.
Get away from the Christmas trees,
everyone get away...
Lance! Lance!
DOCTOR: Stay away from the tree!
Stay away from the tree.
Oh, for God's sake, the man's an idiot.
What harm's the Christmas tree gonna...
Oh!
(SCREAMING)
Oi, Santa, word of advice.
If you're attacking a man with a
sonic screwdriver,
don't let him near the sound system.
(PIERCING TONE)
-It's all right, Stan, you'll be all right.
-Michael, Connie.
-Sanita, do something useful.
-What is it?
-What were they?
-Just stop wittering, just help him.
Look at that,
remote control for the decorations,but there's a
second remote control for the robots.
They're not scavengers any more.
I think someone's taken possession.
Never mind all that,
you're a doctor, people have been hurt.
No, they wanted you alive.
Look. They're not active now.
-All the same, you could help.
-Got to think of the bigger picture.
There's still a signal!
Donna, who is he? Who is that man?
(BUZZING)
There's someone behind this,
directing the roboforms.
But why is it me? What have I done?
If we find the controller, we'll find that out. Oh!
It's up there.
Something in the sky.
Clever, clever, clever boy.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Little travelling man.
(CACKLING)
You shall come to me and the beautiful bride.
Such secrets to unlock.
I shall descend this night.
I shall descend upon this Earth
and shine!
I've lost the signal.
Donna, we got to get to your office, HC Clements.
I think that's where it all started. Lance!
Is he Lance? Lance, can you give me a lift?
To you lot this might just be a locksmith,
but HC Clements was bought up 23 years ago
by the Torchwood Institute.
-Who are they?
-They were behind The Battle of Canary Wharf.
Cyberman invasion.
-Skies over London full of Daleks?
-I was in Spain.
-They had Cybermen in Spain.
-Scuba diving.
That big picture, Donna, you keep on missing it.
Torchwood was destroyed,
but HC Clements stayed in business.
I think someone else came in
and took over the operation.
What do they want with me?
Somehow you've been dosed with
Huon energy and that's a problem
because Huon energy
hasn't existed since the Dark Times.
The only place you find a Huon particle now
is a remnant in the heart of the Tardis.
See, that's what happened.
Say that's the Tardis and that's you.
The particles inside you activated,
the two sets of particles magnetise and wap!
You were pulled inside the Tardis.
-I'm a pencil inside a mug?
-Yes, you are. 4H sums you up.
Lance, what was HC Clements working on?
Anything top secret,
special operations, do not enter?
I don't know, I'm in charge of personnel.
I wasn't project manager.
Why am I even explaining myself?
What the hell are we talking about?
You make keys, that's the point.
And look at this, we're on the third floor.
Underneath reception there's a basement, yes?
Then how come when you look in the lift,
there's a button marked "lower basement".
There's a whole floor
which doesn't exist on the official plan.
-So what's down there?
-You telling me this building's got a secret floor?
No, I'm showing you
this building's got a secret floor.
-It needs a key.
-I don't.
Right then, thanks, you two.
I can handle this, see you later.
No chance, Martian.
You're the man who keeps saving my life.
-I ain't letting you out of my sight.
-Going down.
-Lance?
-Maybe I should go to the police.
Inside!
-To honour and obey.
-Tell me about it, mate.
Oi!
The bride approaches! She is my key.
-Where are we? What goes on down here?
-Let's find out.
Do you think Mr Clements knows
about this place?
The mysterious HC Clements?
Oh, I think he's part of it.
Oh, look, transport.
(DONNA AND THE DOCTOR LAUGHING)
Wait here, just need to get my bearings.
Don't do anything.
-You better come back.
-Couldn't get rid of you if I tried.
Donna, have you thought about this properly?
I mean, this is serious.
What the hell are we gonna do?
Oh, I thought July.
Thames flood barrier. Right on top of us.
Torchwood snuck in
and built this place underneath.
What, there's like a secret base
hidden underneath a major London landmark?
I know. I know, love.
Oh! Look at this.
Stunning.
-DONNA: What does it do?
-Particle extrusion. Hold on.
Brilliant.
They've been manufacturing Huon particles.
Of course, my people got rid of Huons.
They unravel the atomic structure.
Your people?
Who are they? What company do you represent?
Oh, I'm a freelancer.
But this lot are rebuilding them.
They've been using the river.
Extruding them through a flat hydrogen base
so they've got the end result...
Huon particles in liquid form.
And that's what's inside me?
Oh, my God!
Genius.
Because the particles are inert, they need
something living to catalyse inside
and that's you.
Saturate the body and then...
Oh, the wedding!
Yes, you're getting married. That's it!
Best day of your life, walking down the aisle.
Your body is a battleground!
There's a chemical war inside.
Adrenaline, acetylcholine.
Wham go the endorphins! Oh, you're cooking.
You're like a walking oven. A pressure cooker,
a microwave, all churning away.
The particles reach boiling point... Shazam!
-What did I do this time?
-Are you enjoying this?
All right, just tell me,
these particles, are they dangerous?
-Am I safe?
-Yes.
Doctor...
if your lot got rid of Huon particles,
why did they do that?
Because they were deadly.
-Oh, my God.
-I'll sort it out, Donna.
Whatever's been done to you, I'll reverse it.
I'm not about to lose someone else.
(DOOR OPENING)
VOICE: Oh, she's long since lost.
I have waited so long.
Hibernating at the edge of the universe.
Until the secret heart
was uncovered and called out to waken me.
Someone's been digging.
Oh, very Torchwood. Drilled by laser.
How far down does it go?
Down and down.
All the way to the centre of the Earth.
Really? Seriously, what for?
-Dinosaurs.
-What?
Dinosaurs?
-What are you on about? Dinosaurs.
-That film under the Earth with dinosaurs.
-Trying to help.
-That's not helping.
Such a sweet couple.
Only a madman talks to thin air.
And trust me, you don't want to make me mad.
Where are you?
High in the sky.
Floating so high on Christmas night.
DOCTOR: I didn't come all this way
to talk on the intercom.
Come on, let's have a look at you.
Who are you with such command?
I'm the Doctor.
Prepare your best medicines, doctor man,
for you will be sick at heart.
(HISSING)
Racnoss.
That's impossible. You're one of the Racnoss.
Empress of the Racnoss.
If you're the Empress,
where's the rest of the Racnoss?
Or are you the only one?
Such a sharp mind.
That's it. The last of your kind.
The Racnoss come from the Dark Times.
Billions of years ago. Billions.
They were carnivores. Omnivores.
They devoured whole planets.
Racnoss are born starving. Is that our fault?
(HISSING)
They eat people?
HC Clements, did he wear those, uh,
black and white shoes?
He did! We used to laugh.
We used to call him the fat cat in spats.
Oh, my God!
Aye! Christmas dinner.
You shouldn't even exist.
DOCTOR: Way back in history, the Fledgling
Empires went to war against the Racnoss.
-They were wiped out.
-Except for me.
That's what I've got inside me,
that Huon energy thing.
Oi! Look at me, lady, I'm talking.
Where do I fit in?
How come I get all stacked up
with these Huon particles?
Look at me, you. Look me in the eye and tell me.
-The bride is so feisty.
-Yes, I am.
And I don't know what you are, you big thing.
But a spider's just a spider.
And an axe is an axe.
Now, do it!
That was a good one. Your face.
Lance is funny.
What?
-I'm sorry.
-Sorry for what?
-Lance, don't be so stupid. Get her!
-God, she's thick.
Months I've had to put up with her. Months!
A woman who can't even point
to Germany on a map.
I don't understand.
How did you meet him?
-In the office.
-He made you coffee.
What?
Every day I made you coffee.
You had to be dosed with liquid particles
over six months.
He was poisoning me.
It was all there in the job title.
The head of human resources.
This time it's personnel.
But... We were getting married.
Well, I couldn't risk you running off.
I had to say yes.
Then I was stuck with a woman who thinks the
height of excitement is a new flavoured Pringle.
Oh, I had to sit there
and listen to all that yap, yap, yap.
Ooh, Brad and Angelina!
Is Posh pregnant? X Factor. Atkin's diet.
Feng shui. Split ends.
Text me, text me, text me.
Dear God, the never-ending fountain of
fat, stupid trivia.
-I deserve a medal.
-Oh, is that what she's offered you?
The Empress of the Racnoss.
What are you? Her consort.
It's better than a night with her.
But I love you.
That's what made it easy.
LANCE: It's like you said, Doctor. The big picture.
What's the point of it all
if the human race is nothing?
That's what the Empress can give me.
The chance to...go out there.
To see it. The size of it all.
I think you understand that, don't you, Doctor?
Who is this little physician?
-She said Martian.
-Oh, I'm sort of homeless.
But the point is, what's down here?
The Racnoss are extinct.
What's going to help you 4,000 miles down?
That's just the molten core of the Earth, innit?
-I think he wants us to talk.
-I think so, too.
Well, tough. All we need is Donna.
Kill this chattering little doctor man.
-Don't you hurt him.
-No, it's all right.
No, I won't let them.
Ah! Now, except...
Take aim!
Well, I just want to point out the obvious.
They won't hit the bride.
They're such very good shots.
(STUTTERING)
Just hold on. Hold on just a tick.
Just a tiny little, just a...tick.
If you think about it,
the particles activated in Donna
and drew her inside my spaceship.
So reverse it, the spaceship comes to her.
EMPRESS: Fire!
Off we go, then.
My key!
Oh, do you know what you said before
about a time machine?
Well, I lied. And now we're gonna use it.
We need to find out what
the Empress of the Racnoss is digging up.
If something's buried at the planet's core,
then it must've been there since the beginning.
That's just brilliant. Motto bene!
I've always wanted to see this.
Donna, I'm going further back
than I've ever been before.
If a key is lost, then another must be cut.
(YELLING)
We've arrived. You want to see?
I suppose.
The scanner's a bit small. Maybe your way's best.
Come on.
No human's ever seen this. You'll be the first.
All I wanna see is my bed.
Donna Noble,
welcome to the creation of the Earth.
We've gone back 4.6 billion years.
There's no solar system. Not yet.
Only dust and rocks and gas.
That's the sun. Over there. Brand-new.
Just beginning to burn.
-Where's the Earth?
-All around us.
In the dust.
Puts the wedding in perspective.
Lance was right. We're just tiny.
No, but that's what you do. The human race.
Make sense out of chaos.
Marking it out with weddings
and Christmas and calendars.
This whole process is beautiful.
But only if it is being observed.
So I came out of all this.
Isn't that brilliant?
I think that's the Isle of Wight.
Eventually, gravity takes hold.
Say, one big rock, heavier than the others,
starts to pull other rocks towards it.
All the dust and gas and elements get pulled in,
everything piling in until you get...
The Earth.
Now, the question is, what was that first rock?
DONNA: Look.
The Racnoss.
Now I have measured the bride's catalysis,
I can force feed it.
Drink the particles, become the key!
Hold on, the Racnoss are hiding from the war.
-What's it doing?
-Exactly what you said.
Oh, they didn't just bury something
in the centre of the Earth.
They became the centre of the Earth.
The first rock.
(RUMBLING)
-What was that?
-Trouble.
My wonderful key.
Now, my servants, find him.
What the hell is it doing?
A little trick of mine. Particles pulling particles.
Well, it works in reverse,
and they're pulling us back.
Well, can't you stop it?
Hasn't it got a handbrake?
Can't you reverse or warp or fade or something?
Back-seat driver. Oh! Wait a minute.
The extrapolator.
It can't stop us,
but it should give us a good bump!
EMPRESS: The bride shall join her groom.
What a wedding there shall be.
Now!
We're about 200 yards to the right. Come on.
She is close. The holy bride in white.
Find her. Find her!
-What do we do?
-I don't know. I'm making it up as I go along.
-But trust me, I've got history.
-I still don't understand.
I'm full of particles, but what for?
There's a Racnoss web at the centre of the Earth,
but my people unravelled their power source.
If Huon particles cease to exist,
the Racnoss will stop.
They just stayed in hibernation
for billions of years, frozen, dead, kaput.
So you're the new key.
Brand-new particles, living particles.
They need you to open it
and you have never been so quiet.
Oh!
I hate you.
Yeah, I think we've gone bit beyond that now,
sweetheart.
My golden couple, together at last!
Your awful wedded life!
Tell me, do you want to be released?
-BOTH: Yes.
-You're supposed to say, "I do."
-No chance.
-Say it.
-I do.
-I do!
I don't.
(LAUGHING)
Activate the particles.
Purge every last one!
And release!
The secret heart unlocks
and they will waken from their sleep of ages.
Who will? What's down there?
How thick are you?
My children, the long lost Racnoss,
now reborn to feast on flesh.
The web star shall come to me.
My babies will be hungry. They need sustenance.
Perish the web.
Use her, not me. Use her!
Oh, my funny little lad,
but you were quite impolite to your lady friend.
The Empress does not approve.
Lance!
It's Christmas.
Harvest the humans. Reduce them to meat.
EMPRESS: My children are climbing towards me
and none shall stop them.
So you might as well unmask,
my clever little doctor man.
Oh, well, nice try.
I've got you, Donna.
-I'm gonna fall!
-You're gonna swing.
(SCREAMING)
I've got you.
(CRASHING)
(CLATTERING)
Oh, sorry.
Thanks for nothing.
The doctor man amuses me.
Empress of the Racnoss,
I give you one last chance.
I can find you a planet.
I can find you and your children
a place in the universe to coexist.
Take that offer and end this now.
These men are so funny.
-What's your answer?
-Oh! I'm afraid I have to decline.
Then what happens next is your own doing.
I'll show you what happens next.
At arms!
Take aim!
-And...
-Relax.
-What did you do?
-Guess what I've got, Donna.
Pockets.
-How did that fit in there?
-They're bigger on the inside.
Roboforms are not necessary.
My children may feast on Martian flesh.
-Oh, but I'm not from Mars.
-Then where?
My home planet is far away and long since gone.
But its name lives on.
Gallifrey.
-They murdered the Racnoss.
-I warned you.
You did this.
No, no. Don't!
No!
No! No! No!
My children!
(EMPRESS SHRIEKING)
Doctor!
You can stop now.
My children!
Come on, time to find a way out.
Transport me!
Oh, they will suffer. So suffer!
This planet shall be scorched.
What about the Empress?
She's used up all her Huon energy.
She's defenceless.
MAN: Orders of Mr Saxon, fire at will.
Fire!
(SCREAMING)
-There's just one problem.
-What is it?
We've drained the Thames.
(FOG HORNS BLOWING)
(THE DOCTOR AND DONNA LAUGHING)
DOCTOR: There we go.
I told you she'd be all right.
-Survive anything.
-More than I've done.
Well, all the Huon particles are gone.
-No damage. You're fine.
-Yeah, apart from that.
I missed my wedding, I lost my job
and became a widow on the same day.
Sort of.
I couldn't save him.
He deserved it.
No, he didn't.
I better get inside, they'll be worried.
Best Christmas present they could have.
-Oh, no, I forgot, you hate Christmas.
-Yes, I do.
Even if it's snowing?
I can't believe you did that.
Oh, basic atmospheric excitation.
-Merry Christmas.
-And you.
So, what will you do with yourself now?
Not getting married, for starters.
And I'm not gonna temp any more.
I don't know, travel.
See a bit more of planet Earth, walk in the dust.
Just go out there and do something.
-Well, you could always...
-What?
...come with me.
-No.
-Okay.
-I can't.
-No, that's fine.
No, but really, I mean, everything we did today,
do you live your life like that?
Not all the time.
I think you do.
And I couldn't.
But you've seen it out there.
-It's beautiful.
-And it's terrible.
That place was flooded and burning
and they were dying,
and you stood there like,
I don't know, a stranger.
And then you made it snow!
I mean, you scare me to death.
Well, then.
I'll tell you what I will do, though.
Christmas dinner.
-Oh, come on.
-I don't do that sort of thing.
You did it last year, you said so.
And you might as well
because Mum always cooks enough for 20.
All right then. But you go first,
better warn them, and don't say I'm a Martian.
I just have to park her properly.
She might drift off to the Middle Ages.
I'll see you in a minute.
(WHOOSHING)
Doctor!
Blimey, you can shout.
-Am I ever gonna see you again?
-If I'm lucky.
Just promise me one thing.
Find someone.
-I don't need anyone.
-Yes, you do.
'Cause sometimes I think you need someone
to stop you.
Yeah.
Thanks then, Donna. Good luck.
And just...
be magnificent.
I think I will, yeah.
-Doctor?
-Oh, what is it now?
That friend of yours, what was her name?
Her name was Rose.
(WHOOSHING)
-I'm the Doctor.
-Me, too, if I can pass my exams.
-What was your name?
-Martha.
Martha Jones.
Rose her name was.
Not that you're replacing her.
Never said I was.
Monsters! There are monsters.
It's started.
Let her go!
The Globe Theatre.
Mr Shakespeare, isn't it?
What are you standing there for? Come on.
Very well dressed for a hitchhiker.
No!
Tonight, I'm going to perform a miracle.
I'm 76 years old.