(WIND BLOWING)
Quite an Arctic storm
blowing out there. Hm!
Come along, Polly,
my child, with my cloak.
Hey, Doctor, you've got
the most fantastic wardrobe.
Yes. We don't know
what we're in for outside there.
Pretty soon we shall be having visitors.
(BEEPING)
You're different.
You've got no feelings.
I do not understand that word.
Emotions. Love, pride, hate,
fear!
Have you no emotions, sir?
What's happened to you, Doctor?
I guess this old body of mine
is wearing a bit thin.
BEN: Doctor. Wakey, wakey.
It's all over now.
(CREAKING)
No.
It isn't all over.
It's far from being all over.
What are you talking about?
I must get back to the TARDIS.
I can't go through with it.
I will fight it.
I will not change.
Hello? Is someone there.
Hello?
-Who is that?
-I'm the Doctor.
Oh, I don't think so.
No. (CHUCKLES) Dear me, no.
You may be a doctor.
But I am the Doctor.
The original, you might say.
You?
How can it be you?
-Do I know you, sir?
-This is the South Pole.
We're at the South Pole.
Of course, we are.
Don't you know that?
This is where it happened.
Where what happened?
This is it.
The very first time
that I... Well, you...
We regenerated.
You're mid-regeneration, aren't you?
Your face. It's all over the place.
But you're trying to hold it back.
What do you know of regeneration?
Are you a Time Lord?
You know who I am. You must.
(CHUCKLES)
Have you come to take the ship back?
The ship. You still call it a ship.
Oh, dear.
What have you done to it?
Nothing. The windows.
-I don't remember this.
-They're the wrong size!
I don't remember
trying not to change.
-Not back then.
-I'm sure it's changed. Look at it!
It seems to have expanded.
Well, it's all those years
of bigger on the inside.
You try sucking your tummy in that long.
Why are you trying not to regenerate?
I have the courage and the right
to live and die as myself.
Too late. It's started.
A few minutes ago,
you were weak as a kitten, right?
Now, you're fine.
We're in a state of grace, both of us.
But it won't last long.
We have a choice.
Either we change and go on,
or we die as we are.
But, if you...
If you die here...
If your future never happens,
if you don't do the things
that you are supposed to do,
the consequences could be...
-The snow.
-Snow?
Look at it!
How extraordinary.
Everything's stopped.
Why?
Maybe it's us.
Maybe it's something else.
But somehow, something
has gone very wrong with time.
MAN: Hello?
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I don't suppose
either of you is a doctor?
You trying to be funny?
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
CAPTAIN: There is
something I should like to say.
That is,
there is something I should
very much like you to understand
I do not have
the slightest desire to kill you.
The only reason I would do so
is self-defence.
However, since you're aware
I might kill you in self-defence,
there is the strong possibility
you will kill me in self-defence.
(PANTING)
It does rather make me wish
you understood English.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Or that I spoke German.
War is hell, eh?
(SHELL WHISTLING)
(EXPLOSION)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(YELLS)
GLASS WOMAN: Time line error.
There is a time line error.
Time line error.
(COUGHING)
(PANTING)
DOCTOR: Everything stopped.
FIRST DOCTOR: But why?
DOCTOR: Maybe it's us.
Maybe it's something else.
But somehow, something has gone
very wrong with time.
Hello.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I don't suppose
either of you is a doctor?
You trying to be funny?
She's coming.
It's her.
FIRST DOCTOR: Not human, I think.
State your planet of origin
and your intentions.
This is Earth,
a level five civilisation.
And it is protected.
It's what?
Oh, okay.
That doesn't usually work.
Protected by whom?
Oh, it is early days. Isn't it?
May I suggest for your own safety,
you step on board my ship?
What ship?
He means, "Get inside the box."
A little snug from this angle.
But you might be in for a surp...
My TARDIS!
Look at my TARDIS!
This is impossible.
Have I been burgled?
-It's... But it's...
-It's hideous.
Bigger on the inside
than it is on the outside.
You know, I thought it probably was.
Glad it's not just me.
What is this place?
This place is, or ought to be,
my TARDIS.
Technically, that is your TARDIS.
It's about 70 feet that way.
See?
Always remember where you parked.
It's gonna come up a lot.
Is this madness?
Am I going mad?
Madness? Well, you're an officer
from World War One at the South Pole
being pursued by an alien
through frozen time.
(FIRST DOCTOR CHUCKLES)
Madness was never this good.
World War One?
Judging by the uniform, yes.
Yes, but...
What do you mean, "One"?
Oh, sorry, spoilers.
Enough of this.
Who are you?
Um... You know who I am.
You knew the moment you saw me.
I'd say stop being an idiot,
but I kind of know what's coming.
I assure you, I do not have
the faintest idea who you are.
Well, I know who you are.
Is anyone going
to explain what's going on?
DOCTOR: Snap.
You are me.
No. No!
Yes. Yes, I'm very much afraid so.
Do I become you?
Well, there's a few false starts,
but you get there in the end.
But, I thought...
What?
Well, I assumed I'd get younger.
I am younger!
You know, I really don't think
I'm completely following.
-Oh. Oh, dear.
-Oh, you're in shock!
Let me help you.
Brandy.
Get him brandy.
Do you have any?
I had some somewhere.
-Hang on.
-Sit down here, my boy.
Collect your wits.
CAPTAIN: Who are you people?
I am the Doctor and this is my...
It's complicated, actually.
-I am also...
-...my nurse.
Excuse me?
I realise that seems
a little improbable.
-Yes.
-Because he's a man.
What?
Older gentlemen, like women,
can be put to use.
You can't... You can't
say things like that.
Can't 1?
Says who?
Just about everyone you're going to meet
for the rest of your life. Here.
Have you had some of this?
Well, you know,
I may have snuck a glass
at some point in the last 1500 years.
It's been rock and roll.
Here you are.
Get this down you.
You'll feel a lot better.
-Thank you.
-Yes.
FIRST DOCTOR: I, erm...
I don't understand any of this.
Well, of course you understand.
I am your future self.
Are you indeed?
And I suppose this is
meant to be my TARDIS?
Our TARDIS.
What's wrong with the lights?
It's supposed to be like this.
Why?
It's atmospheric.
Atmospheric?
This is the flight deck
of the most powerful space-time
machine in the known universe,
not a restaurant for the French.
Good Lord. What is that?
Oh. Look what someone
has accidentally left here.
I say!
It's some sort of guitar, isn't it?
-Is it yours?
-No.
It appears to have
been played quite recently.
It's the only thing here
that's been cleaned.
In fact, this whole place
could do with a good dusting.
Obviously, Polly isn't around any more.
Please, please.
Please stop saying things like that.
(THUDDING)
(PANTING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
I can't get the engines to start.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
There's some kind of signal
blocking the command path.
(REVVING)
FEMALE VOICE: Exit your capsule.
The Chamber of the Dead awaits you.
DOCTOR: I'll fix the engines
while you keep her talking.
Fields up.
(DOOR RATTLING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Look around you.
(BEEPING)
You stand
in the Chamber of the Dead.
You are known to all here
for you are the Doctor of War.
No, no.
The Doctor, yes.
But the Doctor of War?
Never, Ma'am. Never.
We offer you a gift.
Return to us
the human on your TARDIS.
And in exchange
you may speak with her again.
Speak with whom?
(DOOR RATTLING)
Young lady, who are you?
Is he here?
Is the Doctor here?
BILL: Doctor!
(LAUGHING)
I knew it!
I did! I knew it!
I knew you couldn't be dead.
You don't have the concentration.
Doctor?
What are you doing?
(BEEPING)
Just keep still, please.
Bill Potts?
Yeah.
My friend Bill Potts
was turned into a Cyberman.
She gave her life
so that people
she barely knew could live.
So, let's be clear.
Nobody imitates Bill Potts.
Nobody mocks Bill Potts.
Bill Potts
is standing right in front of you.
How is that even possible?
Well, long story short,
I totally pulled.
You did what?
Heather. Do you remember,
the girl in the puddle?
Well, she showed up.
She came for me.
How romantic.
Where is she?
Well, she's...
-She's...
-And how did you get here?
I don't...
-I can't...
-You can't remember. I bet you can't.
(BEEPING)
That device. What is it?
It's a sonic screwdriver.
A what screwdriver?
It's really a very good job.
An audio screwdriver?
There are only three
low-key markers
indicating that she's a duplicate.
I'm not a duplicate.
So, who has been stealing
the faces of the dead?
Time travel technology, eh? Obviously.
DOCTOR: From the far future.
I know.
-Sunglasses?
-They're sonic.
Indoors?
So, what are you?
We are what awaits
at the end of every life.
As every living soul dies,
so we will appear.
We take from you what we need and
return you to the moment of your death.
We are testimony.
DOCTOR: You come
from the distant future?
You travel back in time,
you find people,
at the exact point of death and what?
You harvest something from them?
Yes.
On behalf of the dying,
what is it that we have
that the future needs so badly?
And what is any of this to do
with a World War One Captain
landing at the South Pole
in the wrong decade?
We were returning him to the appointed
time and place of his death.
An error in the time line ejected him
into the wrong time zone.
Now, his death must proceed
as history demands.
If I may.
Who were you?
-She wasn't anyone.
-(BEEPING)
She's a computer generated interface
connected to a multiform
inter-phasing...
Oh, for heaven's sake, will you put
that ridiculous buzzing toy away
and look at the woman?
You see? Her face.
It's very slightly asymmetrical.
If it were computer generated,
it wouldn't produce that effect.
Yes!
You're absolutely right.
I should've noticed that.
Well, it might help
if you could see properly.
Excuse me? Doctor?
Get back inside.
I'm not quite sure,
but it seemed to me
that this young lady's life
was being offered
in exchange for my own.
Now as it happens, I think my number
is pretty much up anyway.
What are you talking about?
Doctor, what is he talking about?
So, might as well
make it count for something, eh?
I should be happy to take your place
if that would resolve the situation.
GLASS WOMAN: Accepted.
(SCOFFS) That is...
That is not happening.
That's totally not happening.
Agreed?
Tell me what to do then.
Bill Potts would tell me what to do.
Do what you always do.
Serve at the pleasure of the human race.
Here's what's going to happen.
First, I'm going to escape.
-You, with me.
-Where are we going?
Escape is not possible.
It is possible and it is happening.
And I'm taking Bill
and the Captain with me.
Why are you advertising your intentions?
Can't you stop boasting for a moment?
Mr Pastry, too. I could do with a laugh.
GLASS WOMAN: Escape is not possible.
Oh, I'm going to do
way more than escape.
I'm going to find out who you are
and what you are doing,
and if I don't like it, I will come back
and I will stop you.
I will stop all of you.
Who the hell do you think you are?
-The Doctor.
-I am the Doctor.
Who you are, I cannot begin to imagine.
GLASS WOMAN:
Then let us show you, Doctor.
See who you will become.
-DALEK: Doctor!
-Exterminate!
You will be assimilated!
DOCTOR: No, no, no.
That's not a good idea.
They all die.
GLASS WOMAN: The Doctor has walked
in blood through all of time and space.
The Doctor has many names.
MAN: The destroyer of the world!
GLASS WOMAN: The imp of the pandorica.
The shadow of the Vale yard.
The beast of Trenzalore.
The butcher of Skull Moon.
The last tree of Garsennon.
The destroyer of Skaro.
He is the Doctor of War.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What... What was that?
To be fair, they cut out all the jokes.
-Do what I do when I do it.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
Jump!
(ALL GRUNTING)
GLASS WOMAN: They are not escaping!
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
DOCTOR: Jump!
(ALL GRUNTING)
-BILL: What do we do now?
-Run!
Where? They've got the TARDIS.
Yes. That's exactly
what they're supposed to think.
Yeah, but they do, though. Look.
DOCTOR: They've got my TARDIS.
Over to you, Mary Berry.
Come on.
Doctor, is that another TARDIS?
No.
No, it's another of the same TARDIS.
Hang on. The windows are the wrong size.
Inside, quickly.
Take off, now.
Deep space, anywhere.
(RHYTHMIC WHIRRING)
Tell you what. These police boxes,
they're ever so good, aren't they?
The navigation systems
don't function properly.
I'm unable to programme our flight
with any accuracy.
So, my dear,
I presume you travel with him?
Used to. Kind of miss it.
Well, he clearly misses you.
That ship of his is in dire need
of a good spring clean.
No, no, stop, stop... Look, look.
Oh, look, look, look.
Look at the lovely... The astral map.
Look at the lovely blinking lights.
Look at that. (WHISTLES)
BILL: He's you.
He is, isn't he? He's you.
He's one of your old faces.
I find I'm lagging behind
a tiny bit again. (STAMMERS)
Not those again, I forbid it.
There you go. I was right.
-Asymmetrical.
-I said that.
Same difference.
If her face
was based on a human original,
perhaps identifying who that was
will tell us what we need to know
about testimony.
Er, why am I wearing these?
Because I love it.
Never take those off.
What's "browser history"?
I'm trying to match her face
in the TARDIS data bank.
But there's hardly anything in it yet.
We need a bigger database.
Possibly the Matrix on Gallifrey.
No. We need something bigger
than the Matrix.
CAPTAIN: So, basically we're trying
to track the Glass Lady, yes?
BILL: Basically.
FIRST DOCTOR: A striking creature.
Quite beautiful really, isn't she?
Yeah, if you like ladies made of glass.
Well, aren't all ladies
made of glass in a way?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Very good, sir, very good.
Are we now?
Oh, my dear,
I hope it doesn't offend you to know
that I have had some experience
of the, er, fairer sex.
Me too.
Good Lord.
(RUMBLING)
(WHIRRING)
Where are we?
FIRST DOCTOR: But you steered the ship,
you piloted her perfectly.
We are at
the very centre of the universe.
DOCTOR: Out there is the most
comprehensive database
of all life anywhere.
There is just one little problem.
Which is?
It wants to kill me.
(SIGHS)
(CREATURES SCREECHING)
The Weapon Forges of Villengard.
Once the nightmare
of the seven galaxies.
Now home to the dispossessed.
I say, I think there's something
moving over here.
Step away, please.
Probably just rats.
-I'm used to rats.
-(CREATURES SCURRYING)
-(SCREAMING)
-(CREATURE SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
-(GASPING)
-Deep breaths, deep breaths.
Just breathe, Captain, you'll be fine.
FIRST DOCTOR: That creature,
it looked familiar.
It's mutated a bit, but, yes,
I should think it did.
Come along, my dear chap,
you'll be fine.
-Get him into the TARDIS.
-What are those things?
DOCTOR: Er...
What we came here for.
-The biggest database in the galaxy.
-(CREATURES SCREECHING)
They'll settle down in a moment.
So, do we talk to them?
Ask them questions? How does it work?
-We don't do anything, I do.
-(BILL PROTESTING)
-No, no, no...
-You're going to wait in the TARDIS.
-But why?
-You need to look after the Captain.
You're lying.
You think I'm a duplicate. A trick.
I don't know what I think.
But if there's the slightest chance
that Bill Potts is alive,
and standing in front of me,
then I will not under any circumstances,
put her life in danger again.
Seriously? You're looking right at me
and you don't even know I'm here?
Correct. I ask you to respect that.
-And respect me.
-You're an arse.
(STAMMERING)
You're a stupid bloody arse.
As I've always respected you.
If I hear any more language
like that from you, young lady,
you're in for
a jolly good smacked bottom.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
Can we just pretend that
that never happened?
I'm a broad-minded girl.
I mean, I know we have this whole
professor/student thing going on...
Can we just never ever
talk about this again?
Yeah, I hope we talk about it loads.
(CHUCKLES) I hope we spend years
laughing about it.
Come back alive.
Be here when I do.
Perhaps another nip of brandy.
Mmm. So that's where it went.
I'll look after him.
Good girl. Quite right.
Now, young lady,
I don't want to have to repeat myself.
I don't think any of us want that.
I'll see you both presently.
Brandy?
Please.
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
FIRST DOCTOR:
These creatures, what are they?
DOCTOR: Old friends of ours.
But they've
really come out of their shell.
FIRST DOCTOR: Out of their shell?
You all right?
(GASPING)
I'll be... I'll be fine in a moment.
Well, what's the matter?
I died a few hours ago
then I refused to regenerate.
It catches up with you.
You know, it's like a big lunch.
I did exactly the same.
I know you did. But why?
I don't remember this.
Why are you refusing the regeneration?
Fear.
I'm afraid. Very, very afraid.
I don't normally admit that
to, er, anyone else.
Don't worry.
Technically you still haven't.
Why are you?
(DOCTOR GROANS)
FIRST DOCTOR: There's something
in that tower!
DOCTOR: Must be my friend.
FIRST DOCTOR:
Why do you call it your friend?
(BOTH GROAN)
DOCTOR: He's got a great big gun.
Are you suggesting I insult him?
Just scan me.
Go on, scan me.
'Cause I've got big news for you.
I'm dying!
See, it's true.
(MAKES POPPING NOISE)
Dying.
Now, be honest with yourself,
wouldn't you like to see that up close?
Come on, up and at 'em,
Corporal Jones.
I don't know.
Funny thing,
I wasn't afraid in the crater.
One doesn't want to die, of course,
but one gets in a certain frame of mind,
one pulls oneself together
and gets on with the matter in hand.
Big shock for everyone.
Back in Cromer of course.
BILL: You have family?
My wife will miss me.
That's perfectly natural.
But she's a solid woman,
remarkably solid.
And my boys...
Well...
Sons are supposed to
move on from their fathers.
It's the proper way.
BILL: Of course.
Trouble is, I thought I'd been rescued.
Felt rather like a miracle, in fact.
But I do have this feeling
they're going to put me back.
Back in that crater.
In time to die.
And you see,
I'm not ready any more.
I've lost the idea of it.
That's the trouble with hope.
Makes one awfully frightened.
(CHUCKLES)
I must sound like
the most dreadful coward.
Okay, I'd better go up alone.
I won't hear of it.
That thing up there
won't miss the chance to kill me twice.
The paradox would
rip the universe apart.
And you know how much hard work it is
putting it back together again.
You keep a lookout down here.
Oh, if you insist.
You know what? You're
a bit of a legend these days.
Not everyone believes it.
People don't think that it could happen.
Someone like you could
turn against your own kind.
Because your kind don't do that.
Out of their shells.
Because people don't believe
there could be any such thing
as a good Dalek.
I am not a good Dalek!
You are a good Dalek!
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
Oh. Hello, my dear.
Now, Rusty, you know that I'm dying.
If you don't want me to go off and die
somewhere else where you can't watch,
you're gonna have to
stop shooting at me.
I agree to your terms.
Well, I'm going to need some proof.
(METAL SCRAPING)
(CRACKLING)
You know what?
You're the very first Dalek
that ever got naked for me.
(CRACKLING)
You're the first one, yeah,
like the original version of the Doctor?
My dear, you should
get back to the ship.
This place isn't safe.
You're the one who stole the TARDIS
and ran away.
The Captain might be needing you.
No, the Captain"s fine.
Why did you do it?
Oh, I'm sure your Doctor has explained.
Not even sure he remembers.
There were many pressing reasons.
I don't mean what you ran away from.
What were you running to?
That's rather a good question.
Questions are kind of my thing.
How are you with answers?
Been a long time.
Remember the good old days?
When I got miniaturised
and climbed around inside you?
You taught me to hate the Daleks.
Billions of years ago.
What have you been up to since then?
Destroying Daleks.
Yes, all the ones who come here
to murder you, yes.
I saw the mess outside.
Why are you here?
As a Dalek,
you are linked
in to the Dalek hive mind.
All Daleks are.
Biggest database I know.
I'd like to access it.
Why would I help you?
Because helping me in any way
does something wonderful.
It hurts the Daleks.
FIRST DOCTOR:
There is good and there is evil.
I left Gallifrey
to answer a question of my own.
By any analysis, evil should always win.
Good is not
a practical survival strategy.
It requires loyalty,
self-sacrifice and, er, love.
And so, why does good prevail?
What keeps the balance
between good and evil
in this appalling universe?
Is there some kind of logic,
some mysterious force?
Perhaps there's just a bloke.
(MUMBLES)
-A bloke?
-Yeah.
Perhaps there's just some bloke
wandering around
putting everything right
when it goes wrong.
Well, that would be a nice story,
wouldn't it?
That would be the best.
But the real world is not a fairy tale.
You dash around the universe
trying to figure out
what's holding it all together
and you really, really don't know.
You know me in the future.
Do I ever understand?
No.
I really don't think you do.
Everyone who's ever met you does.
You're amazing, Doctor.
Never forget that.
Never ever.
Well, that's very kind of you.
We just needed to
understand you, Doctor.
"Professor Helen Clay.
"University of New Earth,
year 5 billion and 12."
There's footage, can you run it?
A spy.
A spy in the camp.
No, not a spy.
I'm Bill Potts.
But I'm part of Testimony now.
The Testimony Foundation combines
the resources of time travel
with the latest
in memory extraction techniques.
The near dead can be lifted momentarily
from their time streams,
their memories duplicated,
and then their physical souls returned
to the moment of their dissolution,
without pain, distress
or any recall of the process.
Now the dead can speak again.
We can hear the testimony
of the past.
And channel led through
our glass avatars,
they can walk among us again.
This is Heaven on New Earth.
(CRACKLING)
It's not an evil plan.
I don't really know what to do
when it isn't an evil plan.
Why did you stop it? Rusty?
He didn't stop it.
They've frozen time again.
Who has?
(HOLOGRAM HUMMING)
Not everything's evil, Doctor.
(WHOOSHING)
You're not the only kind one
in the universe.
I knew you weren't real.
Oh, shut up and stop being so stupid!
Of course I'm real.
What is anyone supposed to be
except a bunch of memories?
These are my memories,
so this is me. I'm Bill Potts.
And I'm back.
And so long as I'm here,
what the hell do you mean
you're not going to regenerate?
There has to be an end, Bill.
For everyone, everywhere.
What about the Captain?
You know he has to die at his allotted
point in time and space.
To correct the error.
I'm so tired of losing people.
If the Captain has to die,
a request... This was our fault.
How so?
Let us take him back.
FIRST DOCTOR: How was this our fault?
DOCTOR: You and me
tried to die twice
in the same lifetime.
Our lives are woven
throughout time and space.
We caused the time line error
that put the Captain in the wrong place.
We created a whirlpool in time
that landed him at our feet.
But why him? What's so important
about one captain?
Everybody is important to somebody,
somewhere.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine. Absolutely.
Just thinking.
I told the wife
I'd be home for Christmas.
Funny how things work out.
Thank you.
Thank you, all.
You've all been most gracious
under the unfortunate circumstances.
I regret, Captain,
that the universe generally
fails to be a fairy tale.
When time resumes,
you will not remember this.
A perception filter
will also render us invisible.
Yes.
One imagines some
of those words were attached
to actual meanings of some sort.
One thing you could possibly
do for me if you're very kind?
Oh, anything. Name it.
My family. Perhaps you could
look in on them
from time to time.
We should be delighted...
(STAMMERS)
-What's the name?
-Lethbridge-Stewart.
Captain Archibald Hamish
Lethbridge-Stewart.
FIRST DOCTOR:
I shall make it my business.
You can trust him on that.
Thank you so much.
I believe I am now ready.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Cold, isn't it?
It's about to get colder, I suppose.
For one of us.
(WHIMPERING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
(MEN SING IN DISTANCE)
(SINGING GETS LOUDER)
I say...
Is that singing?
(MEN SINGING IN GERMAN)
Is that...
Christmas carols?
# Silent night
# Holy night
# All is calm
# All is bright
# Round yon virgin
# Mother and child #
You know, I could swear
it's coming from both sides.
If I've got my timings right,
and clearly I have,
then we should be
right at the beginning.
SOLDIER: Hold your fire.
DOCTOR: I adjusted the time frame
only by a couple of hours.
Any other day, it wouldn't
make any difference
but this is Christmas 1914,
and a human miracle
is about to happen.
The Christmas armistice.
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Wounded man here!
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Wounded man.
DOCTOR: Never happened again,
any war, anywhere.
I say, wounded man here.
Wounded man!
DOCTOR: But for one day,
one Christmas,
a very long time ago,
everyone just put down their weapons
and started to sing.
Everybody just stopped.
Everyone.
It was just kind.
FIRST DOCTOR: You've saved him.
DOCTOR: Both of them.
Never hurts.
A couple fewer
dead people on the battlefield.
So that's what it means
to be a Doctor
of War.
You were right, you know.
The universe generally
fails to be a fairy tale.
(SOLDIER GROANING)
But that's where we come in.
(SOLDIERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHEERING)
# For auld lang syne, my dear
# For auld lang syne
# We'll take a cup of kindness yet
# For auld lang syne, my dear
# For auld lang syne
# We'll take a cup of kindness yet
# For auld lang syne #
I think I'm ready now.
But I should like to know...
Are you?
You'll find out.
The long way round.
Whatever you decide,
good luck, Doctor.
Goodbye, Doctor.
(EXHALES)
Well then...
Here we go.
The long way round.
BILL: Are you okay?
Shall we go for one last stroll,
Miss Potts?
You know what the hardest thing
about knowing you was?
My superior intelligence.
Bedazzling charisma...
Oh, my impeccable dress sense.
Letting you go...
Letting go of the Doctor
is so, so hard.
Isn't it?
You see, that's... That's not the sort
of thing the real Bill Potts would say.
I am the real Bill!
A life is just memories.
I'm all her memories.
-So I'm her.
-If you say so.
Okay, I'm gonna prove to you
how important memories are.
I've got a little goodbye present
for you.
Oh, that's nice. Will I have to pretend
to like it, because
-honestly, that rug...
-Oh, come here, you.
Merry Christmas, Doctor.
Clara.
Hello.
You stupid old man.
You're back.
You're in my head.
All my memories...
are back.
And don't go
forgetting me again, because...
quite frankly, that was offensive.
Memories. They're important, right?
I know what you're thinking.
Where is he?
Hello, sir.
When you're already dying
you're entitled to think that your day
couldn't get any worse, but...
here you are.
And both of you are here.
How does that work?
We can be everyone.
-We are everyone.
-Mmm-hmm.
Yes, good this, innit?
Now I'm all made of glass,
not just my nipples.
Yeah, they got my hair
a bit wrong, though, didn't they?
You don't have any hair!
I have invisible hair.
Got a suggestion for you then.
Oh, there's a novelty.
Don't die.
Because if you do,
I think everybody in the universe
might just go cold.
Can't I ever have peace?
Can't I rest?
Of course you can.
It's your choice.
Only yours.
We understand.
No.
No, you don't.
You're not even really here.
You're just memories,
held in glass.
Do you know how many of you
I could fill?
I would shatter you.
My testimony would shatter all of you.
A life this long,
do you understand what it is?
It's a battlefield like this one.
And it's empty.
Because everyone else
has fallen.
Thank you, thank you both,
for everything that
you were to me.
What happens now,
where I go
now
has to be alone.
Cuddle.
(SIGHS)
Time to leave the battlefield.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Oh, there it is. Silly old universe.
The more I save it,
the more it needs saving.
It's a treadmill.
(BEEPING)
Yes, yes, I know they'll get it
all wrong without me.
(BEEPING)
Well, I suppose,
one more lifetime
won't kill anyone.
Well, except me.
You wait a moment, Doctor.
Let's get it right.
I've got a few things
to say to you.
Basic stuff first.
Never be cruel, never be cowardly
and never ever eat pears.
Remember...
Hate is always foolish.
Love is always wise.
Always try to be nice,
and never fail to be kind.
Oh, and...
You mustn't tell anyone your name.
No one would understand it anyway.
Except...
(GROANS)
Except children.
Children can hear it
sometimes
if their hearts are in the right place
and the stars are, too.
Children can hear your name.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
But nobody else...
Nobody else...
Ever...
Laugh hard.
Run fast.
Be kind.
Doctor...
I let you go.
Oh, brilliant.
(BEEPING)
(RUMBLING)
Ah! Ah! Ah!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)