DALEK EMPEROR: Purify the Earth with fire.
The planet will become my temple
and we shall rise.
You are the heathen.
You will be exterminated.
DALEKS: Exterminate. Exterminate.
Tardis materialising.
I looked into the Tardis.
And the Tardis looked into me.
You've got the entire vortex
running through your head, you're gonna burn!
I can see the whole of time and space.
Every single atom of your existence
and I divide them.
The Time War ends.
I cannot die.
-My head. ..
-Come here.
-...is killing me.
-I think you need a doctor.
-Doctor!
-Stay away!
Doctor, tell me what's going on.
I absorbed all the energy of the time vortex
and no one's meant to do that.
Time Lords have this little trick.
It's sort of a way of cheating death.
Hello, okay.
New teeth, that's weird. So, where was I?
Oh, that's right, Barcelona!
600 pm.
Tuesday, October, 5006,
on the way to Barcelona.
Now then, what do I look like?
No, no, no, no, no, don't tell me. Let's see.
Two legs, two arms, two hands,
slight weakness in the dorsal tubercle.
Hair! I'm not bald.
Ooh, big hair. Sideburns, I've got sideburns!
Really bad skin. Little bit thinner, that's weird.
Give me time. I'll get used to it.
I have got a mole.
I can feel it.
Between the shoulder blades, there's a mole.
That's all right. Love the mole.
Go on, then, tell me.
What do you think?
-Who are you?
-I'm the Doctor.
No. Where is he?
Where's the Doctor? What've you done to him?
You saw me, I changed. Right in front of you.
I saw him sort of explode
and then you replaced him,
like a teleport or a transmat
or a body swap or something.
You're not fooling me.
I've seen all sorts of things, nanogenes, Gelth,
Slitheen.
Oh, my God, are you Slitheen?
I'm not a Slitheen.
Send him back.
I'm warning you, send the Doctor back right now.
Rose, it's me. Honestly, it's me.
I was dying.
To save my own life, I changed my body.
Every single cell, but still me.
You can't be.
Then how can I remember this?
The very first word I ever said to you,
trapped in that cellar,
surrounded by shop-window dummies.
Ooh, such a long time ago.
I took your hand, I said one word. Just one word.
I said, "Run."
Doctor.
-Hello.
-Oh, my God.
And we never stopped, did we?
All across the universe.
Running, running, running.
And one time we had to hop. Do you remember?
Hopping for our lives. Yeah? All that hopping.
Remember hopping for your life? Yeah?
Hop. Where they... No?
-Can you change back?
-Do you want me to?
-Yeah.
-Oh.
-Can you?
-No.
-Do you want to leave?
-Do you want me to leave?
No, but your choice, if you want to go home.
Cancel Barcelona.
Change to London, the Powell Estate.
Let's say, 24th December.
Consider it a Christmas present.
There.
-I'm going home?
-Up to you.
Back to your mum. It's all waiting.
Fish and chips, sausage and mash,
beans on toast. No, Christmas, turkey!
Although, having met your mother,
nut loaf would be more appropriate.
-Was that a smile?
-No.
That was a smile.
-No, it wasn't.
-You smiled.
-No, I didn't.
-Oh, come on, all I did was change. I didn't...
-wWhat?
-I said...
DOCTOR: Uh-oh.
Are you all right?
What's that?
The change is going a bit wrong. I'm all...
Look, maybe we should go back.
Let's go and find Captain Jack.
He'll know what to do.
Ah, he's busy.
He's got plenty to do rebuilding the Earth.
I haven't used this one in years.
-What are you doing?
-Putting on a bit of speed, that's it.
My beautiful ship, come on. Faster, atta girl.
What do you think? Faster?
Do you wanna break the time limit?
-Stop it!
-Ah, don't be so dull. Let's have a bit of fun.
Let's rip through that vortex.
Regeneration's going wrong.
(MUMBLING)
(GROANING) My head.
Faster! Let's open those engines all the way.
(ALARM BLARING)
-What's that?
-We're gonna crash-land.
-Well, then do something!
-Too late!
-You're gonna kill us!
-Hold on tight, here we go!
Christmas Eve.