(WHISTLING)
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
Not now, I'm busy.
All right then, what?
What? What?
01! Get out of my Tardis!
I let down the defences
for one second...
Must speak to the Doctor.
I don't care. You're a Graske.
And a Graske is trouble. Out!
But that noise...
Beautiful sound in the air, what is it?
If you must know,
that's the music of the spheres.
Music of the spheres is what?
Well, you got all those planets
revolving around suns,
and all those suns
revolving around in a galaxy,
and all those galaxies
revolving around each other.
If you take the gravity patterns
and feed them
through the Tardis harmonic filter,
that, Mr Graske,
is the sound of the universe.
Universe sounds wonderful.
Yeah. It does, doesn't it?
But you're still not staying.
No, Graske came to warn you.
-About what?
-About that.
Oh, now.
-That looks like a space-portal.
-Told you. Danger.
Nah! It's harmless.
Just a hole in space.
I wonder what's on the other side.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Hello.
Where's that, then?
Who are all those people?
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Hold on.
That looks like...
Is that the Albert Hall?
I said, “Is that the Albert Hall?"
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
I said, “Is that the Albert Haiti"
AUDIENCE: Yes!
Oh, great! Hello.
I said, “Hello. "
AUDIENCE: Hello!
No, no, no. Sorry. Sorry.
You'll have to shout.
I said, "Hello!"
AUDIENCE: Hello!
Listen. My name's the Doctor,
I'ma Time lord,
but that is an awful lot of people.
What 're you all doing there? Oh/
Wait a minute. It's the Proms.
Is that the Proms? Are you in the Proms?
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
Oh! I love the Proms.
I was at the very first Proms.
1895, I played the tuba.
I was brilliant.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Is that the orchestra down there?
Oh! Wart there/
'Cause funny thing is,
I've just been
composing something myself.
I said to Beethoven,
I said I can rattle off a tune.
He said, "Pardon?"
But I've just been inspired
by the music of the spheres.
I've written my own symphony.
Yeah. And if I can send these pages
through the portal,
then the orchestra can play it.
Brand new piece of music composed by me.
So, are you ready for this, orchestra?
Stand by. Three, two, one...
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
That's it/ That's it/
There you go! Hurry up!
This portal isn't going to stay
open for long, right...
Now, so, if you don't mind,
Mr Conductor.
Stand down.
I'm in charge of this one. Quiet please.
(DOCTOR SHUSHING)
Silence. Settle down. 01, settle down.
So, ladies and gentlemen, children,
this is the world-wide premier
of Ode to the Universe.
And...
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING CACOPHONIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Oh, come on! That was brilliant/
Thank you, I thank you.
No, I thank you.
Really, you're too kind.
You see, Graske,
that's the thing about planet Ear...
What? What? Where's he gone?
Oh, I've lost a Graske.
He must have slipped through the portal
Have you seen him?
Ahh! There he is! Albert Hall,
you've got a Graske on the loose.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
And he's stolen my water-pistol.
01! Graske, stop it! Behave!
He wasn't trying to warn me. He was
trying to find a shortcut to Earth.
If he escapes, he'll go around
the whole planet causing trouble,
stealing sweets, making smells...
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
I'm just gonna have to reverse
the polarity of the neutron flow
and pull that Graske
back into the Tardis.
-Not fair!
-Oh, I'll give you "not fair”.
I'm gonna reverse
the teleport numbers and send you
all the way to
the other side of the galaxy.
Right.
Well, that was fun and a little bit mad.
But I've got to close this portal
before there's any more trouble.
It's nice to see you all.
But one more thing.
Just remember,
music isn't just orchestras
and pop stars
and special people with albums
and downloads and concerts.
It's you.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING SLOW SONG)
'Cause the music of the spheres
is all around you.
When you're on your own,
Just close your eyes
and you'll hear it.
Music, inside your head.
'Cause everyone's a musician.
Everyone's got a song inside them.
Every single one of you.
Bye.