DOCTOR:
This little girl it's all about her.
Who was she?
RORY: Doctor, what is happening to her?
Contractions.
-Contractions?
-She's going into lab our.
Breathe.
I needed enough information
to block the signal to the Flesh.
What signal?
The signal to you.
-Rory, I don't like this.
-Stand away from her, Rory.
We're coming for you, I swear.
And whatever happens, however hard,
however far, we will find you.
I'm right here.
No, you're not.
And you haven't been
for a long, long time.
(GASPS)
You're ready to pop, aren't you?
(SCREAMS)
AMY: I wish I could tell you
that you'll be loved.
That you'll be safe and cared for
and protected.
But this isn't a time for lies.
What you are going to be, Melody,
is very, very brave.
Two minutes.
But not as brave as they'll have to be,
because there's someone's coming.
I don't know where he is
or what he's doing
but trust me, he's on his way.
Intruder, level nine. Seal level nine.
There's a man
who's never going to let us down.
And not even an army can get in the way.
Leave her. Just you leave her.
(SOBBING) Please, leave her!
Please, leave her!
Intruder, level 11.
Seal levels 12, 13 and 14.
Intruder, level 75.
(CRYING)
He's the last of his kind.
He looks young but he's lived for
hundreds and hundreds of years.
And wherever they take you, Melody,
however scared you are,
I promise you,
you will never be alone.
(CRYING)
Because this man is your father.
Prepare to engage.
He has a name, but the people
of our world know him better...
...as the Last Centurion.
I have a message and a question.
A message from the Doctor
and a question from me.
Where is my wife?
Oh, don't give me those blank looks.
The Twelfth Cyber Legion
monitors this entire quadrant.
You hear everything.
So, you tell me what I need to know.
You tell me now and I'll be on my way.
What is the Doctor's message?
Would you like me
to repeat the question?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
MAN 1: A whole cyber legion, though,
he just blew them all up
to make a point!
MAN 2: We're being paid
to fight him, not praise him.
Praising costs way more.
Level minus-23 transept.
Digger says he once
chased the Atraxi off a planet
then called them back for a scolding.
MAN 2: Fight him, not praise him.
WOMAN ON PA: Alert.
This base is on yellow alert.
Is she sewing?
She's on her break,
she can do what she likes.
-Now, try again.
-(SIGHS)
That one.
No that's the psychic.
You got to look for the fractals.
Don't look bored, we're on yellow alert.
We've been on yellow alert
for three weeks.
WOMAN ON PA: Reminder.
Do not interact with Headless Monks
without divine permission.
We're not supposed to stare at them.
And if they think we're trying to see
under their hoods, they'll kill you.
On the spot.
Why are they called the Headless Monks?
They can't really be headless.
LORNA: They believe
the domain of faith is the heart
and the domain of doubt is the head.
They follow their hearts, that's all.
-You're Lorna Bucket, aren't you?
-Yep.
Hello, I'm the thin one.
This is my husband, he's the fat one.
Don't you have names?
We're the thin-fat, gay, married
Anglican Marines.
Why would we need names as well?
(MONKS CHANTING)
Oh, looks like I'm off.
Time for my conversion tutorial.
See you in a bit.
Do you have Lent?
'Cause I'm not good at giving things up.
Lorna Bucket.
You've had an encounter, haven't you?
-You've met him.
-I was just a kid.
But what's he like, the Doctor?
He said, "Run."
-Just "run"?
-He said it a lot.
And this was in the Gamma Forests, yeah?
Cause you're a Gamma girl, aren't you?
What are you doing here?
The Forests are heaven-neutral.
Yeah.
And 30 seconds of the Doctor is the only
thing that ever happened there.
Oh, this is nice. I like this.
I mean, quite a lot of red.
Hope it's not to hide the stains?
(LAUGHING)
What's in the little boxes?
WOMAN ON PA: Welcome, Applicant,
to the Order of the Headless.
It is traditional for visiting armies
of other faiths
to offer individuals for conversion
to our order.
You have been selected.
Are you ready
to make a donation?
So, what do you think?
If the Doctor's really coming here,
where is he?
He's the Doctor,
he could be anywhere in time and space.
Whoa!
Thank you, Parky.
I won't be needing you again tonight.
DRIVER: Yes, milady.
Oh, you're back early, ma'am.
Another case cracked, I assume?
Send a telegram to Inspector Abberline
of the Yard.
Jack The Ripper
has claimed his last victim.
(WHISPERING) How did you find him?
Stringy.
But tasty all the same.
-I shan't be needing dinner.
-Congratulations, ma'am.
However, um...
a matter has arisen in the drawing room.
It just appeared. What does it mean?
It means
a very old debt is to be repaid.
Pack the cases, Jenny,
we're going to need the swords.
(SHOUTING) Nurse.
Nurse!
Damn it, where's the nurse?
He needs help.
Madam President, I'm sorry,
but we have to go now.
Those things could be here any second.
Did somebody call for a nurse?
Will I be okay?
Of course you will, my boy,
you'll be up and around in no time.
And perhaps one day, you and I
shall meet on the field of battle
and I will destroy you
for the glory of the Sontaran Empire.
-Thanks, nurse.
-Pleasure.
(EXPLOSION)
Commander Strax,
I just have to ask, a Sontaran nurse?
I serve a penance to restore
the honour of my clone batch.
It is the greatest punishment
a Sontaran can endure.
-To help the weak and sick.
-Who came up with that one?
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Tonight, though,
perhaps my penance is over.
Captain Harcourt, I hope someday
to meet you in the glory of battle,
where I shall crush the life
from your worthless human form.
Try and get some rest.
(KLAXONS SOUNDING)
Oh, turn it off,
I'm breaking in, not out.
This is River Song, back in her cell.
(KLAXONS STOP)
Oh, and I'll take breakfast
at the usual time.
Thank you.
Oh, are you boys dressing up
as Romans now?
I thought nobody read my memos.
Dr Song,
it's Rory.
Sorry, have we met yet?
The time streams,
I'm not quite sure where we are.
Yes. Yes, we've met.
Hello, Rory.
What's wrong?
(GASPS) It's my birthday.
The Doctor took me ice skating
on the River Thames in 1814,
the last of the great Frost Fairs.
He got Stevie Wonder to sing
for me under London Bridge.
Stevie Wonder sang in 18147
Yes, he did!
But you must never tell him.
I've come from the Doctor, too.
-Yes, but at a different point in time.
-Unless there's two of them.
Now, that's a whole different birthday.
He needs you.
Demon's Run.
How...
How did you know?
I'm from his future. I always know.
Why on earth are you wearing that?
-The Doctor's idea.
-Of course.
His rules of engagement.
Float like a butterfly,
sting like a bee.
-Look ridiculous.
-Have you considered heels?
They've taken Amy. And our baby.
The Doctor's getting
some people together.
We're going after her,
but he needs you too.
I can't.
Not yet, anyway.
I'm sorry?
This is the battle of Demon's Run,
the Doctor's darkest hour.
He'll rise higher than ever before
and then fall so much further.
And I can't be with him
till the very end.
Why not?
Because this is it.
This is the day he finds out who I am.
(SIGHS)
Goodbye.
You appear to be closing down, Dorium.
What have you heard?
That you pricked the side
of a mighty beast, Madam Kovarian,
and entirely failed to run.
(SIGHS) I admire your courage.
I should like to admire it from afar.
We've been waiting a month.
He's done nothing.
Do you really think so?
There are people all over this galaxy
that owe that man a debt.
By now, a few of them
will have found a blue box
waiting for them on their doorstep.
Poor devils.
You think he's raising an army?
You think he isn't?
If that man is finally collecting
on his debts, God help you.
And God help his debtors.
Why?
Colonel Manton,
all those stories
you've heard about him,
they're not stories, they're true.
(LAUGHING) Really.
You're not telling me
you don't know what's coming?
-We're wasting our time here.
-Agreed.
The asteroid,
where you've made your base,
do you know
why they call it Demon's Run?
How do you know
the location of our base?
(SIGHS) You're with the Headless Monks,
they're old customers of mine.
It's just some old saying.
A very old saying. The oldest.
"Demons run
when a good man goes to war."
(LAUGHING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
No! No, no, please! Not me.
You don't need me.
Why would you need me?
I'm old, I'm fat, I'm blue.
You can't need me!
He is not the Devil.
He's not a god.
He's not a goblin or a phantom
or a trickster.
The Doctor is a living, breathing man.
And as I look around this room,
I know one thing,
we're sure as hell going to fix that.
ALL: Yes!
Yes/
(DOOR CLOSES)
Sorry.
I... I shouldn't be here,
I'm meant to be at the thing.
I brought you something.
Your child's name,
in the language of my people.
It's a prayer leaf, and we believe
if you keep this with you,
your child will always come home to you.
Can I borrow your gun?
Why?
'Cause I've got a feeling
you're going to keep talking.
(CROWD CHEERING)
They're talking like he's famous.
The Doctor isn't famous.
He meets a lot of people.
Some of them remember.
He's sort of like a...
I don't know.
-A dark legend.
-Dark.
-Have you met him?
-Yeah.
But I was just a little girl then.
So was I.
You've been with him a long time, then?
No.
He came back for me.
You must be very special.
Hey,
you can wait a long time for the Doctor
but he's worth it, okay?
Thing is, he's coming,
no question about it.
Just you make sure you're on
the right side when he gets here.
Not for my sake, for yours.
Thank you.
On this day, in this place,
the Doctor will fall.
ALL: (SHOUTING) Hurrah!
The man who talks, the man who reasons,
the man who lies
will meet the perfect answer.
ALL: Hurrah!
Some of you have wondered
why we have allied ourselves
with the Headless Monks.
Perhaps you should have wondered
why we call them "headless".
It's time you knew what these guys
have sacrificed for faith.
As you all know,
it is a level one heresy,
punishable by death,
to lower the hood of a Headless Monk.
But by the divine grant
of the Papal Mainframe herself,
on this one and only occasion,
I can show you the truth.
Because these guys never can be...
persuaded.
They never can be...
afraid.
And they can never ever be...
(ALL GASPING)
Surprised.
(LAUGHS) Hello everyone, guess who?
Please, point a gun at me,
if it helps you relax.
(COCKING GUNS)
You're only human.
Go on, resist, I am ever so hungry.
Now, dear,
which button controls the lights?
Doctor, you will come with me right now.
Three minutes, 40 seconds.
Amelia Pond! Get your coat!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL MUMBLING)
-DOCTOR: I'm not a phantom.
-Doctor?
I'm not a trickster.
-I'm a Monk.
-Doctor, show yourself.
-It's him!
He's here.
It's him!
(GUNSHOT)
Weapons down. Do not fire!
No!
Follow me.
Doctor? Doctor!
-Clever, isn't he?
-And rather attractive.
You do realise he's a man,
don't you, ma'am?
-Mammals, they all look alike.
-Thank you.
Do not fire. Nobody discharge
their weapon in this room.
Nobody.
Do not fire.
Was I being insensitive again, dear?
I don't know why you put up with me.
MANTON: Stop, wait.
Listen to me.
I'm disarming my weapon pack.
Monks, I do this in good faith.
I am now unarmed.
(MURMURING)
All of you discharge you weapon packs.
The Doctor is trying
to make fools of us.
We are soldiers of God.
We are not fools.
COLONEL MANTON: We are not fools.
We're not fools.
-Colonel Manton is regaining control.
-Where has the Doctor gone?
ALL: We are not fools.
We are not fools.
We are not fools!
(HISSING)
(GROWLING)
This space is now under our command.
I have a fleet out there.
If Demon's Run goes down,
there's an automatic distress call.
DOCTOR: Not if we knock out
your communications array.
And you've got incoming.
Danny Boy to the Doctor,
Danny Boy to the Doctor.
Give 'em hell, Danny Boy.
(MIMICKING PLANE)
(MIMICKING GUNFIRE)
I need to get off this station now.
Bring me the child.
(ALARMS SOUNDING)
DANNY BOY: Target destroyed.
(LAUGHING)
Don't slump, it's bad for your spine.
(MELODY CRYING)
KOVARIAN:
Get back in there with the rest of them.
Remember,
the Doctor must think he's winning
right until the trap closes.
I'll take my ship from here.
(MELODY CRYING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Air lock engaged.
Shuttle ready for boarding.
No.
I have a crew of 20.
How do you expect
to gain control of my ship?
(SMIRKS)
The ship is ours, milady.
All airlocks sealed.
Resistance neutralised.
DOCTOR: Sorry, Colonel Manton, I lied.
Three minutes 42 seconds.
Colonel Manton, you will give the order
for your men to withdraw.
No, Colonel Manton,
I want you to tell your men to run away.
What?
Those words, "Run away."
I want you to be famous
for those exact words.
I want people to call you
Colonel Runaway.
I want children
laughing outside your door
'cause they've found the house
of Colonel Runaway.
And when people come to you
and ask if trying to get to me
through the people I love...
(HISSING)
...Is in any way a good idea,
I want you to tell them your name.
Look, I'm angry, that's new.
I'm really not sure
what's going to happen now.
KOVARIAN: The anger of a good man
is not a problem.
Good men have too many rules.
Good men don't need rules.
Today is not the day
to find out why I have so many.
-Hmm?
-Give the order.
Give the order, Colonel Runaway.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Who's that? Who's there?
You watch it, because I am armed
and really dangerous and cross.
RORY: Yeah, like I don't know that.
Rory? Rory, is that you?
Yeah, it's me.
Look, hang on a minute.
They took her.
Rory, they took our baby away.
Now, Mrs Williams,
that is never ever going to happen.
(MELODY COOING)
Oh, my God.
Where's she been?
What have they done to her?
She's fine. Amy, she's fine, I checked.
She's beautiful.
Oh, God, I was going to be cool.
-I wanted to be cool and look at me.
-You're okay.
A crying Roman with a baby.
Definitely cool.
Come here, you.
Ew, kissing and crying.
I'll... I'll be back in a bit.
Oi, you. Get in here, now.
My daughter.
-What do you think?
-Hello. Hello, uh...
-...baby.
-Uh, Melody.
Melody? Hello, Melody Pond.
-Melody Williams.
-Is a geography teacher.
Melody Pond is a superhero.
(DOCTOR SNIFFING)
Well, yes,
I suppose she does smell nice.
Never really sniffed a...
Maybe I should give it a go.
Amelia Pond, come here.
Doctor.
Sorry we were so long. (SNIFFS) Ah.
It's okay. I knew you were coming.
Both of you, my boys.
(MELODY SQUEALS)
It's okay. She's still all yours
and really you should call her Mummy.
-Not Big Milk Thing.
-(MELODY COOS)
-Okay, what are you doing?
-I speak baby.
No, you don't.
I speak everything.
Don't I, Melody Pond?
No, it's not. It's cool.
(LAUGHING)
Doctor, take a look, they're leaving.
Demon's Run is ours
without a drop of blood spilled.
My friend, you have never risen higher.
-(SHUSHING)
-Hey, what's wrong?
She doesn't like the Tardis noise.
I asked him to turn something off,
but it was all,
"But I don't want to punch a hole
"in the space-time continuum."”
Rory, the Judoon have escorted
the clerics out of the quadrant.
Spitfires have returned
to their own time.
Captain Avery and his men are going...
Is she all right?
Yeah, she's just crying.
Give her to me, human fools,
she needs changing.
I just changed her.
I think she might need a feed.
A feed?
Of course, I'll take care of everything.
Uh, I really don't think
you will, actually.
I have gene-spliced myself
for all nursing duties.
I can produce magnificent quantities
of lactic fluid.
She's not hungry, she's tired.
Sorry, Melody,
they're just not listening.
What's this? Melody?
Very pretty, according to your daughter.
-It's, uh...
-It's a cot.
-No flies on the Roman.
-(LAUGHS)
Give her here.
Hey, here we go. Oh, hello.
RORY: But where would you get a cot?
It's old. Really old.
Doctor, um, do you have children?
No.
Have you ever had children?
(COOING)
No, no, it's real, it's my hair.
(LAUGHS) Who slept in here?
VASTRA: Doctor, we need you
in the main control room.
DOCTOR: Be right there.
Things to do. I've still got to work out
what this base is for.
We can't leave till we know.
Uh, but this is where I was.
The whole time I thought I was
on the Tardis, I was really here.
Ah, Centurion, permission to hug?
-Be aware, I do have a sword.
-At all times.
You were on the Tardis, too,
your heart and mind, soul.
But physically, yes,
you were still in this place.
And when I saw that face looking
through the hatch,
that woman looking at me?
Reality bleeding through.
They must've taken you
quite a while back,
just before America.
That's probably enough hugging now.
So, her flesh avatar was
with us all that time?
But that means they were projecting a
control signal right into the Tardis,
-wherever we were in time and space.
-Yeah, they're very clever.
-Who are?
-Whoever wants our baby.
-Why did they want her?
-Exactly.
Is there anything you're not telling us?
You knew Amy wasn't real,
you never said.
Well, I couldn't be sure
they weren't listening.
But you always hold out on us,
please, not this time.
Doctor, it's our baby.
Tell us something. One little thing.
It's mine.
-What is?
-Cot. It's my cot.
I slept in there.
Oh, my God.
It's the Doctor's first stars.
(GIGGLES)
She's...
STRAX: Drop your weapons!
State your rank and intent.
I found it listening at the door.
You've hacked into their software, then?
-I believe I sold it to them.
-Ooh. So what have we learned?
That anger is always
the shortest distance to a mistake.
-I'm sorry?
-The words of an old friend,
who once found me
in the London Underground
attempting to avenge my sisters
on perfectly innocent tunnel diggers.
Well, you were very cross at the time.
As you were today, old friend.
Point taken, I hope.
Now, I have a question. A simple one.
Is Melody human?
Sorry, what? (LAUGHS)
Of course she is. Completely human.
What are you talking about?
They've been scanning her
since she was born.
And I think they found
what they were looking for.
-Human DNA.
-Look closer.
Human plus.
Specifically, human plus Time Lord.
But I heard her talking. This is a trap.
Why would I lie to you?
Well, you might want
to take a look at your uniform.
The only reason I joined the clerics
was so I could meet the Doctor again.
You wanted to meet him
so you joined an army to fight him?
Well, how else
do you meet a great warrior?
-He's not a warrior.
-Then why is he called the Doctor?
It's starting. Please listen to me!
But she's human.
She's Amy and Rory's daughter.
You've told me about your people.
They became what they did through
prolonged exposure to the time vortex.
The untempered schism.
Over billions of years.
It didn't just happen.
So, how close is she...
Could she even regenerate?
No! No. I don't think so.
You don't sound so sure.
Because I don't understand
how this happened.
Which leads me to ask,
when did it happen?
When?
I am trying to be delicate.
I know how you can blush.
(CHUCKLES)
When did this baby...
begin?
-Oh, you mean...
-Quite.
Well, how would I know?
That's all humany private stuff.
It just sort of goes on.
They don't put up a balloon or anything.
Well, could the child have begun
on the Tardis, in flight, in the vortex?
No! No! Impossible.
It's all running about,
sexy fish vampires
and blowing up stuff.
And Rory wasn't even there
at the beginning. Then he was dead.
Then he didn't exist.
Then he was plastic.
Then I had to reboot the whole universe.
Long story.
So, technically,
the first time they were on the Tardis
together in this version of reality
was on their...
-On their what?
-Hmm?
On their wedding night.
Confirmed.
No life forms registering on this base
except us and the Silurians.
The Headless Monks aren't alive.
They don't register as life forms.
(LOW CHANTING)
It doesn't make sense. You can't
just cook yourself a Time Lord.
Of course not.
(SIGHING)
But you gave them one hell of a start
and they've been working very hard
ever since.
And yet they gave in so easily.
Does this not bother anyone else?
Amy, she worried that the baby
would have a time head, she said that...
Only you would ignore
the instincts of a mother.
Or the instincts of a coward.
This is too easy.
There's something wrong.
Why even do it?
Even if you could get your hands
on a brand new Time Lord, what for?
-A weapon?
-Why would a Time Lord be a weapon?
Well, they've seen you.
Me?
VASTRA: Mr Maldavar, you are right.
This was too easy.
We should get back to the others.
(SOFTLY) Me.
I'd say she's human,
going by the life support software.
She climbed out of the suit.
Like, she forced her way out.
She must be incredibly strong.
KOVARIAN: I see you accessed our files.
Do you understand yet?
Oh, don't worry. I'm a long way away.
But I like to keep tabs on you.
The child, then. What do you think?
-What is she?
-Hope.
Hope in this endless, bitter war.
What war? Against who?
Against you, Doctor.
(CHANTING)
What's that?
(GASPS)
-Force field.
-(THUDDING)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
LORNA: And those are the doors.
Locking.
Apparently we're not leaving.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
-Is that the monks?
-Oh, dear God!
That's the attack prayer.
RORY: Quick, come with me.
VASTRA: Commander Strax.
STRAX: I'm trying to seal off this area
of the lighting grid.
This is where we'll make our stand.
Clear lines of sight on all approaches.
(CHANTING)
Rory, no offence to the others,
but you'll let them all die first, okay?
You're so Scottish.
(LAUGHS)
VASTRA: Centurion, you're needed!
There should be some plasma pistols
somewhere. They left everything.
STRAX: Then find them, boy!
-She's definitely a girl.
-Oh, stop it!
We don't have to fight them.
I'm friends to the monks. They know me.
Yeah, and they know
you just sold them out to the Doctor.
Oh, they'll understand. It's only me.
Only silly old me.
You understand, don't you?
VASTRA: Mr Maldavar, get back here.
-STRAX: Arm yourself, fool.
-Dorium!
(MONKS CHANTING URGENTLY)
(SWORD STABBING, THUD)
VASTRA: Mr Maldavar?
Dorium?
VASTRA: The child.
At all costs, protect the child.
The child is not a weapon!
Oh, give us time. She can be.
She will be.
Except you've already lost her,
and I swear
I will never let you
anywhere near her again.
(LAUGHS) Oh, Doctor,
fooling you once was a joy
but fooling you twice the same way?
It's a privilege.
Amy. Amy!
(GUNFIRE, MELODY CRYING)
(STRAX YELLING)
RIVER:
Demons run when a good man goes to war.
Night will fall and drown the sun
when a good man goes to war.
Friendship dies and true love lies,
night will fall and the dark will rise
when a good man goes to war.
Amy!
RIVER: Demons run but count the cost.
-The battle's won but the child is lost.
-Amy!
Wakey wakey.
Amy!
(GASPS)
(SOFTLY) Rory?
(SCREAMING) Rory! Rory!
(WHIMPERING)
Amy, she's not real.
Melody, she's a flesh avatar.
Amy!
(SOFTLY) Amy?
Yeah, we know.
(STRAX GROANING)
STRAX: It's strange.
I have often dreamed of dying in combat.
I'm not enjoying it
as much as I had hoped.
RORY: Come on, Strax.
-Don't give up.
-It's all right.
I've had a good life.
I'm nearly 12.
Listen to me.
You'll be back on your feet in no time.
You're a warrior.
(SIGHING)
Rory,
I'm a nurse.
(COUGHING WEAKLY)
So they took her anyway.
All this was for nothing.
I am so...
sorry.
Amy, it's not his fault.
I know. I know.
Doctor, there's someone
who wants to speak to you.
He name is Lorna. She came to warn us.
(SIGHING)
Hey. Hello.
Doctor.
You helped my friends.
Thank you.
I met you once.
In the Gamma Forests.
You don't remember me.
Hey, of course I remember.
I remember everyone.
Hey. We ran.
You and me.
Didn't we run, Lorna?
Who was she?
I don't know but she was very brave.
They're always brave.
So, what now?
They'd almost certainly
have taken her to Earth,
raised her in the correct environment.
Yes, they did.
And it's already too late.
You're giving up? You never do that.
Yeah, and don't you sometimes
wish I did?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
RIVER: Well, then, soldier,
how goes the day?
Where the hell have you been?
Every time you have asked,
I have been there.
Where the hell were you today?
-I couldn't have prevented this.
-You could have tried.
And so, my love, could you.
I know you're not all right.
But hold tight, Amy,
because you're going to be.
You think I wanted this?
I didn't do this.
This... This wasn't me!
This was exactly you.
All this. ALI of it.
You make them so afraid.
When you began all those years ago,
sailing off to see the universe,
did you ever think you'd become this?
The man who can turn an army around
at the mention of his name.
Doctor.
The word for "healer" and "wise man"
throughout the universe.
We get that word from you, you know.
But if you carry on the way you are,
what might that word come to mean?
To the people of the Gamma Forests
the word "doctor”
means "mighty warrior".
How far you've come.
And now they've taken a child.
The child of your best friends.
And they're going to turn her
into a weapon just to bring you down.
And all this, my love,
in fear of you.
Who are you?
Oh, look, your cot.
Haven't seen that in a very long while.
No. No, you tell me. You tell me
who you are.
I am telling you.
Can't you read?
Hello.
(LAUGHS)
-(GIGGLING) But that means...
-I'm afraid it does.
Ooh. But you and I, we-we-we, uh...
-Yes.
-(LAUGHS)
Ooh.
How do I look?
Amazing.
-I'd better be.
-Yes, you'd better be.
-Vastra and Jenny, till the next time.
-Doctor.
Rory and Amy,
I know where to find your daughter
and on my life, she will be safe.
River, get them all home.
-Doctor?
-Look, where are you going?
No.
(LAUGHS)
(WHOOSHING)
Where is he going?
What did you tell him?
Amy, you have to stay calm.
Tell me what you told the Doctor.
RORY: Amy, no. Stop it.
It's okay, Rory. She's fine. She's good.
It's the Tardis translation matrix.
It takes a while to kick in
with the written word.
You have to concentrate.
I still can't read it.
It's because it's Gallifreyan
and doesn't translate.
But this will.
It's your daughter's name
in the language of the Forest.
I know my daughter's name.
Except they don't have
a word for "pond”
because the only water in the Forest
is the river.
The Doctor will find your daughter
and he will care for her,
whatever it takes.
And I know that.
It's me.
I'm Melody.
I'm your daughter.