(SNOWFLAKES SNARL)
(CHILDREN LAUGH)
Walter?
Don't you want to go and play
with the other boys and girls?
They're very nice.
I don't need anyone else.
He never talks to anyone.
He's so alone.
It's not right.
It's not healthy.
I don't want to talk to them.
They're silly.
MAN'S VOICE, ECHOING: They're silly.
Don't talk to them. They're silly.
Don't need anyone else.
I can help you.
How?
The last of the arrivals
has been sampled.
The great swarm is approaching.
As humanity celebrates, so shall it end.
Will the final piece be ready?
It's in hand. I serve you in this,
as in everything else.
And do you keep my secrets,
those men who helped us tonight?
It won't be a problem.
I promised to feed them.
Oh, beg pardon, Dr Simeon...
it's been a long day.
I don't see any food here.
I do.
(SNARLING, MEN SCREAM)
What is this?!
I said I'd feed you.
I didn't say who to.
(WIND WHISTLES)
- Did you make this snowman?
- No.
Well, who did?
Cos it wasn't there a second ago.
It just appeared, from nowhere.
Maybe it's snow that fell before.
Maybe it remembers
how to make snowmen.
What, snow that can remember?
- That's silly.
- What's wrong with silly?
Nothing. Still talking to you, ain't I?
What's your name?
Clara.
Nice name...
You should definitely keep it.
Goodbye!
Oi!
Where are you going?
I thought we was just getting
acquainted.
Those were the days.
COACHMAN: H'yah!
(HORSE SNORTS AND WHINNIES)
WOMAN: How refreshing to see you
taking an interest again. Was she nice?
I just spoke to her.
And made your usual impact, no doubt.
No, no impact at all.
Those days are over.
You can't help yourself!
It's the same story every time.
And it always begins
with the same two words.
She'll never be able to find me again.
She doesn't even have the name Doctor.
What two words?
Doctor?
Doctor who?
Good evening, sir.
Pond's frozen over.
Hasn't frozen since the night...
Since the night your children's
governess died, a year ago.
Dr Simeon, sir.
He insisted on waiting.
She drowned in this very pond,
which then froze.
You didn't find her till a month later,
when the ice finally melted.
I recall the incident.
It is the sort of thing one remembers.
Ice remembers too.
Who are you? What do you want here?
The pond is yours, Captain Latimer.
But what is growing inside it,
when it is ready,
is ours. Good evening.
Well, Dr Simeon,
you're out very late tonight.
Almost makes you wonder
what you've been up to.
But then, I have often wondered
about the activities of Dr Simeon and
his exceptionally secretive institute.
Well, I am honoured this evening.
The veiled detective
and her fatuous accomplice.
At your service.
You realise Dr Doyle
is almost certainly basing
his fantastical tales
on your own exploits?
With a few choice alterations,
of course.
I doubt the readers of
The Strand Magazine would accept
that the great detective...
is in reality...
...a woman,
and her suspiciously intimate companion.
I resent your implication
of impropriety!
We are married.
More than can be said for you, eh, dear?
Now, then, this snow is interesting,
don't you think?
The ice crystals seem to have
a low-level telepathic field,
almost as if it can detect and respond
to the thoughts and memories
of the people around it.
Memory snow.
Snow that learns.
How fascinating.
I hope it's listening
to the right people.
It could be a terrible weapon
in the wrong hands, don't you think?
I think winter is coming,
such a winter as this world
has never known.
The last winter of humankind.
Do you know why I'm telling you
all this?
I am intrigued.
Because there's not a single thing
you can do to stop it.
Perhaps 7/ can't,
but I know a man who can.
I look forward to meeting him.
Do you mean the Doctor?
He won't help us.
He never helps any more. You know that.
Yes, my dear, I do,
so pray for a miracle,
because I think we are going
to need him.
They've taken samples from snowmen
all over London.
What do you suppose
they're doing in there?
This snow is new.
Possibly alien.
When you find something brand new
in the world,
something you've never seen before,
what's the next thing you look for?
A grenade?
A profit.
That's Victorian values for you.
I suggest a full-frontal assault
with automated laser monkeys,
scalpel mines and acid.
Why?
Couldn't we at least investigate?
It's none of our business.
Sir, permission to express my opposition
to your current apathy.
Permission granted.
- CLARA: Let me out!
- Sir,
I am opposed to your current apathy.
- Thank you, Strax.
- Let me out!
And if ever I'm in the need of advice
from a psychotic potato dwarf,
you'll certainly be the first to know.
But if the snow is new and alien,
shouldn't we be making
some attempt to destroy it?
Be reasonable!
CLARA: Let me out!
It is not our problem.
Over a thousand years
of saving the universe, Strax,
you know the one thing I learned?
(CLARA'S SHOUTS CONTINUE)
The universe doesn't care.
Oi, Doctor! Let me out!
Now, we have a problem of our own
to worry about...
- Oi!
- Don't worry.
No-one's going to hurt you.
- What is that thing?
- Silence, boy!
That's Strax. And as you can see,
he's easily confused.
Silence, girl. Sorry, lad.
Sontaran. Clone warrior race.
Factory produced,
whole legions at a time. Two genders
is a bit further than he can count.
Sir, do not discuss my reproductive
cycle in front of enemy girls!
It's embarrassing.
(WHISPERS) Typical middle child
of six million.
- Who are you?
- It doesn't matter,
because you're about to forget
that you and I ever met.
- We'll need the worm.
- Sir.
You'll need the what?
The worm? What worm?
Don't worry, it won't hurt you,
but one touch on your bare skin
and you lose the last hour
of your memory.
Where is it?
Where's what, sir?
I sent you to get the memory worm.
Did you?
When? Who's he?
What are we doing here?
Look! It's been snowing!
You didn't use the gauntlets, did you?
Why would I need the gauntlets?
Do you want me to get the memory worm?
Well, can you see it?
I think I can hear it.
(SQUEAKING)
Oi! Don't try to run away.
Stay where you are.
Why would I run? I know what's going
to happen next, and it's funny.
- What's funny?
- Well, your little pal,
for a start. He's an ugly little fella,
isn't he?
Maybe. He gave his life
for a friend of mine once.
Then how come he's alive?
Another friend of mine brought him back.
I'm not sure all his brains
- made the return trip!
- Neither am I.
- I can see it.
- Ooh! Can you reach it?
Have you got it?
Got what, sir?
Because these are the gauntlets,
aren't they?
Sir, emergency!
I think I've been run over by a cab!
There you go. One touch and you lose
about an hour of your memory.
Let it bite you...
and you could lose decades.
And you're still not trying to run.
I don't understand how the snowman built
itself. I'll run once you've explained.
- Clara who?
- Doctor who?
- Oh, dangerous question.
- What's wrong with dangerous?
The snow emits
a low-level telepathic field.
- The snowman!
- Seems to reflect
people's thoughts and memories.
And because it's unusual,
somehow it carries
a previous shape and...
No, Doctor! My snowman!
Ah! Interesting.
Well, were you thinking about it?
Yes.
Well, stop.
Clara, stop thinking about the snowmen!
Get down!
Clara, listen to me.
- The snow's feeding off your thoughts.
- I don't understand.
You're caught in their telepathic field.
They're mirroring you.
The more you think about the snowmen,
the more they appear.
Imagine them melted. Picture it.
Picture them melted!
Well, very good.
Very, very good! Ha!
Is that going to happen again?
Well, if it does,
you know what to do about it.
Unless I forget.
Don't come looking for me.
Forget about me. You understand?
What about the snow?
Shouldn't we be warning people?
Not my problem.
Merry Christmas!
Take her back where we found her.
Sir.
(HE WHISTLES "Silent Night")
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
Come on...
Hello.
Invisible.
(CLATTERING AND FOOTSTEPS)
An invisible staircase.
(WIND WHISTLES)
(SHE GASPS)
(METALLIC SPRINGING)
(ELECTRONIC BURBLING)
(CHIRRUPING BUZZ)
Hello?
Tonight the thaw,
tomorrow the snow will
fall again yet stronger.
The drowned woman and the dreaming child
will give us form
at last.
Tomorrow the snow will fall
and so shall mankind.
She is coming.
(DISTANT CHURCH BELLS CHIME)
Look at that.
Must have thawed in the night.
I'm begging you, Clara.
I'm on my knees.
Elsie's back this afternoon.
And I was only helping out.
- I've got my own work to get back to.
- What work?
Why won't you ever tell us?
You'd never believe me. (BLOWS KISS)
Whoa!
Alice,
how smart you look today.
The governess should enter
by the back door,
unless accompanied by the children.
Hm!
And how are the children?
Excited about tomorrow?
Francesca same as ever.
Digby said he missed you every day.
Captain Latimer wants to see you.
Of course.
Every day?
Twice on Saturdays.
That's better.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Captain Latimer.
Ah!
Miss Montague, you're back.
In time for Christmas.
Apologies for my brief absence.
Family illness is so unpredictable.
You wanted to see me?
Francesca has been having nightmares.
- Young girls often do.
- Every night this week, she says.
Won't tell me about them.
Perhaps if you asked her
in the right way...
There's no-one she'd rather tell.
Children are...not...
really my area of expertise.
They are, however, your children.
You have, if I may say,
a remarkable amount of wisdom
in these matters for one so...
...very pretty, Miss Montague.
Young...
I mean.
I'll see to the children now.
(CHILDREN LAUGH)
Miss Montague!
Miss Montague, you're back!
Ah, ah, ah!
- Good morning, Miss Montague.
Good morning, Francesca.
Good morning, Digby.
Christmas Eve is the most thrilling day,
don't you think?
Now, what have you two been up to
while I've been away?
I did seven drawings.
And we saw a dead cow.
Well, how exciting!
Do your secret voice.
'Ello, mates!
They're not exactly nightmares.
Just dreams.
About our old governess,
the one who died.
She's haunting Frannie
from beyond the grave.
Haven't you spoken
to your father about this?
You can't talk about things like that
to Daddy.
You could try.
Do you want to see where she died?
She fell in there.
And then it froze.
She was in the ice for days and days.
I hated her.
She was cross all the time.
In Frannie's dream, she's still
down there, waiting to come back.
Everything else has thawed,
but this pond...
...Is still frozen.
THE DOCTOR: The snow's feeding off
your thoughts.
The more you think about the snowmen,
the more they appear.
Frannie,
this is important.
You dream about her. What do you dream?
She's cross with me.
She says I've been bad
and she's going to come out of the pond
- and punish me.
- When?
She said she'd come back for Christmas.
Tonight.
I think Frannie's gone mad. Don't you?
I think she needs a doctor.
Doctor!
What's she looking at?!
She's asking for a doctor.
Doctor!
Now, then, that's enough noise!
We don't want to attract attention,
do we?
I'm looking for the Doctor.
Do you know about him? The Doctor?
Doctor who?
Do not attempt to escape
or you will be obliterated.
May I take your coat?
Sit.
There are two refreshments
in your world the colour of red wine.
This...is not
red wine.
Madame Vastra will ask you questions.
You will confine yourself
to single-word responses.
One word only.
Do you understand?
Why?
Truth is singular. Lies are words,
words, words.
- You met the Doctor, didn't you?
- Yes.
And now you've come
looking for him again. Why?
Take your time.
One word only.
Curiosity.
- About?
- Snow.
- And about him?
- Yes.
What do you want from him?
- Help.
- Why?
Danger.
Why would he help you?
Kindness.
The Doctor is not kind.
No?
No. The Doctor doesn't help people.
Not anyone, not ever.
He stands above this world
and doesn't interfere
in the affairs of its inhabitants.
He is not your salvation
nor your protector.
Do you understand
what I am saying to you?
Words.
He was different once...
a long time ago.
Kind, yes.
A hero, even,
a saver of worlds.
But he suffered losses which hurt him.
Now he prefers isolation
to the possibility of pain's return.
Kindly choose a word to indicate
your understanding of this.
Man.
We are the Doctor's friends.
We assist him in his isolation,
but that does not mean we approve of it.
So...
...a test for you.
Give me a message for the Doctor.
Tell him all about the snow
and what fresh danger
you believe it presents,
and above all...
...explain why he should help you.
But do it in one word.
You are thinking it's impossible
such a word exists
or that you could even find it.
Let's see if the gods are with you.
(PHONE RINGS)
Yes?
What? I'm trying to read.
Miss Clara and her concerns
about the snow.
I gave her the one-word test.
It's always pointless. What did she say?
Well?
Well?!
Pond.
Strax has already suggested
where to start investigating.
Danger.
- Danger!
- What's wrong?
There is danger here, an intelligence,
an intelligence beyond anything else
in this time and place.
Dr Simeon, sir, there's someone
demanding to see you.
No callers, not in here, not ever.
- Did he leave his name?
- Sir...
it's Sherlock Holmes!
Oh, yeah! Nice office.
Big globey thing. Now...
shut up, don't tell me.
I see from your collar stud
you have an apple tree
and a wife with a limp. Am I right?
- No.
- But you have a wife?
- Bit of a tree? Bit of a wife?
Some apples?
Come on, work with me here.
1 enjoy The Strand Magazine
as much as the next man,
but I'm perfectly aware that Sherlock
Holmes is a fictional character.
- Get out!
- Do you have a goldfish named Colin?
No.
Thought not.
Now...
Ooh! I see this is
one of your business cards.
It says so on the front.
Who are you,
and what are you doing here?
This.
Wakey, wakey!
That is highly valuable equipment.
You must step away now.
We are the Intelligence.
Oh!
Talking snow. I love new things.
You are not of this world.
Takes one to snow one!
Right, let's see.
Multinucleate crystalline organism
with the ability
to mimic and mirror what it finds.
Looks like snow. Isn't snow.
You must leave here now!
Shut up, I'm making deductions.
It's very exciting.
Now, what are you, eh?
A flock of space crystals?
A swarm?
- (RINGS BELL)
- The snowmen are foot soldiers,
mindless predators.
But you, you're the clever one.
You're Moriarty.
So you turn up on a planet,
you generate a telepathic field
to learn what you can.
- (DOOR LOCKS)
- And when you've learnt enough...
...what do you do?
You can't conquer the world
using snowmen.
Snowmen are rubbish in July.
You'll have to be better than that.
You'll have to evolve.
Sir? It appears to be stuck!
What have you done?
Have you locked the doors?
You need to translate yourself
into something more...
well...
human.
- Kick it down!
- To do that,
you need a perfect duplicate
of human DNA in ice form.
Where do you find...
- that?
- Sir!
Get in here! Quickly!
I've got a master key somewhere, sir.
Now, let's see. Most opened file.
Most viewed page.
You know, you really should
delete your history.
"Governess frozen in pond.”
Gotcha!
Got it, sir!
Get in here!
Take him downstairs.
Body frozen in a pond...
where the snow gets a good, long look
at a human being, like a full body scan.
Everything they need to evolve.
A pond.
Good point, Clara.
What are you doing here?
Madame Vastra wondered
if you were needing any grenades.
Grenades?!
She might have said "help".
Help for what?
Well...your investigation.
Investigation?
Who says I'm investigating?
Do you think I'm going
to start investigating
just because some bird smiles at me?
Who do you think I am?
Sherlock Holmes.
Don't be clever, Strax.
It doesn't suit you.
Sorry, sir.
I'm the clever one,
you're the potato one.
Yes, sir.
Now go away.
Yes...
Mr Holmes.
- Oi!
- (CHUCKLES)
Shut up, you're not clever
or funny
and you've got tiny little legs!
OK, just tell her you're leaving,
you're not going up.
(WHISPERS) I'm leaving,
I'm not going up.
What was that all about? Five minutes?
Where did that come from? You...!
It's the human male from the institute.
What's he doing here?
I suggest we melt his brain
using projectile acid fish
and then interrogate him.
Other way round.
Am I going to have
the nightmare tonight?
Definitely not.
- How do you know?
- Because...
someone's coming to help.
Who?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
Is it one of your stories?
Your definitely true ones?
Huh! ALI my stories are true.
Like how you were born
behind the clock face of Big Ben?
Accounting for my acute sense of time.
And you invented fish.
Because I dislike swimming alone.
So, what's this one?
There's a man called the Doctor.
He lives on a cloud in the sky,
and all he does, all day every day,
is to stop all the children in the world
ever having bad dreams.
I've been having bad dreams.
He's been on holiday.
But I am confident
he has now returned to work.
And as a matter of fact,
he's right here.
Aren't you, Doctor?
(THEY SCREAM)
Bloomin' 'ell!
The children have been very naughty!
Just get back, now, quickly.
You're doing your other voice.
Yes, love, did you notice?
Naughty, naughty children!
Run!
What do we do?
Frannie,
imagine her melting.
- What?!
- In your 'ead! Melt her.
I can't!
I'm getting impatient!
You have been very naughty!
What about the man? You said the man
was here, the cloud man.
- Well, he's not, is he?
- Where's the Doctor?
- I don't know!
- Doctor?
Doctor? (CHUCKLES)
Doctor who?
That's the way to do it!
Oi! Ow!
Where did she go? Will she come back?
No, don't worry. She's currently
draining through your carpet.
New setting, antifreeze.
- And you're very welcome, by the way.
- I'm very grateful.
- I knew you'd come.
- No, you didn't, because I don't.
Because this isn't the sort of thing
I do any more.
Next time you're in trouble,
don't expect me to...
What is it? What's wrong?
Sorry, it's just...
Didn't know I'd put it on.
Old habits...
It's cooler.
Yeah, it is, isn't it? It is very cool.
Bow ties are cool!
No, the room. The room's getting colder.
She's coming back!
What's she going to do?
Is she going to punish me?
Uh...uh...
She's learnt not to melt.
Of course, she's not really a governess,
she's just a beast.
She's going to eat you.
Run.
Children, what is the exp...
Who the devil are you?
- What are you doing in my house?
- It's OK.
I am your governess's
gentleman friend,
and we've just been upstairs...
kissing!
Captain Latimer! In the garden!
There's snowmen!
And they're just growing,
out of nowhere, all by themselves.
Look!
Good evening.
I'm a lizard woman
from the dawn of time.
And this is my wife.
(SCREAMS)
This dwelling is under attack.
Remain calm, human scum!
(SCREAMS)
So...
any questions?
You have a...
- gentleman friend?
- Vastra!
What's happening?
The snow is highly localised
and on this occasion
not naturally occurring.
It's coming out of that cab
parked by the gates.
Sir, one pulver grenade
would blow these snowmen
to smithereens!
They're made of snow, Strax,
they're already smithereens.
See, Clara? Our friends again.
Clara? Who is Clara?
Your current governess is in reality
a former barmaid called Clara.
- That's the way to do it!
- Meanwhile, your previous governess
is now a living ice sculpture
impersonating Mr Punch.
Jenny, what have you got?
Should hold it.
Sir, this room.
One observational window on the line
of attack and one defendable entrance.
Right, everyone in there now.
Move it. You, carry her.
It's nice to see you off your cloud
and engaging again.
I'm not engaging again,
I'm under attack.
You missed this, didn't you?
(GOVERNESS SHOUTS ANGRILY)
Shut up!
Strax, how long have we got?
They're not going to attack. They made
no attempt to conceal their arrival.
An attack force would never
abandon surprise so easily.
And they're clearly
in a defence formation.
Why-aye-aye! Well done, Straxie,
- still got it, buddy!
- Sir, please do not
noogie me during combat prep.
- So there's something here they want.
- The ice woman.
Exactly.
- Why's she so important?
- Because she's a perfect duplication
of human DNA in ice crystal form, the
ultimate fusion of snow and humanity.
To live here, the snow needs to evolve,
and she's the blueprint.
She's what they need to become.
When the snow melted last night,
did the pond?
No.
Living ice that will never melt.
If the snow gets hold
of that creature on the stairs,
it will learn to make more of them.
It will build an army of ice.
And it will be the last day
of humanity on this planet.
(BELL TINKLES)
Stay here.
Oi, I told you to stay in there.
- Oh, I didn't listen.
- You do that a lot.
- It's why you like me.
- Who said I like you?
(CRY OF PAIN)
I think you just did.
- You kissed me.
- You blushed.
And we just...
Shut up.
(CRY OF PAIN)
Release her to us.
You have five minutes.
We need to get her out of here
but keep her away from them.
How?
With this. Do I always
have to state the obvious?
Those creatures outside, what are they?
No danger to you, as long as I get that
thing out of here. You, in there, now.
- What are you doing?
- Between you and me,
I can't wait to find out.
Right, if you look after everyone here,
then I can... Clara!
- Doctor!
- That was stupid!
- You were stupid, too!
- I'm allowed, I'm good at stupid!
That's the way to do it!
- Why does she keep saying that?
- Mirroring. Random mirroring.
- We need to get on the roof.
- This way!
No, no! I do the hand grabbing.
That's my job! That's always me!
Come on, quickly!
- Agh!
- What are you doing?
- My bustle is stuck.
- Your bustle?!
You're going to have to
take those clothes off.
- I didn't mean... I just...
- I know. I understand, I do.
- Good.
- What's the plan?
- Who said I've got a plan?
- Course you've got a plan.
- You took that.
- Maybe I'm an idiot.
You're not, you're clever.
Really clever.
Are you?
If I've got a plan, what is it?
You tell me.
That's the way to do it!
- Is this a test?
- Yes.
- What will it do to us?
- Kill us.
That's the way to do it!
So, come on then. Plan. Do I have one?
Oh, I know what your plan is.
I knew straightaway.
- No, you didn't.
- Course I did.
- Show me!
- Why should I?
Because we'll be dead in under
30 seconds. Do I have a plan?
If we'd been escaping,
we'd be climbing down the building.
If we'd been hiding,
we'd be on the other side of the roof.
But no, we're standing...
- right here.
- So?
So...
- After you.
After you, I'm wearing a dress.
Eyes front, soldier!
My eyes are always front!
Mine aren't.
- Stop it.
- No!
I understand
you're the previous governess. I regret
to inform you the position is taken.
Good night.
So you can move your cloud,
you can control it?
No. No-one can control clouds.
That would be silly.
- The wind, a little bit.
- (METALLIC CLANGING)
- She's following us!
- That's the idea.
Keep her away from the snow.
So, barmaid or governess...
- which is it?
- That thing is after us,
and you want a chat?
Well, we can't chat after
we've been horribly killed, can we?
How did we get up so high so quick?
Clever staircase.
It's taller on the inside.
What am I standing on?
What's this made of?
Super-dense water vapour.
Should keep her trapped for the moment.
So you actually live up here?
On a cloud, in a box?
I have done for a long time now.
Blimey, you really know
how to sulk, don't you?
- I'm not sulking!
- You live in a box!
That's no more a box
than you are a governess.
Oh, spoken like a man!
Y'know, you're the same as all the rest.
Sweet little Clara, works at the
Rose & Crown, ideas above her station!
For your information, I'm not sweet
on the inside, and I'm certainly not...
...little.
It's called the TARDIS.
It can travel anywhere
in time and space.
And it's mine.
But it's...
Look at it, it's...
Go on, say it. Most people do.
It's smaller on the outside.
OK. That is a first.
Is it magic? Is it a machine?
- It's a ship.
- (CHUCKLES) A ship?
Best ship in the universe.
Is there a kitchen?
Another first.
I don't know why I asked that,
it's just...
I like making souffles.
Souffles?!
Why are you showing me all this?
You followed me. Remember?
- I didn't invite you.
- You're nearly a foot taller than I am.
You could've reached the ladder
without this.
You took it for me.
Why?
I never know why.
I only know who.
What's this?
Me.
Giving in.
- I don't know why I'm crying.
- I do.
Remember this.
Remember this right now, all of it,
because this is the day,
this is the day,
this is the day everything begins!
Clara!
- Clara!
- Get off of me!
Water vapour doesn't stop ice.
I should've realised!
- Get off!
- Let her go. Let her go now!
- Now!
- Get off of me!
No!
Clara!
(THUD)
What was that?
It's Clara.
- (BLEEPING)
- Dear God.
Oh, dear God.
Where did she fall from?
We have to get her inside.
- Those things will kill you.
- She's hurt.
She's dead.
- (METALLIC THRUMMING)
- What is that?
What is happening?!
He's bringing her in.
That...green woman said she was dead.
- How can she be alive now?
- This technology
has capacities and abilities
beyond anything
your puny human mind
could possibly understand.
Try not to worry.
Isn't the creature still a danger?
It could re-form.
No, not in here.
Then you should be with Miss Clara.
She's going to be fine. I know she is.
She has to be.
Doctor, her injuries are severe.
That equipment will bring back
anyone for a while, but long term...
It was my fault. I am responsible
for what happened to Clara.
What is the point of blaming yourself?
None.
Because she's going to live.
Hm...
Hey.
Hello.
They all think I'm going to die,
don't they?
And I know you're going to live.
How?
I never know how.
I just know...who.
The green lady...
...she said you were
the saver of worlds once.
Are you going to save this one?
If I do...
...will you come away with me?
Yes.
Well, then...
...merry Christmas.
I have in my hand
a piece of the ice lady...
...everything you need to know
about how to make ice people.
Is that what you want?
See you at the office.
So, then, Doctor,
saving the world again? Might I ask why?
Are you making a bargain
with the universe?
You'll save the world to let her live?
Yes! And don't you think,
after all this time
and everything I have ever done,
that I am owed this one?
I don't think the universe
makes bargains.
- It was my fault.
- Well, then...
...better save the world.
You promised us something.
Have you brought it?
Big fella here's been very quiet
while you've been out,
which is only to be expected,
considering who he really is.
You know what this is, big fella?
I do not understand these markings.
A map of the London Underground, 1967.
Key strategic weakness
in metropolitan living, if you ask me,
but then, I have never liked a tunnel.
Enough of this.
We are powerful, but on this planet,
we are limited.
We need to learn to take human form.
The governess is our most
perfect replication... (VOICE DISTORTS)
- CHILD'S VOICE: ...of humanity...
- What's happening to its voice?
Just stripping away the disguise.
No! Stop!
Stop that.
Cease, I command you!
It sounds like a child.
Of course it sounds like a child,
it ls a child.
Simeon as a child.
The snow has no voice without him.
Don't listen to him.
He's ruining everything!
How long has the Intelligence
been talking to you?
I was a little boy.
He was my snowman.
He spoke to me.
They're silly.
Snow doesn't talk, does it?
It's just a mirror.
I don't want to talk to them.
They're silly.
It just reflects back everything
we think and feel and fear.
I don't need anyone else.
Don't need anyone else.
You poured your darkest dreams
into a snowman. And look!
Look what it became!
I don't understand.
It's a parasite
feeding on the loneliness of a child
and the sickness of an old man.
Carnivorous snow...
meets Victorian values...
...and something terrible is born.
We can go on
and do everything we planned.
Oh, yes, and what a plan.
A world full of living ice people.
Oh, dear me...
how very Victorian of you.
What's wrong with Victorian values?
Ah-ah-ah. Are you sure?
I have always been sure.
Good.
I'm glad you think so...
...since your entire adult life
is about to be erased.
No parasite without a host.
Without you, it will have no voice.
Without the governess,
it will have no form.
What...
What... What's happening?
What's happening? What did you do?
You've got nothing left
to mirror any more.
Goodbye.
What did you... Did you...
(VOICE DISTORTS) Did you...
MAN'S VOICE: Did you really think
it would be so easy?
That's not possible.
How is that possible?
Doctor!
(SNOWMEN ROAR)
They're growing!
The snowmen are growing!
What do we do?
But you were just Dr Simeon.
You're not real.
He dreamed you.
How can you still exist?
Now the dream outlives the dreamer
and can never die.
Once I was the puppet...
...now I pull the strings!
I tried...
so long to take on human form.
By erasing Simeon,
you made space for me.
I fill him now.
More than snow, more than Simeon.
Even this old body...
is strong in my control.
Do you feel it?
Winter is coming!
- (CRIES OUT)
- Winter is coming!
No, you must fight!
Hang on and fight, boy. You can do it!
Captain Latimer...
Mm?
...your children...
...they're afraid.
Hold them.
It's not...really my area.
It is now.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(SCREAMING)
What's happening?
Doctor!
The globe. It's turning to rain.
All of it. The snow. Look.
He's dead.
What happened?
The snow mirrors. That's all it does.
It's mirroring something else now,
something so strong
it's drowning everything else.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
There was a critical mass of snow at the
house. If something happened there...
Salty. Saltwater rain.
It's not raining.
It's crying.
The only force on earth
that could drown the snow,
a whole family crying on Christmas Eve.
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
(SOBBING)
I'm sorry.
There was nothing to be done.
She has moments only.
We saved the world, Clara,
you and me.
We really, really did.
Will you go back...
to your cloud?
No more cloud. Not now.
Why not?
It rained.
Run.
Run, you clever boy.
And remember.
(CLOCK CHIMES)
JENNY: It's Christmas.
Christmas Day.
VASTRA: And what about the Intelligence?
Melted with the snow?
THE DOCTOR: No, I shouldn't think so.
It learned to survive
beyond physical form.
Well, we can't be in much danger
from a disembodied Intelligence
that thinks it can invade the world
with snowmen.
Or that the London Underground
is a key strategic weakness.
The Great Intelligence... Rings a bell.
The Great Intelligence...
Doctor?
I never knew her name,
her full name.
Oswin Oswald, junior entertainment
manager, Starship Alaska.
Souffle girl.
(TIMER PINGS)
Oswin.
It was her.
Run, you clever boy.
And remember.
It was souffle girl again!
I never saw her face the first time
with the Daleks, but her voice,
it was the same voice.
- Doctor?
- The same woman,
twice, and she died both times,
the same woman!
Doctor, please,
what are you talking about?
Something's going on,
something impossible, something...
Right, you two stay here.
Stay right here. Don't move an inch.
- Are you coming back?
- Shouldn't think so!
But where are you going?
To find her. To find Clara.
(HE LAUGHS)
But Clara's dead.
What's he talking about,
- finding her?
- I don't know!
But perhaps the universe
makes bargains after all.
Where are you going?
- Short cut.
- Through there?
I hate this place!
Don't you think it's creepy?
No.
I don't believe in ghosts.
Clara!
Oswin!
Oswald!
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
Watch me run!
Ha-ha! Miss me?
Who the hell are you?
I'm the Doctor.
I'm an alien from outer space.
I'm 1,000 years old. I've got
two hearts. And I can't fly a plane!
You're running away with a spaceman
in a box. Anything could happen to you.
That's what I'm counting on.
Where do you want to go, hey?
What do you want to see?
Is that her?
The woman twice dead.
She's rather pretty, isn't she?
She's not possible.
Right, then, Clara Oswald...
...time to find out who you are.