The Master is Prime Minister
of Great Britain.
And these are my friends.
-They're called the Toclafane.
-What?
-Are you going to tell us who he is?
-He's a Time Lord.
He's cannibalised the Tardis.
It's a paradox machine.
We meet at last, Doctor.
Stop this! Stop it now!
We can't stop him.
Down you go, kids.
Remove one tenth of the population.
I'm coming back.
And the Earth was no more.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
WOMAN: Spacelane traffic is advised
to stay away from SOL 3,
also known as Earth.
Pilots are warned SOL 3
ls now entering terminal extinction.
Planet Earth is closed.
-What's your name, then?
-Tom Milligan.
No need to ask who you are,
the famous Martha Jones.
How long since you were last in Britain?
365 days. It's been a long year.
So what's the plan?
This Professor Docherty,
I need to see her. Can you get me there?
She works in a repair shed, Nuclear
Plant Seven. I can get you inside.
What's this all for?
What's so important about her?
Sorry. The more you know,
the more you're at risk.
There's a lot of people depending
on you. You're a bit of a legend.
And what does the legend say?
That you sailed the Atlantic,
walked across America,
that you were the only person
to get out of Japan alive.
Martha Jones, they say,
she's gonna save the world.
A bit late for that.
How come you can drive?
Don't you get stopped?
Medical staff. Used to be
in paediatrics back in the old days.
But that gives me a licence to travel
so I can help out at the lab our camps.
Great. I'm travelling with a doctor.
Story goes that you're the only person
on Earth who can kill him.
That you and you alone
can kill the Master stone dead.
Let's just drive.
ON PA: Citizens, rejoice!
Your Lord and Master stands on high!
Playing track three.
# I can't decide
# Whether you should live or die
# Oh, you'll probably go to heaven
# Please don't hang your head and cry
# No wonder why
# My heart feels dead inside
# It's cold and hard and petrified
# Lock the doors and close the blinds
# We're going for a ride
# Oh, I could throw you in the lake
# Or feed you poisoned birthday cake
# I won't deny
I'm gonna miss you when you're gone
# Oh, I could bury you alive
# But you might crawl out with a knife
# And kill me when I'm sleeping
That's why
# I can't decide
# Whether you should live or die
# Oh, you'll probably go to heaven
# Please don't hang your head and cry
# I wonder why
# My heart feels dead inside
# It's cold and hard and petrified
# Lock the doors
and close the blinds... #
It's ready to rise, Doctor.
The new Time Lord Empire.
It's good, isn't it? Isn't it, good?
Anything?
No? Anything?
Oh, but they broke your heart,
didn't they, those Toclafane?
Ever since you worked out
what they really are.
They say Martha Jones
has come back home.
Now why would she do that?
Leave her alone.
But you said something to her,
didn't you?
On the day I took control.
-What did you tell her?
-I have one thing to say to you.
-You know what it is.
-Oh, no you don't!
Valiant now entering Zone One airspace.
-Citizens, rejoice!
-Come on, people! What are we doing?
Launch day in 24 hours!
Morning, Tish!
Ah! Smell that sea air!
Makes me long
for good old British fish and chips.
(JACK LAUGHING)
And what do I get? Cold mashed swede.
Some hotel.
Last time I book over the internet.
MARTHA: All over the Earth,
those things.
He's even carved himself
into Mount Rushmore.
Best to keep down.
Here we go.
The entire South Coast of England
converted into shipyards.
They bring in slave lab our
every morning,
break up cars, houses, anything,
just for the metal,
building the fleet out of scrap.
You should see Russia.
That's Shipyard Number One.
All the way from the Black Sea
to the Bering Strait,
there's 100,000 rockets
getting ready for war.
-War? With who?
-The rest of the universe.
I've been out there, Tom, in space,
before all this happened,
and there's 1,000 different
civilisations all around us
with no idea of what's happening here.
The Master can build weapons
big enough to devastate them all.
-You've been in space?
-Problem with that?
No! No, just... Wow.
-Anything else I should know?
-I've met Shakespeare.
(SPHERES WHIRRING)
-SPHERE: Identify, little man.
-I've got a licence!
Thomas Milligan, Peripatetic Medical
Squad. I'm allowed to travel.
-I was just checking for...
-Soon the rockets will fly!
SPHERE 2: And everyone will need
medicine! You'll be so busy!
(SPHERES LAUGHING)
But...they didn't see you.
How do you think I travelled the world?
The Master set up Archangel,
that mobile phone network,
15 satellites around the planet.
But really it's transmitting
this low-level psychic field.
That's how everyone got hypnotised
into thinking he was Harold Saxon.
Saxon! Feels like years ago.
But the key's tuned in
to the same frequency.
Makes me sort of, not invisible,
just unnoticeable.
-Well, I can see you.
-That's 'cause you wanted to.
Yeah, I suppose I did.
-Is there a Mrs Milligan?
-No.
-No. What about you?
-There used to be someone.
Long time ago.
Come on, I've got to find
this Docherty woman.
Well, we'll have to wait
till the next work shift.
-What time is it now?
-It's nearly 3:00.
Time for my massage.
Who shall I have today?
Tanya! Come on, sweetheart.
Lucy, have you met Tanya?
She's gorgeous!
Tanya, when we go to the stars,
I'm going to take you to
the Catrigan Nova. Whirlpools of gold.
You two should get to know each other.
That might be fun.
-What the hell?
-Condition red! Repeat, condition red!
-Oh, I see.
-I told you.
I have one thing to say.
Oh, here we go again.
Isomorphic controls.
Which means they only work for me.
Like this!
-Say sorry!
-Sorry, sorry!
-Mum!
-Sorry!
Didn't you learn anything
from the blessed St Martha?
Siding with the Doctor
is a very dangerous thing to do.
Take them away.
MAN: Move! Come on.
MASTER: Okay, got you.
(GRUNTING)
There you go, gramps.
Oh! Do you know...
I remember the days when the Doctor,
oh, that famous Doctor,
was waging a Time War,
battling Sea Devils and Axons.
He sealed the rift
at the Medusa Cascade single-handed!
And look at him now.
Stealing screwdrivers.
How did he ever come to this?
Oh, yeah! Me!
I just need you to listen.
No, it's my turn.
Revenge! Best served hot!
And this time
it's a message for Miss Jones.
(GRUNTING)
-Professor Docherty?
-Busy.
They sent word ahead. I'm Tom Milligan.
This is Martha Jones.
She can be the Queen of Sheba
for all I care, I'm still busy.
-Televisions don't work any more.
-Oh, God, I miss Countdown.
Never been the same since Des took over.
Both Deses.
What's the plural for Des?
Desii? Deseen?
But we've been told
there's gonna be a transmission.
From the man himself! There!
My people! Salutations.
On this, the eve of war. Lovely woman.
But I know there's
all sorts of whispers down there,
stories of a child walking the Earth,
giving you hope.
But I ask you,
how much hope has this man got?
Say hello, Gandalf!
Except he's not that old,
but he's an alien
with a much greater lifespan
than you stunted little apes.
What if it showed?
What if I suspend
your capacity to regenerate?
All 900 years of your life, Doctor,
what if we could see them?
Older and older and older.
Down you go, Doctor!
Down, down.
Down the years.
Doctor?
Received and understood, Miss Jones?
I'm sorry.
The Doctor's still alive.
Obviously, the Archangel network
would seem to be
the Master's greatest weakness.
15 satellites all around the Earth
still transmitting.
That's why there's so little resistance.
It's broadcasting a telepathic signal
that keeps people scared.
We could just take them out.
We could. 15 ground-to-air missiles.
You got any on you?
Besides, any military action,
the Toclafane descend.
They're not called Toclafane.
That's a name the Master made up.
What are they, then?
Well, that's why I came to find you.
Know your enemy.
I've got this.
No one's been able to look at a sphere
close up. They can't even be damaged.
Except once. A lightning strike in
South Africa brought one of them down.
Just by chance.
I've got the readings on this.
Oh!
Whoever thought we'd miss Bill Gates?
So is that why you travelled the world?
To find a disc?
No, just got lucky.
I heard stories
that you walked the Earth
to find a way to build a weapon.
There!
"A current of 58.5 kiloamperes
"transfer a charge
of 510 megajoules precisely.”
-Can you recreate that?
-I think so. Easily, yes.
Right then, Dr Milligan.
We're gonna get us a sphere.
-He's coming! You ready?
-You do your job, I'll do mine!
Now!
(BUZZING)
That's only half the job.
Let's find out what's inside.
FRANCINE: I'm going kill him
if I have to wait 100 years.
I'm going to kill the Master.
One day, he'll let his guard down.
One day. And I'll be there.
No, that's my job.
I swear to you,
I'd shoot that man stone dead.
I'll get him, even if it kills me.
-Don't say that.
-I mean it.
That man made us stand on deck
and watch the islands of Japan burning.
Millions of people.
I swear to you, he's dead.
Tomorrow they launch.
We're opening up a rift
in the Braccatolian space.
-Won't see us coming. Kind of scary.
-Then stop.
Once the empire is established
and there's a new Gallifrey
in the heavens, maybe then it stops.
The drumming.
The never-ending drumbeat.
Ever since I was a child,
I looked into the Vortex.
That's when it chose me.
The drumming, the call to war.
Can't you hear it?
Listen, it's there now, right now.
Tell me you can hear it, Doctor.
-Tell me.
-It's only you.
Good.
SPHERE: Tomorrow, the war!
Tomorrow we rise, never to fall!
You see? I'm doing it for them.
You should be grateful.
After all, you love them.
So very, very much.
There's some sort of magnetic clamp.
Hold on, I'll just trip the...
Oh, my God!
It's alive!
Martha. Martha Jones.
It knows you.
Sweet, kind Martha Jones.
You helped us to fly.
-What do you mean?
-You led us to salvation.
-Who are you?
-The skies are made of diamonds.
No.
You can't be him.
The skies are made of diamonds.
We share each other's memories.
You sent him to Utopia.
Oh, my God!
What's it talking about? What's it mean?
-What are they?
-Martha. Martha, tell us. What are they?
They're us. They're humans.
The human race from the future.
I took Lucy to Utopia.
A Time Lord and his human companion.
I took her to see the stars.
Isn't that right, sweetheart?
Trillions of years into the future.
To the end of the universe.
-Tell him what you saw.
-Dying. Everything dying.
The whole of creation was falling apart.
And I thought, "There's no point.
-"No point to anything. Not ever."
-And it's all your fault.
I'd sort of worked it out,
with the paradox machine,
because the Doctor said,
on the day before
the Master came to power, he said...
When he was stealing the Tardis,
the only thing I could do
was fuse the coordinates.
I locked them permanently.
He could only travel
between the year 100 trillion
and the last place the Tardis landed.
Which is right here, right now.
The Master had the Tardis,
this time machine.
But the only other place he could go
was the end of the universe,
so he found Utopia.
You should have seen it, Doctor.
Furnaces. Burning.
The last of humanity
screaming at the dark.
The Utopia project was the last hope.
Trying to find a way
to escape the end of everything.
There was no solution. No diamonds.
Just the dark and the cold.
All that human invention that had
sustained them across the aeons,
it all turned inward.
They cannibalised themselves.
SPHERE: We made ourselves so pretty.
Regressing into children,
but it didn't work.
MASTER: The universe
was collapsing around them.
But then the Master came
with his wonderful time machine,
to bring us back home.
But that's a paradox.
If you're the future of the human race,
and you've come back
to murder your ancestors,
you should cancel yourselves out.
You shouldn't exist.
And that's the paradox machine.
(LAUGHING)
My masterpiece, Doctor.
A living Tardis, strong enough
to hold the paradox in place.
Allowing the past and the future
to collide in infinite majesty.
But you're changing history.
Not just Earth, the entire universe.
I'm a Time Lord. I have that right.
But even then...
why come all this way just to destroy?
We come backwards in time
all to build a brand-new empire
lasting 100 trillion years!
With me as their Master.
Time Lord and humans combined.
Haven't you always
dreamt of that, Doctor?
What about us? We're the same species.
-Why do you kill so many of us?
-Because it's fun.
(LAUGHING)
Human race.
Greatest monsters of them all.
Night, then.
I think it's time
we had the truth, Miss Jones.
Legend says you travelled the world
to find a way of killing the Master.
Tell us, is it true?
Just before I escaped,
the Doctor told me...
The Doctor and the Master,
they've been coming to Earth for years.
And they've been watched.
There's UNIT and Torchwood,
all studying Time Lords in secret.
And they made this,
the ultimate defence.
All you need is to get close,
I can shoot the Master dead with this.
Actually, you can put that down now,
thank you very much.
Point is, it's not so easy
to kill a Time Lord.
They can regenerate,
literally bring themselves back to life.
-Ah, the Master's immortal! Wonderful!
-Except for this.
Four chemicals slotted into the gun.
Inject him,
kills a Time Lord permanently.
-Four chemicals, you've only got three.
-Still need the last one.
'Cause the components of this gun
were kept safe,
scattered across the world,
and I found them.
San Diego, Beijing, Budapest and London.
Then where is it?
There's an old UNIT base
in North London.
I've found the access codes.
Tom, you've got to get me there.
We can't get across London in the dark.
It's full of wild dogs,
we'll get eaten alive.
We can wait till the morning
then go with the medical convoy.
You can spend the night here,
if you like.
No, we can get halfway,
stay at the slave quarters in Bexley.
-Professor, thank you.
-Oh, and you. Good luck.
Thanks.
Martha. Could you do it?
-Could you actually kill him?
-Got no choice.
You might be many things,
but you don't look like a killer to me.
Let me in, it's Milligan.
-Did you bring food?
-Couldn't get any. And I'm starving.
WOMAN: All we've got is water.
-MARTHA: Sorry.
-It's cheaper than building barracks.
Pack them in, 100 in each house,
ferry them off
to the shipyards every morning.
-Are you Martha Jones?
-Yeah, that's me.
Can you kill him? They said
you can kill the Master. Can you?
Tell us you can do it.
Please, tell us you can do it.
WOMAN: Who is the Master?
(ALL CHATTERING)
Come on, just leave her alone.
She's exhausted.
No, it's all right.
They want me to talk and I will.
Access Priority One.
This is Professor Alison Docherty.
State your intent.
First of all,
I need to know about my son.
State your intent.
Is my son still alive?
I have some information for the Master.
Concerning Martha Jones.
Guess what?
I travelled across the world.
From the ruins of New York
to the Fusion Mills of China,
right across
the Radiation Pits of Europe.
And everywhere I went I saw people
just like you, living as slaves.
But if Martha Jones became a legend,
then that's wrong,
because my name isn't important.
There's someone else.
The man who sent me out there.
The man who told me to walk the Earth.
And his name is the Doctor.
He has saved your lives so many times
and you never even knew he was there.
He never stops, he never stays,
he never asks to be thanked.
But I've seen him. I know him.
I love him.
And I know what he can do.
It's him! It's him! My God, it's him!
It's the Master! He's here!
But he never comes to Earth!
He never walks upon the ground.
Hide her!
He walks among us, our Lord and Master.
Martha! Martha Jones! I can see you.
Out you come, little girl.
Come and meet your Master.
Anybody? Nobody? No? Nothing?
Positions!
(GUNS COCKING)
I'll give the order
unless you surrender.
Ask yourself,
"What would the Doctor do?"
Oh, yes! Oh, very well done! Good girl!
He trained you well.
Bag. Give me the bag.
No, stay there, just throw it.
And now, good companion,
your work is done.
No!
But you, when you die,
the Doctor should be witness, hmm?
(INHALING)
Almost dawn, Martha,
and planet Earth marches to war.
ON PA: Citizens of Earth,
rejoice and observe.
Your teleport device,
in case you thought I'd forgotten.
And now
kneel.
Down below,
the fleet is ready to launch.
200,000 ships set
to burn across the universe.
Are we ready?
MAN: The fleet awaits your signal,
rejoice!
Three minutes
to align the Black Hole Convertors.
Counting down!
I never could resist a ticking clock.
My children, are you ready?
ALL: We will fly and blaze and slice!
We will fly and blaze and slice!
At zero, to mark this day,
the child, Martha Jones, will die.
My first blood.
Any last words? No?
Such a disappointment, this one.
Days of old, Doctor,
you had companions
who could absorb the Time Vortex!
This one's useless! Bow your head.
And so it falls to me, as Master of all,
to establish from this day
a new order of Time Lords.
From this day forward...
(LAUGHING SOFTLY)
What? What's so funny?
-A gun?
-What about it?
-A gun in four parts?
-Yes, and I destroyed it.
A gun, in four parts,
scattered across the world?
I mean, come on!
Did you really believe that?
-What do you mean?
-As if I would ask her to kill.
Oh, well, it doesn't matter.
I've got her exactly where I want her.
But I knew
what Professor Docherty would do.
The Resistance knew about her son.
That's why I came to find you.
Know your enemy.
I told her about the gun
so she'd get me here.
-At the right time.
-But you're still gonna die.
Don't you want to know what I was doing,
travelling the world?
-Tell me.
-I told a story. That's all.
No weapons, just words.
I did just what the Doctor said.
I went across the continents
all on my own.
And everywhere I went I found the people
and I told them my story.
He has saved your lives so many times
and you never even knew he was there.
I know him.
I told them about the Doctor.
I love him.
And I told them to pass it on.
To spread the word so that
everyone would know about the Doctor.
-Faith and hope? Is that all?
-No, 'cause I gave them an instruction.
Just as the Doctor said.
Use the countdown.
I told them that if everyone thinks
of one word, at one specific time...
Nothing will happen!
Is that your weapon?
-Prayer?
-Right across the world.
One word, just one thought,
at one moment,
but with 15 satellites.
-What?
-The Archangel network.
A telepathic field
binding the whole human race together.
With all of them,
every single person on Earth,
thinking the same thing
at the same time.
And that word is "Doctor".
Stop it. No, no, no, no, you don't.
-Doctor.
Don't...
-ALL: Doctor!
-Doctor!
CLIVE: Doctor.
ALL: Doctor! Doctor!
Stop this right now! Stop it!
-Doctor.
-All: (CHANTING) Doctor!
I've had a whole year
to tune myself into the psychic network
and integrate with its matrices.
I order you to stop!
ALL: (CHANTING) Doctor!
Doctor.
The one thing you can't do
is stop them thinking.
Tell me the human race
is degenerate now,
when they can do this.
No!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Then I'll kill them!
You can't do this! You can't do...
It's not fair!
-And you know what happens now.
-No!
No!
No! No!
-You wouldn't listen.
-No!
-Because you know what I'm going to say.
-No.
I forgive you.
My children!
ALL: Protect the paradox!
Protect the paradox!
-Captain, the paradox machine!
-You men, with me!
You stay here.
No!
Now it ends, Doctor!
Now it ends!
(ALARMS BLARING)
We've all six billion spheres
heading right for us!
We've got control of the Valiant.
You can't launch.
Oh, but I've got this.
Black Hole Convertor inside every ship.
If I can't have this world, Doctor,
then neither can you.
We shall stand upon this Earth
together as it burns!
-Can't get in, we'd get slaughtered.
-Yeah, happens to me a lot.
Weapon after weapon after weapon.
All you do is talk and talk and talk.
But over all these years,
and all these disasters, I've always had
the greatest secret of them all.
I know you.
Explode those ships, you kill yourself.
That's the one thing you can never do.
Give that to me.
Everyone, get down! Time is reversing.
(ALL SCREAMING)
The paradox is broken.
We've reverted back.
One year and one day,
two minutes past eight in the morning.
MAN ON RADIO: This is UNIT Central,
what's happened up there?
-We just saw the President assassinated.
-See.
Just after the President was killed,
but just before the spheres arrived.
Everything back to normal,
planet Earth restored.
None of it happened.
The rockets, the terror, it never was.
-What about the spheres?
-Trapped at the end of the universe.
But I can remember it.
We're at the eye of the storm,
the only ones who'll ever know.
Oh, hello! You must be Mr Jones!
We haven't actually met.
Whoa, big fella!
You don't want to miss the party. Cuffs.
-So, what do we do with this one?
-We kill him.
-We execute him.
-DOCTOR: No, that's not the solution.
Oh, I think so.
'Cause all those things,
they still happened.
Because of him.
-I saw them.
-Go on!
Do it.
Francine, you're better than him.
You still haven't answered the question.
What happens to me?
You're my responsibility from now on.
The only Time Lord left in existence.
-Yeah, but you can't trust him.
-No.
The only safe place for him
is the Tardis.
You mean you're just gonna keep me?
Mmm. If that's what I have to do.
It's time to change.
Maybe I've been wandering for too long.
Now I've got someone to care for.
(GUNSHOT)
JACK: Put it down.
There you go.
I've got you, I've got you.
-Always the women.
-I didn't see her.
Dying in your arms. Happy now?
You're not dying, don't be stupid.
It's only a bullet, just regenerate.
-No.
-One little bullet, come on.
I guess you don't know me so well.
I refuse.
Regenerate, just regenerate, please.
Please, just regenerate, come on!
And spend the rest of my life
imprisoned with you?
But you've got to.
Come on, it can't end like this.
You and me. All the things we've done.
Axons! Remember the Axons,
and the Daleks.
We're the only two left.
There's no one else.
Regenerate!
How about that?
I win.
(GROANING)
Will it stop, Doctor?
The drumming? Will it stop?
(DOCTOR YELLING)
Just to say I don't blame you.
But who are you?
Time was every single one
of these people knew your name.
-Now they've all forgotten you.
-Good.
-Back to work.
-I really don't mind, though.
Come with me.
Had plenty of time to think
that past year.
The year that never was.
And I kept thinking
about that team of mine.
Like you said, Doctor. Responsibility.
Defending the Earth.
Can't argue with that.
Hey, I need that!
I can't have you walking round
with a time-travelling teleport.
You could go anywhere. Twice.
Second time to apologise.
And what about me? Can you fix that?
Will I ever be able to die?
Nothing I can do.
You're an impossible thing, Jack.
Been called that before.
Sir.
Ma'am.
But I keep wondering, what about ageing?
'Cause I can't die,
but I keep getting older,
the odd little grey hair, you know.
What happens
if I live for a million years?
I really don't know.
Okay, vanity, sorry. Yeah.
Can't help it. Used to be a poster boy!
When I was a kid,
living in the Boeshane Peninsula,
tiny little place.
I was the first one ever
to be signed up for the Time Agency.
They were so proud of me.
The Face of Boe they called me.
I'll see you.
No.
Can't be.
No. Definitely not. No.
No!
Yeah, could you put me through?
Hi, I'm looking for
a Dr Thomas Milligan.
Yeah? Hello?
Hello?
Right then! Off we go. The open road!
There is a burst of star fire right now
over the coast of Meta Sigmafolio.
Oh, the sky is like oil on water.
Fancy a look? Or back in time.
We could...
I don't know, Charles II? Henry VIII?
I know, what about Agatha Christie!
I'd love to meet Agatha Christie,
bet she's brilliant!
Okay.
-I just can't.
-Yeah.
I've spent all these years
training to be a doctor,
and now I've got people to look after.
They saw half the planet slaughtered
and they're devastated.
-I can't leave them.
-Course not.
Thank you.
-Martha Jones, you saved the world.
-Yes, I did.
I spent a lot of time with you
thinking I was second best,
but you know what?
I am good.
-You going to be all right?
-Always, yeah.
Right, then.
Bye.
'Cause the thing is,
it's like my friend Vicky.
She lived with this bloke,
student housing,
there were five of them, all packed in,
and this bloke was called Shaun.
And she loved him, she did,
she completely adored him,
spent all day long talking about him...
-Is this going anywhere?
-Yes.
'Cause he never looked at her twice.
I mean, he liked her, that was it.
And she wasted years pining after him,
years of her life,
'cause while he was around,
she never looked at anyone else.
And I told her, I always said to her,
time and time again, I said,
"Get out."”
So this is me...getting out.
Keep that.
'Cause I'm not having you disappear!
If that rings, when that rings,
you'd better come running, got it?
Got it.
I'll see you again, mister.
(DISTANT LAUGHTER)
(HORN BLARING)
What?
(BELL RINGING)