(WHOOSHING)
MAN: Mistletoe! Mistletoe!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Come on!
Go on, then.
Warm chestnuts. Chestnuts.
# 0 tidings of comfort and joy
# Comfort and joy
O tidings... #
-You there, boy, what day is this?
-Christmas Eve, sir!
-In what year?
-Are you thick or something?
Oi! Just answer the question!
Year of our Lord, 1851, sir.
Right. Nice year. A bit dull.
WOMAN: Doctor!
Doctor!
Who, me?
Don't worry! Don't worry! Stand back.
What have we got here?
(GROWLING)
Okay, I've got it.
And whatever's behind that door.
-I think you should get out of here.
-Doctor!
No, no, I'm standing right here. Hello.
Don't be so stupid. Who are you?
-I'm the Doctor.
-Doctor who?
-Just the Doctor.
-Well, there can't be two of you!
-Where the hell have you been?
-Right then, don't worry! Stand back.
-What have we got here, then?
-Hold on, who are you?
I'm the Doctor. Simply the Doctor.
The one, the only and the best.
Rosita, give me the sonic screwdriver!
-The what?
-Now, quickly, get back to the Tardis!
-Back to the what?
-If you could stand back, sir,
this is a job for a Time Lord!
Job for a what lord?
-Ooh, that's different!
-Oh, that's new!
BOTH: Allons-y!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
I've been hunting this beast
for a good fortnight.
Now, step back, sir! Oh!
Some sort of primitive conversion,
like they took the brain of a cat
-or a dog.
-Well, talking's all very well. Rosita!
-I'm ready.
-Now, watch and learn.
Excellent! Now then, let's pull
this timorous beastie down to Earth.
(NEXT DOCTOR YELLING)
Or not.
Uh, I might be in a little bit
of trouble.
Nothing changes. I've got you!
(DOCTOR YELLING)
(NEXT DOCTOR YELLING)
You idiots!
Perhaps if you could pull...
I am pulling! In this position,
I couldn't not pull, could I?
Then I suggest you let go, sir!
I'm not letting you out of my sight,
Doctor! Don't you recognise me?
No, should I? Have we met?
This is hardly the right time for me
to go through my social calendar...
Whoa!
(NEXT DOCTOR YELLING)
DOCTOR: Get it!
Get it!
-It's gonna jump!
-We're gonna fall!
(BOTH GROANING)
(LAUGHING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Well, I'm glad you think it's so funny!
You're mad! Both of you!
You could've got killed.
But evidently, we did not.
Oh, I should introduce Rosita,
my faithful companion.
-Always telling me off.
-Well, they do, don't they? Rosita.
Good name. Hello, Rosita.
(SCOFFING)
Now I'll have to go and dismantle
the traps! All of that for nothing!
And we've only got 20 minutes
till the funeral, don't forget.
ROSITA: Then back to the Tardis, right?
-Funeral?
-Oh, long story. Not my own, not yet.
(GROANING)
I'm not as young as I was.
Well, not as young as you were
when you were me.
When I was who?
-You really don't recognise me?
-Not at all.
But you're the Doctor. The next Doctor.
Or the next-but-one.
A future Doctor anyway.
-Oh.
-No, no, don't tell me how it happened.
Although I hope I don't just trip
over a brick.
That'd be embarrassing.
Then again, painless. Worse ways to go.
Depends on the brick.
You're gabbling, sir. Now, might I ask,
who are you exactly?
No, I'm, uh, I'm just... Smith.
John Smith.
But I've heard all about you, Doctor.
Bit of a legend if I say so myself.
Modesty forbids me to agree
with you, sir. But yes. Yes, I am.
A legend with certain memories missing.
Am I right?
How do you know that?
You've forgotten me.
Great swathes of my life have been
stolen away. When I turn my mind
to the past...there's nothing.
-Going how far back?
-Since the Cybermen.
Masters of that hellish wall-scuttler,
and old enemies of mine,
now at work in London Town.
You won't believe this, Mr Smith, but
they are creatures from another world.
Really? Wow.
It is said they fell onto London.
Out of the sky in a blaze of light.
And they found me.
Something was taken.
And something was lost.
What was I like?
In the past?
Well, I don't think I should say. Sorry.
Got to be careful with memory loss.
One wrong word...
It's strange, though.
I talk of Cybermen from the stars
and you don't blink, Mr Smith.
Ah, don't blink, remember that?
Whatever you do, don't blink.
The blinking and the statues
with Sally and the angels. No?
You're a very odd man.
Mmm, I still am.
Something's wrong here.
Oh, the funeral! The funeral's at 2:00!
It's been a pleasure, Mr Smith.
-Don't breathe a word of it.
-Oh, can't I come with you?
Oh, it's far too dangerous! Rest
assured, I shall keep this city safe.
Oh, and, uh, merry Christmas, Mr Smith.
Merry Christmas, Doctor.
(MECHANICAL FOOTSTEPS)
Report.
Cybershade 16 has made contact.
Then observe the enemy.
This man is dangerous.
This man is our enemy.
This man is the Doctor.
I've been hunting this beast
for a good fortnight.
NEXT DOCTOR: Now, step back, sir!
The attack is scheduled
for 1400 hours. Plans for the Ascension
demand a successful intervention.
Is everything in position?
That's rather dependent on you.
Alll can promise is to do my best.
Define the parameters of "best".
As you would say, I will operate
at maximum efficiency.
And you'll keep your part
of the bargain?
You will be heralded in the new age
at the court of the CyberKing.
QYBERMEN: The CyberKing will rise.
The CyberKing will rise...indeed.
How like a man.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a funeral to attend.
(BELL TOLLING)
The late Reverend Fairchild
leaving his place of residence
for the last time.
NEXT DOCTOR: God rest his soul.
Now, with the house empty,
I shall effect an entrance at the rear,
while you go back to the Tardis.
This is hardly work for a woman.
Don't mind me saving your life!
That's work for a woman, isn't it?
The Doctor's companion does what
the Doctor says. Off you go.
-Hello.
-But...how did you get in?
Oh, front door. I'm good at doors.
Um, do you mind my asking?
-Is that your sonic screwdriver?
-Yes.
I'd be lost without it.
But that's a screwdriver.
How is it sonic?
Well, uh, it makes a noise.
That's sonic, isn't it? Now,
since we're acting like common burglars,
I suggest we get out of plain view.
This investigation of yours,
what's it all about?
-It started with a murder.
-Oh, good.
I mean, bad. But whose?
Mr Jackson Lake. A teacher
of mathematics from Sussex.
He came to London three weeks ago,
and died a terrible death.
Cybermen?
It's hard to say. His body was
never found. But then it started.
More secret murders. Then abductions.
Children...stolen away in silence.
So, whose house is this?
The latest murder.
The Reverend Aubrey Fairchild.
Found with burns to his forehead, like
some advanced form of electrocution.
But who was he? Was he important?
You ask a lot of questions.
I'm your companion!
The Reverend was the pillar
of the community.
A member of many parish boards.
A keen advocate of children's charities.
Children again.
But why would the Cybermen
want him dead?
And what's his connection
to the first death, this Jackson Lake?
It's funny.
I seem to be telling you everything
as though you engendered
some sort of...trust.
You seem familiar, Mr Smith.
I know your face.
But how?
I wonder. I can't help noticing
you're wearing a fob watch.
Is that important?
Legend has it that the memories
of a Time Lord can be contained
within a watch.
Do you mind?
(WHISPERING VOICES)
It's said that if it's opened...
Oh. Maybe not.
-It's more for decoration.
-Yeah, anyway. Alien infiltration.
Yes, just look for anything different,
possibly metal.
Anything that doesn't seem to belong.
Perhaps a mechanical device
that could fit no earthly engine.
Could even seem to be organic,
but unlike any organism
of the natural world.
Shh!
What's that noise?
Oh, it's just me. Whistling.
I wonder what's in here, though.
Ah.
Different and metal. You were right.
They are info stamps.
I mean, at a guess. Uh, if I were you,
I'd say they worked something like this.
See? Compressed information. Tons of it.
That is the history of London,
1066 to the present day.
This thing's like a disc, a cyberdisc.
But why would the Cybermen
need something so simple?
They've gotta be wireless.
Unless they're in the wrong century.
They haven't got much power.
They need plain, old, basic info stamps
to update themselves.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
No, what is it? What's wrong?
I've seen one of these before.
I was holding this device
the night I lost my mind.
The night I regenerated.
The Cybermen, they made me change.
My mind. My face. My whole self.
And you were there.
Who are you?
A friend.
I swear.
Then I beg you, John, help me.
Ah.
Two words I never refuse.
But it's not a conversation
for a dead man's house.
It'll make more sense
if we go back to the Tardis.
Your, uh, Tardis. Hold on, I just need
to do a little final check.
Won't take a tick, 'cause there's
one more thing I can't help thinking.
If this room's got info stamps,
then maybe, just maybe,
it's got something
that needs infostamping.
Okay.
I think we should run.
Run, Doctor. Now, Doctor!
Delete.
The Doctor will be deleted.
Stairs! Can't lead him outside!
Delete.
I'm a dab hand with a cutlass.
You don't want to come near me
when I've got one of these.
This is your last warning.
No? Okay, this is really
your last warning! Okay, I give up.
-Delete.
-Listen to me properly!
Whatever you're doing, stuck in 1851,
I can help! I mean it!
I'm the only person in the world
who can help you!
-Listen to me!
-Delete.
I'm the Doctor! You need me!
Check your memory banks.
My name is the Doctor!
Leave this man alone!
The Doctor is me!
Delete.
The Doctor, remember?
I'm the Doctor! You need me alive.
You need the Doctor, and that's me!
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
Delete.
Infostamp with a cyclo-Steinham core.
You ripped open the core
and broke the safety. Zap!
(CHUCKLING)
Only the Doctor would think of that.
I did that.
Last time.
Come here. You'll be okay.
Let me just check.
You told them you were the Doctor.
Why did you do that?
Oh, I was just protecting you.
You're trying to take away
the only thing I've got. Like they did.
They stole something.
Something so precious.
But I can't remember.
What happened to me? What did they do?
We'll find out. You and me, together.
VICAR: Forasmuch as it hath pleased
Almighty God of his great mercy,
to take unto Himself the soul
of our dear brother here departed,
we therefore commit his body
to the ground.
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes
and dust to dust,
in sure and certain hope
of the Resurrection to eternal life
through our Lord Jesus Christ,
who shall change our vile body
that it may be like
unto his glorious body,
according to the mighty working...
Do continue.
Madam, I must protest!
Whatever for?
A lady at the graveside is
debatable enough,
but your apparel!
Is it too exciting?
You're disgracing the ceremony!
Dressed like a harlot!
-Oh, and you should know, Mr Cole.
-How do you know my name?
You've walked past me so many times,
all you good men of charity.
Never once asking my name.
It's Miss Hartigan, isn't it?
Oh, you noticed. I saw you looking,
you cheeky boy.
-I'm sorry, but who is she?
-Matron of the St Joseph Workhouse.
Your humble servant.
Oh, I've watched you all visiting.
Smiling. Bestowing your beneficence
upon the poor,
while I scrubbed down their filthy beds.
I must insist that you depart.
But that's why the late
Reverend Fairchild had to die.
To gather you all in one place.
Where better than a funeral?
Man that is born of woman hath
but a short time to live.
Although I've got some friends
who might disagree with that.
Would you like to meet them?
Hark! I can hear them now.
(MECHANICAL FOOTSTEPS)
(MEN MUTTERING)
Mr Cole, Mr Scoones, Mr Fetch,
Mr Milligan, stay where you are.
You're needed.
The rest of you are disposable. Sorry.
What manner of men are they?
Cybermen.
(GROWLING)
-Save yourselves!
-Quickly! Get away from me!
(ALL YELLING)
I repeat, Mr Cole, Mr Scoones, Mr Fetch,
Mr Milligan, stay!
You monstrous witch!
Merry Christmas to you, too.
But why are we spared?
What do you need us for?
Your children.
It's funny, now I think of it,
but in all these years, not one of you
has asked my first name.
It's Mercy.
Doctor!
-I thought you were dead!
-Oh!
Now then, Rosita. A little decorum.
You've been gone for so long.
He's always doing this.
Leaving me behind. Going frantic.
-What about the Tardis?
-Oh, she's ready. Come on.
I'm looking forward to this.
You were right, though, Rosita.
The Reverend Fairchild's death
was the work of the Cybermen.
So, you live here?
A temporary base
until we rout the enemy.
The Tardis is magnificent,
but it's hardly a home.
And where's the Tardis now?
In the yard.
Um, what's all this luggage?
Evidence. The property of Jackson Lake,
the first man to be murdered.
Oh, but my new friend is a fighter,
Rosita, much like myself.
He faced the Cybermen with a cutlass.
I'm not ashamed to say
he was braver than I.
He was quite brilliant.
Are you whistling again?
Yes. Yes, I am. Yeah. Yeah.
-That's another man's property.
-Well, a dead man's.
How did you two meet, then?
He saved my life.
Late one night by the Osterman's Wharf,
this creature came out of the shadows.
A man made of metal.
I thought I was going to die. And then
there he was.
The Doctor.
Can you help him, sir?
He has such terrible dreams.
Wakes at night
in such a state of terror.
Come now, Rosita.
With all the things a Time Lord
has seen,
everything he's lost,
he may surely have bad dreams.
Yeah.
Oh, now, look.
Jackson Lake had an info stamp.
But how? Is that significant?
Doctor, the answer to all this is
in your Tardis. Could I see it?
Mr Smith, it would be my honour.
There she is.
My transport through time and space.
NEXT DOCTOR: The Tardis!
You've got a balloon.
Tardis. T-A-R-D-I-S.
It stands for Tethered Aerial Release
Developed in Style. Do you see?
Well, I do now.
I like it. Good Tardis!
Brilliant. Nice one.
And it's inflated by gas, yeah?
We're adjacent
to the Mutton Street Gasworks.
I pay them a modest fee. Good work, Jed!
Glad to be of service, sir.
You've got quite a bit of money.
Oh, you get nothing for nothing.
-How's that ripped panel, Jed?
-All repaired. Should work a treat.
Never know, maybe tonight's
the night, Doctor.
Imagine it, seeing Christmas from above.
Not just yet, I think.
One day I will ascend. One day soon.
You've never actually been up?
He dreams of leaving, but never does.
I can depart in the Tardis
once London is safe.
And finally, when I'm up there...
Think of it, John.
The time and the space.
The perfect escape.
Do you ever wonder
what you're escaping from?
With every moment.
Then do you want me to tell you?
'Cause I think I've worked it out now.
How you became the Doctor.
What do you think?
Do you want to know?
Mr Cole, Mr Scoones, Mr Fetch
and Mr Milligan,
you have your instructions and
the court of the CyberKing is waiting.
But first of all, let's just see.
A little test.
Turn right.
Turn left.
And face me.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I could do this forever.
But now, set about your appointed tasks.
And bring them to me.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
The story begins with the Cybermen.
A long time away,
and not so far from here,
the Cybermen were fought,
and they were beaten,
and they were sent into
a howling wilderness called the Void,
locked inside for evermore.
But then a greater battle rose up,
so great that everything
inside the Void perished.
But as the walls of the world weakened,
the last of the Cybermen must have
fallen through the dimensions,
back in time, to land here.
Then they found you.
I fought them. I know that.
But what happened?
At the same time,
another man came to London.
Mr Jackson Lake.
Plenty of luggage. Money in his pocket.
Maybe coming to town
for the winter season, I don't know.
But he found the Cybermen, too.
And just like you, exactly like you,
he took hold of an info stamp.
But he's dead. Jackson Lake is dead.
The Cybermen murdered him.
You said no body was ever found.
And you kept all his suitcases,
but you could never bring yourself
to open them.
I told you the answer was
in the fob watch.
Can I see?
The watch is Jackson Lake's.
Jackson Lake is you, sir?
But I'm the Doctor.
You became the Doctor
because the info stamp you picked up
was a book about one particular man.
DOCTOR: The Cybermen's database.
Stolen from the Daleks inside the Void,
I'd say.
But it's everything you could want
to know about the Doctor.
JACKSON: That's you.
Time Lord. Tardis.
Enemy of the Cybermen.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
The one and the only.
You see, the info stamp must
have backfired.
Streamed all that information
about me right inside your head.
I am nothing but a lie.
No, no, no, no, no.
Infostamps are just facts and figures.
All that bravery.
Saving Rosita. Defending London Town.
Mmm?
And the invention,
building a Tardis, that's all you.
And what else?
Tell me what else.
There's still something missing,
isn't there?
I demand you tell me, sir!
Tell me what they took!
Sorry.
Really, I am so sorry.
But that's an awful lot of luggage
for one man.
'Cause an info stamp is plain technology.
It's not enough to make
a man lose his mind.
What you suffered is called a fugue.
A fugue state.
Where the mind just runs away
because it can't bear to look back.
You wanted to become someone else
because Jackson Lake had lost so much.
(BELL TOLLING)
Midnight.
Christmas Day.
I remember.
Oh, my God.
No!
Caroline!
(BOTH YELLING)
Caroline.
They killed my wife.
They killed her.
(BEEPING)
(LOUD BEEPING)
Oh.
You found a whole cache of info stamps.
But what is it? What's that noise?
Activation. A call to arms.
The Cybermen are moving!
The Doctor needs help.
I learnt that much about him.
There should be someone at his side.
Now, go.
Go.
What is it? What's happening?
That's Mr Cole. He's master
of the Hazel Street Workhouse.
-Maybe he's taking them to prayers.
-No, nothing as holy as that.
Can you hear me?
Hello?
No?
Mr Cole, you seem to have something
in your ear.
Now, this might hurt a bit,
but if I can just...
(GROWLING)
They're on guard. Can't risk a fight.
Not with the children.
But where are they going?
They all need a good whipping
if you ask me.
There's tons of 'em.
I've just seen another lot coming down
from the Ingleby Workhouse
down Broadback Lane.
-Where's that?
-This way!
ROSITA: There's dozens of 'em!
But what for?
You will continue. You will enter
the court of the CyberKing.
(GROWLING)
March. That is an order.
March.
(CRYING)
Where is it?
ROSITA: That's the door to the sluice.
All the sewage runs through there,
straight into the Thames.
Yeah, that's too well-guarded.
We'll have to find another way in.
Oh, that's cheating, sneaking up!
Did you have your legs on silent?
So, what do we have here?
Listen, listen,
just walk towards me slowly.
Don't let them touch you.
Oh, but they wouldn't hurt me,
my fine boys.
They are my knights in shining arm our.
Quite literally.
Even if they've converted you,
that's not a Cyber-speech pattern.
You've still got free will.
I'm telling you, step away!
There's been no conversion, sir.
No one's ever been
able to change my mind.
The Cybermen offered me
the one thing I wanted. Liberation.
Who are you?
You can be quiet.
I doubt he paid you to talk.
More importantly, who are you, sir,
with such intimate knowledge
of my companions?
I'm the Doctor.
Incorrect. You do not correspond
to our image of the Doctor.
Yeah, that's 'cause your database
got corrupted. Oh, look, look, look.
Check this.
The Doctor's info stamp.
Plug it in. Go on, download.
The core has been damaged.
This info stamp would damage cyberunits.
Oh, well. Nice try.
(BEEPING)
Core repaired. Download.
You are the Doctor.
-Hello.
-You will be deleted.
(STUTTERING)
But let me die happy!
Just tell me one thing.
What do you need those children for?
What are children ever needed for?
They're a workforce.
But for what?
Very soon now,
the whole empire will see.
And they will bow down in worship.
And it's all been timed
for Christmas Day.
Was that your idea, Miss...
Hartigan. And yes, it's the perfect
day for a birth,
with a new message for the people.
Only this time, it won't be
the words of a man.
The birth of what?
A birth and a death. Namely yours.
Thank you, Doctor.
Glad to have been part
of your very last conversation.
Now, delete them.
Delete.
At your service, Doctor.
Shades. Shades!
-Run! Come on!
-HARTIGAN: Shades!
One last thing.
Oh, can I say, I completely disapprove!
Come on!
Get off me! I said get off!
(GROWLING)
Tell your masters
we're not waiting till dawn.
The CyberKing will rise
tonight.
That stronghold down by the river.
I need to find a way in.
Now I'm ahead of you.
My wife and I were moving to London
so that I could take up a post
at the university.
And while my memory is still not intact,
this was in the luggage.
The deeds. 15 Latimer Street.
And if I discovered Cybermen there
-in the cellar, then...
-That might be a way in. Brilliant.
But there's still more.
I remember the cellar.
And my wife.
(SCREAMING)
But I swear there was something else
in that room.
If we can find that,
perhaps that's the key
to defeating these invaders. So onwards.
-Maybe you should go back...
-Don't even try!
No...
You have wisdom. If the Doctor
is planning to intervene,
then the Ascension
will commence immediately.
Excellent.
And as for you, Mr Cole,
Mr Scoones, Mr Fetch and Mr Milligan,
your work is done.
Children!
Pay attention.
Now let the new
Industrial Revolution begin.
I want to see you work!
Energy levels 60% and rising.
Soon the CyberKing will awake.
Then show me.
Delete.
Must've been guarding this.
A dimension vault.
Stolen from the Daleks again. That's how
the Cybermen travelled through time.
Jackson, is this it?
The thing you couldn't remember?
I don't think so.
I just can't see. It's like it's hidden.
Yeah, not enough power. Come on! Avanti!
Oh, that is magnificent.
That is royalty indeed.
And that's quite a throne.
Oh, you will look resplendent.
The chair you designate as throne
ls not intended for me.
My function is to serve the CyberKing,
not to become the CyberKing.
Then who sits there?
No! Now, just...
I think if you remember correctly,
you said I was to be heralded.
All hail the CyberKing.
CYBERMEN: All hail the CyberKing.
But you promised me.
You said I would never be converted!
That was designated a lie.
What do the Cybermen want?
They want us. That's what Cybermen are,
human beings with their brains
put into metal shells. They want
every living thing to be like them.
You can't do this to me!
Incorrect. It is done.
But I would have served you anyway!
Your mind is riven with anger
and abuse and revenge.
These have no place
in a cybermind. Activate.
Emotions have tormented you
all of your life.
Now you will be set free.
This is your liberation.
Oh, for the love of God!
Have you no pity?
Correct.
The CyberKing is born.
CYBERMEN: All the hail the CyberKing.
Upon my soul...
What is it?
It's an engine.
They're generating electricity.
But what for?
We can set them free.
No, no, no, no, no.
(SIGHING)
I hold such information/
Power at 90%.
But if we stop the engine,
the power dies down,
and the Cybermen will come running. Ooh.
Hold on. Power fluctuation.
That's not meant to happen.
It's going wrong?
No, it's weird. The software's
rewriting itself. It's changing.
I can see the stars. The worlds beyond.
The vortex of time itself
and the whole of infinity.
Oh, but this is glorious!
That is incorrect. "Glorious" is
an emotional response.
Exactly. There is so much joy
in this machine.
Joy is not acceptable.
Don't you see? My mind is stronger
than you ever thought.
It dominates, sir! It dominates you!
Alert. You are operating beyond
the standard parameters.
I am new.
The might of your technology combined
with my own imagination. Yes!
There will be a new race of Cybermen.
My Cybermen. Logic and strength
combined with fury and passion.
Diagnosis, system failure.
You will be removed from the processor.
Whoa! What the hell is happening?
It's out of control!
It's accelerating. 96%, 97...
When it reaches 100,
what about the children?
They're disposable. Come on!
I am CyberKing.
My mind inside the Cybermen.
And you will obey me.
CYBERMEN: All hail the CyberKing!
Power levels now at 100%.
Delete the workforce.
(ALARM BLARING)
Delete.
DOCTOR: Right, now, all of you, out!
Do you hear me? That's an order!
Every single one of you, run!
All of you, come on!
As fast as you can! Come on!
There's a hot pie for everyone
if you leg it!
Go!
Rosita, get them out of the sluice gate!
Once you're out, keep running!
Far as you can!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Turn right at the corner!
Fast as you can!
And don't stop!
Keep running! Keep running!
Come, my soldiers. Come to me.
Come on, run!
Quick! Keep running! Keep running!
Go! Quick! Quick!
DOCTOR: It's some sort of starter motor,
but starting what?
(SCREAMING)
CAROLINE: No!
Help!
Father!
That's my son.
My son.
-Doctor, my son!
-What?
They took my son.
No wonder my mind escaped.
Those damned Cybermen, they took
my child! But he's alive, Doctor.
-Frederic!
-Come on!
Oh, he's too scared. Stay there.
Don't move! I'm coming!
CyberKing rising.
I can't get up there! Fred!
DOCTOR: They've finished with the motor.
It's gonna blow up!
What are we gonna do, Doctor?
What are we gonna do?
Come on, Jackson.
You know me.
Oh, that's it! Hello!
Now, hold on tight. Don't let go.
Merry Christmas.
Oh!
Go to St Stephen's, ask for the warden.
He'll take care of you.
Now, run! Quickly!
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
It's under the water!
There's something in the Thames!
DOCTOR: Head for the street!
-JACKSON: Come on, Doctor, hurry up.
-Gotcha!
Behold! I am risen.
Witness me, mankind,
as CyberKing of all.
-It's a CyberKing!
-And a CyberKing is what?
It's a ship. Dreadnought class.
Front line of an invasion,
and inside the chest, a cyberfactory,
ready to convert millions!
And I will walk.
I will stride
across this tiny little world!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
My people.
Why do they not rejoice?
Just head south. Take him south!
Go to the parkland!
-But where are you going?
-To stop that thing.
Then I should be with you.
Jackson, you've got your son.
You've got a reason to live.
And you haven't?
God save you, Doctor.
What the hell is that thing, sir?
Oh, good man! Jed, wasn't it?
Jed, I need your help!
I'm not going out there!
I'll give you five pound notes.
Um...
All right. What do you want me to do?
The Tardis is gonna fly!
People of the world, now hear me.
Your governments will surrender.
And if not, then behold my power!
-You're flamin' bonkers, you are, sir!
-It's been said before! Now, give me!
Not enough power. Come on!
Jed, let her loose!
-Ever flown one of these before?
-Nope, never!
-Can I have my money now?
-Oh, get on with it!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
-But, sir, I thought I'd lost you.
-My son, Rosita. This boy is my son.
God's luck to you, sir!
(JED LAUGHING)
It's the Tardis.
She's flying!
Who the hell is that?
His name, sir,
is the Doctor.
(ALARM BLARING)
Attention. Proximity alert.
How is that even possible?
Oh, this I would see. Turn!
Excellent. The Doctor.
Yet another man come to assert
himself against me in the night.
Miss Hartigan,
I'm offering you a choice.
You might have the most remarkable mind
this world has ever seen.
Strong enough to control
the Cybermen themselves!
I don't need you to sanction me.
No, but such a mind deserves to live.
The Cybermen came to this world
using a dimension vault.
I can use that device to find you
a home. With no people to convert.
But a new world where you can live out
your mechanical life in peace.
I have the world below
and it is abundant with so many minds
ready to become extensions of me,
why would I leave this place?
Because if you don't,
I'll have to stop you.
What do you make of me, sir? An idiot?
No.
The question is, what do you make of me?
Destroy him!
You make me into this.
Then I have made you a failure.
Your weapons are useless, sir.
I wasn't trying to kill you.
All I did was break the cyberconnection,
leaving your mind open.
Open, I think, for the first time
in far too many years,
SO you can see.
(HARTIGAN GASPING)
Just look at yourself.
Look at what you've done!
I'm sorry, Miss Hartigan,
but look at what you've become.
(SCREAMING)
I'm so sorry.
(PIERCING SCREAM)
He's killed it!
Whatever he did, he's killed it!
But it's gonna fall!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(BEEPING)
Now you're ready.
Well,
I'd say he used
that dimension vault to transfer
the wreckage of the CyberKing
into the time vortex,
there to be harmlessly disintegrated.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, I've picked up a lot.
Ah, but here.
Ladies and gentlemen, I know that man!
That Doctor on high!
And I know that he has done this deed
1,000 times.
But not once, no, sir, not once,
not ever has he ever been thanked.
But no more, for I say to you
on this Christmas Morn, bravo, sir!
Bravo!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
JACKSON: Bravo, sir!
Bravo, sir!
Bravo, Doctor.
JACKSON: The city will recover.
As London always does.
Though the events
of today will be history,
-spoken of for centuries to come.
-Yeah. Funny that.
JACKSON: And a new history
begins for me.
I find myself a widower,
but with my son,
and with a good friend.
Now, take care of that one.
She's marvellous.
Frederic will need a nursemaid
and I can think of none better.
But you're welcome to join us.
We thought we might all dine together
at the Traveller's Halt,
a Christmas feast in celebration,
and in memory of those we have lost.
You won't stay.
Like I said, you know me.
No,
I don't think anyone does.
Oh! And this is it!
Oh!
Oh, if I might, Doctor,
one last adventure?
Oh.
Be my guest.
Oh!
Oh, my word.
Oh, goodness me.
(CHUCKLING)
But this is...
This is nonsense!
Well, that's one word for it.
Complete and utter, wonderful nonsense!
How very, very silly!
Oh, no, I can't bear it.
Oh, it's causing my head to ache.
No, no, no, no, no!
Oh! Oh, gracious!
That's quite enough.
I take it this is goodbye.
Onwards and upwards.
But tell me one thing.
All those facts and figures I saw
of the Doctor's life,
you were never alone.
All those bright and shining companions.
But not any more?
No.
Might I ask why not?
They leave.
Because they should,
or they find someone else.
And some of them... Some of them
forget me.
I suppose, in the end,
they break my heart.
That offer of Christmas dinner,
it's no longer a request, it's a demand.
In memory of those we've lost.
Oh, go on, then.
-Really?
-Just this once.
You've actually gone
and changed my mind.
And not many people can do that.
Jackson,
if anyone had to be the Doctor,
I'm glad it was you.
The feast awaits. Come with me.
-Walk this way.
-I certainly will!
(JACKSON CHUCKLING)
Merry Christmas to you, Jackson.
Merry Christmas indeed, Doctor.