(SOBBING)
Vincent, can you hear me?
Please...
(CRIES OUT)
It's not enough he goes
drinking all round the town,
now the whole neighbourhood
has to listen to his screaming.
He's very ill, Madame Vernet.
Look at this,
even worse than his usual rubbish.
What's it supposed to be?
(VINCENT CONTINUES TO SCREAM AND SOB)
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
It was found behind the wall
in an attic in France.
It's genuine...it's a Van Gogh...
Why bring it to me?
Because it's obviously a message...
and you can see who it's for.
Can't say I understand it.
You're not supposed to understand it,
Prime Minister.
You're supposed to deliver it.
(PHONE RINGS)
Cell 426.
The Doctor? Do you mean Dr Song?
Give me that. Seriously, just give it
to me. I'm entitled to phone calls.
Doctor?
No, and neither are you.
Where is he?
You're phoning the time vortex,
it doesn't always work.
But the TARDIS is smart,
she's re-routed the call.
Talk quickly. This connection
will last less than a minute.
Dr Song.
Are you finished with that?
You're new here, aren't you?
First day.
Then I'm very sorry.
(ALARM BLARES)
Stay exactly where you are.
She had the lipstick, the hallucinogenic
lipstick. She tried to use it on me.
Your tricks don't work in here,
Dr Song.
This is the Royal Collection.
And I'm the bloody Queen.
What are you doing here?
It's about the Doctor, Ma'am.
You met him once, didn't you?
I know he came here.
- The Doctor?
- He's in trouble.
I need to find him.
- Then why are you stealing a painting?
- Look at it.
I need to find the Doctor,
and I need to show him this.
Now, word on the belt is,
you're looking for time travel.
Are you selling?
A vortex manipulator, fresh off
the wrist of a handsome Time Agent.
(SIGHS)
I said off the wrist.
Not cheap, Dr Song.
Have you brought me a pretty toy?
This is a Calisto Pulse. It can disarm
micro-explosives from up to 20 feet.
What kind of micro-explosives?
The kind I just put in your wine.
- Vavoom!
- Va-what?
I can't believe I've never
thought of this before, it's genius.
Right!
Landed, come on.
- Where are we?
- Planet One.
The oldest planet in the universe.
There's a cliff of pure diamond
and, according to legend,
on the cliff there's writing.
Letters 50 feet high, a message
from the dawn of time,
and no-one knows what it says,
cos no-one's ever translated it.
Till today.
- What happens today?
- Us. The TARDIS can translate anything.
All we have to do is open the doors
and read the very first words
in recorded history.
(GASPS)
Vavoom!
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
Right place?
Just followed the co-ordinates
on the cliff face.
Earth. Britain. 1.02am.
No, pm.
No, AD.
- That's a Roman legion.
- Well, yeah.
The Romans invaded Britain
several times during this period.
Oh, I know.
My favourite topic at school.
"Invasion of the Hot Italians."
Yeah, I did get marked down
for the title.
Hail, Caesar!
- Hi.
- Welcome to Britain.
We are honoured by your presence.
Well, you're only human.
Arise...
Roman person.
- Why does he think you're Caesar?
- Cleopatra will see you now.
Hello, sweetie.
River!
Hi.
You graffitied the oldest
cliff face in the universe.
You wouldn't answer your phone.
- What's this?
- It's a painting.
Your friend Vincent.
One of his final works.
He had visions, didn't he? I thought
you ought to know about this one.
Doctor?
Doctor, what is this?
- Why's it exploding?
- I assume it's some kind of warning.
Something's going to happen
to the TARDIS?
It might not be that literal.
Anyway this is where he wanted you.
- Date and map reference on the door sign.
- Does it have a title?
The Pandorica Opens.
Come on.
Ya!
- The Pandorica? What is it?
- A box. A cage. A prison.
It was built to contain the most
feared thing in all the universe.
It's a fairy tale, a legend.
It can't be real.
If it is real,
it's here and it's opening.
And it's got something to do
with your TARDIS exploding.
Hidden, obviously. Buried for centuries.
You won't find it on a map.
No. But if you buried the most
dangerous thing in the universe,
you'd want to remember
where you put it.
Ya! Come on!
How come it's not new?
Because it's already old.
Been here thousands of years.
No-one knows exactly how long.
OK, this Pandorica thing.
Last time we saw you, you warned us about
it, after we climbed out of Byzantium.
Spoilers!
No, but you told the Doctor you'd see
him again when the Pandorica opens.
Maybe I did. But I haven't yet.
But I will have. Doctor, I'm picking up
fry particles everywhere.
Energy weapons
discharged on this site.
If the Pandorica is here, it contains
the mightiest warrior in history.
Now, half the galaxy would want
a piece of that. Maybe even fight over it.
We need to get down there.
RIVER: Right then...ready.
(BLEEPING)
(DULL CLANKING)
The underhenge.
(ELECTRIC FIZZLING)
- It's a Pandorica.
- More than just a fairy tale.
(CRUNCHING)
There was a goblin.
Or a trickster,
or a warrior.
A nameless, terrible thing, soaked
in the blood of a billion galaxies.
The most feared being
in all the cosmos.
And nothing could
stop it, or hold it,
or reason with it.
One day it would just drop out of
the sky and tear down your world.
- How did it end up in there?
- You know fairy tales.
A good wizard tricked it.
I hate good wizards in fairy tales.
They always turn out to be him.
So it's kind of like
Pandora's Box, then?
Almost the same name.
- Sorry, what?
- The story.
Pandora's Box, with all
the worst things in the world in it.
That was my favourite book
when I was a kid.
- What's wrong?
- Your favourite school topic,
your favourite story.
Never ignore a coincidence,
unless you're busy. In which case,
always ignore a coincidence.
- So can you open it?
- Easily. Anyone can break /nto a prison.
But I'd rather know
what I'm going to find first.
You won't have long to wait.
It's already opening.
There are layers and layers
of security protocols in there,
and they're being disabled, one by one.
Like it's being unlocked
- from the inside.
- How long do we have?
- Hours at the most.
- What kind of security?
Everything.
Deadlocks, time-stops, matter-lines.
- What could need all that?
- What could get past all that?
Think of the fear
that went into making this box.
What could inspire
that level of fear?
Hello, you...
Have we met?
(BEEPING)
- So why would it start to open now?
- No idea.
And how could Vincent have known about
it? He won't even be born for centuries.
The stones! These stones
are great big transmitters,
broadcasting a warning to everyone,
everywhere, to every time zone.
- The Pandorica is opening!
- RIVER: Doctor - everyone, everywhere?
Even poor Vincent heard it
in his dreams.
But what's in there,
what could justify all this?
Doctor, everyone?
Anything that powerful,
I'd know about it. Why don't I know?
Doctor, you said everyone could
hear it. So who else is coming?
Oh.
Oh? Oh, what?
OK, if it is basically a transmitter,
we should be able to fold back the signal.
- Doing it.
- Doing what?
Stonehenge is transmitting, it's been
transmitting for a while...so who heard?
OK, should be feeding back to you now.
River, what's out there? Getting anything?
- Give me a moment.
- River, quickly, anything?
Around this planet,
there are at least 10,000 star ships.
(SCOFFS) At least?
10,000, 100,000, 1 million, I don't know.
There's too many readings.
What kind of star ships?
- (CROAKY VOICES) Maintaining orbit.
- I obey.
- Shield cover compromised on ion sectors.
- Daleks. Those are Daleks.
- Scan detects no temporal activity.
- Soft grid scan commencing.
Reverse thrust
for compensatory stabilisation.
Daleks, Doctor.
Launch preliminary armaments protocol.
Yes, OK. OK, OK, OK. Dalek fleet.
Minimum, 12,000 battleships,
armed to the teeth.
Ahhh! But we've got surprise on our side!
They'll never expect three people
to attack 12,000 Dalek battleships.
Cos we'd be killed instantly.
So it would be a fairly short surprise.
- Forget surprise.
- Doctor, Cyber-ships.
No, Dalek ships, listen to them,
those are Dalek ships.
Yes. Dalek ships and Cyberships.
Well, we need to start a fight,
turn them on each other. That's easy.
- It's the Daleks - they're so cross...
- Sontaran. Four battle fleets.
Sontarans! Talk about cross,
who stole all their handbags?
Terileptil. Slitheen.
Chelonian. Nestene. Drahvin.
Sycorax. Haemo-goth.
Zygon. Atraxi. Draconian.
They're all here. For the Pandorica.
What are you?
What could you possibly be?
(WHIRRING AND THRUMMING)
What do we do?
Doctor, listen to me! Everything that
ever hated you is coming here tonight.
You can't win this.
You can't even fight it.
Doctor, this once, just this one time,
please, you have to run.
- Run where?
- Fight how?
The greatest military machine
in the history of the universe.
- What is?
- The Daleks?
No. No, no, no, no.
The Romans!
(MAN SHOUTS ORDERS IN BACKGROUND)
So...I return to my command
after one week and discover
we've been playing host to Cleopatra.
- Who's in Egypt. And dead!
- Yes.
Funny how things work out.
- (WHIRRING)
- (WHINNYING)
The sky is falling, and you make jokes.
Who are you?
When you fight Barbarians,
what must they think of you?
Oh, riddles now?
Where do they think you come from?
A place more deadly and more powerful
and more impatient
than their tiny minds can imagine.
Where do I come from?
Your world has visitors.
- You're all Barbarians now.
- What is that?
Tell me, what?
A fool would say,
the work of the Gods.
But you've been a soldier too long to
believe there are Gods watching over us.
There is, however, a man.
And tonight he's going to need
your help.
MAN: Sir?
One moment.
(WHISPERED DIALOGUE)
Well, it seems you have a volunteer.
- What's this got to do with the TARDIS?
- Nothing, as far as I know.
But Vincent's painting - the TARDIS was
exploding, is that going to happen?
One problem at a time. There's
force-field technology inside this box.
If I can enhance the signal,
I could extend it all over Stonehenge.
- Could buy us half an hour.
- What good is half an hour?
There are fruit flies
live on Hoppledom 6
that live for 20 minutes
and they don't even mate for life.
There was going to be a point
to that. I'll get back to you.
So...
are you proposing to someone?
I'm sorry?
I found this in your pocket.
No. No, no, that's, er...
a memory.
A friend of mine, someone I lost.
Do you...mind?
It's weird, I feel...
I don't know. Something.
People fall out of the world sometimes,
but they always leave traces.
Little things
we can't quite account for.
Faces in photographs, luggage,
half-eaten meals...
rings...
Nothing is ever forgotten,
not completely.
And...if something
can be remembered,
it can come back.
So, was she nice, your friend?
Remember that night
you flew away with me?
(CLEARS THROAT) Of course I do.
And you asked me why I was taking you
and I told you there wasn't a reason.
I was lying.
- What, so you did have a reason?
- Your house.
- (SCOFFS) My house.
- It was too big, too many empty rooms.
Does it ever bother you, Amy,
that your life doesn't make any sense?
(ELECTRONIC ZAPS)
- What was that?
- OK, I need a proper look.
- Got to draw its fire, give it a target.
- How?
You know how sometimes
I have really brilliant ideas?
- Yes...
- Sorry!
Look at me, I'm a target!
- What is that?
- Cyber arm. Arm of a Cyberman.
- And what's a Cyberman?
- Oh, sort of part man, part robot.
The organic part must have died off
years ago,
now the robot part is looking for,
well...fresh meat.
- What, us?
- Yeah, it's just like being
an organ donor, except you're alive
and sort of...screaming.
I need to get behind it,
could you draw its fire?
Like you did?
You'll be fine if you're quick,
it's only got one arm, literally.
Aaaaaaaaah!
Come here!
Doctor?
Scrambled its circuits, but stay
where you are. It could be bluffing.
Bluffing? It's an arm!
I said, "Stay where you are!"
Doctor?
Amy!
Doctor!
(SHE SCREAMS)
Doctor?
ROBOTIC VOICE: You will be assimilated.
Yeah?
You and whose body?
(HEAVY THUDDING)
Aaargh!
- (THUD!)
- Doctor?!
(THUDDING)
(THUDDING STOPS)
Doctor?
Who...? Who are you...?
Hello, Amy.
Woah, woah, woah!
- Sir, the man's coming round.
- DOCTOR: Amy?!
- Where's Amy?
- She's fine, Doctor, just unconscious.
OK... Yes, she's sedated, that's all.
Half an hour, she'll be fine.
OK, Romans, good, I was just wishing
for Romans, good old River. How many?
50 men up top, volunteers.
What about that thing?
507 Not exactly a legion.
Your friend was very persuasive,
but, er...it's a tough sell.
Yes, I know that, Rory, I'm not
exactly one to miss the obvious.
But we need everything we can get.
OK, Cyberweapons.
This is basically a sentry box.
So headless wonder here was a sentry.
Probably got himself duffed up by
the locals. Never underestimate a Celt.
- Doctor...
- Hush, Rory, thinking.
Why leave a Cyberman on guard?
Unless it's a Cyberthing in the box.
But why would they lock up
one of their own?
OK, no, not a Cyberthing,
but what, what?
No, I'm missing something obvious,
Rory!
Something big, something right
slap in front of me, I can feel it!
Yeah, I think you probably are.
I'll get it in a minute.
(CLANKING)
- Hello again.
- Hello.
- How've you been?
- Good. Yeah, good.
I mean, Roman.
Rory, I'm not trying to be rude,
but you died.
Yeah, I know, I was there.
You died and then
you were erased from time.
You didn't just die, you were never
born at all, you never existed.
Erased? What does...that mean?
How can you be here?
I don't know.
It's kind of fuzzy.
Fuzzy?
Well, I died and turned into a Roman.
It's very distracting!
(MOANS)
Did she miss me?
(RUMBLING AND WHOOSHING)
MAN: Stay your weapons. Stand back.
- What is it? What's happening?
- The final phase.
It's opening.
(CLUNKING)
(RHYTHMIC METALLIC CLUNKING)
(WHOOSHING)
(ZAPPING)
- You're surrounded. Have you got a plan?
- Yes!
Now hurry up and get the TARDIS here.
I need equipment!
What are you?
They're all here, all of them,
all for you.
What could you possibly be?
(WHIRRING AND ZAPPING)
THE DOCTOR'S AMPLIFIED VOICE: Sorry,
sorry, dropped it. Hello, Stonehenge!
Who takes the Pandorica,
takes the universe.
But bad news, everyone...
Cos guess who?! Ha!
Listen, you lot, you're all whizzing
about, it's really very distracting.
Could you all just stay still a minute?
(SHOUTING) Because I...am...talking!
The question of the hour is,
who's got the Pandorica?
Answer - I do. Next question,
who's coming to take it from me?
Come on! Look at me, no plan,
no backup, no weapons worth a damn.
Oh, and something else,
I don't have anything...to...lose!
So if you're sitting up there
in your silly little spaceship,
with all your silly little guns,
and you've got any plans
on taking the Pandorica tonight,
just remember
who's standing in your way.
Remember every black day
I ever stopped you. And then,
and then, do the smart thing.
Let somebody else try first.
(ZAPPING AND WHOOSHING)
That'll keep 'em squabbling
for half an hour!
Romans!
OK...
(METALLIC THRUMMING)
What's the matter with you?
RORY: They're still out there.
What do we do now?
If I can stop whatever's in this box
getting out, then they'll all go home.
Right. Rory, I'm sorry, you're
going to have to be very brave now.
Oh, my head.
- Aaahh.
Just your basic knockout drops.
- Get some fresh air, you'll be fine.
- Is it safe up there?
- Not remotely, but it's fresh.
- Fine.
Ooh!
Oh, you're the guy, yeah,
the one who did the...
- swordy thing.
- Yeah.
Well, thanks for the...swording.
Nice swording.
No problem.
My men are up there.
- They'll...they'll look after you.
- Good. Love a Roman!
She doesn't remember me.
How can she not remember me?
Because you never existed.
- (CRASHING)
- What are you doing?
What's wrong?
There are cracks. Cracks in time.
There's going to be a huge explosion
in the future, on one particular day.
And every other moment in history
is cracking around it.
So how does that work?
What kind of explosion? What exploded?
RIVER: And for those of us who can't
read the base code of the universe?
DOCTOR: Amy's time...
Doesn't matter,
the cracks are everywhere now.
Get too close and you can fall
right out of the universe.
So I fell through a crack
and now I was never born?
- Basically.
- How did I end up here?
I don't know, you shouldn't have.
What happened? From your point
of view, what physically happened?
I was in the cave, with you and Amy.
I was dying...
and then I was just here,
a Roman soldier. A proper Roman.
A head full of Roman...
stuff, a whole other life.
Just here, like I'd woken up
from a dream.
I started to think it was a dream.
You and Amy and Leadworth.
Then today, in the camp, the men
were talking about the visitors,
the girl with the red hair.
I thought you'd come back for me.
But she can't even remember me.
- Oh, shut up.
- What?
Go get her.
But I don't understand.
Why am I here?
Because you are.
The universe is big. It's vast
and complicated and ridiculous,
and sometimes, very rarely,
impossible things just happen
and we call them miracles,
and that's the theory.
900 years, never seen one yet.
But this would do me.
Now get upstairs, she's Amy
and she's surrounded by Romans.
I'm not sure history can take it.
(GROANS)
OK?
Are you OK now?
MAN'S VOICE: Silence will fall.
RIVER: Why have you brought me here?
(OWL HOOTING)
(MACHINE BUZZES)
(BUZZ INCREASES IN INTENSITY
AND FREQUENCY)
OK, so something's been here.
Amy...
Oh, Doctor, why do I let you out?
(BUZZING STOPS)
ROMAN: A place more deadly
and more powerful
and more impatient
than their tiny minds can imagine.
(VOICE ECHOES)
AMY: So it's kind of like
Pandora's box, then?
That was my favourite book
when I was a kid.
(VOICE ECHOES)
(WHISPERS) Oh, no...
Are you OK?
Did the Doctor send you?
I'm fine, he just fusses.
You got a blanket. That's good.
- Who gave you that?
- One of the fellas.
- Which one?
- Just one of them. Does it matter?
No...
No.
Forget him...it.
F-Forget it.
What's your name?
I'm...Rory.
What's wrong?
Nothing. It's just not what you expect
Romans to be called.
What's it short for? Roranicus?
Yeah.
You're crying.
The TARDIS, where is it? Hurry up!
Don't raise your voice,
don't look alarmed, just listen.
- (AMY SOBS)
- Hey, what's wrong?
Nothing. It's like...
It's like I'm happy.
(AMY LAUGHS AND SOBS)
Why am I happy?
They're not real, they can't be.
They're all right here
in the story book,
those actual Romans, the ones I sent you,
the ones you're with right now.
They're all in a book in Amy's house,
a children's picture book.
What are you even doing there?
It doesn't matter. The TARDIS went wrong.
Doctor, how is this possible?
Something's using her memories,
Amy's memories.
- But how?
- You said something had been there.
Yes, there's burn marks
on the grass outside,
- landing patterns.
- If they've been to her house,
they could have used her psychic residue.
Structures can hold memories,
that's why houses have ghosts.
They could've taken a snapshot
of Amy's memories. But why?
Doctor, who are those Romans?
Projections or...duplicates.
But they were helping us.
My lipstick even worked.
They might think they're real.
The perfect disguise.
They actually believe
their own cover story...
right until they're activated.
Doctor...
that centurion...
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I don't know why I'm doing that.
It's me.
Amy, please...
It's a trap, it has to be.
They used Amy to construct a scenario
you'd believe, to get close to you.
Why? Who'd do that?
What for? It doesn't make sense.
Ahh!
River? River?
- River, what's happening?!
- I don't know, it's the engines.
Doctor, there's something wrong
with the TARDIS,
- like something else is controlling it.
- You're flying it wrong.
I'm flying it perfectly.
You taught me.
Where are you?
What's the date reading?
It's the 26th June, 2010.
You need to get out of there now!
Any other time zone, just go.
- I can't break free.
- Well, then, shut down the TARDIS.
- Shut down everything!
- I can't!
MAN'S VOICE: Silence will fall!
Silence will fall/
But I don't know you,
I've never seen you before in my life.
- You have. You know you have. It's me.
- Why am I crying?
Because you remember me.
I came back!
You're crying
because you remember me.
Someone else is flying it.
An external force.
I've lost control.
But how? Why?
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
Listen to me, just land her anywhere.
Emergency landing, now!
There are cracks in time,
I've seen them everywhere,
and they're getting wider. The TARDIS
exploding is what causes them,
but we can stop the cracks
ever happening if you just land her!
It's not safe.
(CLUNKING)
Well, now.
Ready to come out, are we?
Aaargh! No! No, please, no!
I'm not going.
(SHOUTS) I'm Rory!
(CREAKING)
Doctor...
I'm down.
- I've landed.
- OK, just walk out of the doors.
If there's no-one inside, the TARDIS
engines shut down automatically.
Just get out of there.
- I'm going.
- (SHOUTS) Run!
(BUZZING)
- (CREAKING)
- (GROANS)
Doctor! Doctor!
- I can't open the doors!
- Amy!
RORY: Listen to me, you have to run.
You have to get as far away
from here as you can!
I'm a thing. I'll kill you. Just go!
(GROANS) Please, no, I don't want to go.
I'm Rory! I'm...
-I'm...
- Williams.
Rory Williams from Leadworth.
My boyfriend.
- How could I ever forget you?
- (WHISPERS) Amy, you've got to run.
I can't hold on, I'm going.
You are Rory Williams and you aren't
going anywhere ever again.
Doctor, I can't open the doors!
Doctor, please, I've got seconds!
Plastic Romans.
Duplicates, driven by
the Nestene Consciousness, eh?
Deep cover, but what for?
What are you doing?
(WHISPERS) What's in there, eh?
What's coming out?
The Pandorica is ready.
What, you mean it's open?
DALEK VOICE: You have been scanned.
Assessed.
Understood.
Doctor.
The ring. Remember the ring?
You'd never let me wear it
in case I lost it.
- The Doctor gave it to me.
- Show it to me.
Show me the ring.
- Amy...
- Come on!
Just show it to me.
Scanned?
Scanned by what, a box?
DALEK: Your limits and capacities
have been extrapolated.
(GRUNTING)
The Pandorica is ready.
Ready for what?
Ready for you.
There it is.
You remember.
This is you.
And you are staying.
No...
(SHOT RINGS OUT)
(GROANS)
Oh... No!
No!
You lot, working together,
an alliance...
How is that possible?
DALEK: The cracks in the skin
of the universe.
All reality is threatened.
All universes will be deleted.
What?
And you've come to me for help?
No.
We will save the universe from you!
From me?
All projections correlate.
All evidence concurs.
The Doctor will destroy the universe.
No, no, no. You've got it wrong.
The Pandorica was constructed
to ensure the safety of the alliance.
A scenario was devised
from the memories of your companion.
A trap the Doctor could not resist.
DALEK: The cracks in time are the work
of the Doctor. It is confirmed.
No. no, no. Not me, the TARDIS.
And I'm not in the TARDIS, am I?
Only the Doctor can pilot the TARDIS.
- Please, listen to me...
- You will be prevented.
Total event collapse! Every sun will
supernova at every moment in history.
The whole universe will never have
existed! (SHOUTS) Please, listen to me!
- Seal the Pandorica.
- No! Please, listen to me!
The TARDIS is exploding right now
and I'm the only one who can stop it!
(SHOUTS) Listen to me...!
(THUD)
I'm sorry, my love.
(EXPLOSION)