(SIGHING)
(MERRY CHRISTMAS EVERYBODY BY SLADE
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(CLANGING)
Turn that down.
Turn it off, Steve, man. Turn it off!
John, shut up!
(DISTANT WHOOSHING)
Rose!
-Mickey!
-Jackie, it's the Tardis.
I know, I know. I heard it.
She's alive, Mickey.
I said so, didn't I? She's alive!
MICKEY: Just shut up a minute.
JACKIE: Where is it, then?
(JACKIE SCREAMS)
Here we are, then.
London, Earth, the solar system, isn't it?
Jackie, Mickey, blimey!
No, no, no, no. Hold on.
Wait there. What was I going to say?
There was something I had to tell you.
Something important. What was it?
No, hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
(SHUSHING)
Oh! I know.
(PANTING)
Merry Christmas!
-What happened? Is he all right?
-I don't know. He just keeled over.
-But who is he? Where's the Doctor?
-That's him.
Right in front of you. That's the Doctor.
What do you mean, that's the Doctor?
Doctor who?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Here we go. Tina the cleaner's
got this lodger, medical student.
And she was fast asleep so I just took it.
I still say we should take him to hospital.
We can't. They'd lock him up.
They'd dissect him.
One bottle of his blood
could change the future of the human race.
No... Shh.
(HEART BEATING)
-Both working.
-What do you mean, both?
-Well, he's got two hearts.
-Oh, don't be stupid.
He has.
-Anything else he's got two of?
-Leave him alone.
How can he go changing his face?
Is that a different face
or is he a different person?
How should I know?
Sorry.
The thing is, I thought I knew him, Mum.
I thought me and him were...
And then he goes and does this.
I keep forgetting he's not human.
The big question is...
where'd you get
a pair of men's pyjamas from?
-Howard's been staying over.
-What, Howard from the market?
-How long has that been going on?
-A month or so.
First of all he starts delivering to the door
and I thought, "That's odd."
(WOMAN SPEAKING ON TV)
-Next thing you know, it's a bag of oranges.
-Is that Harriet Jones?
-Never mind me.
-Why is she on the telly?
She's Prime Minister now.
I'm 18 quid a week better off.
They're calling it Britain's golden age.
-I keep on saying my Rose has met her.
-Did more than that.
Stopped World War III with her.
Harriet Jones.
What about those calling the Guinevere One
space probe a waste of money?
Now that's where you're wrong.
I completely disagree if you don't mind.
The Guinevere One space probe represents
this country's limitless ambition.
British workmanship
sailing up there among the stars.
This is the spirit of Christmas,
birth and rejoicing
and the dawn of a new age,
and that is what we're achieving
50 million miles away,
our very own miracle.
COMMENTATOR:
The unmanned probe Guinevere One
ls about to make its final descent.
Photographs of the Martian landscape
should be received by midnight tonight.
-So what do you need, 20 quid?
-Do you mind? I'll pay you back.
Call it a Christmas present!
ROSE: God, I'm all out of sync.
You just forget about Christmas and things
in the Tardis.
They don't exist. You get sort of...timeless.
Oh, yeah, that's fascinating because
I love hearing stories about the Tardis.
Ooh, go on, Rose, tell us another one
'cause I swear I could listen to it all day,
"Tardis this, Tardis that."
Shut up.
"Oh, and one time the Tardis landed
in a big, yellow garden full of balloons."
-I'm not like that.
-Oh, you so are.
Hmm, must drive you mad.
I'm surprised you don't give up on me.
Well, that's the thing, isn't it? You can
rely on me. I don't go changing my face.
Yeah.
-What if he's dying?
-Okay...
Sorry!
Just let it be Christmas. Can you do that?
Just for a bit. You and me and Christmas.
No... No Doctor.
No bog monsters. No life or death.
Okay.
-Promise?
-Yes.
Right.
What are we gonna get for your mum?
I'm round there all the time now, you know.
She does me dinner on a Sunday...
(MICKEY RAMBLING)
(PLAYING GOD REST YE
MERRY GENTLEMEN)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
It's us. They're after us.
What's going on? What have we done?
Why are they after us?
Taxi!
They're after the Doctor.
I can't even go shopping with you,
we get attacked by a brass band.
-Who you phoning?
-My mum.
She turns up, no warning.
I've got nothing in.
I said, "Rose, if you want a Christmas
dinner of meat paste, then so be it."
Get off the phone!
Well, who were those...those Santa things?
I don't know.
But think about it, they were after us.
What's important about us? We're nothing.
Except the one thing we've got
tucked up in bed. The Doctor.
Oh, no, don't come round, darling.
No, the flat's all topsy-turvy.
Yeah, she just barges in
and litters the place.
Yeah. No, I'll come round and see you
on Boxing Day.
-Save us a chipolata...
-Get off the phone! Get off the phone.
It's only Bev. She says hello.
Bev? Yeah, look, it'll have to wait.
Right. It's not safe, we've got to get out.
Where can we go?
-My mate Stan. He'll put us up.
-That's only two streets away.
-What about Mo? Where's she living now?
-I don't know. Peak District.
We'll go to cousin Mo's, then.
It's Christmas Eve,
we're not going anywhere.
-What are you babbling about?
-Mum...
Where'd you get that tree?
That's a new tree. Where'd you get it?
-I thought it was you.
-How can it be me?
You went shopping, there was a ring
at the door and there it was.
No, that wasn't me.
Then who was it?
Oh, you're kidding me.
MICKEY: Let's go! Quick, get out!
-We've got to save the Doctor.
-What are you doing?
We can't just leave him.
Mickey!
Mickey! Get out, get out!
Mickey! Get out of there.
-No! Leave him, just leave him!
-Get in here.
Doctor, wake up.
(JACKIE SCREAMING)
I'm gonna get killed by a Christmas tree!
Help me.
Remote control.
But who's controlling it?
-That's them. What are they?
-Shh.
They've just gone!
What kind of rubbish were they?
I mean, no offence,
but they're not much cop
if a sonic screwdriver's
gonna scare them off.
-Pilot fish.
-What?
They were just pilot fish.
(GROANING IN PAIN)
What's wrong?
You woke me up too soon.
I'm still regenerating.
I'm bursting with energy.
You see? The pilot fish could smell it
a million miles away.
So they eliminate the defence,
that's you lot, and they carry me off.
They could run their batteries off me
for a couple of years!
Oh, oh, oh!
My head.
-I'm having a neural implosion. I need...
-What do you need?
-I need...
-Just say. Tell me, tell me.
-Painkillers? Aspirin?
-I need...
Codeine? Paracetamol?
Oh, I don't know. Pepto-Bismol?
Liquid paraffin.
Vitamin C, vitamin D, vitamin E!
-I need...
-Is it food? Something simple.
Bowl of soup? Nice bowl of soup?
Soup and a sandwich?
Oh, soup and a little ham sandwich?
-I need you to shut up.
-Oh, he hasn't changed that much.
We haven't got much time.
If there's pilot fish then...
Why is there an apple
in my dressing gown?
-That's Howard, sorry.
-He keeps apples in his dressing gown?
He gets hungry.
-What, he gets hungry in his sleep?
-Sometimes.
Brain collapsing.
The... The pilot fish...
The pilot fish mean there's something...
There's something...
Something is coming.
Jackie, I'm using the phone line,
is that all right?
Yeah, keep account of it.
(CLOCK CHIMES SOFTLY)
It's midnight.
Christmas Day.
-Any change?
-He's worse.
Just one heart beating.
Scientists in charge
of Britain's mission to Mars
have re-established contact with
the Guinevere One space probe.
They're expecting the first transmission
from the planet's surface
in the next few minutes.
Yes, we are. We are back on schedule.
We've received the signal
from Guinevere One.
The Mars landing
would seem to be an unqualified success.
REPORTER: But is it true that
you completely lost contact early tonight?
Yes, we had a bit of a scare.
Guinevere seemed to fall off the scope
but it was just a blip.
Only disappeared for a few seconds.
She is fine now, absolutely fine.
We're getting the first pictures
transmitted live any minute now.
I'd better get back to it. Thanks.
Here we go. Pilot fish.
Scavengers like the Doctor said.
Harmless, they're tiny.
But the point is the little fish
swim alongside the big fish.
-Do you mean like sharks?
-Great, big sharks.
So what the Doctor means is
we had them, now we get that.
Something is coming.
-(ON TV) ...Martian landscape of rocks...
-How close?
There's no way of telling. But the pilot fish
don't swim far from their daddy.
-So it's close.
-Funny sort of rocks.
That's not rocks.
(ON TV) This is being transmitted
via Mission Control
and it's coming live from the depths
of space on Christmas morning.
(GROWLING)
The face of an alien life form
was transmitted live tonight on BBC ONE.
On the 25th of December, the human race
has been shown absolute proof
that alien life exists.
These remarkable images
have been relayed right across the world.
This way, sir.
Mr Llewellyn.
MAN: (ON PA) Security sweep at 05176.
Mr Llewellyn, ma'am.
-Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
-Well, yes, I know who you are.
-I suppose I've ruined your Christmas.
-Never off duty.
Now, we've put out a cover story.
Alex has been handling it.
We've said it was a hoax.
Some sort of mask or prosthetics.
Students hijacking the signal,
that sort of thing.
Alex is my right-hand man.
I'm not used to having a right-hand man.
-I quite like it, though.
-I quite like it myself.
I don't suppose
there's any chance it was a hoax?
That would be nice.
Then we could all go home.
I don't suppose
anyone's offered you a coffee?
-No.
-No, the transmission was genuine.
And this seems to be
a new species of alien.
At least, not one we've encountered before.
You seem to be talking about aliens
as a matter of fact.
There's an Act of Parliament
banning my autobiography.
-Prime Minister?
-I'm with you.
Miss Jacobs can explain.
I don't think we've been introduced.
Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
Yes. I know who you are.
The transmission didn't come
from the surface of Mars.
Guinevere One was broadcasting
from a point 5,000 miles above the planet.
In other words, they've got a ship
and the probe is onboard.
But if they're not from the surface,
then they might not be from Mars itself.
Maybe they're not actual Martians.
Of course not.
Martians look completely different.
We think the ship was in flight
when they just came across the probe.
And they're moving.
The ship's still in flight now.
We've got it on the Hubble array.
-Moving in which direction?
-Towards us.
-How fast?
-Very fast.
-What was your name again?
-Sally.
Thank you, Sally.
MICKEY: Rose.
Take a look. I've got access to the military.
They're tracking a spaceship.
It's big, it's fast and it's coming this way.
Coming for what, though? The Doctor?
I don't know.
Maybe it's coming for all of us.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Have you seen them before?
No.
Translation software.
Yes, sir.
(ALIENS YELLING)
I don't understand what they're saying.
The Tardis translates alien languages
inside my head
all the time, wherever I am.
So why isn't it doing it now?
I don't know. Must be the Doctor.
Like he's part of the circuit and...
he's broken.
I'm getting demands
from Washington, ma'am.
The President's insisting
that he takes control of the situation.
You can tell the President,
and please use these exact words,
he's not my boss and he's certainly
not turning this into a war.
-What have we got?
-Nothing yet.
Translating an alien language
is going to take time.
How far off is the ship?
About five hours.
Despite claims of an alien hoax,
it's been reported that NATO forces
are on red alert.
Oh, come on, sweetheart.
What do you need?
What is it you need? Tell me.
Speaking strictly off the record,
government sources are calling this
our longest night.
I don't suppose we've had a code 97
-No sign of the Doctor?
-Nothing yet.
You've met him, haven't you?
-Like the stuff of legend.
-He is that.
Failing him...
what about Torchwood?
I know I'm not supposed to know about it,
I realise that.
Not even the United Nations knows.
But if ever there was
a need for Torchwood, it's now.
-I can't take responsibility.
-I can.
See to it. Get them ready.
WOMAN: (ON PA) Attention.
Transmission filters must be maintained...
-Prime Minister.
-Has it worked?
Just about.
"People..." That could be cattle.
"...you belong to us.
"To the Sycorax."” They seem
to be called Sycorax, not Martians.
"We own you. We now possess your land,
your minerals, your precious stones.
"You will surrender or they will die.
"Sycorax strong. Sycorax mighty.
Sycorax rock!"
As in the modern sense, they rock.
"They" will die?
Not "you will die.”
"They will die." Who's they?
I don't know. But it is
the right personal pronoun. It's "they."”
Send them a reply.
Tell them this is a day of peace
on planet Earth.
Tell them we extend that peace
to the Sycorax.
And then tell them
this planet is armed
and we do not surrender.
Come on.
The Doctor wouldn't do this.
The old Doctor, the proper Doctor,
he'd wake up.
He'd save us.
You really love him, don't you?
They got the message.
Here comes the response.
What was that?
-Was that a reply?
-I don't know.
Looked like some sort of energy or static.
Almost like someone casting a spell.
LLEWELLYN: Maybe it's a different form
of language.
Some sort of ideogram or pictogram.
What the hell!
It's the light. It's the same light.
Sally? What are you doing, Sally?
Leave her. You'll hurt her.
-Let them pass.
-Where are they going?
What is wrong with you?
Jason?
-Jason?
-Sandra!
For no reason...he's just walking.
He won't stop walking.
There's a sort of light thing. Jason?
Stop it. Right now.
Please, Jason. Just stop!
They're all heading in the same direction.
It's only certain people.
Why isn't it affecting us?
Prime Minister,
it's happening all over the country.
Alan, come on, now stop this.
It's not funny anymore.
Come on, come back inside the house.
Catherine. Catherine, listen to Mummy.
You come back inside now.
And you, Jonathan.
You come back in with Mummy.
Jonathan, come back in with Mummy.
You're scaring me now. Come on.
Alan, help me out here, please.
As far as I can tell, they're heading for
any sort of high-rise building.
Anything with stairs. Anything with steps.
They're going all the way up.
They're going to the roof.
OFFICER: Just making my way
to the front of the building now.
There's hundreds of them. Oh, my God.
They're going right up to the edge.
They're gonna jump.
They're all gonna jump.
Sally, stop it.
It's Danny Llewellyn. Daniel Llewellyn.
Sally, just concentrate, listen to me.
You're being controlled.
We need you.
Stop it, Sally.
Jason, I'm talking to you! Just stop!
It's not just the whole country.
It's the whole world.
They've stopped. They've all stopped.
They're just standing there.
Right on the edge.
According to reports, it's like a third,
one third of the world's population.
That's two billion people ready to jump.
Surrender or they will die.
What do we do?
Nothing.
There's no one to save us. Not anymore.
Wait a minute. There is a pattern.
All these people tend to be father and son,
mother and daughter, brothers and sisters.
Family groups, but not husbands and wives.
Oh, my God.
It's Guinevere One.
Have you got medical records on file
for all your staff?
Of course we have. Yes.
-What about Torchwood?
-Still working on it.
Bear in mind,
they have just lost a third of their staff.
But do they have what we need?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, tell them to hurry up.
Here it is. Sally Jacobs.
Blood group, A positive.
-Who else walked out?
-Luke Parsons.
Luke Parsons. A positive.
Jeffrey Baxter.
Baxter. A positive.
That's it, they're all A positive.
How many people in the world
are A positive?
No idea.
But I bet it's one third.
-What's so special about that blood group?
-Nothing. But it's my fault.
Guinevere One, it's got one of those
plaques identifying the human race.
A message to the stars.
I mean, you don't expect anything
to come of it
but I put on maps and music and samples.
There's wheat seeds and water and...
And blood.
A positive.
The Sycorax have got a vial of A positive.
And, well, I don't know how,
but through that...
They control the blood.
-Oh, my God.
-There's only one more thing I can try.
Major, with me.
Ladies and gentlemen, if I may take
a moment during this terrible time.
It's hardly the Queen's speech,
I'm afraid that's been cancelled.
Did we ask about the royal family?
Oh.
They're on the roof.
But, ladies and gentlemen,
this crisis is unique,
and I'm afraid to say
it might get much worse.
I would ask you all to remain calm.
But I have one request.
Doctor...
if you're out there, we need you.
I don't know what to do.
If you can hear me, Doctor,
if anyone knows the Doctor,
if anyone can find him,
the situation has never been
more desperate.
Help us.
Please, Doctor, help us.
He's gone.
The Doctor's gone.
He left me, Mum.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sonic wave! It's the spaceship.
It's hit the atmosphere.
Mickey, we're gonna carry him.
Mum, get your stuff and some food.
We're going.
-Where to?
-The Tardis.
It's the only safe place on Earth.
-What are we going to do in there?
-Hide.
-Is that it?
-Mum, look in the sky.
There's a great, big alien invasion
and I don't know what to do, all right?
I've travelled with him
and I've seen all that stuff,
but when I'm stuck at home, I'm useless.
Now all we can do is run and hide
and I'm sorry.
Now, move.
Lift him up.
They're transmitting on screen.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
"Will the leader of this world
stand forward?"
I'm proud to represent this planet.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
"Come aboard."”
Well, how do I do that?
What's happening?
I would imagine it's called a teleport.
It's a helmet. They might be like us.
Or not.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Mum, will you just leave that stuff
and give us a hand?
It's food. You said we need...
Just leave it!
"You will surrender
or I will release the final...curse
"and your people will jump.”
If I can speak...
-Mr Llewellyn, you're a civilian.
-No.
I sent out the probe, I started it.
I made contact with these people.
This whole thing's my responsibility.
With respect, sir...
the human race is taking its first steps
towards the stars,
but we are like children compared to you.
Children who need help,
children who need compassion.
I beg of you now, show that compassion.
That man was your prisoner.
Even your species must have
articles of war forbidding...
Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
"Yes, we know who you are."”
"Surrender or they will die.”
If I do surrender,
how would that be better?
"Half is sold into slavery,
"or one third dies.
"Your choice."
(HISSING)
-No chance you can fly this thing?
-Not anymore, no.
You did it before.
I know, but it's sort of been
wiped out of my head, like it's forbidden.
If I try it again,
I think the universe rips in half.
-Ah. Better not, then.
-Maybe not.
-So what do we do? Just sit here?
-That's as good as it gets.
Right. Here we go.
-Nice cup of tea.
-The solution to everything.
Now stop your moaning.
I'll get the rest of the food.
Tea. Like we're having a picnic
while the world comes to an end.
It's very British.
How does this thing work?
'Cause if it picks up TV, maybe we can see
what's going on out there.
Maybe we've surrendered.
What do you do to it?
I don't know. It sort of tunes itself.
(BEEPING)
The noise, the bleeping.
They say it's machinery.
"Foreign machinery."
They're accusing us of hiding it. Conspiring.
"Bring it on board."
Rose?
Rose!
-Maybe it's a distress signal.
-Fat lot of good that's gonna do.
-Are you gonna be a misery all the time?
-Yes.
You should look at it from my point of view,
stuck in here with your mum's cooking.
Where is she?
I'd better give her a hand.
It might start raining missiles out there.
-Tell her anything from a tin, that's fine.
-Why don't you tell her yourself?
-I'm not that brave.
-Oh, I don't know.
Rose?
ROSE: Get off! Get off me!
The door! Close the door!
MICKEY: Leave her alone!
Rose.
Rose, I've got you.
My Lord. Oh, my precious thing.
The Doctor, is he with you?
No.
We're on our own.
(HISSING)
"The yellow girl,
she has the clever blue box.
"Therefore she speaks for your planet.”
-But, she can't.
-Yeah, I can.
-Don't you dare.
-Someone's got to be the Doctor.
-They'll kill you.
-It never stopped him.
(ALL ROARING)
I, um...
I address the Sycorax...
according to Article 15
of the Shadow Proclamation.
I command you to leave this world
with all the authority of...
the Slitheen Parliament
of Rexicoricophalvitorius
and, um...
the Gelth Confederacy...
as, uh, sanctioned...
by the Mighty Jagrafess and...
Oh! The Daleks.
Now leave this planet in peace!
In peace...
(ALL LAUGHING)
"You are very, very funny."
"And now you're going to die."”
-Leave her alone!
-Don't touch her!
"Did you think you were clever
"with your stolen words?"
"We are the Sycorax
and we stride the darkness.
(GASPING)
"Next to us, you are but a wailing child.
"If you are the best your planet
can offer as a champion..."
(IN ENGLISH) ...then your world
will be gutted...
-and your people enslaved.
-"...and your people enslaved."”
-Hold on, that's English.
-He's talking English.
You're talking English.
I would never dirty my tongue
with your primitive bile!
That's English. Can you hear English?
-Yeah, that's English.
-Definitely English.
I speak only Sycoraxic!
If I can hear English,
then it's being translated.
Which means it's working.
Which means...
Did you miss me?
-You can have someone's eye out with that.
-How dare...
Just can't get the staff. Now, you just wait.
I'm busy.
Mickey, hello!
And Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
Blimey, it's like 7his is Your Life.
Tea! That's all I needed. A good cup of tea.
Super-heated infusion
of free radicals and tannin,
just the thing for healing the synapses.
Now, first things first. Be honest...
-how do I look?
-Um...
-Different.
-Good different or bad different?
Just different.
Am I...ginger?
No, you're just sort of brown.
Oh, I wanted to be ginger.
I've never been ginger.
And you, Rose Tyler,
fat lot of good you were.
You gave up on me. Oh, that's rude.
Is that the sort of man I am now?
Am I rude? Rude and not ginger.
-I'm sorry. Who is this?
-I'm the Doctor.
He's the Doctor.
What happened to my Doctor?
Or is it a title that's just passed on?
I'm him. I'm literally him.
Same man, new face. Well, new everything.
-But you can't be.
-Harriet Jones.
We were trapped in Downing Street
and the one thing that scared you
wasn't the aliens, wasn't the war,
it was the thought of your mother
being on her own.
Oh, my God.
-Did you win the election?
-Landslide majority.
If I might interrupt?
Yes. Sorry. Hello, big fella.
-Who exactly are you?
-Well, that's the question.
I demand to know who you are!
(IMITATING SYCORAX LEADER)
I don't know!
See, that's the thing, I'm the Doctor
but beyond that, I just don't know.
I literally do not know who I am.
It's all untested.
Am I funny? Am I sarcastic?
Sexy?
A right old misery? Life and soul?
Right-handed, left-handed,
a gambler, a fighter,
a coward, a traitor, a liar, a nervous wreck?
I mean, judging by the evidence,
I've certainly got a gob.
And how am I gonna react when I see this?
A great big threatening button.
(DOCTOR LAUGHS)
A great big threatening button which must
not be pressed under any circumstances.
Am I right?
Let me guess,
it's some sort of control matrix. Hmm?
Hold on. What's feeding it?
And what have we got here?
Blood?
Yeah, definitely blood. Human blood.
A positive, with just a dash of iron.
But that means...
Blood control. Blood control!
Oh!
I haven't seen blood control for years!
You're controlling all the A positives.
Which leaves us with
a great big stinking problem,
'cause I really don't know who I am.
I don't know when to stop.
So if I see a great big threatening button
which should never, ever, ever be pressed,
-then I just want to do this.
-No!
-What the hell am I doing up here?
-Get away from the edge.
-You killed them!
-What do you think, big fella?
-Are they dead?
-We allow them to live.
Allow? You've no choice.
That's all blood control is.
Cheap bit of voodoo.
Scares the pants off you
but that's as far as it goes.
It's like hypnosis,
you can hypnotise someone
to walk like a chicken or sing like Elvis,
you can't hypnotise them to death.
Survival instinct's too strong.
Blood control was just
one form of conquest.
I can summon the armada
and take this world by force.
Well, yeah, you could. Yeah.
You could do that, of course you could.
But why?
Look at these people. These human beings.
Consider their potential.
From the day they arrive on the planet
and, blinking, step into the sun,
there is more to see than can ever be seen,
more to do than... No, hold on.
Sorry, that's 7he Lion King.
But the point still stands.
-Leave them alone.
-Or what?
Or...
I challenge you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Well, that struck a chord.
Am I right that the sanctified rules
of combat still apply?
-You stand as this world's champion?
-Thank you.
I've no idea who I am,
but you've just summed me up.
So, do you accept my challenge?
Or are you just a...
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(ALL ROARING)
-For the planet?
-For the planet.
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
Look out!
Oh, yeah, that helps. I wouldn't have
thought of that otherwise. Thanks.
Bit of fresh air?
Stay back!
Invalidate the challenge
and he wins the planet.
You cut my hand off.
Sycorax!
And now I know what sort of man I am.
I'm lucky 'cause quite by chance,
I'm still within the first 15 hours
of my regeneration cycle.
Which means I've got just enough
residual cellular energy
to do this.
Witchcraft.
Time Lord.
Doctor!
-Oh, so I'm still the Doctor, then?
-No arguments from me.
You want to know the best bit?
This new hand...
it's a fighting hand!
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
I win.
Then kill me.
I'll spare your life
if you'll take this champion's command.
Leave this planet and never return.
-What do you say?
-Yes.
Swear on the blood of your species.
I swear.
There we are, then. Thanks for that.
Cheers, big fella.
Bravo!
That says it all. Bravo.
Not bad for a man in his jiro jams.
Very Arthur Dent.
Now, there was a nice man.
Hold on, what have I got in here?
A satsuma.
Ah, that friend of your mother's.
He does like his snacks, doesn't he?
But doesn't that just sum up Christmas?
You go through all those presents
and right at the end,
tucked away at the bottom,
there's always one stupid old satsuma.
Who wants a satsuma...
No second chances.
I'm that sort of a man.
By the ancient rites of combat,
I forbid you to scavenge here
for the rest of time.
And when you go back to the stars
and tell others of this planet,
when you tell them of its riches,
its people, its potential,
when you talk of the Earth,
then make sure that you tell them this.
It is defended.
-ROSE: Where are we?
-We're just off Bloxsome Road.
We're just round the corner. We did it!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Go on, my son! Oh, yeah!
Yeah. Don't come back!
It is defended!
-My Doctor.
-Prime Minister.
Absolutely the same man.
-Are there many more out there?
-Ooh, not just Sycorax.
Hundreds of species.
Thousands of them.
And the human race
is drawing attention to itself.
Everyday you're sending out probes,
messages and signals.
This planet's so noisy.
You're getting noticed, more and more.
You better get used to it.
-Rose!
-Mum.
Talking of trouble...
-Oh, my God! Rose.
-He did it, Mum.
(MOBILE RINGING)
You did it, too!
It was the tea. Fixed his head.
That's all I needed. Cup of tea.
-I said so.
-And look at him.
Is it him, though? Is it really the Doctor?
Oh, my God!
It's the bleeding Prime Minister!
Come here, you.
JACKIE: Are you better?
It's a message from Torchwood.
They say they're ready.
JACKIE: You left me.
What do I do with the food?
Tell them to fire.
Fire at will.
What is that? What's happening?
-That was murder.
-That was defence.
It's adapted from alien technology.
-A ship that fell to Earth ten years ago.
-But they were leaving.
You said yourself, Doctor,
they'd go back to the stars
and tell others about the Earth.
I'm sorry, Doctor, but you're not here
all the time. You come and go.
It happened today.
Mr Llewellyn and the Major.
They were murdered. They died right
in front of me while you were sleeping.
In which case, we have to defend ourselves.
-Britain's golden age.
-It comes with a price.
I gave them the wrong warning.
I should have told them
to run as fast as they can.
Run and hide because the monsters
are coming. The human race.
Those are the people I represent.
I did it on their behalf.
And I should have stopped you.
What does that make you, Doctor?
Another alien threat?
Don't challenge me, Harriet Jones,
"cause I'm a completely new man.
I could bring down your government
with a single word.
You're the most remarkable man
I've ever met,
but I don't think
you're quite capable of that.
No. You're right. Not a single word.
-Just six.
-I don't think so.
-Six words.
-Stop it.
Six.
Don't you think she looks tired?
-What did he say?
-Nothing, really.
-Nothing. I don't know.
Doctor!
Doctor, what did... What was that?
What did he say?
What did you say, Doctor? Doctor!
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's yours.
It's pink! It should be yours.
Look, it's Harriet Jones.
REPORTER: Prime Minister, is it true
you're no longer fit to be in position?
No. Now, can we talk about other things?
Is it true you're unfit for office?
Look, there is nothing wrong
with my health.
I don't know where these stories
are coming from.
And a vote of no confidence
ls completely unjustified.
Are you going to resign?
On today of all days, I find I'm fine.
Look at me, I'm fine. I look fine, I feel fine.
-It's Bev. She says go and look outside.
-Why?
I don't know. Just go outside and look.
Come on, shift.
That's beautiful.
What are they? Meteors?
It's the spaceship
breaking up in the atmosphere.
This isn't snow. It's ash.
Okay, not so beautiful.
And this is a brand-new planet Earth.
No denying the existence of aliens now.
Everyone saw it.
Everything's new.
And what about you?
What are you gonna do next?
Well...
back to the Tardis, same old life.
-On your own?
-Why, don't you want to come?
-Well, yeah.
-Do you?
-Yeah.
-Well, I just thought...
-'cause I'd changed.
-Yeah, I thought 'cause you'd changed...
you might not want me anymore.
-Oh, I'd love you to come.
-Okay.
You're never gonna stay, are you?
There's just so much out there.
So much to see. I've got to.
Yeah.
Well, I reckon you're mad. The pair of you.
-It's like you go looking for trouble.
-Trouble's just the bits in-between.
It's all waiting out there, Jackie.
And it's brand-new to me.
All those planets, creatures and horizons,
haven't seen them yet.
Not with these eyes.
And it is gonna be...
fantastic.
That hand of yours
still gives me the creeps.
So, where are we gonna go first?
Um...
That way. No, hold on.
-That way.
You think?
Yeah. That way.
-So, where are we going?
-Further than we've ever gone before.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
-I don't believe we've met.
-I'm the Doctor.
May I introduce Miss Sarah Jane Smith?
DOCTOR: K-9!
Said he'll talk to a wanderer.
To the man without a home.
Might I introduce
Her Majesty, Queen Victoria?
Give her back to me.
Bullets can't stop it.