(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
DOCTOR ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
Oh, blimey! Okay.
You can probably leave a message
at the tone or something.
Sorry, I wasn't really trying to
do this, I was looking for the brakes!
(ANSWERPHONE BEEPS)
AMY: Doctor?
Doctor, can you hear me?
Are you ever going to hear this?
You don't even know you've
got an answerphone.
How can you be so clever and so
completely stupid at the same time?
Or if you can hear this,
please just pick up the phone.
Don't get confused, I'm not invisible
or trapped in a space bottle
or something.
I'm just talking on the answerphone.
Just pick up the phone!
You said you'd find my baby.
You said you'd find Melody.
Have you found her?
Because you promised.
I know she's going to be okay.
I know she'll grow up to be River,
but that's not the point.
I don't want to miss all those years,
you know, I..
I can't stand it. Can't!
Please, Doctor, please.
Okay, phone me back
when you know something.
Please, Doctor, at least do that.
As soon as you know. Okay?
All right, bye.
(HANGS UP, ANSWERPHONE BEEPS)
(SIGHS)