(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Hello.
Why are you sitting on the swing?
-Why shouldn't I?
-Because you're old.
Yeah, that's true. That, that...
That is very true.
My mum says
I shouldn't talk to strange men.
Ah, your mum's right.
-Are you strange?
-(LAUGHS)
Oh, dear. I'm way past strange.
-I think I'm probably incredible.
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
Are you lonely?
-And why would I be lonely?
-Because you're sad.
-Have you lost something?
-No.
When I lose something,
I go to a quiet place
and I close my eyes
and then I can remember where I put it.
-Good plan.
-I'm always losing things.
I lost my best pencil,
my schoolbag, my gran
-and my mojo.
-Your mojo?
-I got it back, though.
-Hey, that's good.
-What did you lose?
-My friend.
I met her twice before
and I lost her both times
and now I don't think
I'll ever find her again.
-Have you been looking?
-Yeah, everywhere.
-That's sad.
-It is a bit.
-Hey. Is that your mum?
-Yeah.
I'd better go and see
if she's all right.
Yeah. I think you better had.
How are you going to find her?
Well, the first two times I met her
I just sort of bumped into her,
so I thought maybe if I just
wandered about a bit,
I might bump into her again.
You know, like...destiny, sort of.
-That's rubbish.
-(CHUCKLES)
I think it probably is.
Hey, maybe I could find a quiet room
and have a good think about it instead.
-That would be better.
-Yeah.
-Goodbye.
Mister!
I hope you find her again.
So do 1.
-Who was that?
-I was talking to a sad man.
Clara Oswald, what have I told you
about talking to strange men?