Silence will fall.
RIVER: 7he Doctor we saw on the beach
was a future version.
AMY: Well, that's still going to happen,
he's still going to die.
-I'm pregnant.
-Whatever happens, we will find you.
(GASPING)
AMY: The whole time that I thought I was
on the Tardis, I was really here.
They've taken Amy, and our baby.
I'm going after her.
Amelia Pond! Get your coat.
Is Melody human?
-Course she is.
-Look closer.
Human plus Time Lord.
-What is she?
-Hope, in this endless, bitter war.
Against who?
Against you, Doctor.
And now they've taken a child,
and they're going to turn her
into a weapon just to bring you down.
Who are you? Why are you in prison?
Who did you kill?
Tell me who you are.
I am telling you.
Rory and Amy, I know where
to find your daughter
and on my life, she will be saved.
WOMAN: The Doctor will find
your daughter,
and he will care for her,
whatever it takes.
It's me. I'm your daughter.
Okay, left, sharp turn.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Okay, right! No, no, no!
I mean left. No, sorry, right, right.
I definitely meant right!
(YELPS)
Now loop the loop.
Stop. Stop!
Seriously?
Well, you never answer your phone.
Okay, you've had all summer,
have you found her?
Have you found Melody?
-Permission?
-Granted.
You know who she grows up to be.
So you know I will find her.
But you haven't yet.
Hang on, what's this bit?
AMY: That wasn't us.
Um...
I don't...
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
You said he was funny.
-You never said he was hot.
-Mels!
What are you doing here?
Following you. What do you think?
Um, where did you get the car?
It's mine...ish.
Oh, Mels, not again.
You can't keep this,
you're going to end up in prison.
Sorry. Hello.
Doctor not following this.
Doctor very lost.
You never said I was hot?
Is that the phone box?
The "bigger on the inside" phone box?
Oh, time travel. That's just brilliant.
Yeah, I've heard a lot about you.
I'm their best mate.
Then why don't I know you?
I danced with everyone at the wedding.
The women were all brilliant.
The men were a bit shy.
I don't do weddings.
(SIREN WAILING)
And that's me, out of time.
-Mels, what are you doing?
-For God's sake!
I need out of here, now.
Anywhere in particular?
Let's see, you've got a time machine,
I've got a gun.
What the hell? Let's kill Hitler.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
-Is he hot?
-No, he's funny.
But how can he travel in time?
'Cause he's got a time machine, stupid.
I thought we were playing hide-and-seek.
I've been hiding for hours.
Well, we just haven't found you yet.
Okay.
-Hi, Mels.
-Hi, Rory.
Mels, did you not understand
the question?
I'm asking you why the Titanic sank.
Because the Doctor didn't save it.
Except you don't know about the Doctor,
'cause you're stupid.
Why are you always in trouble?
You're the most in trouble
in the whole school, except for boys.
-And you.
-I count as a boy.
-Am I getting warm?
-MELS: Yes, Rory.
Mels...
A significant factor
in Hitler's rise to power
was the fact
that the Doctor didn't stop him.
(BELL BUZZING)
You can't keep doing this.
Mels!
I was late. I took a bus.
-Uh, you stole a bus.
-Who steals a bus?
I returned it.
You drove it through
the Botanical Garden.
Shortcut.
Why can't you just act like a person?
Hmm?
Like a normal, legal person?
I don't know. Maybe I need a Doctor.
Stop it.
Uh, I'd better go,
I'm on ear lies tomorrow.
It's all right for you. You've got
Mr Perfect keeping you right.
He's not even real,
just a stupid dream when I was a kid.
No, I wasn't talking about him.
What, Rory?
How have I got Rory?
Yeah, how has she got me?
-He's not mine.
-No.
No. I'm not hers.
Oh, come on. Seriously,
it's got to be you two.
Oh, cut to the song,
it's getting boring.
Nice thought, okay?
But completely impossible.
Yeah, impossible.
I'd love to, he's gorgeous. He's my
favourite guy, but he's, you know,
-gay.
-A friend.
-I'm not gay.
-Yes, you are.
No. No, I'm not.
Course you are. Don't be stupid.
In the whole time I've known you,
when have you shown
the slightest interest in a girl?
Penny in the air.
I've known you for, what, ten years?
I've seen you practically every day.
Name one girl you've paid
the slightest bit of attention to.
Oh, my God, Rory!
And the penny drops.
Rory!
Catch you later, time boy.
(GUNSHOT)
You shot it!
You shot my Tardis!
You shot the console!
It's your fault!
Ahhh!
How is it my fault?
You said guns didn't work in this place.
You said we were in
a state of temporal grace.
That was a clever lie, you idiot.
Anyone can tell that was a clever lie!
(SCREAMING)
(WHIRRING)
(CHATTERING)
Okay, do we like him?
Costume want to know about the suit.
Just colour and shape.
Don't need anything detachable.
Musculature good to go.
-That was quick.
-Just showing off.
Art Department want to
talk about skin tone.
Yes, I do, I don't trust the senses.
I want to take a look myself.
We're in a hurry,
we're not trying to win an award.
Yeah, that's what you said
when you made Rasputin green.
Okay, get your fat one up there.
-Run!
-Yes, Captain.
Harriet's going to eyeball.
Everyone else, good to go. Please.
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Musculature, online.
511", confirmed.
Harriet, are you up there yet?
(ALARM BLARING)
MAN: Welcome. You are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
Harriet, have you updated
your privileges?
Yes, of course I have.
Look, I'm staff, see? Look, staff.
You are authorised.
Your existence will continue.
I don't understand.
Harriet, the ship.
Five seconds to eyeball.
Shades 44 to 89, peaking at 60.
Standard density.
He's sweating a bit, so compensate.
What are you?
MAN ON PA: All hands, prepare for
tessellation, prepare for tessellation.
(GASPING)
Okay. Clean up.
(SCREAMING)
-Who is he?
-Erich Zimmerman.
Loyal member of the Nazi Party.
Guilty of category III hate crimes.
Well, then, leave him to the antibodies.
(BUZZING)
Welcome. You are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
Welcome. You will experience a tingling
sensation and then death.
Remain calm
while your life is extracted.
(SCREAMING)
What do you want?
Who let you in here?
What's wrong with the shock absorbers?
-Problem in the knees.
-Let's hope we don't have to run.
Do not call for help.
This room has been sound-screened.
You have been found guilty.
Justice mode activating.
Hang on! This is 1938, we're too early.
We need to go later in his time stream.
Something else. We've got incoming.
Onscreen.
(WHOOSHING)
What the hell is that?
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
Out, out, out! Everybody out. Don't
breathe in the smoke, let's get out.
-Where are we?
-A room. A long room.
I don't know what room.
I haven't memorised every room
in the universe yet,
I had yesterday off.
Mels! Don't go in there.
Bad smoke. Don't breathe
the bad, bad smoke.
Bad, deadly smoke,
because somebody shot my Tardis!
Doctor, this guy, I think he's hurt.
MAN: Transmit normal life signs.
Artificial gravity holding,
we should get it upright while we can.
Hang on.
No, he's fine.
Oh! Hello. Sorry,
is this is your office?
Had a sort of collision with my vehicle.
Fault's on both sides,
let's say no more about...
it.
What's up? No, it can't be, Doctor.
Thank you, whoever you are.
I think you have just saved my life.
Believe me,
it was an accident.
What is this thing?
What did he mean
we just saved his life?
We could not have just saved Hitler.
You see? Time travel.
It never goes to plan.
This box, what is it?
It's a police telephone box
from London, England.
That's right, Adolf.
The British are coming.
No! Stop him!
Damage report! Damage report!
Sit still. Shut up.
-Are you okay?
-Yes.
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
I think he missed.
-He was going to kill me.
-Shut up, Hitler.
Rory, take Hitler and put him
in that cupboard over there. Now. Do it.
Right.
Putting Hitler in the cupboard.
Cupboard.
Hitler, Hitler, cupboard. Come on.
-But I am the Fuhrer!
-Right, in you go.
Who are you?
DOCTOR: Are you okay?
WOMAN: Sir, what do we do now?
Suggestion.
We should go into surveillance mode.
Agreed. Let's faint.
Oh! I...
-I think he just fainted.
-Yes, that was a faint.
Perfect faint.
Mels?
MELS: Hitler...
What about him?
Lousy shot.
Mels! Mels?
-Rory!
-N 0, ho, no, no!
Right, we've got to stop the bleeding.
Sir, that blue box...
We've got a match.
We're trying to bag war criminals,
we've got the biggest one ever
right under our noses.
Forget Hitler.
We take this one down,
the Justice Department
will give us the rest of the year off.
-Are you sure?
-There's no question.
It's her.
How bad is it, Rory? What can we do?
Just keep her conscious.
Stay with us, Mels!
Hey, look at me. Just hold on.
I used to
dream about you.
All those stories Amy used to tell me.
What stories? Tell me what stories?
Vampires in Venice?
When I was little,
I was going to marry you.
Good idea, let's get married.
You stay alive and I'll marry you. Deal?
Shouldn't you ask
my parents' permission?
As soon as you're well,
I'll get them on the phone.
Might as well do it now.
Since they're both right here.
Penny in the air.
Penny drops.
What the hell is going on?
Back, back, back. Get back!
Last time I did this, I...
I ended up a toddler.
In the middle of New York.
Okay, Doctor,
explain what is happening, please.
Mels, short for...
Melody.
Yeah, I named my daughter after her.
You named your daughter
after your daughter.
It took me years to find you two.
I'm so glad I did.
And you see?
It all worked out in the end, didn't it?
You got to raise me after all.
You're Melody?
-But, if she's Melody, that means...
-Shut up, Dad.
I'm focusing on a dress size.
(MELS SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Right. Let's see, then.
Ooh, it's all going on down there,
isn't it?
The hair!
(GASPING) The hair!
It just doesn't stop, does it?
Look at that.
Everything changes.
Oh, but I love it. I love it!
I'm all sort of...mature.
Hello, Benjamin.
(WHISPERS) Who's Benjamin?
The teeth.
(GASPING) The teeth.
The teeth. Oh, look at them!
Watch out, that bow tie.
Excuse me, you lot.
I need to weigh myself.
That's Melody.
It's River Song.
Who's River Song?
Spoilers.
Spoilers? What spoilers?
Hang on, just something I have to check.
Does anybody else find this day
just a bit difficult?
I'm getting this sort of banging
in my head.
Yeah, I think that's Hitler
in the cupboard.
That's not helping.
This isn't the River Song we know yet.
This is her right at the start.
Doesn't even know her name.
RIVER: Oh! That's magnificent!
I'm going to wear lots of jodhpurs.
Well, that's her, all right.
Melody Pond.
The woman who kills the Doctor.
Well, now, enough of all that.
-Down to business.
-Oh! Hello.
I thought we were getting married?
I told you. I'm not a wedding person.
Doctor, what's she doing?
-What she's programmed to.
-And where'd she get the gun?
Hello, Benjamin.
You noticed.
(GUN CLICKS)
Of course I noticed.
(SCREAMING)
(CLICKS)
As soon as I knew you were coming,
I tidied up a bit.
I know you did.
Watch out, that bow tie.
I know you know.
Goodness, is killing you
going to take all day?
Why? You busy?
Oh, I'm not complaining.
If you were in a hurry, you could have
killed me in the cornfield.
We'd only just met.
I'm a psychopath, I'm not rude.
(GUN CLICKING, AMY SCREAMS)
You are not a psychopath.
Why would she be a psychopath?
Oh, Mummy, Mummy, pay attention.
I was trained and conditioned
for one purpose.
-I was born to kill the Doctor.
-Demon's Run.
Remember?
This is what they were building.
My bespoke psychopath.
-I'm all yours, sweetie.
-Only River Song gets to call me that.
-And who's River Song?
-An old friend of mine.
Stupid name.
(GASPING) Look at that!
Berlin on the eve of war.
A whole world
about to tear itself apart.
Now, that's my kind of town.
Mum, Dad, don't follow me.
And yes, that is a warning.
No warning for me, then?
No need, my love.
The deed is done. And so are you.
Doctor, what's wrong?
What have you done?
River!
Oh, River, River, River.
More than a friend, I think.
What have you done?
It was never going to be a gun for you,
Doctor,
the man of peace,
who understands every kind
of warfare except,
perhaps, the cruellest.
I'm all yours, sweetie.
Kiss, kiss.
What's wrong with you?
What's she done to you?
Poisoned me, but I'm fine.
Well, no. I'm dying.
-But I've got a plan.
-What plan?
Not dying, see? Fine.
Scanning him.
-He's dying, all right.
-But he can't be.
(GROANING IN PAIN)
Okay, what do we do? How do we help you?
Take this. The Tardis can override it.
Now, go, get after her.
(MEN SHOUTING)
Hello, boys.
You said the smoke was deadly.
No, the smoke's fine,
the poison will kill me first.
-Now, get after River...
-I don't understand, okay?
One minute she's going to marry you,
and then she's going to kill you.
Ah, well, she's been brainwashed,
it all makes sense.
Plus, she's a woman.
Oh, shut up, I'm dying.
Extractor fans on!
Oh! That worked.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was on my way to this gay gypsy
Bar Mitzvah for the disabled,
when I suddenly thought,
"Gosh, the Third Reich's a bit rubbish.
"I think I'lLL kill the Fuhrer.”
Who's with me?
Shoot her.
-No!
-(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
Tip for you all,
never shoot a girl
while she's regenerating.
(RIVER LAUGHING)
Ah!
RIVER: Now, that hit the spot.
Thanks, boys. Ha! Call me.
What are you doing?
New body, new town...
I'm going shopping.
Look, I know how this looks.
Let me explain everything
from the beginning.
-Heil!
Come on!
Can you ride a motorbike?
I expect so. It's that sort of day.
Okay. This time, let's do the bike, too.
You see? He can't be dying.
But the Doctor is confirmed deceased.
We have his record.
But he doesn't die here.
He does in Utah, by Lake Silencio,
April 22nd, 2011.
Time can be rewritten. Remember Kennedy?
This time can't.
It's a confirmed, fixed point.
The Doctor must always die exactly then.
He always has. And he always will.
Then someone screwed up,
because he's dying right now.
Shut it down. I need an interface.
Voice interface, come on, emergency.
Voice interface enabled.
No, no, no! Give me someone I like!
Oh! Thanks! Give me guilt.
Also guilt.
More quilt. Ahh...
Come on! There must be someone left in
the universe I haven't screwed up yet.
-Ah.
-AMELIA: Voice interface enabled.
Oh.
Amelia Pond!
Before I got it all wrong.
My sweet little Amelia.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
Hey, let's run away and have adventures.
Come along, Pond.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
You are so Scottish. How am I doing?
Your system has been contaminated
by the poison of the Judas Tree.
You will be dead in 32 minutes.
Okay, so, basically better regenerate.
That's what you're saying?
Regeneration disabled.
You will be dead in 32 minutes.
Unless I'm cured, yeah?
There is no cure.
You will be dead in 32 minutes.
Why do you keep saying that?
Because you will be dead in 32 minutes.
You see? There you go again.
Basically skipping 31 whole minutes
when I'm absolutely fine.
It's Scottish, that's all I'm saying.
You will be fine for 31 minutes.
You will be dead in 32 minutes.
Scotland's never conquered anywhere,
you know.
Not even a Shetland.
River needs me.
She's only just beginning,
I can't die now.
You will not die now.
You will die in 32 minutes.
I'm going out in the first round.
Ringing any bells?
Ahh!
Need something for the pain now.
Come on, Amelia.
It's me.
Please.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
Amelia, listen to me.
I can be brave for you.
But you have got to tell me how.
I am not Amelia Pond.
I am a voice interface.
(SOFTLY) Amelia...
Please...
Fish fingers and custard.
What did you say?
Fish fingers and custard?
Ah! Amelia Pond.
Fish...fingers...and custard!
Fish...fingers...
and custard!
-Mmm...
-It's good.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
(GUNSHOTS)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I don't have a thing to wear.
(CHUCKLES)
Take off your clothes.
Okay. All of Berlin, how do we find her?
I don't know. Look for clues.
-Clues? What kind of clues?
-Shut up!
(SCREAMING)
Okay...
No...
Hmm... Now look at that.
Now, that's fun!
(GIGGLING) From every angle.
Now, dear, I told you not to follow me.
(GASPING)
Okay. Okay.
I'm trapped inside
a giant robot replica of my wife.
I'm really trying not to see this
as a metaphor.
AMY: How can we be in here?
How do we fit?
-Miniaturisation ray.
-How would you know that?
Well, there was a ray
and we were miniaturised.
(DOOR OPENING)
Welcome, you are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
Um, what's that?
Uh, I don't know. It's in your head!
Please remain calm
while your life is terminated.
-We come in peace!
-Ha ha. When has that ever worked?
Oh, shut up!
Please cooperate in your officially
sanctioned termination.
It is normal to experience fear
during your incineration.
-Stop, I got a sonic.
-What are you doing?
-I don't know.
-Okay, psychic intervention.
-Just point and think.
-What do I think?
I don't know!
It's okay. Stay still and don't move.
Privileges activated.
See? Activated.
You are authorised.
Your existence will continue.
You can put your hands down.
This is Justice Department
Vehicle 6018.
You're not guilty of anything.
Welcome aboard the Tesselecta.
I might take the age down a little.
Just gradually,
to freak people out.
You killed the Doctor.
Oh, yes, I know, dear.
I hope you're not going to keep on
about it.
Oh! Regeneration.
It's a whole new colouring to work with.
(CHUCKLING)
You killed the Doctor.
On the orders of the movement known as
the Silence and Academy of the Question.
You accept and know this to be true.
Quite honestly, I don't really remember.
It was all a bit of a jumble.
No, no! Get off me!
Sorry?
Did you say she killed the Doctor?
The Doctor?
Doctor who?
-You said he was dying!
-WOMAN: He is.
When you're done here,
your memories will be wiped
-and you'll be able to...
-Doctor?
RIVER: You're dying.
And you stopped to change?
Oh, you should always waste time
when you don't have any.
Time is not the boss of you! Rule 408.
Amelia Pond, judgement death machine.
Why am I not surprised?
Sonic cane.
Are you serious?
DOCTOR: Never knowingly.
Never knowingly be serious.
Rule 27. You might want to
write these down.
Oh! It's a robot!
With 423 life signs inside,
a robot worked by tiny people.
Love it! But how did you all
get in there, though?
Bigger on the inside?
No. Basic miniaturisation
sustained by a compression field.
Ooh! Watch what you eat.
It'll get you every time.
Amy, if you and Rory are okay,
signal me.
(BUZZING)
Thanking you.
MAN: How did you do that?
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
So sorry. Leg went to sleep.
Just had a quick left-leg power nap.
I forgot I had one scheduled.
Actually, better sit down.
I think I heard the right one yawning.
(SCREAMING)
Don't you touch her!
Do not harm her in any way!
(MOANING)
Why would you care?
She's the woman who kills you.
I'm not dead.
You're dying.
Well, at least I'm not
a time travelling, shape-shifting robot
operated by miniaturised cross people,
which I have got to admit
I didn't see coming.
What do you want with her?
She's Melody Pond.
According to our records,
the woman who kills the Doctor.
And I'm the Doctor,
so what's it got to do with you?
(BEEPING)
Throughout history, many criminals
have gone unpunished in their lifetimes.
Time travel has...responsibilities.
(LAUGHING)
What? You got yourselves time travel
so you decided to punish dead people?
We don't kill them. We extract them
near the end of their
established time lines.
Then what?
Give them hell.
I'd ask you who you think you are, but
I think the answer is pretty obvious.
So who do you think I am?
Huh?
The woman who killed the Doctor.
It sounds like you've
got my biography in there.
I'd love a peek.
Our records office is sealed
to the public.
Foreknowledge is dangerous.
Yeah, well, I'll be dead
in three minutes.
There isn't much foreknowledge left.
Sorry, can't do that.
That man is my best friend.
That woman is my daughter.
You give him anything he wants.
If she's family, she has privileges.
Say, "Access personal records,
the Doctor."”
Access personal records, the Doctor.
Records available.
(GRUNTS)
Question.
I'm dying.
-Who wants me dead?
-The Silence.
What is the Silence?
Why is it called that? What...
What does it mean?
The Silence is not a species.
It is a religious order or movement.
Their core belief is that silence
will fall when the question is asked.
What question?
The first question.
The oldest question in the universe.
Hidden in plain sight.
Yes, but what is the question?
Unknown.
Oh, well, fat load of use that is,
you big ginge!
You call yourselves the records...
(SCREAMING)
Kidneys are always the first to quit.
Ahh... I've had better, you know.
Okay, he's finished.
Oh, my God!
Well, then, let's do what we do.
Give her hell!
(SCREAMING)
Amy, Rory...
Amy...
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
(BEEPING)
You can talk to him.
What do we do?
This is me. This is me actually talking.
Just stop them. She's your daughter.
Just stop them!
How, how? How?
Just do it!
Privileges activated. See?
She is your daughter. Just stop them.
RORY: What are you doing?
Hunting and thinking. Get ready to run.
(ALARM RINGING)
You are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
Okay, Captain, release her now
or I take down the whole Tesselecta.
-Amy...
-You can't.
Hey.
(ALARMS BLARING)
Rory, go!
-All privileges withdrawn.
-What have you done?
All life forms prepare
for immediate decease.
You will experience a tingling sensation
and then death.
-Shut it down!
-I'm trying!
Shut everything down!
Ahh!
Please. Now we have to
save your parents.
Don't run. Now, I know you're scared.
But never run when you're scared.
Rule seven. Please.
Remain calm
while your life is extracted.
-Come on, keep running!
-Where?
I don't know. Just run!
Mothership.
Mothership, get us out of here.
Emergency beam-up now.
Everyone!
Only two life forms remain.
This will be rectified.
-Where'd everyone go?
-How can they just disappear?
Doctor, can you hear us?
Doctor?
Doctor, help us!
Doctor, please!
(MOANING)
AMY: Doctor...
Help!
RIVER: Look at you,
you still care.
Doctor, help!
Doctor, help us!
Please help us!
It's impressive, I'll give you that.
River, please.
Again!
Who is this River?
She's got to be a woman.
Am I right?
DOCTOR: Help me...
save Amy and Rory.
Help me.
Tell me about her.
Go on.
Ahh! Just...
help me.
(ECHOING) You are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
You are unauthorised.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You are unauthorised.
Your death will now be implemented.
Doctor?
Doctor, you did it!
(BOTH LAUGHING) You did it!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
I seem to be able to fly her.
She showed me how.
She taught me.
The Doctor says I am the child
of the Tardis.
What does he mean?
Where is he?
You can't die now.
I know you don't die now.
Oh, Pond!
You've got a schedule for everything.
It doesn't... It doesn't make any sense.
Doctor, what do we do? Come on!
How do we help you?
Sorry, Rory, you can't.
Nobody can.
Ponds, listen to me.
I need to talk to your daughter.
Find her.
Find River Song.
And tell her something from me.
Tell her what?
(WHISPERING)
(GASPING) Well, I'm sure she knows.
Who's River Song?
Are you still working?
Because I'm still a relative.
Access files on River Song.
Records available.
Show me her.
Show me River Song.
Melody...
What did he say?
The Doctor gave you
a message for River Song.
What was it?
What's happening?
River, what are you doing?
Just tell me.
The Doctor...
Is he worth it?
Yes! Yes, mmm-hmm, he is.
(GASPING)
River?
No... What are you doing?
Hello, sweetie.
Hey.
-Where am I?
-You're safe now.
Apparently, you used all your remaining
regenerations in one go.
You shouldn't have done that.
Mother,
I had to try.
I know.
He said no one could save him.
But he must have known I could.
Rule one,
the Doctor lies.
She just needs to rest.
She'll be absolutely fine.
No...
she won't.
She will be...
amazing!
So that's it? We just leave her there?
Sisters of the Infinite Schism,
greatest hospital in the universe.
Yeah, but she's our daughter.
Doctor, she's River,
and she's our daughter.
Amy, I know.
But we have to let her
make her own way now.
We have too much foreknowledge,
it's a...
dangerous thing, foreknowledge.
-What's that?
-Nothing!
Just some data I downloaded from
the Tesselecta, very boring.
Doctor, River was brainwashed
to kill you, right?
Well, she did kill me and then she used
her remaining lives to bring me back.
As firsts dates go,
I'd say that was mixed signals.
But that stuff
that they put in her head.
Is that gone now?
The River that we know in the future,
she is in prison, for murder.
Whose murder?
Will we see her again?
Oh, she'll come looking for us.
Yeah, but how? How do people
even look for you?
Oh, Pond!
Haven't you figured that one out yet?
So then, tell me,
why do you want to study archaeology?
Well, to be perfectly honest, Professor,
I'm looking for a good man.
(WHISPERING) Please save me
from the monsters.
DOCTOR: Tell me about George.
Well, he's scared to death
of everything.
George, you have to face your fears.
You have to face them now!
(SCREAMING)
We're dead, again.
You see these eyes? They're old eyes.
(SCREAMING)
The only thing I can tell you...
monsters are real.
(LAUGHING)