Danger!
This is a warning.
A warning to the whole world.
You're looking for wi-fi.
Sometimes you see something...
a bit like this.
Don't click it.
Do not click it.
Once you've clicked it,
they're in your computer.
(BEEPING)
They can see you.
If they can see you,
they might choose you.
And if they do, you die.
In 24 hours, you're dead.
For a while.
People's souls are being
uploaded to the internet.
Some people get stuck.
Their minds,
their souls, trapped in the wi-fi.
MAN: (ECHOING) I don't know where I am.
Like echoes, like ghosts.
Sometimes you can hear their screams,
on the radio,
on the telly or on the net.
WOMAN 1: I don't know where I am.
WOMAN 2: I don't know where I am.
-This is real. This is not a hoax...
-WOMAN 3: Please help me.
I don't know where I am.
-...or a joke...
-(SPEAKING JAPANESE)
-...or a story.
-I don't know where I am.
This is real and I know that.
(VOICE BREAKING)
'Cause I don't know where I am.
Please.
Please, if... If you can hear me...
If you can hear me,
I don't know where I am.
ALL: (OVERLAPPING)
(ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Wake the Abbot,
the bells of Saint John are ringing.
(BELL TOLLING)
We must go to him.
They call him the Mad Monk, don't they?
They shouldn't.
He's definitely not a monk.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm sorry to intrude.
The bells of Saint John are ringing.
I'm going to need a horse.
Is that her?
The woman twice dead.
And her final message.
He has withdrawn to this place
of peace and solitude
that he might divine her meaning.
If he truly is mad,
then this is his madness.
Angie? Is the internet working?
I'm trying to phone the helpline,
they won't answer.
-It's working for me.
-Can I use it when you're finished?
More than one person can use
the internet at a time, Clara.
-You doing your homework?
-Shut up, you're not my mum.
And I'm not trying to be, okay?
Right.
Yes! Angie's probably fine on her own.
You could probably have the night off.
I'm okay. I'll be upstairs trying
to figure out my computer.
Anyway, the adverts are in.
So, hopefully, we'll find someone.
I'm here as long as you need me.
GEORGE: Good. Right.
Come on, Artie. Time to go.
-What chapter are you on?
-Ten.
(GASPS) Eleven is the best.
You'll cry your eyes out.
GEORGE: Artie!
Oh, come on! Just answer.
Just pick it up. Pick it up. Pick it up.
Pick it up. Pick it up.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
That is not supposed to happen.
-Hello?
-Ah, hello! I can't find the internet.
-Sorry?
-It's gone. The internet.
Can't find it anywhere. Where is it?
-The internet?
-Yes, the internet.
Why don't I have the internet?
It's 1207.
I've got half past three.
Am I phoning a different time zone?
Yeah, you really sort of are.
-Will it show up on the bill?
-Oh, I dread to think.
Listen, where did you get this number?
The woman in the shop wrote it down.
It's a helpline, isn't it?
She said it's the best helpline
out there. In the universe, she said.
What woman? Who was she?
I don't know. The woman in the shop.
So, why isn't there internet?
Shouldn't it just sort of be there?
Look, listen. I'm not actually...
This isn't...
You have clicked on the wi-fi button,
haven't you?
Hang on. Um...
Wi-fi...
Click on the wi-fi,
you'll see a list of names.
-You see one you recognise...
-It's asking me for a password.
Is it okay if I go and see Nina?
-You can call her mum.
-Sure.
Um, what's the password
for the internet?
R-Y-C-B-A-R-1-2-3.
-How am I supposed to remember that?
-(SIGHS)
-Is it an evil spirit?
-It's a woman.
Hang on. Just a mo.
Run you clever boy and remember...
One...
Run, you clever boy...
Two...
...and remember.
-Three...
-What did you say?
Don't shout!
Now you made me type it wrong.
It's thrown me out again.
What do I do? How do I get back in?
It's just a, um,
a thing to remember the password,
"run you clever boy and remember”.
-(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-Hang on.
(WOMAN SOBBING, ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
-(BANGING ON DOOR)
-Hello, yes!
-(DOORBELL RINGING CONTINUOUSLY)
-I hear you!
Yep!
Uh-huh!
Hello?
(PANTING) Clara.
Clara Oswald?
-Hello.
-Clara Oswin Oswald!
Just Clara Oswald.
What was that middle one?
Do you remember me?
-No. Should I? Who are you?
-The Doctor.
No? The Doctor?
-Doctor who?
-No, just The Doctor.
Actually, sorry.
-Could you just ask me that again?
-Could I what?
Could you just ask me
that question again?
Doctor who?
-Okay, just once more.
-Doctor who?
Oh, yeah.
Ooh...
Do you know, I never realise how much
I enjoy hearing that said out loud.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
Hey! No! Clara!
Please! Clara, I need to talk to you!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Listen! Please!
ALEXEI: Clara Oswald.
We've got a positive lock on her
but I think she's borderline.
Very clever but no computer skills.
Upload her anyway.
Splice her a computer skills package.
I'll activate a spoon head.
Alexei, we call them servers,
not spoon heads.
Sorry, Miss Kizlet.
I'm ever so fond of Alexei.
But my conscience says
we should probably kill him.
I'll inform HR.
Actually, he's about to go on holiday.
Kill him when he gets back.
Let's not be unreasonable.
Didn't you want to speak to me?
We're uploading
too many people too quickly,
we're going to get noticed.
If your conscience is bothering you,
think of it like this.
We're preserving living minds
in permanent form in the data cloud.
It's like immortality.
-Only fatal.
-My conscience is fine.
Good. Because our client has his needs.
(TABLET TONE WHOOSHES)
Did you just hack me?
Because you changed your mind?
I hope I did.
(WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: Please!
I just need to speak to you.
Why are you still here?
Why are you here at all?
Oi, you phoned me.
You were looking for the internet.
-That was you?
-Of course it was me.
How did you get here so fast?
I just happened to be
in the neighbourhood
on my mobile phone!
When you say "mobile phone”,
why did you point at that blue box?
Because it's a surprisingly
accurate description.
Okay. We're finished now.
Oi, no! Look...
(DOOR SLAMS)
(FLOOR CREAKING)
Angie?
Angie, are you upstairs?
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
Angie, are you still here?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Hello.
Are you a friend of Angie's?
I'm a friend of Angie's.
What were you doing upstairs?
I was upstairs.
I know you, don't I?
You know me. Don't you?
(GASPS)
(WHIRRING)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Right! Don't be a monk!
Monks are not cool!
Ah!
(LAUGHS EXCITEDLY)
Ha! Clara! (KNOCKING)
-Clara?
-Hello?
(CHUCKLES) See, look it's me.
De-monked. Sensible clothes.
Um, can I come in now?
-I don't understand.
-Could you just open the door?
I don't know...
Of course you can.
...where I am.
(CLARA BREATHING HEAVILY)
I don't know where I am/!
Where am I?
Please tell me where I am.
I don't know where I am/!
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-I don't know where I am/!
-I don't know where I am.
-Clara!
-Clara?
-(BREATHING HEAVILY)
CLARA: (PANICKED)
I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I am/!
I don't understand.
I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I am/!
(PANTING) Where am I?
I don't know where I am.
-(WHIRRING)
-I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I am.
(ALARM BLARING)
I've got a problem.
(WHIRRING)
Walking base station.
Walking wi-fi base station.
Hoovering up data,
hoovering up people!
Oh, no, you don't!
Oh, no, you don't.
Looks like someone's trying
to reverse an upload.
KIZLET: Is that possible?
If the upload isn't fully
integrated yet. In theory, yes.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Oh, my God.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Not this time, Clara. I promise you.
MAHLER: Can you stop this?
No.
(SPOONHEAD WHIRRING)
(GASPING)
-(COUGHING)
-Okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
You're fine. You're back.
Yes, you are.
Oh, yes, you are.
Well?
Our hacker sent us a message.
MAHLER: I assume
he's talking about the girl.
Get out.
I have to speak to the client.
Sir.
The one you told me about, he's here.
The Doctor is here.
Ha.
(SNIFFS)
Mmm.
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(FRONT DOOR CLOSES)
(DOG BARKING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Hello?
Hello!
Are you all right?
-I'm in bed.
-Yes.
-I don't remember going.
-No.
-What did I miss?
-Oh!
Quite a lot, actually. Uh...
Angie called.
She'd going to stay over at Nina's.
Apparently that's all completely fine
and you shouldn't worry
like you always do,
for God's sake, get off her back.
Also, your dad phoned.
Mainly about the government,
he seems very cross with them.
I've got several pages on that.
I said I'd look into it.
I fixed that rattling noise
in the washing machine,
indexed the kitchen cupboards,
optimised the photosynthesis
in the main flower bed
-and assembled the quadricycle.
-Assembled the what?
I found a disassembled quadricycle
in the garage.
I don't think you did.
I invented the quadricycle!
(CHUCKLES)
What happened to me?
Don't you remember?
I was scared. Really scared.
Didn't know where I was.
-Do you know now?
-Yes.
Well, then, you should go to sleep.
Because you're safe now, I promise.
Goodnight, Clara.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
-Are you guarding me?
-Well, yes.
Yes, I am.
Are you seriously going to
sit down there all night?
Yeah, I promise.
I won't budge from this spot.
Well, then, I'll have to come to you.
Eh?
- I take it the girl's inside and alive?
-Yes.
Alexei,
I need you to do
something creative about that.
(ALEXEI TYPING, COMPUTER BEEPING)
-I like your house.
-It isn't mine.
-I'm a friend of the family.
-You look after the kids.
Oh, yes. You're a governess, aren't you?
Just like...
Just like what?
I thought you probably would be.
Are you gonna explain
what happened to me?
There's something in the wi-fi.
-Okay.
-This whole world is swimming in wi-fi.
We're living in a wi-fi soup.
Suppose something got inside it.
Suppose there was something
living in the wi-fi,
harvesting human minds, extracting them.
Imagine that.
Human souls trapped like flies
in the World Wide Web.
Stuck forever.
Crying out for help.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Isn't that basically Twitter?
-What was that face for?
-A computer can hack another computer.
A living, sentient computer...
Maybe that could hack people,
edit them, re-write them.
-Why would you say that?
-Because a few hours ago,
you knew nothing about the internet.
-And you just made a joke about Twitter.
-Oh.
Oh!
Oh, that's weird.
I know all about computers now
in my head.
Where did all that come from?
You were uploaded for a while.
Wherever you were,
you brought something extra back.
Which I very much doubt
you're going to be allowed to keep.
(MAN WHIRRING)
You and me, inside that box now.
-I'm sorry?
-Look, just get inside.
-Both of us?
-Trust me.
-You'll understand once we're in there.
-I bet I will!
-Look, please...
-What is that box, anyway?
-Why have you got a box?
-Clara?
Is it like a snogging booth?
-A what?
-Is that what you do? You bring a booth.
There's such a thing as too keen.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
Clara, look around you.
What's going on?
What's happening?
Is the wi-fi switching on the lights?
DOCTOR: No, the people
are switching on the lights.
The wi-fi's switching on the people.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
What is that thing?
DOCTOR: A walking base station.
You saw one earlier.
I saw a little girl.
DOCTOR: They must have taken
an image from your subconscious,
thrown it back at you. Ah!
Active camouflage.
They could be everywhere.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
Doctor? Doctor.
CLARA: What's going on?
MAHLER: Do we need another
London-wide activation?
We can't always pass it off as a riot.
Our lights are on,
everybody else's off. Why?
(AEROPLANE ENGINE ROARING)
Some planes have wi-fi.
I'm sorry?
We must be one hell
of a target right now.
(GASPS)
You, me, box. Now!
Yes, it's a spaceship!
Yes, it's bigger on the inside!
No, I don't have time to talk about it!
But... But...
-But... But it's...
-Shut up.
Please, short hops are difficult.
-Bigger on the inside. Actually bigger.
-(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(THUD, CLARA EXCLAIMS)
-Right, come on!
-We're going to go back out there?
We've moved.
It's a spaceship. We flew away.
-Away from the plane?
-Not exactly.
(BOTH SCREAM)
(GASPS) How did we get here?
It's a ship! I told you!
It's all very stretchy!
Is this is the plane? The actual plane?
Are they all dead?
(GRUNTS)
Asleep. Switched off by the wi-fi.
Never mind them.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CLARA EXCLAIMS)
What is going on? Is this real?
Please tell me what is happening!
I'm the Doctor.
I'm an alien from outer space.
I'm a thousand years old,
I've got two hearts
and I can't fly a plane! Can you?
-No.
-Oh, fine.
Well, let's do it together.
(SHOUTING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
Whoo!
Oh!
(PANTING)
Would a victory roll be too showy-offy?
-What the hell's going on?
-Well,
I'm blocking your wi-fi.
So you're waking up, for a start.
Tell you what, do you want to drive?
(PANTING)
(CLARA GASPS)
I don't understand. What's happened?
That box. Where's it gone?
Find that box!
Okay. When are you going to explain
to me what the hell is going on?
-Breakfast.
-(THUD)
-Right.
-What? I ain't waiting till breakfast.
It's a time machine.
You never have to wait for breakfast.
(CROWD CHEERING)
DOCTOR: Thank you! Thank you!
-(APPLAUSE)
-Yes, magic blue box.
All donations gratefully accepted.
Roll up! Roll up! Give us your dosh.
Oh, pennies, pounds,
anything you've got.
Keep collecting.
We need enough for breakfast.
Just popping back to the garage.
Garage?
This way.
So... So, this is tomorrow, then?
Tomorrow's come early.
No. It came at the usual time,
we just took a short cut.
-(CROWD APPLAUDS)
-Thank you. Thank you.
Tomorrow, a camel!
Clara.
What's happening?
Blue box. Southbank.
Definitely wasn't there
five minutes ago.
Are we sure this time?
Earl's Court was an embarrassment.
If you've got a flying time machine,
why are we on a motorbike?
I don't take the Tardis into battle.
Because it's made of wood?
Because it's the most powerful ship
in the universe
and I don't want it falling
into the wrong hands.
Ah! Okay!
(REVS ENGINE)
I do love London.
So many cameras.
CLARA: So if we can travel anywhere
in time and space,
why did we travel to the morning?
What's the point in that?
DOCTOR: Whoever's after us has spent
the whole night looking for us.
-Are you tired?
-Yes.
Well, then imagine how they feel.
They came the long way round.
They've got to be close.
Definitely London,
going by the signal distribution.
I can hack the lowest level
of their operating system
but I can't establish
a physical location,
their security's too good.
-Are you an alien?
-I am.
-Yes, okay with that?
-Fine, yeah.
-I think I'm fine.
-Oh, good.
So, what happens if you do find them?
What happens then?
I don't know. I can't tell the future,
I just work there.
-You don't have a plan?
-Oh, you know what I always say
-about plans.
-What?
-I don't have one.
-People always have plans.
(CLARA SLURPING)
Yes. Yes, I suppose they do.
So, tell me, how long have you been
looking after those kids?
-About a year. Since their mum died.
-Okay.
Why you?
Family friend, I get that,
but there must have been others.
Why did it have to be you?
I mean, you don't
really seem like a nanny.
-Give me.
-Ha!
Sorry. What?
You need to know
where they physically are,
-their exact location?
-Yes.
- I can do it.
-0}, hang on. I need that.
You hacked the lower
operating system, yeah?
I'll have their physical location
in under five minutes.
Pop off and get us a coffee.
If I can't find them,
you definitely can't.
They uploaded me, remember?
I got computing stuff in my head.
-So do 1.
-I have insane hacking skills.
I'm from space and the future
with two hearts and...
27 brains.
And I can find them
in under five minutes plus photographs.
-Twenty-seven?
-Okay.
-Slight exaggeration.
-Coffee. Go get.
Five minutes. I promise.
-The security is absolute.
-It's never about the security.
It's about the people.
Why do you keep looking at me like that?
Sorry, no, it's nothing. It's just...
You're a nanny. Isn't that a bit, well,
-Victorian?
You're young, shouldn't you be doing,
you know, with the...
(STUTTERS) Young things with...
-young people.
-What, you mean like you, for instance?
-Down, boy.
-No, no.
I didn't... Oh, shut up!
(GASPS) Shh...
(CHUCKLES)
Ooh!
(SNIFFS)
Two more cappuccinos over there, please.
(ITALIAN ACCENT) One moment, sir.
(ENERGY PULSATES)
(BRITISH ACCENT) You realise
you haven't the slightest chance
of saving your little friend?
(ENERGY PULSATES)
I'm sorry, what?
(ITALIAN ACCENT)
I said, "One moment, sir."
-(ENERGY PULSATES)
-(BRITISH ACCENT) I said,
"There is not the slightest chance
that you can save your little friend."
And don't annoy the old man,
he isn't, in fact, speaking.
-(ENERGY PULSATES)
-I'm speaking.
Just using whatever's to hand.
Oh, she's rather pretty, isn't she?
Do you like her?
I can make her like you, too,
if you want.
(ENERGY PULSATES)
You all right, sir?
Um, yes.
Yes. Fine.
-You okay?
-Sure. Setting up stuff.
-Need a username.
-Learning fast.
Clara Oswald for the win. Oswin!
You could always call me Oswin,
seeing as that's my name.
(ENERGY PULSATES)
WAITRESS: Now, I want
you to take a look around.
Go on. Have a little stroll.
And see how impossible
your situation is.
Go on. Take a look.
I do love showing off.
(ENERGY PULSATES)
(NEWSREADER SPEAKING ON TV)
Just let me show you what control
of the wi-fi can do for one.
-KIZLET: Stop!
-Stop!
I saw what you can do last night.
And clear!
-(ENERGY PULSATES)
-We can hack anyone in the wi-fi
once they've been exposed long enough.
So there's one of your walking
base stations here, somewhere close?
-There's...
-...always someone close.
We've released thousands into the world.
They home in on the wi-fi
like rats sniffing cheese.
(CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING)
There's something up with the webcams.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know who you are
or why you are doing this
but the people of this world
will not be harmed.
They will not be controlled!
They will not be...
-The people of this world are in no...
-...danger whatsoever.
My client requires a steady diet
of living human minds.
Healthy, free-range human minds.
He loves and cares for humanity.
In fact, he can't get enough of it.
It's obscene.
-It's murder.
-It's life.
The farmer tends his flock
like a loving parent.
The abattoir is not a contradiction.
No one loves cattle
more than Burger King.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm sure of it. Someone's hacking
the webcams, all of them.
Everybody check your webcams.
But what would be the point,
taking mugshots of us lot?
Who's on Facebook?
Uh, Bebo, MySpace? Habbo?
(CHUCKLES)
Put your hands down
if you didn't mention where you work.
This ends.
I'm going to end this today.
How? You don't even know...
...where we are.
Who's doing this? Who is your client?
Hmm? Answer me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Miss Kizlet, we have a problem.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
I did it. I really did!
I did it. I did it. I found them.
-You found them?
-The Shard.
They're in the Shard, floor 65.
-Floor 65.
-Are you listening to me, Doctor?
-I found them.
-I'm listening to you. You found them.
(WHIRRING)
We've got her.
This time we've really got her.
(SIGHS)
Clara? Clara!
CLARA: Doctor? Doctor, help me.
IL.. I don't know where I am.
I don't understand.
Doctor, help me, please.
I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I am/!
Doctor, please.
Please help me. Please help me!
I don't know where I am.
-(WHIRRING)
-Doctor, help me.
I don't know where I am.
(ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
Should we pulp her
or keep her as a hostage?
There's no point.
She's fully integrated now.
She can't be downloaded again.
I'm sure he knows that.
I'm not sure he does.
He's coming.
We could stop him, I suppose.
Why bother? Might be quite funny.
(TYRES SCREECH)
Really, Doctor? A motorbike?
It hardly seems like you.
I rode this
in the Anti-Grav Olympics, 2074.
I came last.
The building is in lockdown.
I'm afraid you're not coming in.
Did you even hear the word "Anti-Grav"?
(ENGINE ROARS)
(ENGINE REVS)
(TYRES SCREECHING, MOTORBIKE REVVING)
Seriously, he can do that?
He can really actually do that?
-Oh...
-...dear...
...Lord.
(WHIRRING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
I think that was your office.
-(MOTORBIKE REVVING)
-Excuse me.
I believe there's someone to see me.
KIZLET: Do come in.
Download her.
Sorry about the draught.
Download her back into her body
right now.
-I can't.
-Yes, you can.
She's a fully integrated part
of the data cloud now,
she can't be separated.
Then download the entire cloud,
everyone you've trapped in there.
You realise what would happen?
Yes, those still with bodies
to go home to would be free.
A tiny number.
Most would simply die.
They'd be released from a living hell.
It's the best you can do for them.
So give the order.
-And why would I do that?
-'Cause I'm going to motivate you.
Any second now.
You ridiculous man.
Why did you even come here?
Whatever for?
I didn't.
-What?
-I'm still in the cafe.
I'm finishing my coffee.
Lovely spot.
What are you talking about?
You hack people. But me...
I'm old-fashioned.
I hack technology.
Here's your motivation.
(WHIRRING)
No!
-(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
-KIZLET: Not me!
Not me!
Put me back. Put me back!
WOMAN 1: Can anybody hear me?
WOMAN 2: Where am I?
Download me at once!
That is an order. That is an order!
(ALL TALKING, INDISTINCT)
Mahler, she's fully integrated now.
We'd have to download the entire cloud.
-We can't do that.
-No, we can't.
KIZLET: Download me!
(TABLET WHIRRING)
(ENERGY PULSATES)
Do what she says.
(MURMURING) Mmm. Doctor?
Doctor?
Doctor!
You have no right to be in this office
and I am demanding
that you leave at once!
OFFICER 1: This building
is under UNIT's control.
What is UNIT? I've never heard of UNIT.
OFFICER 2: I suggest you calm down, sir.
UNIT are here.
Friends of the Doctor, I presume?
Oh, old friends. Very old friends.
Then I appear to have failed you,
Great Intelligence.
I have feasted on many minds,
I have grown.
But now it is time for you to reduce.
You've been whispering
in my ear so long
I'm not sure I remember
what I was before.
Goodbye, Miss Kizlet.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE BLARING)
(ALL GROANING)
-MAN: Where am I?
-(ALL TALKING AT ONCE, INDISTINCT)
(PANTING) I'm sorry.
Where am I? What am I doing here?
Are you soldiers? Uh, what's happening?
-ALEXEI: How did I get here?
-Excuse me, where are the toilets?
-The toilets?
-I'm here to fix the toilets, the gents.
How long have I been here?
OFFICER: Stay where you are!
Ma'am, identify yourself.
Where are my Mummy and Daddy?
They said they wouldn't be long.
Are they coming back?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(ALL CHATTERING, INDISTINCT)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in!
So...he comes back, does he?
You didn't answer my question.
What question?
You don't seem like a nanny.
I was going to travel.
I came to stay for a week before I left
and during that week...
She died.
So you're returning a favour then.
But 101 places to see
and you haven't been to any of them,
have you?
That's why you keep the book.
I keep the book...
because I'm still going.
But you don't run out on the people
you care about.
Wish I was more like that.
You know,
the thing about a time machine,
you can run away all you like
and still be home in time for tea.
So what do you say?
Anywhere.
All of time and space
right outside those doors.
-Does this work? (LAUGHING)
-Eh?
Is this actually what you do?
Do you just crook your finger
and people just jump
in your snog box and fly away?
-It is not a snog box!
-I'll be the judge of that.
Starting when?
Come back tomorrow. Ask me again.
-Why?
-Because tomorrow I might say yes.
Sometime after 7:00 okay for you?
It's a time machine.
-Any time's okay.
-See you then.
-Clara?
-Uh-huh?
In your book, there was a leaf.
Why?
That wasn't a leaf.
That was page one.
It was...
Right, then, Clara Oswald.
Time to find out who you are.
(WHOOSHING)
-What do you want to see?
-Something awesome.
-DOCTOR: Akhaten.
-Can we see it? Up close?
-Oh!
-You okay?
-Have you seen her?
-Who?
-I'm Merry Galel.
-(SCREAMING)
MAN: The Queen of Years.
MERRY: I'm the vessel of our history.
-(GASPS)
-CLARA: What's happening?
Is that supposed to happen?
-Doctor!
-Don't walk away.
CLARA: Merry!
Stay back! I'm armed!
With a screwdriver.
(GROWLING)
DOCTOR: Grandfather's awake.
You have it all!