(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SIRENS BLARING IN THE DISTANCE)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
-DOCTOR: Hey, you!
-(COUGHS)
DOCTOR: Hello, there.
Oh! Hello. (GRUNTING)
-Hello?
-Hello!
-What are you doing?
-I was setting a trap!
-A trap?
-DOCTOR: Are you rough?
-YOUNG GRANT: What happened?
-I tried it out!
-How?
-Accidentally.
-(SNEEZES)
-Bless you.
Thanks.
-What's your name?
-Grant.
-Hello, Grant. What floor is this?
-Sixty.
(YELLS)
Would it be all right if I came in?
Oh, I have to ask my mum.
-Ow!
-Mum! Wake up!
(CONTINUES COUGHING)
(CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Mum says you can come in.
You're expected.
(PANTING) Expected?
(SCREAMS)
(STRAINING)
-So, did you say I was expected?
-Yeah.
Who did you say I was?
I told her I saw an old guy
at the window.
(SNEEZES)
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
Merry Christmas, Grant.
Mum and Dad are asleep now.
I can get you back on the roof.
-I know the way.
-Shh.
-What are you doing?
-Take a look at that picture.
-Okay.
-Now, this one.
Take a good long look.
Takes a moment to see it.
YOUNG GRANT: See what?
Superman and Clark Kent
are one and the same person.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
Look, I drew specs on Superman.
Everyone knows they're the same person.
DOCTOR: Uh...
Well, Lois Lane doesn't.
And she's a reporter.
DOCTOR: Why did they call him
Spider-Man? Don't they like him?
He was bitten by a radioactive spider
and guess what happened?
Radiation poisoning, I should think.
No, he got special powers.
What, vomiting, hair loss and death.
Fat lot of use.
Hey.
-What do you think?
-YOUNG GRANT: That looks...
-DOCTOR: I know.
-Cheap.
-Oh, shut up.
-(SNEEZES)
-Got a cold there, Grant?
-I always get a cold on Christmas.
Me too. What an invasion.
-Where did you get that from?
-My pocket.
How did you put a glass of water
in your pocket?
Skills. Now, hush.
I got a lot of work to do.
Take this.
Ah.
-Who are you?
-The Doctor.
-Yeah, but who are you?
Which one, though?
There's lots of doctors.
The one, the main one. The original.
I started it. They're all based on me.
Now, everyone who wants to sound clever
calls themselves doctor.
Bandwagon.
In a comic book,
you know what you'd be called?
Doctor Mysterio.
Well, I like that.
Doctor Mysterio! I'll have that.
-Nearly ready.
-What is it?
Well, in terms
that you would understand...
Sorry, there aren't any.
(STAMMERS) It's a time distortion
equalizer thingy.
A what?
Well, there's a little bit of
a localised disruption here in New York,
so, uh, my fault, actually.
Hopefully, this will
make it all calm down.
I don't understand.
DOCTOR: Uh, do you know what
a lightning conductor is?
-YOUNG GRANT: Yeah.
-Well, it's not like that.
-I thought you were setting a trap.
-I was. To protect this.
I don't want anyone turning it off,
or stealing it for a Christmas tree.
-But it looks like a Christmas tree.
-Of course it does. It's science.
-Do you want to turn the lights on?
-Can I?
Go on. It's Christmas day.
-What do I do?
-Ah.
Right. Put this into this.
And you flick
all those little switches on.
(BEEPING)
YOUNG GRANT: Nothing's happening.
Yeah, because now,
we get to the cool bit. Come here.
Do you see that little door there?
Pop it open.
Now we turn on the lights.
Pop the gemstone right in there.
What gemstone?
The gemstone that I gave you.
Pop it right in there.
-(WHISPERS) That was a gemstone?
-Well, it's more than just a gemstone.
It's also like a kind of
on-board computer. Come here.
Can you see...
Can you see that little yellow star?
Near the end of that curve.
It comes from near there.
Formed in the heart of a red hole.
Stabilised a pure dwarf star crystal.
The gemstone is intuitive.
It knows what you want.
And it draws energy from
the nearest star to make it happen.
There's only four of them
left in the universe.
The apocalypse monks of the Andorax
called this one the "Hassandra,"
the ghost of love and wishes.
Okay then, pop it in.
I thought it was medicine.
-What?
-It looked like medicine.
What have you done with it?
Well, you gave me medicine
and a glass of water
and you said you were a doctor.
-I thought it was for my cough.
-Oh... You swallowed it.
You can't go around swallowing things.
What age are you, 367
-Eight.
-(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Am I gonna get sick?
No, no, no, no. Quite the opposite.
The opposite? What's the opposite?
-What happened?
-DOCTOR: Nothing.
What's wrong with me?
Well, uh, you've got a cough
and a slight case of levitation.
-Stay calm.
-What happens if I don't stay calm?
-(GRUNTS) Don't panic!
-What happens if I panic?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BABY CRYING)
(WHISPERS) Oh, hey, you're all right.
Hi. You're okay.
(BABY COOING)
Yeah.
(SHUSHING)
Hey, Mrs Lombard.
No, don't worry. Jennifer's fine.
She just woke up
and I'm gonna put her back to sleep.
No, it's okay, Mrs Lombard,
It's what you pay me for.
Okay. Goodnight.
DOCTOR: (YELLS) You need to calm...
YOUNG GRANT: What's happened to me?
Intuitive crystal,
plus too many comic books.
The gemstone is giving you
what it thinks you want!
(SCREAMS) You're a superhero!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
MR BROCK: Any questions after today
can be handled by
Miss Schuster or Miss Segal
who can be contacted
on the e-mail addresses
provided in your welcome pack.
That's all we have time for,
ladies and gentlemen.
I hope you had a stimulating day.
And maybe saw a little of
what makes Harmony Shoal
the foremost innovator
in science and technology
the world over.
Like we always say,
we're here to open your minds.
LUCY: Mr Brock, just one more question.
I've been looking into your funding,
and you seem to have a lot of
benefactors for a research institute.
Well, the world is changing,
Miss Fletcher.
Science got sexy.
Yeah, but your benefactors,
I can't seem to find any of them.
Very simple reason for that.
I killed them all.
-Buried them in my backyard.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
How big is your backyard, Mr Brock?
-At the last count, Wyoming.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
Now, if you good people will excuse me,
this young lady will guide you
to the exit.
MAN: Mr Brock... Uh, Mr Brock.
Mr Brock? Mr Brock?
Apparently, we have one more question.
Yes. Uh, where is the little boys' room?
I think you'll find the restrooms
to the left on your way out.
No, not the restrooms,
the little boys' room.
If you successfully
locate the restrooms,
I think you'll find
everything you need in there.
-Thank you, all.
-WOMAN: This way, ladies and gentlemen.
I don't wanna rest.
If I was just having a rest,
I might cause an incident.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Dr Sim, is there a problem?
It's the brains.
There's something I need to show you.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
DR SIM: It's necessary.
MR BROCK: Later.
Meet me here. Midnight.
Thank you, sir.
(SIGHS) Mr Brock. You startled me.
Shall we?
Of course.
(WHISPERS) All clear.
(DOOR OPENS)
-Well?
-Look at them.
You see nothing unusual?
I see brains, every place except here.
MR BROCK: These specimens were donated
to this facility by our benefactors
for a top secret research project.
A project which is not to be questioned,
impeded, or in fact,
mentioned by any of the employees
at the Harmony Shoal institute.
Even I don't have the clearance
to know what's going on in here.
-DR SIM: But why?
-Is that your job to ask questions?
Stick to science.
Something wrong with your eyes?
Sir, the first time I came in here,
I counted 24 specimens.
The second time I counted,
there were 30.
Now, there are 36.
-Well, I guess they got the space.
-You don't understand.
There have been no deliveries.
I checked it.
Some of these brains, sir, they just...
Arrived.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
It's okay. I'm an intruder, too.
Yeah, I brought snacks.
Mark of a pro. Keep listening.
MR BROCK: It looks like a brain to me.
Kind of blue, I guess,
but that's the fluid, right?
DR SIM: Yes, that's the fluid.
Tap the glass, sir.
(CHUCKLING) What'd you say?
Tap the glass, please.
MR BROCK: What? What the hell is that?
Is that a joke?
No, sir, it's not a joke.
It's got eyes. Look at them.
They're like...
They're like your eyes.
Yes, sir. They are.
MR BROCK: Dr Sim!
-What are you pointing at?
-I'm pointing at Dr Sim.
Don't look so alarmed.
We merely exchanged containers.
You might call this a hijack.
(GRUNTS)
(CHOKING)
(GASPS)
What happened to you?
I don't understand.
The same thing
that is about to happen to you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I had a change of mind.
(DOORS OPENING)
MR BROCK: No. Please. No.
Let me out of here!
What's happening?
(STRUGGLING) What are you doing?
-(GRUNTS)
-(CONTAINER CREAKING)
(LOCK ENGAGES)
Who are you?
Lucy Fletcher,
reporter from the Daily Chronicle.
Hang on, why am I telling you the truth?
-Spooky, isn't it? Looking for a story?
-I think I just found one.
"Brains with minds of their own."
No one will believe that.
This is America.
Who are you?
Special agent Damn Dangerous
from Scotland Yard, Scotland,
the Doctor, for short.
See, they've got institutes
all over the world.
They're always in capital cities.
-Nope.
-Yes.
Yes, they are. See?
New York's not capital city, is it?
You don't need to point out mistakes.
That's not what you're for.
-Washington's got its own one, yeah.
-(LIGHT SWITCH CLANKS)
I would call security,
but they might leave you alive.
I do not want any awkward questions
about the intruders
I was forced to shoot
for my own protection.
(CHUCKLES)
DOCTOR: Good plan.
Here's another one. Go on.
Tell them you shot us in the back
in self-defence.
We'll be laughing
all the way to the slab.
-Face me.
-Maybe not.
Face me now.
-(THUDDING)
-What is that?
-It's not me.
-LUCY: It sounds like...
(KNOCKING)
-Like someone knocking at a window.
-We're on the 100th floor.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God. He's real.
-DOCTOR: Who's real?
-The Ghost.
DOCTOR: Who's the Ghost?
-LUCY: Masked vigilante, but he's...
-What?
Super.
-(SNAPS FINGERS)
-(SHATTERS)
Mind if I come in?
Impressive.
Those windows,
like everything in this building,
are built to withstand a blast
equivalent to four nuclear explosions.
Sorry about that.
Would you like me to call a glazier?
Hmm.
(GUN CLICKING)
(GASPS)
Please understand that
it's against my personal code
to cause lasting harm to any individual.
(GROANS)
However, light to
moderate injury is fine.
-That was good.
-GHOST: Hello.
-Was that man annoying you?
-LUCY: You're real?
I can't believe that you're ac...
Actually real.
I'm afraid I am.
I enjoy your column, Miss Fletcher.
You read my column? You read?
You're real and you read?
Though I find the political bias
in your paper's editorial
not entirely to my taste.
-I'll pass that on.
-Thank you.
-And who are these gentlemen?
-They're, erm...
I don't actually know.
-Uh, this is my friend, Nardole.
-Hello, Ghost.
And I'm the Doctor.
The Doctor?
I thought we had lots of doctors.
I'm the main one.
-Can I give you a ride home?
-You have a car?
-No.
-(GASPS)
-I hope you're okay with heights.
-I'm okay so far.
Have a good evening, gentlemen.
(LUCY SCREAMS)
This seems nice.
Grant.
YOUNG GRANT: So, I'm a superhero now?
DOCTOR: Well, once the gemstone
is gone from inside you,
you'll be back to normal.
-It will pass.
-But how will it get out?
Uh, like I said, it will pass.
-Looking forward to that.
-Are you sure?
Of course I'm not sure.
Nothing's ever sure.
Just promise me one thing.
For as long as you have these powers,
you will never ever use them.
Sure.
-Is this the right building?
-(GASPS)
They all look the same from up there.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, this is me. Thanks.
Well, I certainly hope
this unpleasant experience
hasn't put you off
your career in journalism.
Oh, no. No, no. Not at all.
(BEEPING)
Sorry, duty calls.
Look at that.
The bat signal's an app now?
What is it? Bank robbery, hijack?
Uh... Something like that.
Excuse me.
Go get 'em.
(BABY CRYING)
(PANTING)
With great power
comes great responsibility.
(EXHALES)
No man worthy of a title
leaves a baby alone.
-How'd you find me?
-I tracked the gemstone inside you.
(GRANT STAMMERS)
DOCTOR: Your powers,
they don't belong in this world.
They're an anomaly.
-You promised me you'd never use them.
-May I take her?
-She's yours?
-Uh, I'm hers. I'm her nanny.
You're her nanny?
Yeah, her nanny.
You got a problem with that?
No. No, it's just... (STAMMERS)
Okay, so you are a superhero
and a nanny?
Well, you got to make a buck somehow.
I mean, you don't get paid
for saving people.
Oh, you don't have to tell us.
Here you go.
Nice and warm and tasty. Ooh, elephant.
I mean, it's fine.
It's a long range baby monitor.
-(TOY SQUEAKING)
-I can get back to this apartment
quicker than most people can get
to their kid's bedrooms.
Grant. Grant, this is insane.
Look, I'm me, the Doctor.
-And even I think this is insane.
-Even him?
I can cope.
Of course, you can't.
When do you sleep?
-When are you not on call?
-(DOOR OPENS)
How complicated
do you need your life to be?
-(DOOR CLOSES)
-Well,
not as complicated as it's about to get.
-Uh, we're in here, Mrs Lombard.
-MRS LOMBARD: Oh, Jennifer.
Look at you. Up again?
Don't you ever sleep?
GRANT: Did you have a good evening,
Mrs Lombard?
MRS LOMBARD: Oh, well, it was work.
Why would it be good?
GRANT: Uh... Well, erm, I don't know,
you seem a little buzzed.
-I thought maybe you met someone.
-Maybe I did, maybe I didn't.
-Uh... Grant, what...
-(SIGHS)
What are you doing here?
We could ask you the same question.
But it's your apartment,
so we probably won't.
Well...
(BABY COOING)
(STAMMERS) We were worried about you.
We wanted to make sure that
you were all right,
so, uh, we followed you.
You followed me and got here first?
Well, that's just a measure
of our concern.
-Very concerned.
-They said they knew you. I let them in.
Oh, we met tonight.
We need to talk, you and me.
GRANT: Oh! Did something happen?
(TOY SQUEAKS)
Nothing for you to worry
your pretty little head about.
I'll put her to bed.
-I can do that.
-No, no, it's okay. I want to.
Lombard's her married name.
He ran off when the baby came along.
Lucy.
Of course.
-(BELL RINGING)
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-Hey.
-What are you doing here?
I'm your relief algebra teacher.
Thought I'd check in on you,
and see how you're coping.
Well, it hasn't passed,
if that's what you wanna know.
I think that
it's a part of your DNA now.
It's bonded with you.
I'm sorry.
-Why aren't you looking at me?
-I don't want to.
You're not looking at anyone.
Are you shy now?
Is that floor really interesting?
I'm not shy. I just can't stop it.
-Can't stop what?
-The X-ray vision.
Oh.
TEEN GRANT: I'm in hell, naked hell.
I just can't look at people.
It's the gemstone responding to puberty.
-Hey, Grant.
-Hey, Lucy.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
You really like her, don't you?
I have X-ray eyes. I like everyone.
But Lucy is your favourite?
Who says?
GRANT: A couple of years after
high school, I ran into her again.
-She remembered me.
-DOCTOR: Ooh, that was lucky.
And I was with my best friend
at the time,
and she couldn't take her eyes off him.
-Okay.
-Love at first sight.
-Right.
-Then marriage, then a baby.
And then he ran off with someone else.
Leaving, I suppose,
a field open for you to move in.
Yeah.
And care for the child she'd had
by another man?
Yeah.
So she could keep working and
possibly date other friends of yours?
-Pretty much.
-You tiger!
-Thank you!
-Who are you thanking?
The universe.
Somebody once said this to me.
(SIRENS BLARING)
(HORNS HONKING)
Excuse me.
(WHOOSHES)
(TOY SQUEAKS)
This is Mr Huffle.
Mr Huffle feels pain.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
-Meet me in the kitchen.
-(TOY SQUEAKS)
(SIGHING)
(REPORTER SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY ON TV)
-With you in a minute.
-(TYPING)
-So, you're from Scotland Yard?
-Yes.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
It's fine if you don't tell me
your secrets.
I intend to keep mine,
but don't lie to me.
-Or what?
-I hurt Mr Huffle.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
I assume you belong to
some kind of, I don't know, agency,
I don't care which one.
And that your current assignment is to
investigate Harmony Shoal, correct?
-No, I was just passing...
-(TOY SQUEAKS)
Okay, okay. Yes, fine.
Okay, yes. Broadly speaking, yes.
(TOY CONTINUES SQUEAKING)
What are those brain things?
-I don't know.
-(TOY SQUEAKING)
It's nothing that need concern you.
I'm a reporter.
That category does not exist.
What are they?
Well, you wouldn't believe me
if I told you.
No reason not to tell me then.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
Those brains, they aren't just brains.
They're independent alien life forms.
And?
(TOY SQUEAKING)
They migrate from planet to planet,
extracting and replacing
the central nervous systems
of compatible hosts.
And?
Harmony Shoal
Is a multinational corporation
whose true purpose is to extract
and replace the brains
of key authority figures
from around the world
and prepare Earth for full colonisation.
(TOY SQUEAKS)
-Huh.
-You believe me?
I don't think you're lying.
Slightly different.
What has Harmony Shoal
got to do with the Ghost?
Nothing.
Ah. So you know
who the Ghost really is, then.
No, I have no idea...
-Oh, stop it!
-(TOY SQUEAKS)
We just went to a top secret science
research facility,
apparently run by brains from space,
and a flying man
with super powers turns up.
Anybody would assume
that you're connected,
except for somebody
who already knew they weren't.
So, clearly you know the Ghost
and trust him.
Nobody trusts anybody
without knowing who they are.
So you know who he really is.
So now you can tell me.
Who is he?
Oh, that's interesting.
You don't work for an agency, do you?
Don't I?
You're not used to being spoken
to you like this,
which means you don't have
a boss or an employer.
So why are you
investigating Harmony Shoal?
-What's in it for you?
-I like to keep busy.
-Why? What happened to you?
-Nothing.
-Oh, look!
-(TOY SQUEAKS)
-(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
-LUCY: Whoa.
...because fire prevention is
the responsibility of every citizen.
-So, get a smoke detector!
-(BABY CRIES)
-(BABY MONITOR BEEPS)
-Sorry, duty calls.
LUCY: Oh, look at him go.
I need to know who he is.
Oh, you're all right.
She just needs a change.
It's okay. I'll do it.
-You're so quick, Grant.
-Oh, yes. He's definitely quick.
-Do you have any time off?
-Sure.
...it became clear that two children
were still trapped on the big wheel.
- The two small figures,
-(WHOOSHING)
As you can see are clinging on to the...
LUCY: Doctor?
So, can you put me in touch with him?
-(SIGHS)
-The real guy behind the mask?
You're smart.
(WHISPERS) You're so clever
I actually noticed,
and I hardly ever listen
when other people are talking.
-So what?
-So why can't you find him yourself?
-I got a lead.
-What lead?
You. You know him.
Don't even try telling me you don't.
Well, maybe you know him too?
-Hey, where did Grant go?
-Right here, Mrs Lombard.
-Oh.
-Would you like your coffee?
Oh, no. I'm okay, thanks.
-LUCY: Are you all right?
-Sure, why?
-You're kind of wet.
-I prefer mild-mannered.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Can you put me in touch with him?
-The Ghost?
-Yeah. The Ghost.
Mrs Lombard,
there are some situations which are just
too stupid to be allowed to continue.
-(MOBILE RINGS)
-(DOCTOR SIGHS)
Hang on.
-Hello?
-MAN: Is this Lucy Fletcher?
-Yes, who is this?
-Sorry, I had to fly.
(GASPS) Am I? Sorry.
Am I speaking to the Ghost?
Hello, Lucy.
So, I'm hoping this means
I'm getting an interview?
An interview is entirely possible.
(IN A GRUFF VOICE)
But I must make one thing clear,
there must be no talk
of who I really am.
Hey, you make the headlines,
you make the rules.
Discussion of my true identity would
put the people closest to me at risk.
-That is not acceptable.
-Fair enough. Get that.
How about tomorrow night?
For what?
The interview? We could get dinner.
-Dinner?
-Do you eat dinner?
-Of course I eat dinner.
-Okay then.
Pick me up here,
tomorrow night, erm, 8:00.
I'll wait for you on the roof?
(LUCY COOS AND GASPS)
Wait a second.
Grant, could you babysit for me
tomorrow night?
-(IN NORMAL VOICE) Erm...
-Please, it's important.
BOTH: I've got a date.
BOTH: A date?
-Uh, kind of a date.
-Okay.
An interview.
-Are you seeing someone?
-Erm...
None of my business. I mean...
But are you?
I mean, you never even go out
and suddenly you got a date?
Yeah, well, it kind of came
as a surprise to me too.
-I'm sorry?
-It's complicated.
I can confirm that.
It's definitely complicated.
You know, don't worry about it.
I'll look after Jennifer.
-You will?
I'll figure it out.
Let me take care of it.
-Okay.
-(WHISPERS) She's jealous.
-I'm jealous.
Grant, you are jealous of you.
Technically, she's jealous of her?
Grant, how long have you
known this woman?
Since elementary school? 24 years.
Twenty-four years?
Yeah, of course it would be then...
You okay?
Time passes for everyone, even for me.
So, please,
as much as it is possible for
a human male, try not to be an idiot.
No, seriously, are you okay?
I'm always okay.
(SIRENS WAILING IN THE DISTANCE)
(GROANS SLOWLY)
(WHOOSHING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
-Ah! Welcome, brother.
-(SIGHS)
How's your vehicle?
-(BONES CRACKING)
-A little cramped.
It will relax with wear.
-Observe this.
-(KEYBOARD CLACKS)
DR SIM: The finest vehicle
this planet has to offer.
MR BROCK: Interesting.
But, can it be acquired?
DR SIM: A plan is being formulated.
This one. Who is he?
-(COMPUTER BEEPING)
-I'm not sure,
but he may be dangerous.
He doesn't look dangerous.
Boo!
I'm talking to you live! In person!
You can jump back in your skins now.
Except, of course,
they're not your skins, are they?
-What do you want?
-Mercy.
-We have none.
-It's not a request, it's an offer.
I'll give you a head start.
I'll close my eyes
and I'll count to ten.
I will make no attempt to follow you.
But, starting now,
all of you, everywhere,
pack your bags and
get off of this planet.
Are you declaring war on us?
I am drawing a line.
And I'm suggesting you step back from it
with awesome speed.
Then war it is.
Multi-nucleate organism
functioning as an infinitely adaptable,
independently functioning
peripatetic central nervous system.
Good to keep an open mind. (CHUCKLES)
-Of course, it won't work.
-What won't work?
Whatever it is.
Whatever you've got planned.
Stating the obvious, you've set up
in every capital city in the world,
so clearly, the plan is to unzip
the head of every world leader,
pop yourselves inside.
Of course, you can't just roll up
with a team of surgeons
to the White House or to the Kremlin,
because they've got big fences,
shouty people and cross dogs.
They will come to us.
And they will come running.
Oh.
I very much doubt it. Take this!
Yes, take that!
MR BROCK: Who are you?
There have been many attempts
to conquer the Earth, I've lost count.
Not one of them has succeeded.
Not a single one.
They all lost and burned, and ran.
That's who I am.
(WHISTLING)
-What is this?
-(CONTINUES WHISTLING)
It's a burger. I always bring a snack.
I don't want it.
Oh, he's put me off my dinner.
(WHOOSHING)
-Very good. Right on target.
-Extraordinary to be honest.
A few accidental stop-offs
along the way.
-Where did you get the robes?
-Twelfth century Constantinople.
I rode firmly but wisely.
Uh-uh-uh!
-How did it go?
-Oh, you know, issued a warning,
donated a burger.
Next I'm stationed with the Ghost.
What have you got?
The whole story!
Fact me, baby.
It's why I reassembled you.
No, sir, that's not the reason, is it?
Oh, just get on with it.
You cut me out of Hydroflax because
you were worried you'd be lonely.
And we both know why, don't we?
But, oh! Look at you,
avoiding the subject.
I'm not avoiding anything.
I'm just trying to save a planet.
Which is what you always do
when the conversation turns serious.
(SIRENS BLARING IN THE DISTANCE)
-(COOING)
-Good girl...
GRANT: Mrs Lombard?
You look nice.
-You look surprised.
-No, no, no.
It's just, well, normally you wear
the little red dress when you're, uh...
This is business, Grant.
Strictly business.
So...
-I won't be late.
-Okay.
(DOOR OPENING)
Hi.
(IN A GRUFF VOICE) Hi.
Is something wrong?
You look nice.
-You look surprised.
-I am.
A little.
He's not supposed to be using
those powers, he made a promise.
Well, like the Time Lord
promise never to interfere
in the affairs of
other peoples or planets?
I glued your head back on.
Should have a little bit more respect.
-(BEEPS)
-Oh.
Come on.
-Where are we?
-Where we were, except not.
-Oh... What?
-(DOOR OPENING)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-Oh, Tokyo branch?
-Yep!
Bit empty, isn't it?
Yes, I created a distraction.
I flooded downstairs with Pokemon.
-You're not supposed to be here.
-I know, it's terrible.
Sorry, I'm doing everything
I can to stop me. See that?
NARDOLE: It's a signal, isn't it?
It's a signal beaming into space.
There's one from
the New York office, too.
Something in low orbit.
I did book a restaurant.
I'm not comfortable in restaurants.
I suppose you get a lot of stares
dressed like that.
Right back at you.
-You sure you're warm enough?
-Yeah.
Okay, no. (CHUCKLES)
-(SNAPS FINGERS)
-(GASPS)
-Now?
-Yeah. Definitely.
-Yep, low orbit.
-But you can't get a fix on it?
-I'm trying. Their shield is too good.
-Why can't we track the signals?
DOCTOR: Tracking them now.
-Boom.
-(LAUGHS)
So what powers do you have?
Well, basic flying,
basic super strength.
-Basic X-ray vision?
-Yep.
Is that ever tempting?
-Adolescence was difficult.
-In what sense?
-It went on a lot longer.
-How much longer?
I'll let you know.
(LAUGHS)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
MR BROCK: We're moving into position.
It won't be long now.
DR SIM: The Ghost is located.
MR BROCK: Action the surgeons.
(DOORS HISSING)
DOCTOR: That's what Harmony Shoal
is signalling to.
Shall we pop over and have a look?
Pretty sure no one's on board.
How do you know?
Did you scan for lifeforms?
No. All the lights are off.
NARDOLE: Hmm!
Do you have a girlfriend?
Boyfriend?
Well, there has been speculation.
You do fly around New York dressed
in rubber with a big G on your chest.
Are we very slightly stereotyping here?
I get it. There's some stuff
you'd like to keep private.
Was it the mask that tipped you off?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
How do you cope with your double life?
I'm nothing special.
Everyone has a day job.
Come on.
You spend half your time
as a regular person...
I spend all my time that way.
And the other half saving the world.
How do you cope?
How do you cope with a career
and a baby?
-How do you know I have a baby?
-I...
Did my research.
Uh, I have a nanny.
That's basically your answer.
-Yes, of course.
-He's downstairs right now.
-I see.
-And yes, I said he.
-Yes, you did.
-Yes, I did.
-Is that a problem?
-I'm sorry,
it's just that guys like you sometimes
find it funny a man being a nanny.
With respect, Miss Fletcher,
there aren't too many guys like me.
There aren't too many guys
like Grant either.
-You okay?
-(GASPS)
Excuse me a minute.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Bridge is this way.
(ALARM BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Move.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(BEEPING, DOORS HISSING)
GHOST: I didn't mean to imply that
there's something wrong
with your friend, Grant.
You know,
not everyone can be a superhero.
Well, not everyone can be a nanny.
Sorry.
He's downstairs right now.
And he was supposed to be on a date
and he cancelled it,
and you know
what's really bugging me about that?
Who is he dating?
Why is that bugging me?
Why do I care?
What's wrong with me?
There's probably something
I ought to tell you.
LUCY: Grant.
The perfect name.
A man I take for granted.
Erm, really if you can just look up
about now?
Always there. Always kind. Never lies.
I even lied to him about this dress.
But I don't think he's ever told
a single lie to me.
Not once. About anything.
Not once.
-That's very commendable.
-(DOOR OPENING)
Good evening.
Please take no aggressive action
or your friend's life is over.
Mr Brock, what do you want here?
The same thing you do, Miss Fletcher.
His body.
(RAPID BEEPING)
(GRUNTS)
Bit rubbish, isn't it?
(WHISPERS) Don't touch anything.
No, it's quite safe.
You're just afraid...
- I said don't touch.
-(MUMBLES)
See? The reactor core.
It's cycling at critical.
Someone's been reviving.
This isn't a ship any more.
-It's a giant bomb.
-Ooh...
(GASPS) Doctor!
(BEEPS)
Security drones, that's all.
So what do they want a bomb for?
Oh, why does anybody want a bomb for?
Surely they want to conquer the Earth,
not blow it up?
Oh, you couldn't blow up the Earth
with this...
But you can wipe out a city.
-Good point, well made.
-What point?
New York! It's not a capital city.
You're quite right.
Oh. I don't understand.
What if you dropped this ship
on New York? What would happen?
The reactor core would split
and New York would vapourise.
Not all of it.
Not all of it, Nardole.
Remember what he said?
The scary little German fellow.
This building can withstand the blast
up to four times
the strength of a nuclear explosion.
Oh, this is very good. Very meta.
Do you understand?
You're stage managing an alien attack,
when the aliens have already landed.
But why?
Because of what happens next
when everyone thinks that
the Earth is being attacked
from space, what then?
-Mass panic.
-(BANGING ON DOOR)
(WHIMPERS) Speaking of panic.
Don't worry,
it's triple deadlock sealed.
It'll hold for at least ten minutes.
The people will panic, yes.
But what about the world leaders?
The presidents, the kings,
the prime ministers and generals.
What will they do?
What do the rich old men
always do when the fighting starts?
They'll find the safest place
to hide themselves away,
and send all the young people to die.
And where's the safest place
in every capital city now?
What's the only part of
New York still standing?
Harmony Shoal.
New York isn't a capital city.
(BANGING CONTINUES)
It's a shop window.
When the world is in danger,
come hide with us.
Harmony Shoal will open its doors
to the terrified leaders of the world.
And they will come running.
DOCTOR: And a few hours later,
every politician and commander-in-chief
will have a zip in their head.
An alien sitting inside their skull.
One day of terror,
the executive authority of planet Earth
will pass to Harmony Shoal.
It's a good plan. I like it.
How come our side
never gets plans like that?
The humans have no plan at all.
(LAUGHS) That's where you're wrong.
They have the same plan
they always have.
-What plan?
-Me.
(CHEERS)
-Don't do that.
-Sorry.
(GHOST GRUNTS)
The operation is swift
and quite painless.
You realise I'm talking
to my colleague in the jar?
You'll find me a lot harder to cut open
than your previous victims.
Harmony Shoal have been conquering
your world for five years.
Whatever our faults,
we have the virtue of patience.
Ghost, don't worry about me.
Do what you got to do.
-Do anything at all and we'll kill her.
-Don't listen to him.
MR BROCK: Remove the mask.
I like to see their faces.
I'm truly sorry.
(SURGEONS GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
On the bright side,
at least I get to kill you.
(GASPS)
LUCY: No, you can't.
That's the trouble with one hostage.
You kill me,
and the only reason
he'll come back is for revenge.
-You really want to deal with that?
-One hostage?
Isn't there a child downstairs?
(GRUNTING)
Nobody touches that child.
Now who are you?
I'm the nanny.
Stand away from the controls, Doctor.
Any attempt to interfere with them
will precipitate the attack immediately.
Yes, I see that. Very clever.
One question as long as I am here.
Why haven't you done it already?
When the time is right,
there will be no delay.
Whoa! You told me something there.
You told me something useful,
you shouldn't have done that.
What did I tell you?
You told me that
the time is currently wrong!
Oh, it's the smile.
I don't like the smile.
Sword of Damocles hanging over New York.
I can't destroy it. I can't remove it.
I can't stop it falling.
-There's only one thing I can do.
-NARDOLE: What?
The unexpected!
The thing about being in a room
full of buttons and switches is...
-I love buttons and switches!
-Oh, don't! Stop!
What are you doing?
-NARDOLE: Help!
-(MACHINE POWERING UP)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Thrusters engaged.
Next stop, blue rock!
-Say whee!
-(WHIMPERS)
-(ALARM BLARING)
-Lower shields!
Brace for impact!
New York is under attack.
It occurs to me, Miss Fletcher,
I now have three hostages.
Why don't you point the gun at me?
What difference will it make?
Besides, this is the one
the Ghost will come for, I think.
Ghost!
Can you hear me?
Do you have super hearing?
I'm going to kill her.
I'm going to kill her right now!
(ALARM BLARING)
Stop! You're going to destroy New York!
Of course not! Now the bomb is arming,
and the shields are down.
-Help!
-We can use the Tardis!
(WHIMPERING)
Hijack the controls
and divert it into space!
No bomb. No plan.
-No problem.
-No! Wait, those things are out there.
This ship is crashing, they're not
going to be worried about us.
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS) Okay, Plan B!
-Doctor!
-(GRUNTS)
-Help me!
-Oh, you'll be fine.
This ship will have blown
before you've been strangled to death.
-Oh, what's Plan B?
-I have no idea!
But it's going to be a very big relief
when I think of it.
You are completely out of your mind!
How is that news to anyone?
Look, I know you miss her,
but couldn't you just write a poem?
Excellent! The controls are locked.
But they've still got a lot of
enough give, means I can take aim.
NARDOLE: At what?
DOCTOR: New York.
There's exactly one chance
and that is all you need.
(CRYING) No!
(RUMBLING)
MR BROCK: No. No, it's too soon.
DOCTOR:
Grant! Grant! This is the Doctor!
You're the only living thing on Earth
that can hear this frequency.
Look up!
We're coming right at you.
If that thing hits the ground,
then New York is finished.
Over to you.
(IN A GRUFF VOICE)
Mrs Lombard, please get down.
What? (GASPS)
-Nardole!
-(WHIMPERS) Yeah!
Brace for impact!
(NARDOLE WHIMPERS, SCREAMS)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Nardole. Nardole!
NARDOLE: (IN ROBOTIC VOICE)
Okay, one more...
Nardole, it worked!
The reactor core didn't split.
Why not?
Shock absorber.
Mrs Lombard, I realise in many ways
it would've been better
to have mentioned something
about this earlier in the evening,
but please don't slap me.
I think I'm holding a giant bomb.
(WHOOSHING)
There. On you go. Take a look at him.
That's why you don't stand a chance.
You want to know why?
He's actually left-handed.
Sorry, instinct.
I couldn't let go of this.
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
If you two are about to get excited,
maybe you could get rid
of that spaceship first?
You know what?
I think I prefer you
in your superhero costume.
It's a bit difficult for me
to change right now.
I'll do it for you.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
DOCTOR: Grant...
Grant, uh, remember
when you're finished,
to throw that thing into the sun.
Jennifer's still downstairs!
(COOING ON MONITOR)
So, Doctor?
-You think this is over?
-Yeah.
-(GRUNTS)
-Your bomb's gone, your plan's finished.
And look, there's UNIT on the way
to close your head office.
It's almost like
they've been tipped off.
The vengeance of Harmony Shoal is known
and feared throughout
the Five-star System.
Ooh! Is it? Is it really?
Well, I'd like to
stick around and listen,
but it's been a very long night.
-(BABY CRYING ON THE MONITOR)
-Also, someone needs changing.
You're not the only one
that's full of it.
(DOOR OPENING)
SOLDIER: Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Get down, down here!
WOMAN: Hey, get off me!
SOLDIER: And he was like this
when you found him?
MAN: Yes, sir!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
SOLDIER: Wait here.
I'm putting a call into Osgood.
So no more Ghost then?
Ah, laid to rest.
-LUCY: Sure?
-Yeah, of course I'm sure.
I mean, life's not a comic book.
Right, Doctor?
Possibly I'm not
the right person to ask.
What if something happens?
What if the whole world is in danger?
Well, you know,
maybe I'll keep the outfit then?
-You know, just in case?
-Mmm.
The world will be fine.
I'd been away for a while, but I'm back.
I'll take care of anything
that comes up.
-You were away?
-Yeah.
Twenty-four years. What a night.
Where did you go?
Wrong question.
What was her name?
I'm sure that I must be busy now,
I better go.
-You okay?
-Yes! Yes, yes! I'm okay.
(TOY SQUEAKING)
Things end.
That's all.
Everything ends...
And it's always sad.
But everything begins again too,
and that's always happy.
Be happy.
I'll look after everything else.
Nardole.
Hey, Doctor?
-(SQUEAKS)
-Keep it real.
Her name was River Song.
They were together for a while
and they were very happy.
And then she died,
a long time ago in a library.
You sure he's gonna be all right?
(CHUCKLES) He's the Doctor.
He's very brave and he's very silly.
And I think for a time
he's going to be very sad.
But I promise,
in the end he'll be all right.
I'll make sure of it.
Bye.
-(SIGHS)
-You never explained.
Who exactly is he? Doctor who?
(TARDIS POWERING UP)
GRANT: Doctor...
Mysterio.
(WHOOSHING)
I'm Bill. I serve chips.
He's a professor or a lecturer.
Or as I call him...
Doctor what?
And now we go everywhere...
-It's like a... Kitchen!
-Spaceship.
Any space.
Where are we?
Which way is Earth? What's a Dalek?
Can I use the toilet?
Any time.
Get in!
Whoa!
And now I see everything differently.
(SCREAMING)
(DALEKS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-Where are we?
-Basically in the middle of a war.
-(SCREAMS)
-And it's not as bad as it sounds.
I'm the Doctor.
I will save all your lives
and when I do,
you will spend the rest of them
wondering who I was.
Are you out of your mind?
Yes. Completely.
But that's not a recent thing.