Positions!
(BEEPING)
(POWER HUMMING)
'Night, boys.
(CREAKING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Sorry, lover.
(SIREN WAILING)
We've got the place surrounded, sir.
Hello. I'm so terribly sorry.
That card-paying-device thing,
that's a Lobster card, am I right?
-Oyster card.
-Ah, well, that's the problem, you see.
I only use my Oyster
when there's an "R" in the month.
It's April.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Go, go, go!
Diamonds. Genuine.
-Drive.
-Works for me.
No sign of her on the pavement.
Just in time, mate!
(BEEPS)
Hello, I'm the Doctor. Happy Easter!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(SIREN WAILING)
Right, close off the area.
Get all these people cleared.
She's got to be here somewhere.
Robinson, clear the road!
Get the whole place sealed off.
She's on the bus. She's on the...
Come on, get the car.
It's definitely her, come on. Move it.
Jackson, follow that bus!
(SIRENS WAILING)
Funny thing is, I don't often do Easter,
I can never find it.
It's always at a different time.
Although, I remember the original.
Between you and me,
what really happened was...
(BEEPING)
Oh, sorry, hold on to that for me.
Actually, go on, have it, finish it.
It's full of sugar and I'm determined
to keep these teeth.
Ah!
Oh, we've got excitation!
(BEEPING)
I'm picking up something very strange.
(STATIC WARBLING)
I know the feeling.
(SIRENS WAILING)
All units in pursuit,
registration Whisky 974,
Golf, Hotel, Mike. They're heading
for the Gladwell Road Tunnel.
Please stop all traffic,
seal off the north end.
The bus has entered
the south entrance of the tunnel.
Officers in pursuit.
Units now arriving
at the north entrance.
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
Tango 183 at the far end, sir.
I've sealed off the exit.
There's no way out, over.
I'm right behind. We've got her.
Rhondium particles,
that's what I'm looking for.
This thing detects them.
The little dish should go round,
that little dish there.
Right now, a way out
would come in pretty handy.
Can you detect me one of those?
CARMEN: Lou, can you hear them?
-Hear what, sweetheart?
-The voices.
So many voices. Calling to us.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Calling so far.
-Oh, the little dish is going round!
-Fascinating.
And round. Oh!
-Excuse me. Do you mind?
-Sorry, that was my little dish.
Can't you turn that thing off?
-What was your name?
-Christina.
Christina, hold on tight.
Everyone! Hold on!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(CRASHING)
The voices! The voices!
They're screaming!
What's going on?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Tango 183, units in position, sir.
Uh, sorry to report,
but no sign of the bus, over.
It's gone. Right in front of me.
The bus has just gone.
Over.
End of the line.
Call it a hunch, but I think we've
gone a little bit further than Brixton.
(CHIRRUPING)
LOU: We should get out.
Even if that's the Sahara,
we can't stay onboard this thing.
I'm not going out there.
They're still calling. All around us.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
The voices are crying.
What voices, sweetheart?
The dead.
We are surrounded by the dead.
That's impossible. There are three suns.
Three of 'em!
Like when all those planets
were up in the sky!
But it was the Earth
that moved back then, wasn't it?
Oh, man, we're on another world!
DRIVER: It's still intact, though.
Not as bad as it looks, though,
the chassis is still holding together.
Oh, my boss is gonna murder me!
Can you still drive it?
Oh, no, no. The wheels are stuck.
Look at them, they're never gonna budge.
Dennison, listen.
We've sealed off the far end.
Nothing is to come through.
But I don't understand, sir.
How can a bus just disappear?
Ready for every emergency.
(MECHANICAL BUZZING)
Me, too!
-And what's your name?
-I'm the Doctor.
-Name, not rank.
-The Doctor.
-Surname?
-You're called "The Doctor"?
-Yes, I am.
That's not a name,
that's a psychological condition.
Funny sort of sand, this.
There's a trace of something else.
(EXCLAIMING IN DISGUST)
-Blah, that's not good.
-Well, it wouldn't be, it's sand.
No, it tastes like...
-Never mind.
-What is it, what's wrong?
Hold on a minute. I saw you, mate!
You had that thing, that machine.
Did you make this happen?
Oh, humans on buses, always blaming me.
Look, look, if you must know,
I was tracking a hole
in the fabric of reality.
Call it a hobby. But it was a tiny,
little hole, no danger to anyone.
Suddenly it gets big
and we drive right through it.
Then where is it?
There's nothing, there's just sand!
DOCTOR: All right.
If you want proof,
we drove through this.
What the hell was that?
-And that's...
-A door.
A door in space.
So what you're saying is,
on the other side of that is home?
We can get to London through there?
The bus came through, but we can't.
-Then what are we waiting for?
-No, no, don't.
-I'm going home, mate!
-I said don't!
(DRIVER SCREAMING)
(CRACKLING)
He was a skeleton, man!
He was bones, just bones.
Dennison, uh, I think we're
out of our depth here.
We need experts.
Get me UNIT, Emergency Code One.
The bus, look at the damage.
It was the bus protecting us.
-Great big box of metal.
-Rather like a Faraday cage?
Like in a thunderstorm, yeah?
Safest place is inside a car,
'cause the metal conducts the lightning
right through. We did it in school.
But if we can only travel back
inside the bus...
A Faraday cage needs to be closed.
That thing's been ripped wide open!
Slightly different dynamics
with a wormhole.
There's enough metal to make it work,
I think. I hope.
Then we have to drive
five tonnes of bus,
which is currently buried in the sand,
and we've got nothing
but our bare hands, correct?
I'd say nine-and-a-half tonnes,
but the point still stands, yeah.
Then we need to apply ourselves
to the problem with discipline.
-Which starts with appointing a leader.
-Yes, at last, thank you, so...
Well, thank goodness you've got me.
Everyone, do exactly as I say.
Inside the bus, immediately!
-Is it safe in there?
-I don't think anything's safe any more.
But if it's a choice between
baking in there or roasting out here,
I'd say baking is slower.
Come on. All of you, right now!
And you, "The Doctor."
Yes, ma'am.
CHRISTINA: Up, come on.
Point five,
the crucial thing is, do not panic.
Quite apart from anything else,
the smell of sweat inside this thing
is reaching atrocious levels.
We don't need to add any more.
Point six, team identification.
Names, I'm Christina.
-This man is apparently "The Doctor”.
-Hello.
-And you?
-Nathan.
-I'm Barclay.
-Angela, Angela Whittaker.
My name's Louis, everyone calls me Lou,
and this is Carmen.
Excellent. Memorise those names.
There might be a test.
Point seven, assessment
and application of knowledge.
Over to you, The Doctor.
-I thought you were in charge.
-I am.
And a good leader utilises her strength.
You seem to be the brain box.
So, start boxing.
Right. So, the wormhole.
We were in the wrong place at the
wrong time, it was just an accident.
No, it wasn't.
That thing, the doorway,
someone made it for a reason.
How do you know?
LOU: She's got a gift.
Ever since she was a little girl,
she can just tell things.
-We do the lottery twice a week.
-You don't look like millionaires.
No, but we win £10.
Every week, twice a week, £10.
Don't tell me that's not a gift.
Tell me, Carmen.
How many fingers am I holding up?
Three.
-Four.
-Very good.
Low-level psychic ability,
exacerbated by an alien sun.
What can you see, Carmen?
Tell me, what's out there?
Something... Something is coming.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Riding on the wind.
-And shining.
-What is it?
Death.
-Death is coming.
-We're going to die.
Oh, I knew it, man. I said so.
We can't die out here,
no one's gonna find us.
-This isn't exactly helping.
-Shut up, we're not your soldiers.
-It's not doing any good.
-You're upsetting her, be quiet.
-Will we be bones, like the bus driver?
-CHRISTINA: Stop whimpering, all of you.
All right, now stop it,
everyone, stop it!
(SOBBING)
Angela, look at me. Angela? Angela?
Answer me one question, Angela.
That's it, at me, at me. There we go.
Angela, just answer me one thing.
When you got on this bus,
where were you going?
-Doesn't matter now, does it?
-Answer the question.
-Just home.
-And what's home?
Me, and Mike and Suzanne,
that's my daughter. She's 18.
Suzanne. Good. What about you?
-I don't know. Going round Tina's.
-Who's Tina? Your girlfriend?
Not yet.
Good boy. What about you, Nathan?
Bit strapped for cash,
I lost my job last week.
I was gonna stay in. Watch TV.
-Brilliant. And you two?
-I was going to cook.
It's his turn tonight, then I clear up.
-What's for tea?
-Chops.
Nice couple of chops and gravy.
Nothing special.
Oh, that's special, Lou.
That is so special.
Chops and gravy. Mmm!
What about you, Christina?
I was going...so far away.
Far away. Chops and gravy. Watching TV.
Mike and Suzanne, and poor old Tina.
-Hey!
-Just think of them.
'Cause that planet out there,
all three suns and wormholes and
alien sand, that planet is nothing.
You hear me? Nothing, compared to
all those things waiting for you.
Food and home and people.
Hold on to that.
"Cause we're gonna get there, I promise.
I'm gonna get you home.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
MAN 1: Section one, assume position.
Section two, assume position.
MAN 2: Section three, assume position.
MAN 3: Section four, assume position.
MAN 1: Spread out!
MAN 2: Take basic intervention mode.
-Isolate the area!
-Yes, ma'am.
Establish an exclusion zone.
Any media, move them back.
Any trouble, arrest them.
SOLDIER: Yes, ma'am.
I want the vehicles in a standard
Procedure Five layout.
All outreach officers will report to me
via Sergeant Calhoun.
-Is that understood?
-Yes, ma'am.
Captain,
I'm Detective Inspector McMillan...
Clear the area, thank you.
Yes, but I was here when the thing...
The bus with... The tunnel thing...
I've read the report.
Now clear the area!
Pandovski, get these men
out of the zone.
Yes, but there's somebody
on board that bus...
-Just move back, sir.
-She's mine!
-All right.
Perimeter guard, stand ready.
(GUNS COCKING)
Stay alert. Any hostile activity,
shoot to kill.
-BARCLAY: Here we go!
-That's my boys!
You see, we lay a flat surface
between the bus and the wormhole,
like duckboards, and we reverse into it!
Let some air out of the tyres,
just a little bit.
Spreads the weight of the bus,
gives you more grip against the sand.
-Oh, that's good!
-Holidays in the Kalahari.
-Yeah, but those wheels go deep.
-Then start digging.
-With what?
-With this.
Got anything else in there?
Try that. Might help with the seats.
Thanks!
ANGELA: I can't find the keys.
Buses don't have keys.
There's a master switch.
Then it's one button for start,
the other one for stop, yeah?
Right. Hold on. Oh, I've got it.
Here we go, hold tight, ding-ding!
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Oh, that doesn't sound too good.
Oh.
Never mind losing half the top deck,
do you know what's worse? Sand.
Tiny little grains of sand.
The engine's clogged up.
Anyone know mechanics?
Me, I did a two-week NVQ at the garage.
-Never finished it, but...
-Off you go, then.
Try stripping the air filter,
fast as you can.
-I'll be back in two ticks.
-Wait a minute.
You're the man with all the answers.
I'm not letting you out of my sight.
(CHIRRUPING)
Easier if you left that backpack behind.
Where I go, it goes.
A backpack, with a spade and an axe.
Christina, who's going so far away
and yet scared by the sound of a siren.
-Who are you?
-You can talk.
Let's just say
we're two equal mysteries.
We'd make quite a couple.
We don't make any sort of couple,
thank you very much.
Come on, then. Tell me.
If Carmen's right, if that wormhole's
not an accident, then what is it?
-Has someone done this on purpose?
-I don't know.
But every single instinct of mine
is telling me to get off this planet
right now.
-And do you think we can?
-I live in hope.
That must be nice.
It's Christina de Souza.
To be precise, Lady Christina de Souza.
Oh, that's handy. 'Cause I'm a lord.
Seriously? The Lord of where?
It's quite a big estate.
No, but there's something
more about you.
That device you were carrying,
and the wormhole. Like you knew.
And the way you stride
around this place, like...
-Like?
-Like you're not quite...
Anyway, come on!
-Allons-y!
-0ui,
mars pas s/ nous allons
vers urn cauchermar.
DOCTOR: (LAUGHING)
We were made for each other!
Ah, don't like the look of that.
CHRISTINA: Storm clouds.
Must be hundreds of miles away.
But getting closer.
If that's a sandstorm,
we'll get ripped to shreds.
It's a storm. Who said it's sand?
Closer and closer and closer.
Where is it?
There, there, on the seat.
You're hardly going to get a signal,
we're on another planet!
Oh, just watch me.
Right, now, bit of hush, thank you!
I've got to remember the number,
a very important number.
(PHONE RINGS)
MAN: Hello, Pizza Geronimo.
Then again! Ah! Seven-six not six-seven.
(DIALLING)
(PHONE RINGS)
MALE VOICE.: This is the Unified
Intelligence Taskforce.
Please select one of
the following four options.
Oh, I hate these things!
No, if you keep your finger pressed on
zero, you get through to a real person.
- I saw it on Watchdog.
-Thank you, Angela.
WOMAN: UNIT helpline,
which department would you like?
Listen, it's the Doctor! It's me!
Captain! Urgent call, ma'am,
relayed direct from HQ.
-Who is it?
-It's him, ma'am. It's the Doctor.
Doctor, this is Captain Erisa Magambo.
Might I say, sir, it's an honour.
Did you just salute?
No.
Erisa, it's about the bus.
HQ said you're at the tunnel, yeah?
-And where are you?
-I'm on the bus.
But apart from that, not a clue.
Except it's very pretty
and pretty dangerous.
A body came through here.
Have you sustained any more fatalities?
No, and we're not going to.
But I'm stuck, I haven't got the TARDIS,
and I need to analyse that wormhole.
We have a scientific adviser on site,
Dr Malcolm Taylor.
Just the man you need, he's a genius.
DOCTOR: Oh, is he? We'll see about that.
-Here's the Doctor.
-No, I'm all right now, thanks.
It was just
a little bit of a sore throat.
Although, I've got to be honest,
a cup of tea might be nice.
It's The Doctor.
Do you mean "The Doctor" Doctor?
I know, we all want to meet him one day,
but we all know
what that day will bring.
DOCTOR: I can hear
everything you're saying.
(EXCLAIMS INCREDULOUSLY)
-Hello, Doctor. Oh, my goodness!
-Yes, I am. Hello, Malcolm!
(CHUCKLES)
The Doctor! Cor blimey!
I can't believe
I'm actually speaking to you!
-I mean, I've read all the files!
-Really?
What was your favourite,
The Giant Robot?
No, no, hold on,
let's sort out that wormhole.
-Excuse me.
-On speakerphone, please.
I don't want anyone keeping secrets.
Malcolm, something's not
making sense here.
I've got a storm and a wormhole
and I can't help thinking
there's a connection.
I need a complete full-range analysis
of that wormhole, the whole thing.
Well, I've probably got the wrong idea,
but I've wired up an integrator.
I thought it could measure
the energy signature.
No, no, no, that'll never work.
Just listen to me.
It's quite extraordinary, though!
I'm measuring an oscillation
of 15 Malcolms per second.
-Fifteen what?
-Fifteen Malcolms.
It's my own little term.
A wavelength parcel of 10 kilohertz
operating in four dimensions
equals one Malcolm.
You named a unit of measurement
after yourself?
Well, it didn't do Mr Watt any harm.
Furthermore, 100 Malcolms
equals a Bernard.
Who's that, your dad?
Don't be ridiculous, that's Quatermass.
Right.
Fine. But before I die of old age,
which in my case would be quite an
achievement, so congratulations on that,
is there anyone else I can talk to?
No, no, no, no, but listen.
I set the scanner to register what
it can't detect and inverted the image.
-You did what?
-Is that wrong?
No, Malcolm, that's brilliant! So you
can actually measure the wormhole.
Okay, I admit, that is genius.
-The Doctor called me a genius.
-I know, I heard.
Now, run a capacity scan.
I need a full report.
Call me back when you've done it.
And, Malcolm?
-You're my new best friend!
-And you're mine, too, sir.
-Barclay, I'm holding on to this.
-Then you'd better bring it back!
You're, you're mine...
He's gone. He's gone.
(CHIRRUPING)
DOCTOR: Send this back to Earth,
see if Malcolm can analyse the storm.
There's something in those clouds.
Something shining, look.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
DOCTOR: Like metal.
CHRISTINA: Why would there
be metal in a storm?
So fast and strong, they ride the storm.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
They are the storm.
What are they?
They devour.
(CHIRRUPING)
-Did you hear something?
-Hold on. Busy.
There was a noise, like a sort of...
(GRUNTING)
(CHIRRUPING)
Doctor...
There's something new.
(CHIRRUPING)
(GRUNTING)
(MOUTHING)
That's "wait".
I shout "wait", people usually wait.
-You speak the language?
-Every language.
(CHIRRUPING)
(GRUNTING)
That's begging for mercy.
(CHIRRUPING)
-That means "move".
-Oh, you're learning.
CHRISTINA: These fly things,
they must be responsible.
They brought us here.
DOCTOR: No, no, no, no!
Look at the ship, it's a wreck.
They crashed just like us.
CHRISTINA:
Oh, but this place is freezing!
DOCTOR: Hmm.
The hull's made of Photafine steel.
Turns cold when it's hot.
Boiling desert outside,
freezing ship inside.
Since I met you, Christina,
we've been through all the extremes.
That's how I like things. Extreme.
(HISSING)
(CHIRRUPING)
Oh, this is beautiful.
Intact, it must've been magnificent.
A proper, streamlined deep-spacer!
Oh, I'll remember that
as I'm being slowly tortured.
At least I'm bleeding on the floor
of a really well-designed spaceship.
(CHIRRUPING)
Oh, right, good, yes. Hello!
That's a telepathic translator.
He can understand us.
(WARBLING)
Still sounds like gibberish to me.
That's what I said,
he can understand us.
Doesn't work the other way round.
(CHIRRUPING)
"You will suffer for your crimes."”
EX cetera. "You have committed
an act of violence
"against the Tritovore race.”
Tritovores, they're called Tritovores.
"You came here in the 200
to destroy us."
Sorry, what's the 2007
It's the bus, number 200,
they mean the bus.
Oh, no, look, I think you're making
the same mistake Christina did.
I'm the Doctor, by the way,
and this is Christina,
the honourable Lady Christina,
at least I hope she's honourable.
But we got pulled through that wormhole.
The 200 doesn't look like that normally.
It's broken, just the same as you.
(CHIRRUPING)
-What are they doing?
-They believe me!
-What, simple as that?
-I've got a very honest face.
And the translator says
I'm telling the truth.
Plus, the face.
Right! So, first things first,
there's a very strange storm heading
our way, can you send out a probe?
(CHIRRUPING)
Oh. They've lost power.
Hmm. The crash knocked the mainline
crystallography out of synch,
but if I can jiggle it back...
(GRUNTING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
I thank you!
(CHIRRUPING)
Yes, I am! Frequently.
Okey-doke, let's launch that probe.
The Scorpion Nebula.
We're on the other side of the universe.
Just what you wanted, so far away.
The planet of San Helios.
And that's us.
We're on another world.
-We have been for quite a while.
-I know, but seeing it like that...
-It's good, isn't it?
-Wonderful.
(CHIRRUPING RAPIDLY)
(GRUNTING)
The Tritovores were going to trade
with San Helios.
Population of 100 billion.
Plenty of waste matter
for them to absorb.
By waste matter, you mean...
They feed off what others leave behind.
From their...
Behind,
if you see what I mean.
It's perfectly natural. They are flies.
Charming.
Just remind me never to kiss them.
(CHIRRUPING)
DOCTOR: San Helios City.
CHRISTINA: That's amazing.
But you've seen this sort of thing
before, haven't you?
DOCTOR: Thousands of times.
That Lordship of yours.
The Lord of where, exactly?
Of Time. I come from a race of people
called Time Lords.
-You're an alien?
-Yeah.
But you don't have to kiss me either.
-You look human.
-You look Time Lord.
-Anyway...
-So, if that's San Helios,
all we need to do is find that city.
They can help us!
I don't think it's that simple.
We're in the city right now.
CHRISTINA: But it's sand.
That first image, the temples
and things, what's that, then?
Ancient history?
(CHIRRUPING)
-The image was taken last year.
-It became a desert in one year?
I said there was something in the sand.
The city, the oceans,
the mountains, the wildlife,
and 100 billion people, turned to sand.
All those voices in Carmen's head.
She's hearing them die.
But I've got sand in my hair.
That's dead people!
Oh, that's disgusting! Oh!
Something destroyed
the whole of San Helios.
Yes, but in my hair!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
DOCTOR: Malcolm! Tell me the bad news!/
Oh, you are clever!
It is bad news!
It's the wormhole, Doctor,
it's getting bigger!
We've gone way past 100 Bernards,
I haven't invented a name for that.
How can it get bigger by itself?
(BEEPING)
That's why I'm phoning!
You'll work it out, if I know you, sir!
Doctor, we estimate the circumference
of your invisible wormhole
is now four miles, heading outwards.
I've grounded all flights above London,
we can't risk anyone else
falling through.
-Good work, both of you.
-But I have to know.
Does that wormhole constitute
a danger to this planet?
(BEEPING)
Oh, sorry, call waiting. Gotta go!
-Call waiting?
-He's a devil, that one!
-Yeah?
-Doctor, it's Nathan.
We got those duck board
things down, but...
-It's my fault.
-No, it's not, don't say that.
-Why, what's happened?
-We kept on turning the engine, but...
We're out of petrol. Used it all up.
Even if we can get those wheels out,
this bus is never going to move.
What is it, what's wrong?
Doctor, tell me.
You promised you'd get us home. Doctor?
-Are you still there?
-Doctor, tell me, what did he say?
(BEEPING)
(CHIRRUPING)
It's the probe. It's reached the storm.
-And what's he saying?
-It's not a storm.
(SQUEALING)
It's a swarm.
-Millions of them.
-DOCTOR: Billions.
Ah! We've lost the probe.
I think it got eaten.
-Everything on this planet gets eaten.
-How far away is that swarm?
Hundred miles. At that speed,
it'll be here in 20 minutes.
(CHIRRUPING)
No, no, they're not just coming for us.
They want the wormhole.
-They're heading for Earth!
-Show the analysis!
Incredible!
They swarm out of a wormhole,
strip the planet bare,
then move on to the next world,
start the life cycle all over again.
-So, they make the wormholes?
-They must do.
But how? They don't exactly
look like technicians.
And if the wormhole belongs to them,
why are they 100 miles away?
Because they need to be?
No, that's bonkers. Hang on.
Yes! Oh, do you see?
Billions of them flying in formation,
all the way around the planet,
round and round and round,
faster and faster and faster,
till they generate a rupture in space!
The speed of them, and the numbers,
and the size,
all of that rips the wormhole
into existence!
-And the wormhole's getting bigger.
-Because they're getting closer!
But how do they get through?
'Cause that wormhole's a killer,
we've seen it.
-No, no, look. See the exoskeleton?
-Metal.
They've got bones of metal.
They eat metal and extrude it
into the exoskeleton.
So their velocity makes the wormhole,
then their body makes it safe.
Perfect design.
Those things are going to turn
the entire Earth into a desert.
So why exactly are you smiling?
-Worse it gets, the more I love it!
-Me, too.
(SQUEALING)
(RUMBLING)
-Sounds like a storm.
-If it rains, we've got water.
No water. All of it, dust.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
-But the girl...
-Don't now, sweetheart. What girl?
The girl, she will fly.
The thing is, Doctor,
you're missing the obvious.
We came here through the wormhole, yes?
But our Tritovore friends didn't.
They came here to trade with San Helios.
Therefore, the question is,
why did they crash?
Ah. Good question! What a team!
Like she said, why did you crash?
Oh, yes!
Gravity Well. Look, goes all the way
down to the engine.
So what happened?
(CHIRRUPING)
He says the drive system stalled.
Ten miles up, they fell out of the sky.
But what caused that?
(CHIRRUPING)
-Which means, "No idea."
-Yeah.
But wait a minute, that's
a crystal nucleus down there, yes?
(GRUNTS)
And it looks like it survived the crash.
If the crystal's intact...
Oh, yes, that's better than diesel!
What, you can use the crystal
to move the bus?
I think so.
The spaceship's a write-off,
but the 200's small enough.
How does a crystal drive a bus?
In a super-clever, outer-spacey way.
Just trust me.
There's the crystal.
It's fallen to the bottom of the well.
Have you got access shafts?
(CHIRRUPING)
All frozen. Well, maybe I can open them!
Ah! Internal comms, put that on!
You stay here! Keep an eye on the shaft!
Tell me if anything happens!
If I can use that sunlight
to start the automatic maintenance.
Christina?
(GRUNTS) If you see a panel
opening in that shaft, let me know.
-Nothing yet.
-Anything now?
-Afraid not.
-Any sign of movement?
Nope.
-How's that?
-Nothing.
-Any result?
-Not a Dickie bird.
So let me get this right.
You need that crystal?
-Then consider it done.
-Why, what do you mean?
Christina?
Christina!
The aristocracy survives for a reason.
We're ready for anything.
No!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, come on, come on!
-That's better.
-I decide when I stop, thank you.
You were about to hit
the security grid. Look!
Excellent. So what do I do?
DOCTOR: Try the big red button.
-Well done!
-Now come back up! I can do that.
-Oh, don't you wish.
-Slowly!
CHRISTINA: Yes, sir.
Quite the mystery, aren't you?
Lady Christina de Souza.
-Carrying a winch in her bag.
-No stranger than you, spaceman.
I had this friend once.
-She called me spaceman.
-And was she right?
Do you zoom about the place in a rocket?
Well, a little, blue box.
Travels in more than space.
It can journey through time, Christina.
Oh, the places I've been. World War I.
Creation of the universe,
end of the universe,
the war between China and Japan.
And the court of King Athelstan
in 924 AD.
But I don't remember you being there.
So what are you doing with this?
Excuse me. A gentleman never
goes through a lady's possessions.
(CHIRRUPING)
It's the Cup of Athelstan.
Given to the first king of Britain
as a coronation gift from Hywel,
King of the Welsh.
But it's been held in the
International Gallery for 200 years,
which makes you, Lady Christina,
a thief.
I like to think I liberated it.
-Don't tell me you need the money.
-Daddy lost everything.
Invested his fortune
in the Icelandic banks.
No, no, no, if you're short of cash,
you rob a bank.
-Stealing this, that's a lifestyle.
-I take it you disapprove?
Absolutely.
Except, that little, blue box.
-I stole it. From my own people.
-Good boy.
You were right. We're quite a team.
(SCREECHING)
What the blazes was that?
We never did find out
why the ship crashed.
Christina, I think you should
come back up.
Too late. I can see it.
Careful. Slowly.
Have you got an open-vent system?
-I thought so.
-What does that mean?
It's like when birds fly
into the engines of an aircraft.
(GRUNTING)
-One of the creatures.
-Got trapped in the vents.
Caused the crash. Christina, get out.
It's not moving. I think it's injured.
No, it's dormant
because it's so cold down there.
But your body heat
is raising the temperature.
I tend to have that effect.
Almost there.
Not just the crystal.
I need the whole bed, the plate thing.
-CHRISTINA: I've got it!
-Come on! Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on!
It's gonna eat its way up!
(SQUEALING)
Ooh! She's good!
-That's it! That's it! That's it!
-Ooh!
I've got you. I've got you.
(GRUNTING)
-Isn't she just?
-Yeah.
Commander! Mission complete!
Now we've got to get back to the 200,
all of us.
Oh, don't be so daft.
A captain can leave his ship
if there's a bus standing by.
(RUMBLING)
What the hell was that?
Is this place safe?
It's the creature. It's not dead.
(CHIRRUPING)
Maybe you didn't hit just one of them.
If you hit a swarm...
Do you mean, if there's more on board?
This ship's built inside a metal sleeve.
They can move through
the infrastructure all around us.
(THUDDING)
And those things wake up hungry.
Commander, you've got to come with us,
right now!
You can come back to Earth,
we'll find you a home!
And that's the word of a lady! Come on!
(CRASHING)
(SCREAMING)
(SQUEALING)
(GRUNTING)
No, don't!
There's nothing we can do. Run!
What sort of storm is that?
Run, run, run, run, run, run, run!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
-Ah, Doctor.
-Not now, Malcolm!
Fair do's. He's a busy man.
At last! Where've you been?
Get inside, get them sitting down!
Now then, let's have a look.
-So what does that crystal do?
-Oh, nothing, don't need the crystal.
-I risked my life for that!
-No, you risked your life for these.
The clamps!
One there!
One there.
One there! And one there!
CHRISTINA: But what are the clamps for,
do they turn the wheels?
Something like that.
Just need to fix this.
-Have you got a hammer in that bag?
-Funnily enough.
Now press redial!
-Malcolm! It's me!
-I'm ready!
-Ready for what?
-I don't know! You tell me!
I'm gonna try to get back, but there
might be something following us.
You need to find a way
to close the wormhole.
Would that be
a compressed burst of feedback
-on a counter-oscillation, perchance?
-Oh, Malcolm! You're brilliant!
Coming from you, sir,
that means the world!
MAGAMBO: Doctor, what sort of something?
That wormhole is now measuring
10 miles and growing,
I need to know
the exact nature of the threat.
Sorry, gotta go!
All troops, mobilise and stand ready!
Possible Code Red, unknown!
-Understood. Code Red! Repeat, Code Red!
-SOLDIER: Position!
(MEN SHOUTING)
(CRACKLING)
Ah, it's not compatible!
Bus, spaceship, spaceship, bus.
I need to weld the two systems together.
-And how do you do that?
-I need something non-corrosive,
something malleable,
something ductile, something...
-Gold.
-Oh, no, you don't.
-Christina, what is it worth now?
-Hey! Use this!
-I said gold!
-It is gold!
Oh, they saw you coming. Christina!
It's over 1,000 years old.
Worth £18 million.
-Promise me you'll be careful.
-I promise.
I hate you.
(BEEPING)
Done it! Transmit that
and the wormhole should close.
Then do it.
Well, after the Doctor's
come through, obviously.
I'm sorry. Believe me.
That wormhole
constitutes a major threat,
and I have a duty to every man,
woman and child on this planet.
-It's got to be closed immediately.
-No, no, no.
-That's an order.
-No, no, no, no.
No, we can't just abandon him!
He's the Doctor!
How many times has he saved our lives?
I won't let you, ma"am. I simply won't!
(GUN COCKING)
Right now, soldier.
This is your driver speaking.
Hold on tight.
-What for, what's he doing?
-Do as he says!
(ENGINE CRANKING)
-What are you doing?
-Come on! That's it.
You can do it, you beauty!
One last trip!
(ENGINE POWERING UP)
(RATTLING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Oh! You are so kidding me!
-We're flying! It's flying!
-Yes!
He's flying the bus!
-It's a miracle!
-Anti-gravity clamps! Didn't I say?
Round we go!
(EXCLAIMING)
Doctor! They're coming!
I will never surrender. Never.
Do you think this thing
will survive the journey back?
-Only one way to find out! Next stop...
-Planet Earth!
(ALL YELLING)
-It's London!
-We're back home!
He did it! He did it!
Captain!
Captain! They're back!
It's the bus, ma'am, it's come back.
And it's flying!
Code Red! Fire at will!
(SCREECHING)
(BULLETS ZIPPING)
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
-Malcolm! Close that wormhole.
-Yes, sir! My pleasure, sir!
He's hung up on me!
Yes!
No, no, no!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
-Malcolm?
-Not now, I'm busy!
He's hung up again!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
-Malcolm! Listen to me!
-It's not working!
I need that signal, we've got billions
of those things about to fly through!
Well, what do I do?
Loop it back through the integrator
and keep the signal ramping up!
-By how much?
-500 Bernards! Do it now!
Yes!
SOLDIER: Maintain rapid fire!
Fire!
(FIRING CONTINUES)
Yes!
Target at nine o'clock!
I don't believe it, guns don't work!
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
Doctor, it's coming for us!
(ALL YELLING)
Oh, no, you don't!
(CRASHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
-Twelve o'clock! Take it out!
-SOLDIER: Fire!
(CRASHING)
-Cease fire! Arms down!
-SOLDIER: Cease fire!
Did I say I hated you?
I was lying.
(ALL SIGHING WITH RELIEF)
Do not stand forward of this point.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you have reached your final destination.
Welcome home, the mighty 200!
(BELL DINGING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Welcome back, everyone.
If you could step away from the bus,
just to be safe. As fast as you can,
thank you.
It's standard procedure,
we need to screen you
then you'll all be taken for debriefing.
-I don't count.
-No, but, Doctor...
With me, ma'am.
-Doctor!
-You must be Malcolm!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, I love you.
I love you. I love you.
To your station, Dr Taylor.
Yes, ma'am.
I love you.
Doctor, I salute you,
whether you like it or not.
Now, I take it
we're safe from those things?
They'll start again.
Generate a new doorway.
It's not their fault,
it's their natural life cycle.
But I'll see if I can nudge
the wormholes on to uninhabited planets.
Closer to home, Captain. Those two lads,
very good in a crisis.
Nathan needs a job, Barclay's good
with engines, you could do a lot worse.
Privates Nathan and Barclay,
UNIT's finest.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
MAGAMBO: I'll see what I can do.
And I've got something for you.
(LAUGHS)
Better than a bus, any day! Hello!
Found in the gardens
of Buckingham Palace.
Oh, she doesn't mind.
Now, I've got three dead
alien stingrays to clear up.
I don't suppose you fancy
helping with the paperwork?
Not a chance!
-Till we meet again, Doctor.
-I hope so.
I said I'm back, Suzanne, I'm home!
Didn't even know I was gone!
(DEVICE WARBLING)
That's quite enough of that!
She is not getting away this time.
Little, blue box! Just like you said.
Right, then, off we go!
Come on, Doctor, show me the stars!
-No.
-What?
-I said no.
-But I saved your life.
-And you saved mine.
-So?
We're surrounded by police.
I'll go to prison.
-Yeah.
-But you were right,
it's not about the money,
I only steal things for the adventure,
and today, with you,
I want more days like this.
I want every day to be like this.
We're made for each other,
you said so yourself.
The perfect team.
Why not?
People have travelled with me
and I've lost them.
Lost them all. Never again.
Lady Christina de Souza!
Oh, I've waited a long time to say this.
I'm arresting you on suspicion of theft.
You do not have to say anything,
et cetera, et cetera.
Dennison, take her away!
Doctor? You take care, now.
-You, too! Chops and gravy, lovely!
-No, but you be careful.
Because your song is ending, sir.
-What do you mean?
-It is returning.
It is returning through the dark.
And then, Doctor...
Oh, but then...
He will knock four times.
Alpha, alpha, five-one, alpha.
(MECHANICAL BUZZING)
-Hey!
-Hey, no, no! Stop that woman!
Stop that woman! Stop her!
Don't just stand there! Stop her!
Open the door!
I'll add resisting arrest!
I'd stand back, if I were you.
I'm charging you, too!
Aiding and abetting!
Yes, I'll just step inside
this police box and arrest myself.
Out! Now!
(WHIRRING)
-No! Come back!
-Go on!
(LAUGHING)
-We could've been so good together.
-Christina, we were.
(CHEERING)
State your name, rank and intention.
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN: They're on the roof.
(TRICKLING)
Water always wins.