(CREAKING)
What? (GRUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(CAR HONKING)
(GASPS)
-Oh, my stars! Are you all right?
-Yeah. I'm fine.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
-So I've got something for you.
-What?
-You kept it?
-Of course I kept it.
Why?
Because this exact leaf had to grow
in that exact way, in that exact place,
so that precise wind could tear it
from that precise branch
and make it fly into this exact face
at that exact moment.
And if just one of those
tiny little things had never happened,
I'd never have met you.
Which makes this the most important leaf
in human history.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
-There!
-There.
-Go on, kick it.
-(WHISTLING)
Oh, my stars! Are you all right?
Fine. Marvellous! Refulgent!
Possibly a touch embarrassed.
That's not dangerous, is it?
-What's not?
-(WHISPERING) Embarrassment.
Not usually. Not to my knowledge.
Good! Hey? Phew!
(CHUCKLING) I am so sorry.
She wants to be Bryan Robson.
No worries, my fault. No harm done.
-Hello there...
-Clara.
Ah.
Hello there, Clara.
(CROW CAWING)
(SIGHING)
She's just a girl. How can she be?
She can't be!
She is! She can't be!
She's not possible!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(TARDIS DOOR OPENING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
CLARA: So we're moving
through actual time?
So what's it made of, time?
I mean, if you can just
roll right through it,
it's got to be made of stuff,
like jam's made of strawberries,
-so what's it made of?
-Well, not strawberries, no.
No, no, no. That would be unacceptable.
-And we can go anywhere?
-Within reason. Well, I say reason...
-So we could go backwards in time.
-And space, yes.
-And forwards in time.
-And space, totally.
So where do you want to go, hey?
What do you want to see?
I don't know.
Do you know when somebody asks you
what's your favourite book
and straightaway you forget
every single book that you've ever read?
-No, totally not.
-Well, that's a thing that happens.
-And? Back to the question.
-Okay, so...
So... So...
So I'd like to see...
I would like to see...
What I would like to see is...
something awesome.
-Can you feel the light on your eyelids?
-Mmm-hmm.
That is the light of an alien sun.
Forward a couple of steps.
Okay.
-Are you ready?
-Yes.
No! Yes.
Welcome to the Rings of Akhaten.
-It's...
-Ooh! Yeah, it is. It so completely is.
But wait. There is more.
-More what?
-Wait, wait, wait.
In about five...
four...
three...
Look at that.
-What is it?
-The pyramid of the Rings of Akhaten.
It's a holy site for
the Sound Singers of Akhate.
-The who of what?
-Seven worlds orbiting the same star,
all of them sharing the belief that
life in the universe originated here,
on that planet.
-All life?
-In the universe.
-Did it?
-Well...
it's what they believe.
It's a nice story.
Can we see it? Up close?
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
(ALIENS CHATTERING)
(ALL SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
-(GIGGLING)
-DOCTOR: I can't pay for that.
CLARA: Where are they from?
Oh, you know, the local system, mostly.
-And what do I call them?
-Well, let's see.
Ah, there go some Pan-Babylonians.
A Lugarlirakush.
Uh...some Eukanians.
A Hooloovoo.
Ah!
(CONVERSING IN ALIEN DIALECT)
That chap's a Terraberserker
of the Kodonian Belt.
You don't see many of them
around any more.
Ho-ho! That's an Ultramanta!
You know, I forget
how much I like it here.
We should come here more often.
-You've been here before?
-Yes, yes, yes.
I came here a long time ago
with my granddaughter.
Hang on!
(SNARLING)
Mmm!
Exotic fruit of some description.
All right, non-toxic,
non-hallucinogenic,
high in free radicals and low
in other stuff, I shouldn't wonder.
No?
So why is everyone here?
Ah! For the Festival of Offerings.
Takes place every 1,000 years or so
when the rings align.
It's quite a big thing locally,
like Pancake Tuesday.
-Oh!
-(GROWLS)
(BARKING)
Um, Doctor?
What's happening? Why is it angry?
This isn't an it. It's a she.
Dor'een, meet Clara.
Clara, meet Dor'een.
-Dor'een?
-Loose translation.
She sounds a bit grumpy
but she's a total love, actually.
-Aren't you? Yes, you are.
-(PURRING)
You know, actually, she's just asking
you if you fancy renting a moped.
(MIMICS MOPED HUMMING)
(DOR'EEN SNARLS)
(BARKS)
-So how much does it cost?
-Not money. Something valuable.
Sentimental value. A photograph,
love letter, something like that.
That's what's used for currency here.
Psychometry. Objects psychically
imprinted with their history.
The more treasured they are,
the more value they hold.
-That's horrible.
-Much better than using bits of paper.
-Then you pay.
-With what?
You're a thousand years old,
you must have something you care about.
Hmm... (SCOFFING)
(CLARA LAUGHING)
Doctor?
Oh!
Hi. You okay?
-Have you seen her?
-Who?
-The Queen of Years.
(LIQUID DRIPPING)
Hello?
(ECHOING CRASH)
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
(GASPING)
Hi.
Are you okay? Are you lost?
(PANTING)
(SHRIEKS)
(LAUGHS)
You all right?
-What are you doing?
-Hiding.
Oh. Why?
You don't know me?
Sorry, actually not.
-So why did you follow me?
-To help. You looked lost.
I don't believe you.
I've got no idea who you might be.
I've never been here before.
I've never been anywhere
like here before.
I just saw a little girl
who looked like she needed help.
-Really?
-Really really.
-Can you help me?
-That's why I'm still here.
Because I need to hide.
(DISTORTED, WHISPERY VOICE) Merry.
Where are you, Merry?
I know the perfect box.
Merry!
(SOFT GROWL)
Where are you, Merry?
-Merry!
(GROWLING)
(WHISTLING NONCHALANTLY)
What's this?
A spaceshippy-thing, timey, spacey.
-It's teeny.
-Ha! You wait.
(DOOR RATTLING)
-Oh, come on!
-What's wrong?
I don't know.
I don't think it likes me.
(KNOCKING)
Come on! Let me in!
Hey, hey, little girl!
My name's Merry.
(CLARA CLEARS THROAT)
So what's happening?
-Is someone trying to hurt you?
-No.
I'm just scared.
-Of what?
-Getting it wrong.
Okay, can you pretend like
I'm totally a space alien and explain?
I'm Merry Galel.
I'm really not local, sorry.
The Queen of Years?
They chose me when I was a baby,
the day the last Queen of Years died.
-Okay.
-I'm the vessel of our history.
I know every chronicle, every poem,
every legend, every song.
Every single one?
Blimey, I hated history.
Now I have to sing a song
in front of everyone.
A special song,
I have to sing it to a god.
I'm really scared.
Everyone's scared when they're little.
I used to be terrified of getting lost.
I used to have nightmares about it.
And then, I got lost.
Blackpool Beach. Bank Holiday Monday,
about 10 billion people,
I was about six.
My worst nightmare come true.
What happened?
My world ended, my heart broke
and then my mum found me.
We had fish and chips
and she drove me home
and she tucked me up
and she told me a story.
Doesn't matter where you are,
in the jungle or the desert
or on the moon.
However lost you might feel,
you'll never really be lost, not really.
Because I will always be here
and I will always come and find you.
Every single time.
(FADING) Every single time.
And you were never scared again?
Oh, I was scared lots of times,
but never of being lost.
So, this special song,
what are you scared of exactly?
Getting it wrong.
Making Grandfather angry.
And do you think you'll get it wrong?
Because I don't.
I don't think you'll get it wrong.
I think you, Merry Galel,
will get it very, very right.
(METALLIC CHATTERING)
-What have you been doing?
-Exploring.
Where are we going now?
CHORISTER: # Sleep, my precious king
# Lay down
# My warrior
# Rest now
# My hero #
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
DOCTOR: (SHUSHING) Sorry, sorry.
-Excuse me, sorry, excuse me.
-CLARA: Sorry. Sorry.
(CLARA CLEARING THROAT)
-Are we even supposed to be here?
-Shh!
-But are we?
-Sorry.
-(GROWLING)
# Akhaten
-# Lay down
-MERRY: # Akhaten
# My king
# Sleep now eternal
# Sleep, my precious king
# Lay down
# O God of Akhaten
Oh, look.
They're singing to the mummy
in the temple.
They call it the Old God,
sometimes Grandfather.
# O God of Akhaten
What are they singing?
The Long Song.
A lullaby without end,
to feed the Old God. Keep him asleep.
It's been going for millions of years,
Chorister handing over to Chorister
generation after generation
after generation.
# Akhaten #
(ALIEN SNORTING)
-What are they doing?
-These are offerings.
Gifts of value.
Mementos to feed the Old God.
(CHUCKLING)
# O God of
O God of
# Sleep, my precious king
# Akhaten
(LAUGHS)
(ALL SINGING)
# Lay...
ALL: # Lay down
# Akhaten
# O God of
O God of
# 0 God of Akhaten
# Rest now your heart...
(RUMBLING)
(GASPING)
# Old God
# Protect us
# Old God, protect... #
Okay, what's happening?
Is that supposed to happen?
-(SCREAMING)
-Is somebody going to do something?
Excuse me,
is somebody going to help her?
(MERRY SCREAMING)
Why are we walking away?
We can't just walk away.
This is my fault,
I talked her into doing this.
Listen, there is one thing you need
to know about travelling with me.
Well, one thing apart from the blue box
and the two hearts.
We don't walk away.
(SOBBING)
(BARKING)
(GROWLING)
-I need something precious.
-Well, you must have something.
All the places you've seen,
there must be something.
This. And I don't want to give it away
because it comes in handy.
You're a thousand years old
and that's it? Your spanner?
Screwdriver.
It was my mum's.
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
CLARA: Merry!
(SCREAMING)
Wait! Wait!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
-Okay. Time to let go.
-I can't.
-Clara, you have to.
-Why?
-Because it really hurts.
-Sorry.
(WHIRRING)
Oh, that is interesting,
a frequency-modulated acoustic lock.
The key changes 10 million zillion
squillion times a second.
-Can you open it?
-Technically, no. In reality, also no.
-But still, let's give it a stab.
-Oh!
CHORISTER: # Don't wake from slumber
Old God, never wake from slumber #
CLARA: How can they just
stand there and watch?
Because this is sacred ground.
-But she's a child!
-Yeah, and he's a god.
Well, he is to them, anyway.
# Do not wake from slumber, Old God
Do not wake from slumber
# Rest your weary holy head
and cast our lives asunder
# Do not wake from slumber... #
I don't know what to do next.
What happens?
(SCREAMING)
CLARA: Merry! Merry, hold on!
We'll be there soon!
-Doctor.
-Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
-Oh, hello.
-Hello what?
Sonic locked onto
the acoustic tumblers.
-Meaning?
-Meaning I get to do this.
Ah! Hello there, I'm the Doctor.
And you met Clara, she was supposed
to be having a nice day out.
Still, it's early yet.
Are you coming, then?
Did I mention
that the door is immensely heavy?
Leave! You'll wake him.
Really quite extraordinarily heavy.
(GRUNTING)
-Clara!
-Uh-huh.
# ...from slumber, Old God,
never wake from slumber... #
-Merry, we need to leave.
-No! Go away.
CLARA: Not without you.
You said I wouldn't get it wrong
and then I got it wrong.
And now this has happened.
Look what's happened!
You didn't get it wrong.
How do you know?
You don't know anything!
You have to go.
Go now or he'll eat us all.
Well, he's ugly but you know,
to be honest...
I don't think he looks big enough.
Not our meat, our souls.
He doesn't want you, he wants me.
If you don't leave,
he'll eat you all up, too.
Yes. And you don't want that, do you?
You want us to walk out of this
really quite astonishingly heavy door
and never come back.
-Yes.
-I see. Right. Clarified.
Absolutely never going to happen.
(VOCALISING)
-Did you just lock us in?
-Yep.
-With the soul-eating monster?
And is there actually a way to get out?
What? Before he eats our souls?
-Ideally, yeah.
-Possibly.
-Probably. There usually seems to be.
-(CHORISTER CONTINUES SINGING)
Doctor, why's he still singing?
# ...God, rest your weary holy head... #
He's trying to sing
the Old God back to sleep,
but that's not going to happen.
He's waking up, mate.
He's coming, ready or not.
You want to run.
# .. .head and... #
That's it, then? Song's over?
The song is over.
My name is Chorister Asbethix
and the Long Song
ended with me.
That's it, then, song's over.
(SNARLING)
-Well! Ah, look at that!
-You've woken him!
-It's awake? What's it doing?
-(SNARLING)
Oh, you know, having a nice rest.
No, we didn't wake him
and you didn't wake him, either.
He is waking because it's his time
to wake and feed.
On you, apparently, on your story.
-She didn't say story, she said soul.
-Same thing.
The soul's made of stories, not atoms.
Everything that ever happened to us,
people we love, people we lost,
people we found again
against all the odds.
He threatens to wake,
they offer him a pure soul,
the soul of the Queen of Years.
-(SOFTLY) Stop it. You're scaring her.
-Good.
She should be scared,
she's sacrificing herself,
she should know what that means.
Do you know what it means, Merry?
-A god chose me.
-It's not a god.
It'll feed on your soul
but that doesn't make it a god.
It is a vampire and you don't
need to give yourself to him.
Hey, do you mind if I tell you a story?
One you might not have heard.
All the elements in your body were
forged many, many millions of years ago,
in the heart of a faraway star
that exploded and died.
That explosion scattered those elements
across the desolations of deep space.
After so, so many millions of years,
these elements came together
to form new stars and new planets
and on and on it went.
The elements came together
and burst apart,
forming shoes and ships
and sealing wax and cabbages and kings.
Until, eventually,
they came together to make you.
You are unique in the universe.
There is only one Merry Galel.
And there will never be another.
Getting rid of that existence
isn't a sacrifice, it is a waste.
So if I don't, then everyone else...
-Will be fine.
-(OLD GOD GROWLING)
-But how?
-There's always a way.
You promise?
Cross my hearts.
CLARA: Having a nice stretch?
(LOUD RUMBLING)
Something's coming. What's coming?
The Vigil.
And what's the Vigil?
If the Queen of Years is unwilling
to be feasted upon...
DOCTOR: Yes?
It's their job
to feed her to Grandfather.
VIGIL: Merry.
MERRY: I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
-Don't you dare.
-Yep. Stay back! I'm armed!
-With a screwdriver.
-(ROARING)
Whoa!
(ROARING)
(SNARLING)
VIGIL: Here...
(GROWLING)
Clara, the sonic.
(ROARING)
(DOCTOR SHOUTING)
You know all the stories. You must know
if there's another way out.
(STAMMERING) There's a tale.
A secret song, the people
of the temple only knew this door.
And the secret songs
open the secret door?
How does it go? Can you sing it?
(VOCALISING)
DOCTOR: Go!
(OLD GOD SNARLING)
Doctor!
(WHIRRING)
(ROARING)
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
CLARA: Where did they go?
Grandfather's awake.
They're of no function any more.
Well, you could sound happier about it.
(RUMBLING)
Actually, I think I may have made
a bit of a tactical boo-boo.
More of a semantics mix-up, really.
What boo-boo?
I thought the Old God
was Grandfather but it wasn't,
it was just Grandfather's alarm clock.
Sorry, a bit lost.
Who's the Old God? Is there an Old God?
Unfortunately, yes.
(RUMBLING)
Oh, my stars.
What do we do?
Against that? I don't know. Do you know?
I don't know. Any ideas?
But you promised. You promised.
I did. I... I did promise.
He'll eat us all.
He'll spread across the system,
consuming the seven worlds.
And when there's no more to eat,
he'll embark on a new odyssey
among the stars.
- I say leg it.
-Leg it where, exactly?
-Don't know. Lake District?
-Oh, the Lake District's lovely.
Let's definitely go there.
We can eat scones.
They do great scones in 1927.
(RUMBLING)
You're going to fight it, aren't you?
Regrettably, yes.
I think I may be about to do that.
-It's really big.
-I've seen bigger.
-Really?
-Are you joking? It's massive!
-I'm staying with you.
-No, you're not.
-Yes, I am. I can assist.
-No, you can't.
What about that stuff you said?
We don't walk away.
No. We don't walk away.
But when we're holding on to
something precious, we run.
We run and run, fast as we can.
And we don't stop running
until we are out from under the shadow.
Now, off you pop.
Take the moped, I'll walk.
Any ideas?
No, didn't think so.
Righty-ho, then.
(RUMBLING)
Lordy.
Isn't he frightened?
I think he is.
I think he's very frightened.
-I want to help.
-So do 1.
# Rest now
# My warrior
# Rest now #
-Okay, then. That's what I'll do.
-(MERRY CONTINUES SINGING)
I will tell you a story.
# ...world then
ALL: # Live
# Wake up
# And let the cloak
# Of life
# Cling to your bones #
Can you hear them?
All these people who lived in terror
of you and your judgement,
all these people
whose ancestors devoted themselves,
sacrificed themselves to you.
Can you hear them singing?
# Live
# Wake up #
DOCTOR: Oh, you like to think
you're a god.
But you're not a god.
You're just a parasite,
eaten out with jealousy and envy
and longing for the lives of others.
You feed on them.
On the memory of love and loss and birth
and death and joy and sorrow, so...
So...come on, then.
Take mine.
Take my memories.
But I hope you've got a big appetite.
Because I've... (GRUNTING)
...lived...a long life.
And I have seen a few things.
MERRY: # Wake up
# And let the cloak
# Of life
# Cling to your bones #
DOCTOR: I walked away
from the last great time war.
I marked the passing of the Time Lords.
I saw the birth of the universe
and I watched as time ran out,
moment by moment,
until nothing remained.
No time, no space.
Just me!
I walked in universes
where the laws of physics were devised
by the mind of a madman.
And I watched universes freeze
and creations burn.
I have seen things you wouldn't believe!
I have lost things
you will never understand!
And I know things.
Secrets that must never be told,
knowledge that must never be spoken.
Knowledge that will make
parasite gods blaze!
So, come on, then!
Take it! Take it all, baby!
Have it! You have it all!
MERRY: # Wake up
# Wake up #
(RUMBLING)
And I will always come and find you.
Every single time.
We don't walk away.
(GROANING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Still hungry?
Well, I've brought something for you.
This.
The most important leaf
in human history.
(GRUNTS)
The most important leaf
in human history.
It's full of stories. Full of history.
(LAUGHING)
And full of a future
that never got lived.
Days that should have been
that never were,
passed on to me.
This leaf isn't just the past.
It's a whole future that never happened.
There are billions and millions
of unlived days
for every day we live, an infinity.
All the days that never came.
And these are all my mum"s.
Well, come on, then.
Eat up.
Are you full?
I expect so.
Because there's quite a difference,
isn't there,
between what was
and what should have been.
There's an awful lot of one
but there's an infinity of the other.
And infinity is too much,
even for your appetite.
(RUMBLING)
(WHOOSHING)
Home again, home again, jiggety-jig.
It looks different.
No. Same house, same city, same planet.
Ha-hey! Same day, actually, huh?
Ooh, not bad.
Hole in one!
You were there.
At Mum's grave, you were watching.
-What were you doing there?
-I don't know. I was just making sure.
Of what?
-You remind me of someone.
-Who?
Someone who died.
Well, whoever she was,
I'm not her, okay?
If you want me to travel with you,
that's fine.
But as me.
I'm not a bargain-basement stand-in
for somebody else.
-I'm not going to compete with a ghost.
-No.
They wanted you to have it.
-Who did?
-Everyone.
All the people you saved.
You. No one else.
Clara.
Alarm!
DOCTOR: How many were there left?
Twelve.
This sub's stuffed
with nuclear missiles.
What are you going to do
when he finds that out?
Bring her up!
Who's there?
MAN: We are all that stands
between this creature
and the destruction of the world.
He's arming the warheads.
DOCTOR: Clara, get out of there.
Get out!
I will blow this sub up before
you can even reach that button.