Oh, I missed you. I can't
believe River blew you up.
OK, I didn't mean to do that.
I didn't do that. I'm
sure I didn't do that.
And more importantly, where's my fez?
Doctor, that is you, is it?
Can you explain how my fez got here?
Albert Einstein, nice to see
you. What are you doing here?
I was working on my time
machine when it started shaking.
I put my hand in to try to turn it off,
went straight through it and ended up here.
So how's it going, your time machine?
Oh, not great. I've singed my eyebrows,
almost died twice and fallen off a cliff.
In fact, I'm quite close to perfecting
it. I think this liquid is the key.
Oh, yes. But no.
Is it yes or no?
No.
So how did I get here?
You're the original owner of this fez.
The fez I happen to be carrying during
an unavoidable collision with this lever.
My lever plus your fez equals
time window in the TARDIS.
My TARDIS, by the way, so don't
get any ideas trying to steal it again.
You said you were going
to give my toothbrush back.
About that, the Daleks kind of exterminated
it last week. Or was it last century?
So, going back to this, I
guess it's not bionic fusion liquid.
Never mind. Pass it to me.
I'll just run some tests on it.
I made it. I'll do the test.
That's the 20th century physicist for
you. Always wanting to do it themselves.
Where have you hidden my
bicarbonated processing machine, huh?
A genius like me needs
better than this old trash.
Old trash?
I'll have you know this old trash
will be around until the end of time.
In fact, it was.
Ah, and, Albert, I almost forgot, whatever
you do, do not drink that liquid. It may...
Ooh, I like your new
look. It's an Ood, isn't it?
I can tell you've got the
wiggly bits and everything.
Death is the only answer.
Ooh, can you hear me? What's your name?
What do you mean? Answer to what?
OK, you don't want to tell me, but wait,
wait, this is what you're looking for, huh?
Power source for your time machine.
What just happened?
Long story. You went
a bit Ood. Er, a bit odd.
Nice hair. You should keep
it. It looks more science-y.
I don't feel too good. Will
you drop me off home, please?
Sorry about that.
Exactly what year did you come from?
Er, 1945, I think.
Here we go. 1945, 18th of
September, about to occur.
Oh, well, back to the drawing board.
I guess you're keeping the fez, then?
Well, fezes look better on
me than you. Like bow ties.
Typical doctor. Some
things will never change.
Oh, well, goodbye.
Goodbye, Albert.