Hello, Mum.
Susie says hello. Don't you, sweetheart?
(GASPING) That's it. Give a little wave.
(CHUCKLING) What was I gonna say?
Uncle Soon called in. He says hello.
He keeps saying,
"You must be missing her."”
I said, "She's been gone for over
two years now. I'm getting used to it.”
(DISTORTED) [It's breaking up.
It must be the solar flares.
Talk faster.
About the deposit on the house, I've...
(BABY CRYING)
Oh. Um... I've spoken to the bank...
(WHOOSHING)
DOCTOR: The red planet.
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALARM STOPS)
ED ON RADIO: Sun sets
in 19 minutes, Yuri.
You're gonna lose the light.
MIA: That's it. Got you on external 10.
YURI: Almost there.
That's the radial clamp down.
One more thing...
Get back inside.
You're using power and oxygen.
Oh, hold on. Get this on camera.
(LAUGHING)
What do you think?
Hey, looks good. Nice one, Yuri.
You wasted an entire solar panel
just to make that.
Oh, lighten up. It's a joke.
We come all this way to an empty planet
untouched by civilisation
and what do we do? Put up cheap jokes.
That's not funny, that's pollution.
-Having fun?
-I was just telling him...
I expect better of you, Ed.
Now get back to work, all of you.
Oh, beautiful.
ELECTRONIC VOICE: Rotate, slowly.
You are under arrest for trespassing.
Gadget-gadget.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
State your name, rank and intention.
The Doctor. Doctor...Fun.
What the hell?
It's a man!
Man on Mars. How?
He was wearing this thing.
I have never seen anything like it.
What did Mission Control say?
They're out of range for 10 hours
with the solar flares.
If you could cut the chat, everyone.
Actually, chat's second on my list,
the first being gun pointed at my head.
Which then puts my head second
and chat third, I think.
Gun, head, chat. Yeah. I hate lists.
But you could hurt someone
with that thing. Just put it down.
Oh, you'd like that.
Can you find me someone who wouldn't?
-Why should I trust you?
-Because I give you my word.
At 40 million miles away from home,
my word is all you've got.
Keep Gadget covering him.
Gadget-gadget.
Oh right, so you control that thing.
Auto-glove response.
You got it. To the right.
-Gadget-gadget.
-And to the left.
It's a bit flimsy.
Gadget-gadget.
Does it have to keep saying that?
I think it's funny.
I hate funny robots.
Excuse me, boss. Computer log says
we've got an extra person on site.
How's that possible?
Keep the Bio-dome closed. And when using
open comms, you call me Captain.
Yeah, but who is it?
(RADIO DISCONNECTING)
Disconnected! She's cut me off.
Can you believe her?
It's like we're just gardeners.
As long as they leave us alone,
it's fine with me.
Oh, you beauties.
Look at this.
Better start planting some more
if there's an extra mouth to feed.
The very first garden off Earth.
Everything brand new.
Eden. That's what we should have
called this place.
It's the Philippines, I bet.
If there's someone else on Mars,
it's got to be the Philippines.
All those stories about them
building a rocket.
(SCOFFING) Adelaide is gonna love that.
Stealing her thunder.
Mind you, worth it to see her face.
Or it could be the Spanish.
They've kept that space link project
under wraps.
Didn't your sister work for them?
Are you all right, mate?
(CHUCKLING) Come on, stop mucking about.
Andy?
Are you okay?
(SCREAMING)
It can't be a World State flight
because we'd know about it.
Therefore he's got to be one
of the independents, yeah?
Was it the Branson Inheritance lot?
They've been talking
about a Mars shot for years.
Right, yes. Okay, you got me.
So, I'm the Doctor and you are?
Oh, come on. We're the first
off-world colonists in history.
Everyone on planet Earth
knows who we are.
You're the first?
The very first humans on Mars?
-Then this is Bowie Base One.
-Bowie Base One.
Number One. Founded July 1st, 2058.
Established Bowie Base One
in the Gusev Crater.
-You've been here how long?
-Seventeen months.
It's 2059 right now.
(EXCLAIMING)
My head is so stupid.
You're Captain Adelaide Brooke!
And Ed, you're Deputy Edward Gold.
Tarak Ital, MD.
Nurse Yuri Kerenski.
Senior technician Stef ft Ehrlich.
Junior technician Roman Groom.
Geologist Mia Bennett.
You're only 27 years old.
As I said, Doctor,
everyone knows our names.
Oh, they'll never forget them.
What's the date today?
What is it? Tell me the exact date.
November 21st, 2059.
Right. Okay, fine.
Is there something wrong?
What's so important about my age?
I should go.
I really should go. I'm sorry.
(STAMMERING) I'm sorry
with all of my hearts,
but it's one of those very rare times
when I've got no choice.
It's been an honour.
Seriously, a very great honour
to meet you all.
The Martian pioneers.
Oh, thank you. Ah!
Gadget-gadget.
Thank you.
There's the other two. Hold on.
Margaret Cain and Andrew Stone.
Maggie, if you want to meet
the only new human being
that you're gonna see
in the next five years,
better come take a look.
(SNARLING)
What was that?
Oh, I really should go.
This is Central.
Bio-dome, report immediately.
Show me the Bio-dome.
Internal cameras are down.
Show me the exterior.
I'm going over.
Doctor, with me.
I'm sorry. I'd love to help,
but I'm leaving right now.
Take his spacesuit, lock it up.
This started as soon as you arrived,
so you're not going anywhere,
except with me.
Gadget-gadget.
ADELAIDE: What's so important
about Mia's age?
You said she's only 27.
Why does it matter? What did you mean?
Oh, I just open my mouth
and words come out.
-They don't make much sense.
-You're telling me.
-Thank you, Doctor.
-Anytime, Doctor.
Gadget-gadget.
I hate robots, did I say?
Yeah, and he's not too fond of you.
What's wrong with robots?
It's not the robots, it's the people.
Dressing them up
and giving them silly voices,
like you're reducing them.
Yeah. A friend of mine, she made
her domestic robot look like a dog.
Oh, well, dogs, that's different.
But I adapted Gadget out of the worker
drones. Those things are huge.
They built this place when the shell
was lowered down from orbit.
They've got a strength capacity
of 15 tonnes...
The channel is open
for essential communications only.
Sorry.
Love those drones.
I've read all that stuff about you,
Captain Adelaide.
One thing they never said,
was it worth it, the mission?
We've got excellent results
from the soil analysis.
I know... But all of it.
They say you sacrificed everything,
devoted your whole life to get here.
It's been chaos back home.
Forty long years, climate,
the ozone, the oil apocalypse.
We almost reached extinction.
And to fly above that,
to stand on a world with no smoke,
where the only straight line
is the sunlight,
-yes, it's worth it.
-Ah.
That's the Adelaide Brooke
I always wanted to meet.
The woman with starlight in her soul.
What's that?
-It's Maggie.
-Don't touch her!
I know the procedure. Maggie,
can you hear me? It's Tarak. Maggie?
It's okay. She's still breathing.
She's alive.
Yuri, I've got Margaret Cain,
head trauma. I need a full med pack.
I've got it. Med pack on its way.
I'm going to help!
In the absence of the Captain,
you're in charge, sir!
You've got to stay in the dome!
Don't touch her. Use the gloves.
Do what he says. Get her to sickbay.
Put her in isolation.
We're going on to the Bio-dome.
Tarak, with me.
Yuri can take care of her. Ed, go back.
Gadget, stand guard.
Keep an eye on this area.
Gadget-gadget.
Captain, you're gonna need me.
Andy is the only other
crew member out here.
And if that wasn't an accident,
then he's gone wild.
You've deserted your post.
Consider that an official warning.
Now, get back to work. Doctor!
(SNARLING)
Captain, that sound we heard
from the Bio-dome,
I've run it through diagnostics.
According to the computer, it's Andy.
It registers as the voice print
of Andy Stone.
Understood. Double-check, thanks.
Air pressure stabilised.
(DOOR OPENING)
Andrew? Andrew Stone?
It's Captain Brooke.
Andrew, report. I need to see you.
Where are you?
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
DOCTOR: There you go.
-What's that device?
-Screwdriver.
-Are you the Doctor or the janitor?
-I don't know. It sounds like me.
The maintenance man of the universe.
You, stay with me.
Don't step out of my sight.
Tarak, go to external door south.
Make sure it's intact.
Yes, ma'am.
Quite an achievement.
First flower on Mars in 10,000 years.
And you're growing veg!
It's that lot. They're already
planning Christmas dinner.
Last year it was dehydrated protein.
This year they want the real thing.
-Still, fair enough. Christmas.
-If we must.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
-You've got birds!
-It's part of the project,
to keep the insect population down.
-Good sign.
-In what way?
Well, they're still alive.
Captain, good news. It's Maggie.
She's awake. She's back with us.
(GROANING)
Hey, how are you, soldier?
Just take it easy.
Can you remember what happened?
I was just working.
Then I woke up here.
What about Andy? We can't find him.
Was he all right?
I don't know. I just...
ADELAIDE: If you remember anything,
let me know straightaway.
Yuri, does she know
how she ended up in the tunnel?
And keep the comms clear.
Everything goes through me, got that?
(SIGHING)
Come on, just let me out of here.
I'm fine. Just groggy.
You know the rules. 24 hours.
TARAK: Andy?
Andy? Andy?
(WATER RUNNING)
There you are.
You all right?
Andy?
Andrew,
look at me.
(SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Is that your brother?
Well, it's only a repeat.
The solar flares are still up.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. Just, you know.
(LAUGHING) He makes me laugh, though.
It's his husband.
He spends money like an idiot.
Last year for Mikhail's birthday,
he said, "Don't buy me anything.
"Let's save money."
George says, "Fine, okay."
His birthday comes around,
turns out George has bought him a car,
top of the range.
And the thing is
he's used Mikhail's credit stamp.
So Mick's saying,
"That means I bought it myself."
George says,
"It's the thought that counts.”
-Where does he live?
-Oh, just outside Dagestan.
-Where's that?
-On the Caspian Sea. Here you go.
-By the sea?
-Well, technically, it's more of a lake.
-Earth is so much water.
-Yeah.
Just look at her. 40 million miles away.
MAGGIE: It has so much beauty.
(DISTORTED VOICE)
We should like that world.
This is sickbay. We have a situation.
Maggie's condition is...
(STAMMERING) I don't know...
I don't know what it is.
It's water, just pouring out.
ADELAIDE: Yuri, calm down.
Just tell me what's happened to her.
The skin is sort of broken
around the mouth.
And she is exuding water,
like she's drowning.
Tarak, this area's unsafe.
We're going back.
Tarak?
-Tarak!
-Where was he?
Yuri, keep her contained.
Seal the door at maximum. I'm on my way.
Andy, just leave him alone.
-Step away from him.
-I can help, I promise. I can help.
Just leave that man alone.
Andy, I'm asking you,
please just take your hand away from him
-and listen to me.
-Stop or I'll shoot.
There now, that's better, hmm?
So, you must be Andy. Hello.
We've got to go.
DOCTOR: Set the seals at maximum!
What the hell?
That's not Maggie.
What's happened to her?
Yuri, what is she?
Captain, we need you back here.
Just tell me that Maggie is contained.
Can you confirm, Ed?
Confirmed.
She's locked in.
Keep surveillance till I get back
and close down all water supplies.
All pipes and outlets.
Don't consume anything.
Have you got that, everyone?
That's an order.
Don't drink the water.
Don't even touch it. Not one drop.
Can you talk?
Human beings are 60% water,
which makes them the perfect host.
What for?
I don't know.
I never will...because I've got to go.
Whatever started here,
I can't see it to the end. I can't.
(GASPING)
(SNARLING)
-This thing's airtight, yeah?
-And, therefore, watertight.
Depends how clever the water is.
-They're fusing the system.
-Abandon ship!
Doctor, we haven't got time.
They can run faster than us.
We need a lift.
Hey!
Gadget-gadget.
(SCREAMING)
-Get on behind me.
-That thing goes at two miles an hour.
Not any more. Trust me.
-Gadget-gadget.
-DOCTOR: Gadget-gadget.
(SCREAMING)
The central dome airlocks have got
Hardinger seals.
There's no way they can get in.
-DOCTOR: Come on! Come on!
-Gadget-gadget.
Come on, come on, come on!
-I thought you hated robots.
-I do!
We're safe. It's hermetically sealed.
They can't get in.
Water is patient, Adelaide.
Water just waits.
It wears down the cliff tops,
the mountains, the whole of the world.
Water always wins. Come on.
ADELAIDE ON RADIO: Bio-dome tunnel
ls out of bounds.
Andy and Tarak are infected,
repeat, infected.
Make no contact. And if they make
the slightest move, tell me.
I'm going to the Medical dome.
(BEEPING)
Blimey, it's the distance.
You could do with bikes in this place.
Every pound in weight equals
three tonnes of fuel.
Yeah, I know, but bikes...
-Has that door got a Hardinger seal?
-No, just basic.
Then the moment she heads for the door,
we evacuate, got that?
Pulse is low. Electrical activity
in the brain seems to be going haywire.
-Can she talk?
-YURI: Don't know.
She was talking
before we noticed the change, but...
Maggie, can you hear me?
Do you know who I am?
Your commanding officer
Captain Adelaide Brooke.
Can you tell me what happened?
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
What language is that?
Ancient North Martian.
-Don't be ridiculous.
-It's like she recognised it.
And her eyes are different.
They're clear,
like she's closer to human.
Not close enough for me.
-Where do you get your water from?
-The ice field.
That's why we chose the crater.
We're on top of an underground glacier.
Tonnes of water. Marvellous.
But every single drop is filtered.
It's screened, it's safe.
Looks like it, yeah.
If something was frozen down there,
a viral life form out in the ice
for all those years...
Look at her mouth. All blackened
like there's some sort of fission.
This thing, whatever it is, doesn't just
hide in water, it creates water.
Tell me what you want.
She was looking at the screen, at Earth.
She wanted Earth. A world full of water.
Captain, with me.
I'm sorry, but it's an unknown infection
and it's spreading.
That demands Action Procedure One.
-You think I don't know that?
-I think you need reminding.
Yeah.
-Well, at least I'm good for something.
-Now and again.
That's almost a compliment.
Things must be serious.
(STAMMERING) Sorry, sorry, but
Action One, that means evacuation, yeah?
We're going home.
This is Captain Brooke.
I'm declaring Action One.
Repeat. To all crew members,
this is Action One
with immediate effect.
Evacuate the base.
(ALARM BLARING)
I'll store the central computer.
Mia, strip the cargo down to essentials.
-Roman, on your feet.
-But we came all this way.
Gadget-gadget.
And you can kiss that robot goodbye.
It's too heavy.
Now shove it in storage and hurry up.
ADELAIDE ON RADIO: Stef ft what's
your estimate on shuttle viability?
It's a nine-month flight.
It'll take us at least three hours
to load up everything we need.
You've got 20 minutes.
And give me a report on Andy and Tarak.
Still in the Bio-dome tunnel.
They're just standing there,
like they're waiting.
Keep an eye on them.
And make that 20 minutes 15.
Ed, line up the shuttle.
Go straight to ignition status.
-Doing it now.
-But what about Maggie?
She stays behind. We've got no way
to contain her on board.
Close this place down. I want the power
directed to the shuttle.
Of course, the only problem is...
Thank you, Doctor. Your spacesuit
will be returned and good luck to you.
The problem is this thing is clever.
It didn't infect the bird or the insects
in the Bio-dome, it chose the humans.
You were chosen.
And I told you, Adelaide,
water can wait.
Tarak changed straightaway,
but when Maggie was infected,
it stayed hidden inside her, no doubt,
so it can infiltrate the Central dome.
Which means...
Any one of us could already be infected.
-We've all been drinking the same water.
-And if you take that back to Earth...
One drop, just one drop...
But we're only presuming infection.
If we can find out how this thing
got through, when it got through...
Yuri, continue with Action One.
I'm going to inspect the ice field.
Right. I should leave.
Finally, I should leave.
Yuri, me old mate,
no point in me seeing the ice field.
No point at all. No.
Adelaide!
All I'm saying is bikes.
Little, foldaway bikes.
Don't weigh a thing.
I'm sorry.
Even if she gets past the Medical dome,
she'll never get past the Hardinger seal
at this end, right?
So we keep saying.
Camera's down.
We've lost her.
(SCREAMING)
They tell legends of Mars from long ago
of a fine and noble race
who built an empire out of snow.
-The Ice Warriors.
-I haven't got time for stories.
Perhaps they found something down there.
Used their might and their wisdom
to freeze it.
Doctor, we need to find any sort
of change in the water process.
We've got to date the infection.
COMPUTER: Access denied.
You don't look like a coward,
but all you've wanted to do is leave.
-You know so much about us.
-Well, you're famous.
It's like you know more.
This moment, this precise moment
in time, it's like...
I mean, it's only a theory.
What do I know?
But I think certain moments in time
are fixed.
Tiny, precious moments.
Everything else is in flux,
anything can happen,
but those certain moments,
they have to stand.
This base on Mars
with you, Adelaide Brooke,
this is one vital moment.
What happens here must always happen.
Which is what?
I don't know.
I think something wonderful happens,
something that started 50 years ago,
isn't that right?
I've never told anyone that.
You told your daughter.
And, maybe, one day she tells a story
to her daughter
of the day the Earth was stolen
and moved across the universe.
And you...
I saw the Daleks.
We looked up,
the sky had changed.
Everyone was running and screaming.
And my father took hold of me.
Stay here. Don't move.
I've got to go out.
I'm going to find your mother.
But I'm coming back, I promise you.
I'm coming back.
ADELAIDE: I never saw him again.
Nor my mother. They were never found.
But, out on the streets,
there was panic and burning.
I went to the window.
And there, in the sky...
I saw it Doctor.
And it saw me.
It stared at me.
It looked right into me.
And then...
It simply went away.
I knew, that night,
I knew I would follow it.
-But not for revenge.
-What would be the point of that?
That's what makes you remarkable.
And that's how you create history.
-What do you mean?
-Imagine it, Adelaide.
If you began a journey
that takes the human race
all the way out to the stars.
It begins with you.
And then your granddaughter,
you inspire her
so that, in 30 years,
Susie Fontana Brooke
is the pilot of the first
light-speed ship to Proxima Centauri.
And then everywhere.
With her children and
her children's children forging the way
to the Dragon Star,
the Celestial Belt of the Winter Queen,
map of the Water Snake Wormholes.
One day, a Brooke will even fall in love
with a Tandonian prince
and that's the start of
a whole new species.
But everything starts with you,
Adelaide.
From 50 years ago to right here, today.
Imagine.
Who are you?
Why are you telling me this?
Doctor, why tell me?
As consolation.
(BEEPING)
Andy Stone. He logged on yesterday.
Maintenance log 2120, November, 20589.
Number three water filter's bust.
And guess what?
The spares they sent don't fit.
What a surprise.
Over and out.
A filter.
One tiny little filter
and then the flood.
But that means the infection
arrived today,
and the water's only cycled out
of the Bio-dome after a week.
The rest of us can't be infected.
We can leave.
Ed, we're clean. How are we doing?
Shuttle's active, stage one.
I haven't got time to
convey the protein packs.
If you want food, you're going to
have to carry it by hand.
Start loading. Right now.
-You were right, Doctor.
-What about?
Bikes.
(LAUGHING)
Now, get to your ship.
I'm saving my people, you save yourself.
I know what this moment is.
It's the moment we escape. Now get out.
-Come on!
-How many do we need?
(CREW ISSUING INSTRUCTIONS)
ADELAIDE: Roman, what about you?
Protein packs, 30 to 36.
ED: Hurry up, Roman!
I'm on it!
(BEEPING)
Stef ft, ditch the central containers.
We don't need them.
Units 41, 42 and 43.
No, wait, 41 is here.
I'll swap them around.
(BEEPING)
Roman, try to condense
the oxygen membranes.
We can lose ten pounds. Faster! Come on!
-Ed, how's the fuel jets?
-Cooling down in about 30 seconds.
(BEEPING)
(SENSORS BEEPING)
What the hell is that noise?
Mia, you lot, shut up.
(SENSORS CONTINUE BEEPING)
It's the module sensors.
Exterior as well.
The cameras are down, but there's
pressure on top of the module.
Two signals right above us.
That means...they're on the roof?
-How did they get inside the dome?
-They used the maintenance shafts.
But the shaft's open
and they haven't got spacesuits.
-ED: They breathe water.
-They'd freeze.
YURI: They've got that internal fission.
MIA: Are we safe?
They can't get through, can they?
(CEILING CREAKING)
Can they?
-This place is airtight.
-Can it get through? Ed?
-Can it get through?
-I don't know.
Water itself isn't motile,
but it has some sort of resistance.
Everyone, listen to me. That's
10 feet of steel combination up there.
We need all the protein packs
or we're going to starve.
Now, keep working.
Roman, watch the ceiling.
Ed, get to the shuttle, fire it up.
I can carry more than this lot, Captain.
-That's an order.
-Captain.
COMPUTER: Access denied. Access denied.
ADELAIDE ON MONITOR:
Tell me what happens.
I don't know.
Yes, you do. Now tell me.
-You should be with the others.
-Tell me!
I could ramp up the pressure
in that airlock and crush you.
Except you won't.
You could have shot Andy Stone,
but you didn't.
I loved you for that.
Imagine...
Imagine you knew something.
Imagine you found yourself somewhere,
I don't know, Pompeii.
Imagine you were in Pompeii.
What the hell has that
got to do with it?
And you tried to save them,
but, in doing so, you make it happen.
Anything I do
just makes it happen.
Captain, we need you right now.
ADELAIDE: I'm still here.
You're taking Action One.
There are four more standard
action procedures and Action Five is...
Detonation.
The final option.
The nuclear device at the heart
of the Central dome.
Today, on the 21st of November, 2058,
Captain Brooke activates that device,
taking the base
and all her crew members with her.
No one ever knows why.
But you were saving Earth.
That's what inspires your granddaughter.
She takes your people out
into the galaxy
because you die on Mars.
You die today.
She flies out there
like she's trying to meet you.
I won't die.
I will not.
But your death creates the future.
Help me.
Why won't you help, Doctor,
if you know all of this?
-Why can't you change it?
-I can't.
-Why can't you find a way? Tell me.
-Adelaide, I swear, I can't.
I'm sorry, but I can't.
Sometimes I can, sometimes I do.
Most times, I can save someone.
Or anyone. But not you.
You wondered all your life why that
Dalek spared you. I think it knew.
Your death is fixed in time forever.
And that's right.
-You'll die here, too?
-No.
What's going to save you?
Captain Adelaide Brooke.
(AIR WHOOSHING)
Damn you.
(DOOR OPENING)
Water! We've got water!
MIA: Captain! Get back! Get back!
Captain!
Don't touch it, Roman!
Don't let it touch you!
ADELAIDE: Get back!
Everyone, we're abandoning this section.
Get to the shuttle.
Yuri, lead the way.
Section B corridor, now.
STEFFI: Get that. And that.
Close it!
STEFFI: Yuri, did that water touch you?
-I'm safe.
-Did it touch you? Yuri?
-Did that water touch you?
-I'm clean, I'm dry.
Everyone, Section B is out.
Listen to me.
Take every pack that you can.
We'll go round.
We'll make our way out
through Section F.
STEFFI: Transferring authorisation,
Section F.
Mia, you take the red line stock.
And hurry up!
(CLANGING)
YURI: Stef ft! Go!
MIA: Stef ft, get back!
-Get back!
-Stef ft, keep back!
YURI: Get back!
ADELAIDE: Stef ft!
YURI: Just get back! Stef ft!
MIA: Get back!
-Get back! Hurry!
-MIA: You'll be safer there!
ROMAN: Just shut the door!
Close the door!
Stef ft, we'll come get you, okay?
We'll come get you!
(EXCLAIMING)
-Stef ft!
-Captain!
We'll open the access panel.
We'll get you out through the back.
Get her out! Move it!
(STEFFI SCREAMS)
Captain, it's inside!
ROMAN: Stef ft!
MIA: Stef ft, get back. Stef ft!
ADELAIDE: We're coming, Stef ft. Hold on!
ROMAN: The access panel's
fused, Captain.
-We can't open it.
-YURI: We can't get through.
STEFFI: Don't! Don't please!
YURI: 7here's nothing we can do.
STEFFI: 7 can't move!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SOBBING)
(GIRL CONTNUES SPEAKING GERMAN
ON MONITOR)
Stef ft, can you hear me?
Oh, my God.
(CHILD CONTINUES SPEAKING GERMAN
ON MONITOR)
Out. Get out.
Ed, we're going around the long way.
How are we doing?
All systems online 100%.
Not a single delay.
Don't you worry, Captain,
we are gonna fly.
ADELAIDE: I need air in Section F,
right now.
YURI: Locking chamber three.
Locking chamber four.
ADELAIDE: Keep looking.
ROMAN: Gate 5 is open. Gate 6 is open.
YURI: Quickly. Come on.
MIA: I've got 25 to 30 lockdown.
-Roman, come on, with me.
-You better go.
ADELAIDE: Don't just stand there, move.
ROMAN: You'd really better
go without me.
I'm sorry, Captain.
One drop.
Roman! Roman!
Leave him. Come on.
MIA: We can't just leave him!
YURI: Sorry. Come on!
MIA: Left me go!
YURI: 7 can't let you go.
MIA: (CRYING) Roman!
YURI: I'm so sorry.
(GROANING)
-ED: Captain, the shuttle is down.
-What the hell do you mean?
Compromised. It was Maggie.
-ADELAIDE: Get out of there.
-Too late.
And they want this ship to get to Earth.
Got no choice.
(ED GROANING)
Hated it Adelaide.
(GROANING) This bloody job.
You never gave me a chance.
(BEEPING)
You never could forgive me.
See you later.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(AIR ESCAPING)
We're losing oxygen!
The hull is broken!
DOCTOR: I'm not just a Time Lord,
I'm the last of the Time Lords.
MAN: You'll never come back, Doctor.
DOCTOR: I've got a TARDIS.
Same old life, last of the Time Lords.
And they died, took it all with them.
The walls of reality closed,
the worlds were sealed, gone forever.
And the Time Lords kept their eye
on everything. And it's gone now.
But they died, the Time Lords.
All of them, they died.
I'm the last of the Time Lords.
(ALARM BLARING)
Mia, take this sealant and fix that rig.
Yuri, open the emergency oxygen.
Adelaide, don't just sit there.
That's better.
The dome's still got integrity.
It's 10 feet of steel combination
made in Liverpool.
Magnificent workmanship.
It can't be stopped. Don't die with us.
No, because someone told me
just recently,
they said I was going to die.
They said he will knock four times
and I think I know what that means.
And it doesn't mean
right here, right now.
'Cause I don't hear anyone knocking,
do you?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Three knocks is all you're getting.
(SCREAMING)
Water and electricity, bad mix.
Now then, what else have we got?
But there's no way to fight them.
Heat! They use water,
so we can use heat.
Works against the Ice Warriors,
works against the flood.
We'll ramp up the environment controls
and steam them!
But you said we die.
(THUDDING)
For the future, for the human race.
Yes, because there are laws.
There are laws of time.
Once upon a time, there were people
in charge of those laws, but they died.
They all died.
Do you know who that leaves? Me!
It's taken me all these years to realise
the laws of time are mine
and they will obey me!
(GROANING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Environmental controls are down.
Sorry, Doc, but it looks like
history's got other ideas.
Not beaten yet. I'll go outside!
Look at the heat regulator.
Not beaten, not beaten!
You've got spacesuits
in the next section!
We're not just fighting the flood,
we're fighting time itself
and I'm gonna win!
(ROARING)
Something is happening to the glacier.
Think, think, think. What have we got?
Not enough oxygen.
Protein packs, useless.
Glacier, glacier...
Mints, minty, Monty, motto bene,
bunny, bonny, bish, bash, bosh!
Ahh! The room! The room! The room!
Look at the room.
Section F... What's in Section F?
-Anyone?
-Nothing. It's just storage.
-Storing what?
-I don't know. The weather spikes,
the robots, the atom clamps...
Atom clamps, atom clamps!
Who needs atom clamps?
I love a funny robot!
Gadget-gadget.
(CONTINUES ROARING)
-You take that. Good boy.
-Gadget-gadget.
-Off we go, then.
Come on! Come on!
COMPUTER: Implementing
Captain's protocol.
Adelaide, what are you doing?
Oh, my God. Action Five.
If I have to fight you as well,
then I will.
COMPUTER: Nuclear device now active
and primed.
Nuclear device now active and primed.
Blast off!
Gadget-gadget.
Faster!
(CONTINUES ROARING)
(ALL ROARING)
COMPUTER: Nuclear device
entering final process.
(EXCLAIMING)
Gadget-gadget.
And we're in!
(LAUGHING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Gadget-gadget.
(EXCLAIMING)
Isn't anyone going to thank me?
He's lost his signal.
Doesn't know where he is.
That's my house.
Don't you get it?
This is the 21st of November, 2059.
Same day on Earth.
And it's snowing. I love snow.
What is that thing?
It's bigger...
I mean, it's bigger on the inside.
Who the hell are you?
-Look after her.
-Yes, ma'am.
-You saved us.
-Just think, though.
Your daughter and your daughter's
daughter, you can see them again.
-Family reunion.
-But I'm supposed to be dead.
Not any more.
But, Susie,
my granddaughter,
the person she's supposed to become
might never exist now.
Nah, Captain Adelaide
can inspire her face-to-face.
Different details,
but the story's the same.
You can't know that.
And if my family changes,
the whole of history could change.
The future of the human race.
No one should have that much power.
Tough.
You should have left us there.
Adelaide, I've done this
sort of thing before,
in small ways, saved some little people.
But never someone as important as you.
Oh, I'm good.
Little people? What, like Mia and Yuri?
Who decides they're so unimportant? You?
For a long time now, I thought I was
just a survivor, but I'm not.
I'm the winner. That's who I am.
The Time Lord Victorious.
-And there's no one to stop you?
-No.
This is wrong, Doctor.
I don't care who you are.
The Time Lord Victorious is wrong.
That's for me to decide.
Now, you'd better get home.
Oh, it's all locked up.
You've been away.
Still, that's easy.
(WHIRRING)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
All yours.
Is there nothing you can't do?
Not any more.
(GUNSHOT)
ADELAIDE: I don't care who you are.
The Time Lord Victorious is wrong.
I've gone too far.
Is this it? My death?
Is it time?
No.
(LAUGHING)
Every night, Doctor, we have bad dreams.
But I was told he will knock four times.
MAN: Because a shadow is
falling over creation.
Something vast is stirring in the dark.
I'm going to die.
My name is the Master.
MAN: The darkness heralds
only one thing...
(LAUGHING)
The end of time itself.