(ALARM SOUNDING)
WOMAN: Would all passengers
please return to their seats
and fasten their safety belts.
We are experiencing slight turbulence.
Both engines failed and
the storm gate's critical.
The ship is going down.
Christmas is cancelled.
Entering atmosphere now.
Level! Keep her level!
With what? I can't see.
What's that stuff?
Clouds?
What kind of clouds?
Are you sending a distress signal?
Ah!
It's not me.
Who's in the honeymoon suite?
-I've sent for help.
-Who the hell are you?
Look, there's a friend of mine, okay?
And he can help us. He'll come.
And what are you wearing?
That doesn't matter.
Are you from the honeymoon suite?
Oh... Shut up.
Oh! Amy! The light's stopped flashing.
Does that mean he's coming?
-Honeymoon suite?
-Oh...
Oh, the clothes. Um...
It is just a bit of fun.
Rory, shut up!
Excessive oscillating
in the centre hull.
I'm sorry, does this mean he's coming or
does it mean I need to change the bulb?
He'll come. He always comes.
Right, well, he is cutting it
kind of fine.
If we can't stabilise the orbit,
we're finished.
MAN 1: There's nothing to lock on to.
MAN 2: I'm flying blind.
Come on, Doctor. Come on.
There's something coming alongside us.
Something small, like a shuttle.
Just this once, don't be late.
Ma'am, incoming message.
It's from the other ship.
On screen.
What does that mean?
It's Christmas.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Get your Chronicle here.
Sardicktown Chronicle!
Here you go.
MAN: On every world,
wherever people are,
in the deepest part of the winter,
at the exact midpoint,
everybody stops and turns and hugs,
as if to say, "Well done!
"Well done, everyone!
"We're halfway out of the dark.”
Back on Earth, we call this Christmas,
or the winter solstice.
On this world, the first settlers
called it the Crystal Feast.
You know what I call it?
I call it expecting something
for nothing!
Sir? Mr Sardick,
we're only asking for one day.
Just let her out for Christmas.
She loves Christmas.
Does she? Oh, does she? I see.
Hello! Oh, wakey, wakey!
It's Christmas!
Do you know what? I think
she's a bit cool about the whole thing.
(LAUGHING)
That was funny.
BOY: She's frozen.
She's what, sorry?
She's in the ice. She can't hear you.
Oh, what a clever little boy.
You must be so irritated.
How much?
Uh, it's, uh, 4,500 gideons, sir.
You took a loan of 4,500 gideons
and little Miss Christmas
is my security.
We're not asking for her back.
Just let her have one day.
Let her have Christmas with us.
Sir, it's the, uh, president.
Tell him I'm busy.
Now...
(CHUCKLING)
Where were we?
Oh, yes.
She's pretty, though, your daughter.
Maybe I should keep her.
She's not my daughter, sir.
She's my sister.
She volunteered for the ice
when the family were in difficulties
many years ago.
Sorry, sir, the president says
there's a Galaxy-class ship
trapped in the cloud layer and,
well, we have to let it land.
Or?
Well... Or it'll crash, sir.
Oh. Well, it's a kind of landing,
isn't it?
It's from Earth, sir, registering
over 4,000 life forms on board.
(LAUGHING)
KAZRAN: Not if we wait a bit.
MAN: We can't just let it crash, sir.
KAZRAN: Says who?
(WHOOSHING)
Oh, give it here.
Look, petal, we already have
a surplus population.
No more people allowed on this planet.
-I don't make the rules.
-Huh?
Oh, no, hang on. I do.
All right, you lot.
Poor, begging people.
Off home and pray for a miracle.
(COUGHING)
Ah!
Yes! Blimey, sorry!
Christmas Eve on a rooftop,
saw a chimney,
my whole brain just went,
"What the hell?"
Don't worry, fat fella will be
doing the rounds later.
I'm just scoping out the general...
chimneyness! Yes!
Nice size. Good traction.
(SIZZLING)
Big take.
-Fat fella?
-Father Christmas.
Santa Claus,
or, as I've always known him, Jeff.
There's no such person
as Father Christmas.
Oh, yeah? Me and Father Christmas,
Frank Sinatra's hunting lodge, 1952.
See him at the back with the blonde?
Albert Einstein,
the three of us together.
Vroom! Watch out! Okay?
Keep the faith.
Stay off the naughtiness.
Ooh, now what's this, then? I love this.
A big, flashy lighty thing,
that's what brought me here.
Big, flashy lighty things have got me
written all over them.
Not actually,
but give me time and a crayon.
Now, this big, flashy lighty thing
is connected
to the spire in your dome, yeah?
And it controls the sky.
Well, technically,
it controls the clouds,
which technically aren't clouds at all.
Well, they're clouds
of tiny particles of ice.
Ice clouds, love that. Who's she?
Nobody important.
Nobody important!
Blimey, that's amazing.
Do you know,
in 900 years of time and space,
I've never met anyone
who wasn't important before?
Now, this console is the key
to saving that ship
or I'll eat my hat, if I had a hat.
I'll eat someone's hat,
not someone who's using their hat,
I don't want to shock a man
or something.
Sorry, rambling.
That's because this isn't working!
Controls are isomorphic, one-to-one.
They respond only to me.
Oh, you fibber! Isomorphic!
There's no such thing.
(SYSTEM POWERING DOWN)
(SYSTEM REVVING UP)
(WARBLING)
These controls are isomorphic.
The skies of this entire world are mine.
My family tamed them and now I own them.
Tamed the sky? What does that mean?
It means I'm Kazran Sardick.
How could he possibly not know who I am?
Well, just easily bored, I suppose.
So, I need your help, then.
Make an appointment.
There are 4,003 people in a spaceship
trapped in your cloud belt.
Without your help, they're going to die.
Yes.
You don't have to let that happen.
I know, but I'm going to.
Bye-bye. Bored now. Chuck!
Oh, look at you, looking all tough now.
There are 4,003 people
I won't allow to die tonight.
Do you know where that puts you?
Where?
4,004,
Was that a sort of threaty thing?
Whatever happens tonight, remember,
you brought it on yourself.
Yeah, yeah, right. Get him out of here!
And next time, try and find me
some funny poor people.
(YELPS)
-No! Stop!
-Don't you dare! You leave him!
(GASPS)
Get them out of here!
Get that foul smelling family
out of here! Out!
BOY: We're going!
What? What do you want?
A simple life.
But you didn't hit the boy.
Well, I will next time.
You see, you won't. Now, why?
What am I missing?
Get out! Get out of this house!
The chairs. Of course, the chairs.
Stupid me. The chairs.
Chairs?
There's a portrait
on the wall behind me,
looks like you, but it's too old,
so it's your father.
All the chairs are angled away from it.
Daddy's been dead for 20 years
but you still can't get comfortable
where he can see you.
There's a Christmas tree
in the painting,
but none in this house on Christmas Eve.
You're scared of him,
and you're scared of being like him,
and good for you, you're not like him,
not really. Do you know why?
Why?
Because you didn't hit the boy.
Merry Christmas, Mr Sardick.
I despise Christmas.
Shouldn't. It's very you.
It's what? What do you mean?
Halfway out of the dark.
Get her downstairs with the others!
And clean up this mess!
MAN 1: I'm still blind!
Secondary burn shield vented.
-Have you got a plan yet?
-Yes, I do.
Are you lying?
Yes, I am.
Don't treat me like an idiot.
Is he lying?
(LAUGHING)
-No, no.
-DOCTOR: Okay.
The good news, I've tracked the machine
that unlocks the cloud belt,
I could use it to clear your flight
corridor and you could land, easily.
Well, hey, hey, that's great news.
But I can't control the machine.
Less great.
-But I met a man who can.
-Ah, well, there you go.
-And he hates me.
-Were you extra charming and clever?
-Yeah, how did you know?
-Lucky guess.
Sir? Sir?
Hang on.
I've never seen anybody
stand up to Mr Sardick like that.
Bless you, sir. And merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Lovely, sorry, a bit busy.
You'd better get inside, sir.
The fog's thick tonight
and there's a fish warning.
All right, yeah. Sorry, fish?
Yeah, you know what they're like
when they get a bit hungry.
Yeah, fish, I know, fish. Fish?
It's all Mr Sardick's fault, I reckon.
He always lets a few fish through the
cloud layer when he's in a bad mood.
Thank you,
and bless you once again, sir.
Fish?
Doctor, the captain says
we've got less than an hour.
What should we be doing?
Fish.
AMY: Sorry, what?
Fish that can swim in fog.
I love new planets.
Doctor... Doctor, please,
don't get distracted.
Now, why would people be frightened
of you tiny, little fellas?
Look at you,
sweet, little fishy-wishies.
Mind you, fish in the fog,
so the cloud cover... Ooh.
Careful up there!
Oh. Oh, great, thanks, Doctor,
because there was a real danger
we were all going to nod off.
We've got less than an hour!
DOCTOR: I know.
(DING DONG MERRILY ON HIGH PLAYING)
Doctor, how are you getting us off here?
Oh, just give me a minute!
Can't use the Tardis,
'cause it can't lock on.
So that ship needs to land,
but it can't land
unless a very bad man
suddenly decides to turn nice
just in time for Christmas Day.
Doctor, I can't hear you.
What is that? Is that singing?
-A Christmas carol.
-A what?
A Christmas carol!
AMY: Doctor?
-Kazran Sardick.
-AMY: Doctor!
Merry Christmas, Kazran Sardick.
(SNORING)
Hello.
My name is Kazran Sardick.
I'm twelve and a half.
And this is my bedroom.
(GRUNTING)
Top-secret special project.
This is my top-secret special project,
for my eyes only.
-Merry Christmas.
-ELLIOT: Kazran! Kazran!
Kazran, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
I've warned you before about this.
Stupid, ignorant, ridiculous child!
YOUNG KAZRAN: I was just going to
make a film of the fish.
ELLIOT: Fish are dangerous!
I just want to see them.
Don't be stupid. You're far too young.
YOUNG KAZRAN:
Everyone at school's seen the fish.
ELLIOT: 7hat's enough. You'll be singing
to them next, like gypsies.
Singing works. I've seen It.
The fish like the singing.
ELLIOT: What does it matter
what fish like?
YOUNG KAZRAN: People say we don't
have to be afraid of the fish.
They're not really interested in us.
You don't listen to people!
You listen to me!
(YOUNG KAZRAN YELPS)
YOUNG KAZRAN: Sorry, Father.
(ELLIOT SHOUTING)
(SOBBING)
It's okay. It's okay.
What have you done? What is this?
Found it on an old drive.
Sorry about the picture quality.
Had to recover the data using quantum
enfolding and a paper clip.
Oh, I wouldn't bother
calling your servants. They quit.
Apparently, they won the lottery
at exactly the same time,
which is a bit lucky,
when you think about it.
There isn't a lottery.
Yeah, as I say, lucky.
ELLIOT: 7here's a fog warning tonight.
You keep these windows
closed. understand? Closed!
(YOUNG KAZRAN SOBBING)
Who are you?
Tonight,
I'm the Ghost of Christmas Past.
ELLIOT: Mrs Mantovani will be
looking after you tonight.
You stay here 'til she comes.
Do you understand? Do you understand?
DOCTOR: Did you ever get to see a fish
back then when you were a kid?
What does that matter to you?
Look how it mattered to you.
(SOBBING)
I cried all night
and I learnt life's
most invaluable lesson.
Ah.
Which is?
Nobody comes.
Get out! Get out of my house!
Okay! I'll go, but I'll be back.
Way back.
Way, way back.
(SOBBING)
(WHOOSHING)
See? Back.
-YOUNG KAZRAN: Who are you?
-Hi I'm the Doctor.
I'm your new babysitter.
Where's Mrs Mantovani?
Ah, you'll never guess.
Clever old Mrs Manto,
she only went and won the lottery.
There isn't any lottery!
-There isn't any lottery.
-I know! What a woman!
YOUNG KAZRAN: If you're my babysitter,
why are you climbing in the window?
If I was climbing out the window,
I'd be going in the wrong direction.
Pay attention.
But Mrs Mantovani's always
my babysitter.
Times change. Wouldn't you say?
See? Christmas past.
Who are you talking to?
You.
Now, your past is going to change.
That means your memories
will change, too.
Bit scary,
but you'll get the hang of it.
-I don't understand.
-I'll bet you don't.
I wish I could see your face.
But that never happened!
But it did.
Right then, your bedroom!
Great, let's see, you're 12 years old,
so we'll stay away from under the bed.
Cupboard! Big cupboard!
I love a cupboard.
Do you know,
there's a thing called a face spider?
It's just like a tiny baby's head
with spider legs.
And it specifically evolved to scuttle
up the backs of bedroom cupboards.
Which, yeah, I probably
shouldn't have mentioned.
Right, so what are we going to do?
Eat crisps and talk about girls?
I've never actually done that,
but I bet it's easy. Girls! Yeah?
Are you really a babysitter?
I think you'll find
I'm universally recognised
as a mature and responsible adult.
It's just a lot of wavy lines.
Yeah, shorted out.
Finally, a lie too big.
Okay, no, not really a babysitter,
but it's Christmas Eve.
You don't want a real one. You want me.
Why?
What's so special about you?
Have you ever seen Mary Poppins?
-No.
-Good.
Because that comparison
would have been rubbish.
Fish in the fog. Fish in the clouds.
How do people ever get bored?
How did boredom even get invented?
My dad's invented a machine
to control the cloud belt.
Tame the sky, he says.
The fish will be able to come down,
but only when we let them.
We can charge whatever we like.
Yeah, I've seen your dad's machine.
What? You can't have.
Tame the sky.
Human beings, you always manage to
find the boring alternative, don't you?
Do you want to see what, fish?
We can do that. We can see a fish.
But aren't you going to tell me
it's dangerous?
Dangerous? Come on, we're boys!
And you know what boys say
in the face of danger.
-What?
-"Mummy."
YOUNG KAZRAN: Are there any
face spiders in here?
No, not at this time of night.
They'll all be sleeping
in your mattress.
So, why are you so interested in fish?
'Cause they're scary.
Good answer.
-What kind of tie is that?
-A cool one.
Why is it cool?
Why are you really interested in fish?
My school.
During the last fog belt,
the nets broke and there was an attack.
Loads of them. A whole shoal.
No one was hurt, but it was the most
fish ever seen below the mountains.
Were you scared?
I wasn't there.
I was off sick.
Ooh, lucky you.
Not lucky.
It's all anyone ever talks about now.
The day the fish came.
Everyone's got a story.
But you don't.
I see him.
YOUNG KAZRAN:
Why are you recording this?
Do you pay attention at school, Kazran?
Sorry, what?
'Cause you're not paying attention now.
Shh.
Now I remember.
No, Doctor, you mustn't!
Doctor, are you sure?
Trust me.
Okay.
Oi! Eyes on the tie. Look at me.
I wear it and I don't care.
Trust me.
Yes.
That's why it's cool.
Hello, fishy.
Let's see.
Interesting.
Crystalline fog, eh?
Maybe carrying a tiny electrical charge.
Is that how you fly, little fishy?
What is it? What kind? Can I see?
DOCTOR: Just stay there a moment.
-Is it big?
-No.
Just a little one.
So, little fella, what do you eat?
How little?
-Um...
-Can I come out?
No, no.
Maybe just wait there for a moment.
YOUNG KAZRAN: Well, what colour is it?
Big. Big colour.
What's happening?
Well, concentrating on the plusses,
you've definitely got
a story of your own now.
(DOOR BANGING)
Also, I got a good look at the fish and
I think I understand how the fog works,
which is going to help me
land a spaceship in the future
and save a lot of lives.
And I bet I'll get some
very interesting readings
off my sonic screwdriver when I get it
back from the shark in your bedroom.
There's a shark in my bedroom?
Oh, fine! Focus on that!
(DOOR BANGING)
Has it gone?
What's it doing?
What do you call it
if you don't have any feet
and you're taking a run-up?
No!
It's going to eat us.
It's going to eat us. It's going to...
It's going to... It's going to eat us.
Well, maybe we're going to eat it,
but I don't like the odds.
It's stuck. Let's see.
Tiny shark brain.
If I had my screwdriver
I could send a pulse and stun it.
Well, where's your screwdriver?
Well, concentrating on the plusses...
(ROARING)
Within reach.
You know, there's a real chance,
the way it's wedged in the doorway
-is keeping its mouth open.
-There is?
Just agree with me, 'cause I've only got
two goes and then it's your turn.
Two goes!
Two arms! Right then, okay...
Geronimo.
Open wide!
DOCTOR: What's the big fishy
done to you?
Swallowed half of you, that's what.
Half a screwdriver? What use is that?
Bad, big fishy.
YOUNG KAZRAN: Doctor?
I think she's dying.
Half my screwdriver's still inside.
But, yeah, I think so, I doubt they can
survive long outside the cloud belt.
Just quick raiding trips on a
foggy night.
(SNIFFLING)
Can't we get it back up there?
We were just going to stun it.
I didn't want to kill it.
She was trying to eat you.
She was hungry.
DOCTOR: I'm sorry, Kazran.
I can't save her.
I could take her back up there,
but she'd never survive the trip.
We'd need
a fully functioning life-support.
YOUNG KAZRAN: You mean, like an ice box?
Okay.
DOCTOR: Oh, a tree! Look at the tree!
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
DOCTOR: What is this?
YOUNG KAZRAN: The surplus population.
That's what my dad calls it.
Oh, it's not turning.
We're running out of time.
Ah, what's the number?
7258.
I don't know.
The place is full of alarms.
It's not just the door.
I need the number.
7258!
I need the number!
I'm not allowed to know until I'm older.
7258!
Just what I was after! Thank you!
(GROANING)
Ah, there's fish down here, too.
Yeah, but only tiny ones.
The house is built on a fog lake.
That's how Dad freezes the people.
They're all full,
but we could borrow one.
Yeah, this one.
DOCTOR: Hello again.
YOUNG KAZRAN: You know her?
Why, uh...
Important, is she?
She won't mind. She loves the fish.
My name is Abigail Pettigrew,
and I'm very grateful
for Mr Sardick's kindness.
She starts to talk about the fish
in a minute.
ABIGAIL: ...but I would not allow it.
And I could not have chosen this path
were it not for
the compassion and generosity
of the great philanthropist and patron
of the poor, Mr Elliot Sardick.
But I'm also surrounded by the fish,
the beautiful, iridescent, magical fish.
Why are these people here?
What's all this for?
My dad lends money.
He always takes a family member as...
He calls it security.
Hard man to love, your dad.
I suppose you know that.
I am not alone and I am at peace.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WARBLING)
What's wrong?
Just my half of the screwdriver
trying to repair itself.
It's signalling the other half.
(BEEPS APPROACHING)
The other half's inside the shark.
Yeah.
Sounds like she's woken up.
Okay, so it's homing on the screwdriver.
(ROARING)
Run!
(SHARK GROWLING)
(GASPS)
ABIGAIL: # In the bleak midwinter
# Frosty wind made moan
# Earth stood hard as iron
# Water like a stone
# Snow had fallen, snow on snow
# Snow on snow
# In the bleak midwinter
# Long ago #
-(ABIGAIL CONTINUES SINGING)
-It's not really the singing, of course.
-Yes, it is.
-Nah.
The fish love the singing, it's true.
Nah, the notes resonate
in the ice crystals,
causing a delta-wave pattern in the fog.
Ow, fish bit me!
Shut up, then.
# Heaven and Earth shall flee away
Of course. That's how the machine
controls the cloud belt.
The clouds are ice crystals.
If you could vibrate the crystals
at exactly the right frequency,
you could align them into...
Ow! Why do they keep biting?
Look, the fish like the singing, okay?
Now, shut up.
(MOUTHING)
Okay.
# Fall down before
# The ox and ass and camel
# Which adore #
It's bigger on...
The inside.
Yes, the colour really
knocks the walls back.
Shark in a box, to go.
KAZRAN: Abigail.
This is amazing.
Nah, this is transport.
I keep amazing...
Out here.
DOCTOR: Come on, then.
Let's get this shark out.
(BEEPING)
(CAMERA CLICKING)
YOUNG KAZRAN: Wah-hey! Look at them go!
Abigail, this number.
What does it mean?
It pertains to me, sir, not the fish.
Yeah, but how?
You are a doctor, you say?
Are you one of mine?
Do you need a doctor?
(TICKING)
(BELL DINGING)
-Ah! Sorry! Time's up, kids.
-Why?
It's nearly Christmas day.
If you should ever wish
to visit again...
Well, you know,
if I'm ever in the neighbourhood.
-He comes every Christmas Eve.
-What?
-Yeah, he does, every time, he promises.
-No, I don't...
-Merry Christmas!
Doctor!
ABIGAIL: What are we gonna do?
YOUNG KAZRAN: The Doctor's got
a great plan. Wait 'til you hear.
ABIGAIL: You are out of your mind,
this will never work.
Oh! Don't think shark, think dolphin.
A shark isn't a dolphin.
-It's nearly a dolphin.
-No, it isn't.
Well, that's where you're wrong
because... Shut up.
Oh, it could be anywhere.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WARBLING)
Will it really come?
No chance, completely impossible.
(BEEPS APPROACHING)
Except at Christmas.
ABIGAIL: How are we going to get back?
DOCTOR: I don't know!
Do you have a plan?
Not at all!
(ALL WHOOPING)
(ABIGAIL SHOUTING)
(WHOOPING)
Best Christmas Eve ever!
'Til the next one.
New memories.
How can I have new memories?
-Merry Christmas!
Doctor!
ABIGAIL: Where to this time?
DOCTOR: Did I mention at any point
all of time and space?
-Merry Christmas!
Doctor.
-Doctor!
-Merry Christmas!
Kazran.
ABIGAIL: You've grown.
Yeah.
And now you're blushing.
-Sorry.
-That's okay.
So, Doctor. Where this time?
Pick a Christmas Eve,
I've got them all right here.
Might I make a request?
Of course.
This one.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING SOFTLY)
MAN: Thank you, darling.
-Who are they?
-Her family.
The lady"s her sister.
I met her once when she was older.
Abigail's crying.
Yes.
When girls are crying,
are you supposed to talk to them?
I have absolutely no idea.
My sister's family.
ABIGAIL: They're so happy.
They look very poor.
They are very poor.
Doesn't mean you can't be happy.
MAN: Close the curtains.
Then why aren't you?
Because this is the life
I can never have.
Why not?
I think you're blushing again.
DOCTOR: Come in!
Pick a card. Any card at all.
Every Christmas Eve?
-I don't understand.
-I'm not sure I do.
DOCTOR: You memorise a card,
you put it back in the deck.
Don't let me see it.
Is this what it looked like last year?
Well, it doesn't have to be
exactly the same.
I'm starting again.
Come on, Kazran. We're starting again.
That's Sardick's boy, isn't it.
He's not like his father.
His father treats everyone like cattle.
-One day that boy will do the same.
-No.
He's different.
Three of clubs.
No.
You sure?
Because I'm very good at card tricks.
It wasn't the three of clubs.
Well, of course it wasn't,
because it was the seven of diamonds.
-No.
-0i, stop it, you're doing it wrong.
I see him around the town sometimes.
-Never any friends.
-He's got me.
All those Christmas Eves...
You never once came to see us.
I'm here now.
Then stay! Stay for tomorrow.
Have Christmas dinner with us.
I can't.
Well, then.
Tomorrow's Christmas dinner
is cancelled,
-as my sister refuses to attend.
-Isabella!
Instead, we'll have it tonight.
Three, two, one, pull!
(ALL CHEERING)
How did you do that?
Your card, I believe.
No.
Oh, shut up.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-Merry Christmas.
-ALL: Merry Christmas.
Best Christmas Eve ever.
Ah! 'Til the next one.
I look forward to it.
Now I'd like to say goodnight to Kazran.
Of course, yes.
Well, on you go.
Oh, oh. Yes, right. Sorry.
I'll... I'll go, then.
Good night. Good luck... Night.
Good night.
-(CRASHING)
-Sorry.
Doctor. I think she's going to kiss me.
Yeah, I think you're right.
(KAZRAN GROANS)
I've never kissed anyone before.
What do I do?
Well,
try and be all nervous and rubbish
and a bit shaky.
-Why?
-Because you're gonna be
like that anyway,
might as well make it part of the plan,
then it will feel on purpose.
Off you go, then.
KAZRAN: (SOFTLY) Now? I kiss her now?
Kazran, trust me,
it's this or going to your room
and designing a new kind of screwdriver.
Don't make my mistakes.
Now, go!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
KAZRAN: Abigail.
Are you coming back?
The Doctor is gonna do a duet
with Frank.
Abigail?
What's wrong?
I have something to tell you.
A bad thing?
A very bad thing.
What is it?
(SIGHING)
The truth...
Guys!
We've really got to go quite quickly,
I just accidentally got engaged
to Marilyn Monroe.
(STUTTERING)
Is...
How do you keep going like that?
Do you breathe out your ears?
Hello? Sorry.
Hello? Guys, she's phoned a chapel,
there's a car outside,
this is happening now.
MARILYN: Yoo-hoo!
DOCTOR: Yoo-hoo.
(SIGHING) Right.
Fine, thank you. I'll just go
and get married then, shall I?
See how you like that.
Marilyn, get your coat!
What are we going to do?
(CRYING) There is nothing to be done.
(BEEPING)
Good night, Abigail.
Good night, Kazran.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Here we go, another day,
another Christmas Eve.
I'll see you in a minute, okay?
I mean, a year.
Doctor?
Listen, why don't we leave it?
Sorry? Leave what?
You know, this. Every Christmas Eve,
it's getting a bit old.
Old?
Well, Christmas is for kids, isn't it?
I've got some work with my dad now,
I'm going to focus on that.
Get that cloud belt under control.
Sorry, I didn't realise
I was boring you.
Not your fault.
Times change.
Not as much as I'd hoped.
Kazran.
I'll be needing a new one, anyway.
What the hell.
Merry Christmas.
And if you ever need me,
just activate it, I'll hear you.
I won't need you.
What's happened?
What are you not telling me?
What about Abigail?
I know where to find her.
(SOFTLY) Nah.
(DOOR LOCKING)
ELLIOT: Another Christmas Eve, Kazran.
But a very special one.
It's complete, look at it!
Sound waves. It's as simple as that.
We can control the clouds,
the fog, the fish.
Why do we want to control the fish?
People are cattle.
If you want to control cattle,
you need to control their predators.
What's the face for?
Look what I'm giving you.
The sky and everything beneath it.
Only you and I can control this.
This planet is ours.
Excuse me, Father.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yes, what?
Oh, Mr President,
we've been through this.
It's not going to crash on my house
so what's it got to do with me?
Yes, I know, 4,003.
As a very old friend of mine
once took a very long time to explain,
life isn't fair!
Hello.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
You didn't think this was over, did you?
I'm the Ghost of Christmas Present.
A ghost? Dressed like that?
Eyes off the skirt.
-You turned into a Roman.
-Yeah, yeah, I do that.
-I also do this.
-Do what?
What are you talking about?
(FAINTLY) # Silent night
# Holy night
# All is calm
# All is bright
# Round yon virgin mother and child
(BEEPING)
# Holy infant so tender and mild
# Christ the Saviour is born
# Christ the Saviour is born #
They're holograms. Projections, like me.
Who are they?
The people in the ship up there,
the ones that you're going
to let die tonight.
Why are they singing?
For their lives.
Which one's Abigail?
-The Doctor told me.
-Did he now?
Well, he doesn't hold back,
you know the Doctor.
How do I?
I never met him before tonight.
Now I seem to have known him
all my life. How? Why?
You're the only person
who can let that ship land.
He was trying to turn you
into a nicer person.
But he was trying to do it nicely.
He's changed my past, my whole life.
Time can be rewritten.
You tell the Doctor,
tell him from me, people can't!
AMY: That's Abigail.
I would never have known her
if the Doctor hadn't
changed the course of my whole life
to suit himself.
Well, that's good, isn't it?
No.
Why is she still in there?
You could let her out any time.
Oh, yes.
Any time at all. Any time I choose.
AMY: Then why don't you?
This is what the Doctor did to me.
Abigail was ill when she went into
the ice, on the point of death.
I suppose the rest in the ice helped her
but she's used up her time.
All those Christmas Eves with me.
I could release her any time I want
and she would live a single day.
So tell me, Ghost of Christmas Present,
how do I choose which day?
I'm sorry.
(STAMMERING) I really am, I'm very...
Very sorry.
But you know what?
She's got more time left than I have.
More than anyone on this ship.
Good.
Rory, widen the beam.
(ALARM BLARING)
CAPTAIN: Major update on engine one.
KAZRAN: How did I get here?
You didn't.
It's your turn to be the hologram.
Since you're going to let a lot of
people die tonight,
I thought you might like to see
where it's all going to happen.
# All is bright
The singing.
What is it?
I don't understand.
It's the Doctor's idea. The harmonies
resonate in the ice crystals,
that's why the fish like it.
(CRASHING)
He thought that maybe it would
stabilise the ship but it isn't working.
It's not powerful enough.
Why are they still singing, then?
Because we haven't told them.
Sir, I understand you have a machine
that controls this cloud layer.
If you can release us from it,
we still have time to make a landing.
Nobody has to die.
Everybody has to die.
-Not tonight.
-Tonight's as good as any other night.
How do you choose?
-Doctor?
-DOCTOR: Yeah?
-Are you hearing this?
-I can hear.
He's here. Where is he?
Doctor!
DOCTOR: I'm sorry.
I didn't realise.
All my life I've been called heartless.
My other life, my real life,
the one you rewrote.
Now look at me.
Better a broken heart
than no heart at all.
Try it. You try it.
-Why are you here?
-Because I'm not finished with you yet.
You've seen the past, present
and now you need to see the future.
Fine, do it. Show me.
I'll die cold, alone and afraid.
Of course I will, we all do.
What difference does showing me make?
Do you know why I'm going to let
those people die?
Not a plan,
I don't get anything from it.
It's just that I don't care.
I'm not like you,
I don't even want to be like you.
I don't and never, ever will care.
And I don't believe that.
Then show me the future, prove me wrong.
I am showing it to you,
I'm showing it to you right now.
So what do you think?
Is this who you want to become, Kazran?
Dad?
This planet is ours.
(INAUDIBLE)
(GASPING)
(CRYING)
I'm sorry, I'm so, so sorry.
It's okay to be frightened.
I'm so, so sorry.
(BOTH CRYING)
Kazran,
we don't have much time.
Structural integrity at 30%.
We have five minutes, max,
we need to land!
DOCTOR: Hello? Hello?
Ah, hello everyone!
Prepare to lock on to my signal.
Doctor, what's happening?
I just saved Christmas. Don't go away.
Doctor? Doctor!
We good to go?
The controls, they won't respond.
Of course they will, they're isomorphic,
they're tuned to your brain waves,
-they'll only respond to you.
-They don't respond.
Well, that doesn't make sense.
That's ridiculous, why would...
Oh. Oh, of course.
Stupid, stupid Doctor.
-What's wrong, tell me, what is it?
-It's you.
It's you. I've changed you too much.
The machine doesn't recognise you.
I know my father programmed it...
No, your father would never have
programmed it for the man you are now.
-Then what do we do?
-Um...
Um... I don't know, I don't know.
There must be something.
This. You can use this, I kept it, see?
What, half a screwdriver?
With the other half up in the sky
in a big old shark
right in the heart of the cloud layer.
If we use your aerial to boost the
signal and set up a resonation pattern
between the two halves...
Oh, come on, that would work.
My screwdriver, coolest bit of kit
on this planet, coolest two bits,
-it could do it.
-Do what?
While my screwdriver's still trying to
repair, it's signalling itself.
We use the signal
but we send something else.
Send what?
Well, what? What?
I'm sorry, Kazran.
I truly am.
I don't understand.
We need to transmit something into
the cloud belt, something we know works.
We need her to sing.
DOCTOR: Her voice resonates perfectly
with the ice crystals,
it calmed the shark,
it will calm the sky too.
Could you do it?
Could you do this?
Think about it, Doctor.
One last day with your beloved.
Which day would you choose?
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
ABIGAIL: Christmas.
-Christmas Day.
-(GASPING)
Look at you.
You're so old now.
I think you waited a bit too long,
didn't you?
-I'm sorry.
-Hoarding my days like an old miser.
(LAUGHING)
But if you leave the ice now...
We've had so many
Christmas Eves, Kazran,
I think it's time for Christmas Day.
Doctor!
We can't hold this! Time's up!
We're going down.
Doctor!
Captain, I've got...
I don't know what I've got.
(ABIGAIL SINGING OVER INTERCOM)
What is that? What are you listening to?
This is coming from outside.
This is coming from the actual clouds.
(ABIGAIL SINGING)
# When you're alone
# Silence is all you know
-Well?
The singing resonates in the crystals,
it's feeding back and forth
between the two halves
of the screwdriver now.
One song filling the sky.
The crystals will align
and I'll feed in a control phase loop
and the clouds will unlock.
What does that mean? Unlock?
What happens when a cloud unlocks?
Something that hasn't happened
in this town for a very long time now.
# When you're alone
# Silence is all you see
# Silence is all you'll be
# Give me your hand
Oh come to me
We're flying normally.
Can you land?
I can even land well.
Oh, he did it.
The Doctor did it.
Yeah, he gets all the credit.
Which is actually fair enough,
if you think about it.
(AMY CHUCKLING)
# When you are here
# Music is all around
# When you are near
# Open your eyes
# Don't make a sound
Hello, my old friend.
# Let in the shadow
Let's go.
# Let in the light
# Of your bright shadow
# Let in the shadow
(WHOOSHING)
# Let in the light
# Of your bright shadow #
AMY: You know, that could almost
be mistaken for a real person.
Snowman isn't bad either.
Ah, yes, you two, about time.
Why are you dressed like that?
(STAMMERING) I kind of lost our luggage.
Kind of crash landed?
Yeah, but why are you
dressed like that at all?
Yeah, they really love their snowmen
around here, don't they?
I've counted about 20.
Yeah, I've been busy.
Yeah. Yeah, you have.
Thank you.
Pleasure. Right.
Come on, then. Let's go.
Got any more honeymoon ideas?
Well, there's a moon that's made of
actual honey, well, not actual honey.
And it's not actually a moon,
and technically it's alive
and a bit carnivorous
but there are some lovely views.
Yeah? Great. Thanks.
Are you... Are you okay?
-Of course I'm okay. You?
-Of course.
It'll be their last day together,
won't it?
Everything's got to end sometime.
Otherwise,
nothing would ever get started.
Uh, your phone was ringing.
Someone called Marilyn.
Actually sounds like "the" Marilyn.
Doctor?
Tell her I'll phone her back
and that was never a real chapel.
Where are they? Kazran and Abigail.
Off on a little trip, I should think.
-Where?
-Christmas.
Christmas?
Yeah, Christmas.
Halfway out of the dark.
Where's the Doctor?
DOCTOR: I've been running,
faster than I've ever run.
Now it's time for me to stop.
I'm going to need a SWAT team
ready to mobilise,
street-level maps
covering all of Florida,
pot of coffee,
12 Jammie Dodgers and a fez.
DOCTOR: Somewhere different
somewhere brand new.
I wear a Stetson now.
Stetson's are cool.
(GUNSHOT)
RIVER: We've been recruited.
DOCTOR: Recruited by who?
RIVER: You're going to have to
trust us this time.
AMY: You have to do this
and you can't ask why.
(SCREAMING)
My life in your hands.
Amelia Pond.
See these eyes? They're old eyes.
And one thing I can tell you,
monsters are real.