Okay, so tell me you have a plan.
Hey? Why do I have to have a plan?
You could have a plan.
I chose the restaurant.
Yes, and accidentally took us
to the planet of the Rain Gods,
where we are now being sacrificed.
-Plan!
-Okay.
The plan is we need to distract them
with something
before they actually sacrifice
us to the Rain Gods.
Then when they're distracted,
we run away.
That's not a plan, that's just hoping.
Hey, it's a start.
Can you smell something?
Why are they sacrificing us
to the Rain Gods, anyway?
Appeases their wrath.
Apparently, it's very good
for the crops, you know, sacrificing.
There is actually
some scientific evidence...
Oh, so you're in favour of
being burnt alive now?
Just looking on the bright side, dear.
-(THUNDER ROARS)
-Huh!
Ha, ha! And there it is! Oi!
If there are any Rain Gods up there,
you're rubbish!
Strike me dead if I'm wrong!
What are you doing?
Smelling the ozone, dear.
-(THUNDER CRASHING)
-Down!
-Oh dear.
-Sweetie...
(LAUGHING) Hey!
River, run. Run away!
I think the Rain Gods are going to
do that again, you know.
RIVER: That was your plan?
DOCTOR: Well, it worked, didn't it?
RIVER: Basically, you hoped
for lightning, that was it.
DOCTOR: And here we are.
RIVER: We should be burning
at the stake right now.
It's lucky for you you're pretty.
DOCTOR: You were in no danger.
I knew something would come up.
RIVER: No, you didn't.
DOCTOR: I did! I promise I did.