(THUNDER CRASHING)
(WHOOSHING)
-The dress is a little daring.
-Yep, so I went for this instead.
-Are we going out?
-Parents are asleep.
How's Storm Cage?
I'm on the first night of 12,000
consecutive life sentences.
Kind of early to say.
Where are we going?
Alderin Beta. Boring,
planet of the chip shops.
But there is a 400-foot tree
growing out of a clifftop
on the north side of a mountain
in the middle of the sea.
And if you take the lift to the top
and look up,
at exactly 12 minutes past midnight
on the 21st of September, 2360,
you can see more stars in one sky
that at any other moment
in the history of the universe.
It's like daylight, only magic.
You could read a book by it.
-Whoo!
-Is it okay if I don't?
-(WHOOSHING)
-We've got 10 minutes. Get dressed.
Oh, that's so close
to the perfect sentence.
Hmm.
-Did you bring the diary?
-It's a diary?
It is now, because River,
from now on, there are rules.
Ooh, you've gone all strict.
Not that I mind.
River, you and I,
it's all in the wrong order.
We never meet in sequence.
You put everything in the diary
so we know where we are.
Put what in the diary? Sweetie,
I'm in the highest security prison
in all of the known universe.
River Song could walk in and out of
the prison like the walls aren't there.
-I'm River Song.
-Then you'll be fine.
If you don't like the dress,
there's plenty more in the wardrobe.
First right, second left,
just past the helter-skelter.
(LASER GUNS FIRING)
-River!
-I knew you'd come back here,
you nostalgic idiot.
-Hold me!
-River! River!
River!
River?