NARRATOR: It is said
that in the final days of planet Earth,
everyone had bad dreams.
To the west of the north of that world,
the human race did gather
in the celebration of a pagan rite
to banish the cold and the dark.
Each and every one of those people had
dreamt of the terrible things to come,
but they forgot, because they must.
They forgot their nightmares
of fire and war and insanity.
They forgot, except for one.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(BAND PLAYING CAROLS)
(CHOIR SINGING HYMN)
WOMAN: They call it the
legend of the blue box.
Oh...
Well, I've never been in here before.
I'm not one for churches.
Too cold.
This was the site of a convent
back in the 1300s.
It's said a demon fell from the sky.
Then a man appeared.
A man in a blue box.
They called him a sainted physician.
He smote the demon and then disappeared.
Well, that's a bit of a coincidence.
It's said there's no such thing
as coincidence.
(WILFRED SCOFFING)
Who knows? Perhaps he's coming back.
Oh, that would make my Christmas.
Huh?
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(WHOOSHING)
Ah! Now! Sorry! There you are.
So, where were we?
I was summoned, wasn't I?
An Ood in the snow, calling to me.
Well, I didn't exactly
come straight here.
Had a bit of fun, you know,
travelled about, did this and that.
Got into trouble, you know me.
It was brilliant.
I saw the phosphorous carousel
of the Great Magellan Gestalt.
Saved a planet
from the Red Carnivorous Maw.
Named a galaxy Allison.
Got married. That was a mistake.
Good Queen Bess.
And let me tell you,
her nickname is no longer...
(CLEARING THROAT) Anyway...
What do you want?
You should not have delayed.
Last time I was here,
you said my song would be ending soon.
And I'm in no hurry for that.
You will come with me.
Hold on. Better lock the TARDIS.
(BEEPING)
See? Like a car. I locked it like a car.
That's funny.
No? Little bit?
(EXCLAIMING) Blimey.
Try to make an Ood laugh...
So, how old are you now, Ood Sigma?
Ah!
(DOCTOR LAUGHING)
DOCTOR: Magnificent!
Oh, come on! That is splendid.
You've achieved all this in how long?
One hundred years.
Then we've got a problem,
'cause all this is way too fast.
Not just the city.
I mean, your ability to call me.
Reaching all the way back
to the 21st century.
Something's accelerating your species
way beyond normal.
And the mind of the Ood is troubled.
Why? What's happened?
Every night, Doctor.
Every night we have bad dreams.
ELDER OOD: Returning, returning,
returning, it is slowly returning,
to the dark and the fire and the blood,
always returning.
Returning to this world.
It is returning and he is returning
and they are returning,
but too late, too late, far too late,
he has come.
OOD: (ECHOING) He returns...
OO0D SIGMA: Sit with the elder of the Ood
and share the dreaming.
(ECHOING CONTINUES)
So... Right.
Hello.
ELDER OOD: You will join. You will join.
You will join. You will join.
You will join.
(LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
He comes to us, every night.
I think all the peoples of the universe
dream of him now.
That man is dead.
There is yet more. Join us.
(INHALING)
Events are taking shape, so many
years ago and yet changing the now.
There is a man...
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
ELDER OOD: So scared...
Wilfred. Is he all right?
What about Donna? Is she safe?
You should not have delayed.
For the lines of convergence are being
drawn across the Earth even now.
The king is in his counting house.
I don't know who they are.
And there is another.
The most lonely of all.
Lost and forgotten.
(SOBBING)
DOCTOR: The Master's wife.
We see so much, but understand little.
The woman in the cage, who is she?
She was... It wasn't her fault.
She was...
The Master, he's a Time Lord, like me.
I can show you.
DOCTOR:
The Master took the name of Saxon.
He married a human, a woman called Lucy,
and he corrupted her.
MAN: No!
DOCTOR: She stood at his side
while he conquered the Earth.
I reversed everything he'd done,
so it never even happened,
but Lucy Saxon remembered.
(GUN FIRING)
DOCTOR: I held him in my arms.
I burnt his body.
The Master is dead!
And yet you did not see.
00D: (ECHOING) See it!
What's that?
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Part of him survived.
I have to go!
But something more is happening, Doctor.
The Master is part of a greater design,
because a shadow is falling
over creation.
Something vast is stirring in the dark.
The Ood have gained this power
to see through time
because time is bleeding.
Shapes of things once lost
are moving through the veil.
And these events from years ago
threaten to destroy this future.
And the present and the past.
What do you mean?
This is what we have seen, Doctor.
The darkness heralds only one thing,
the end of time itself.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Events that have happened
are happening now.
(BEEPING)
Mrs Saxon, let me introduce myself.
I'm your new governor.
I'm afraid the previous governor
met with something of an accident,
which took quite some time to arrange.
Miss Trefusis, if you will prepare.
You kept your silence well, Mrs Saxon.
Your trial was held in secret
with no jury,
so no one knows who Harold Saxon was,
where he came from, why you killed him.
Make her kneel.
There are those of us
who never lost faith.
And, in his wisdom, Harold Saxon
prepared for this moment.
He knew that he might die
and he made us ready.
Tonight, Mrs Saxon,
he returns.
(MASTER LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
REPORTER: (ON TV)
This shocking discovery...
(TRANSMISSION DISRUPTING)
REPORTER ON TV:
That supports conservation...
GOVERNOR: As it was written
in the secret books of Saxon,
these are the potions of life.
Listen to me. Whatever he told you,
you've got no idea what you're doing.
Miss Trefusis, the catalyst.
LUCY: What are you doing?
Leave me alone! Don't!
You were Saxon's wife.
You bore his imprint.
That's what we needed.
The final biometrical signature.
(CRYING) You can't bring him back,
you can't!
I'm begging you!
Stop this now, before it's too late!
We give ourselves that Saxon might live!
Can't you see? He lied to you!
His name isn't even Harold Saxon!
GOVERNOR: And this was written also!
For his name is the Master!
Never. Never! Never! Never!
Never dying. Never dying! Never dying!
Never dying! Never dying!
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Oh, Lucy...
Sweet Lucy Saxon, my ever-faithful...
Did the widow's kiss
bring me back to life?
You're killing them!
Oh, let them die.
They're just the first.
The whole stupid,
stinking human disgrace
can fall into the pit!
Can't you hear it, Lucy?
The noise. The drumbeat.
Louder than ever before.
The drums, the never-ending drums.
Oh, I have missed them.
(MASTER CHUCKLING)
But no one knew you better than I did.
I knew you'd come back!
And all this time,
your disciples have prepared!
But so have we!
What are you doing?
The secret books of Saxon
spoke of the potions of life,
and I was never that bright,
but my family had contacts.
People who were clever enough
to calculate the opposite!
Don't you dare! I'm ordering you, Lucy!
You will obey me!
Till death do us part, Harry!
No!
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENING)
I think we might be in luck, darling.
It's the footage from Broadfell Prison
the night it burnt down.
Take a look at this.
Someone survived? Do you think it's him?
Oh, that would be
such a Christmas present.
(LAUGHING)
You just leave it to Daddy.
Ladies and gentleman,
it seems help is at hand.
Christmas is cancelled!
Prepare the gate!
(WHISTLING) Just going down The Lion!
Quick little snifter. Christmas drinks.
All right, ta-ta!
Parachute 1 to Parachute 2,
we are mobilised.
I repeat, we are mobilised.
Rendezvous 1300 hours.
Over and out.
Come on!
(WILFRED LAUGHING)
Way-hey! Shake a leg! Yay-hey!
Whoa!
Whoop!
(MAN WHISTLING)
Come on! Let's get going.
(ALL CHEERING)
WILFRED: Off we go.
Everybody all right?
We've got a job to do.
(WILFRED CHEERING)
Right, he's tall and thin.
Wears a brown suit, maybe a blue suit.
He's got a long brown coat,
modern sort of hair.
All sticky-uppy. All right?
Oh, and on page two,
be on the lookout for a police box,
exactly like the old ones.
I got locked inside one of them.
August Bank Holiday, 1962.
Were you misbehaving, Minnie?
I certainly was. Way-hey!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah. All right, all right. Now listen.
This is important.
We have got to find it.
Right, so phone around. Phone everybody.
Sally, will you
get on to the Bridge Club?
Right. Winston, you try the old boys.
Bobby, I want you to ring, uh,
the skiffle band, right?
Between us, we got the city covered.
-The silver cloak.
-Yeah.
Who is he, then, this Doctor?
No, I can't tell you that, I swear.
Yeah, but answer me this.
You've been having bad dreams?
All of you? Dreams you can't remember.
Yeah. Well, that's why we need him.
We need the Doctor,
more than ever.
WOMAN: Onions with that?
MAN: Oh, yeah, go on, pile them on.
What about you, Ginger? Onions?
He don't say much. Give him onions.
He's down from Huddersfield.
WOMAN: Well, you look after him.
And don't forget, tomorrow night,
Christmas broadcast...
-President Obama...
-Oh...
WOMAN: He's promised
to end the recession.
Bad times will soon be over, Ginger.
-Well, season's greetings to you.
-WOMAN: And you. Happy Christmas!
Now, what can we get you, sir?
Everything.
I am so hungry.
(MASTER LAUGHING)
They're saying that the President's
got this grand plan.
He's gonna save the world
with some big financial scheme.
Whatever it is,
bet it won't reach you and me.
Uh-oh, somebody's lively on his feet.
Starving.
Now, you see,
that's what you don't want to do.
Eat it all at once. Tempting, I know,
but if you make it last,
it can last all day.
MASTER: I want more.
Cheese and chips and meat and gravy
and cream and beer and pork and beef
and fat and great big chunks
of hot, wet, red...
Good for you, mate.
Well, we'd better be going.
(STUTTERING) You look like that bloke.
Harold Saxon.
The one that went mad.
(LAUGHING)
Now, isn't that funny?
Isn't that just the best thing of all?
The master of disguise, stuck
looking like the old Prime Minister.
(LAUGHING) I can't hide anywhere.
He can see me.
He can smell me.
I can't let him smell me.
Doctor, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor,
got to stop the smell!
The stink! The filthy, filthy stink!
Ginger, come with me! Right now!
Because it's funny! Don't you see?
Look at me! I'm splitting my sides!
I am hilarious!
I am the funniest thing
in the whole wide world!
(ROARING)
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Save us!
God help us! There's this man!
Dinnertime!
MAN: No!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SHIP'S HORN BLOWING)
(INHALING)
(BARREL CLANGING)
(SCREAMING)
(MASTER LAUGHING)
(DOCTOR PANTING)
(LAUGHING)
(ROARING)
Please, let me help!
You're burning up your own life force.
(GROWLING)
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Oh, my gosh, Doctor,
you're a sight for sore eyes.
-Out of my way!
-Oh? |
(LAUGHING)
MAN 1: Did we do it? Yeah! Is that him?
MAN 2: Tall and thin. Big brown coat.
MINNIE: The silver cloak.
It worked, 'cause Will phoned Nettie,
who phoned June.
And her sister lives opposite Broadfell
and she saw the police box.
And her neighbour saw this man
heading east.
Wilfred, have you told them who I am?
You promised me...
No, I just said you were a doctor,
that's all.
Hmm. And might I say, sir,
it is an honour to see you again.
Oh! But you never said he was a looker.
-He's gorgeous! Take a photo.
-Not bad, eh?
-ALL: No...
-V nice.
I'm Minnie. Minnie the Menace.
It's a long time since I had a photo
with a handsome man.
Could you just get off him?
Leave him alone!
Hush, you old misery. Come on, Doctor.
Give us a smile.
-That's it!
-MAN: Hold on.
-Did it flash?
-No, there's a blue light. Try again.
I'm all fingers and thumbs.
I'm really kind of busy, you know.
Oh, it won't take a tick. Keep smiling.
Is that your hand, Minnie?
Good boy.
WILFRED: All right, let's...
Come on, then! Here we are. Hurry up.
WILFRED: Goodbye. Go on.
Come on, over here.
DOCTOR: Well, what's so special
about this place?
We passed 15 cafes on the way.
(LAUGHING) Yeah. Afternoon.
WILFRED: But we had some good times,
didn't we, though?
I mean, all those Atmos things
and planets in the sky
and me with that paint gun.
(IMITATES PAINT GUN FIRING)
(WILFRED EXHALING)
I keep seeing things, Doctor,
I... This face at night.
Who are you?
I'm Wilfred Mott.
No. People have waited
hundreds of years to find me,
and then you manage it
in a couple of hours.
Well, I'm just lucky, I suppose.
No, we keep on meeting, Wilf.
Over and over again,
like something's still connecting us.
Yeah, but what's so important about me?
Exactly. Why you?
I'm going to die.
-Well, so am I, one day.
-Don't you dare.
All right, I'll try not to.
(CHUCKLING)
But I was told.
He will knock four times.
(INHALING)
That was a prophecy.
Knock four times and then...
Yeah, but I thought...
When I saw you before, you said that
your people could change, like,
your whole body.
I can still die.
If I'm killed before regeneration,
then I'm dead.
Even then...
Even if I change, it feels like dying.
Everything I am dies.
Some new man goes sauntering away.
And I'm dead.
-Hmm...
-What? Oh...
I'm sorry, but I had to...
-Look, can't you make her better?
-Stop it.
No, but you're so clever.
Can't you bring her memory back?
Look... Just go to her now, go on.
Just run across the street.
Go up and say, "Hello".
If she ever remembers me,
her mind will burn and she will die.
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
Don't you touch this car!
(DOCTOR AND WILFRED LAUGHING)
She's not changed.
WILFRED: No...
Oh, there he is.
Shawn Temple. They're engaged.
Getting married in the spring.
-Another wedding?
-Yeah.
Hold on, she's not gonna be called
Noble Temple?
-That sounds like a tourist spot.
-No, it's Temple Noble.
Right.
Is she happy? Is he nice?
Yeah, he's sweet enough.
He's a bit of a dreamer.
Mind you, he's on minimum wage.
She's earning tuppence,
so all they can afford
is a tiny, little flat.
And then sometimes
I see this look on her face.
Like she's so sad,
but she can't remember why.
She's got him.
She's making do.
Aren't we all?
Yeah, how about you?
-Who have you got now?
-No one.
I'm travelling alone.
I thought it would be better alone.
But I did some things that went wrong.
I need...
Oh, my word...
(DOCTOR GASPING)
(EXHALES)
Uh...
Merry Christmas.
Yeah, and you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Look at us.
WILFRED: Well, don't you...
Don't you see?
You know, you need her, Doctor!
I mean...
Look, wouldn't she make you laugh again?
Good, old Donna.
Eh? Hmm?
NARRATOR: And so it came to pass that
the players took their final places,
making ready the events
that were to come.
The madman sat in his empire
of dust and ashes,
little knowing of the glory
he would achieve,
while his saviour
looked upon the wilderness
in the hope of changing
his inevitable fate.
Far away, the idiots and fools
dreamt of a shining new future.
A future now doomed to never happen.
As Earth rolled onwards into night,
the people of that world
did sleep and shiver,
somehow knowing
the dawn would bring only one thing.
The final day.
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
(GROANING)
I had estates.
Do you remember
my father's land back home?
Pastures of red grass stretching far
across the slopes of Mount Perdition.
(SIGHING)
We used to run across those fields
all day, calling up at the sky.
Look at us now.
All that eloquence.
But how many people have you killed?
I am so hungry.
Your resurrection went wrong.
That energy... Your body's ripped open.
Now you're killing yourself.
And that's human Christmas out there.
They eat so much!
All that roasting meat,
cakes and red wine.
Hot, fat, blood food.
Pots, plates of meat and flesh
and grease and juice.
And baking, burnt, sticky, hot skin.
Hot! It's so hot!
-Stop it!
-Slice!
It's mine! It's mine!
-Eat it! Eat it! Eat it! Eat it!
-Stop it!
What if I ask you for help?
(EXCLAIMING)
(SNICKERING)
There are more at work tonight
than you and me.
Oh, yeah?
I've been told something is returning.
And here I am.
No, something more.
But it hurts.
-I was told the end of time...
-It hurts...
Doctor, the noise.
The noise in my head, Doctor.
One, two, three, four. One, two,
three, four. One, two, three, four.
Stronger than ever before.
Can't you hear it?
Listen, listen, listen, listen.
(RHYTHMIC TAPPING)
Every minute, every second,
every beat of my hearts,
there it is,
calling to me.
Please listen.
I can't hear it.
Listen!
(BANGING TAPPING)
(GASPING)
What?
I._..
-What?
-I heard it.
But that's no noise.
There never has been,
it's just your insanity.
What is it? What's inside your head?
(LAUGHING DELIRIOUSLY) It's real.
It's real!
(MASTER LAUGHING)
All these years you thought I was mad!
King of the wasteland.
But something is calling me, Doctor.
What is it? What is it?
What is it?
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(YELLING)
No!
Let him go!
(MERRY XMAS, EVERYBODY BY SLADE
PLAYING ON RADIO)
Now then, steady on.
It's never too early for margaritas,
that's what I say.
I forgot to get lemons
so I used oranges instead.
It's all fruit, same difference.
Oh, now that's lovely. Look at that!
Absolutely beautiful.
Oh, "Love from Donna."
Did you keep the receipt?
Yes, I did.
Come on, Gramps. You've been
a right misery ever since you got up.
Do you like it then, the book?
Joshua Naismith?
I mean, what did you get me this for?
I don't know.
I just saw it in the shop
and thought of you.
It just felt like
the sort of thing you should have.
SYLVIA: (LAUGHING)
Oh, now, look at that.
That's from Charlie Morton.
Isn't that rude?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
If you would, Mr Danes.
I'm starving.
You have my daughter to thank for this.
It's all her idea.
She heard rumours of Harold Saxon,
his disciples, his return.
It's the sort of thing
she finds rather thrilling.
And I was right. He's back.
The very man we need and he's here.
Oh, this is gonna be wonderful.
Aye-aye! Here are the presents.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
I'm sorry I couldn't afford much.
But not for long.
Not if President Obama ends
the recession tonight. Come here!
WILFRED: Whoa, whoa, whoa,
keep it quiet, you lot.
It's the Queen's Speech. Now, come on.
Sit down, show respect. Come on.
-Merry Christmas, Mr Mott.
-Thank you.
Will you behave! Honestly.
All right now. She's on, she's on.
It's our sovereign.
Eh?
Events are moving, Wilfred.
-Eh?
-Faster than we thought.
Can you see that?
Frankly, I'd tell Her Majesty
it's time for trouser suits.
No, no, no, no. That's not...
Only you can see.
Only you stand
at the heart of coincidence.
Why? What have I done?
You're an old soldier, sir.
Only you were too late.
The war was won and passed you by.
I did my duty.
You never killed a man.
No, I didn't. No, I did not, no,
but don't say that like it's shameful.
A time will come
when you must take arms.
Who are you?
Tell the Doctor nothing of this.
His life could still be saved,
so long as you tell him nothing.
Did...
(SIGHING)
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
(CLATTERING ON GLASS)
I lost him.
I was unconscious. He's still on Earth.
I can smell him, but he's too far away.
Listen, you can't park there.
What if Donna sees it?
You're the only one, Wilf.
The only connection I can think of.
You're involved.
If I could just work out how.
Tell me, have you seen anything?
I don't know.
Anything strange, anything odd?
-Well, there was...
-What?
-What is it? Tell me!
-Well, it...
Nah, it's nothing.
Think, think, think!
Maybe something out of the blue.
Something connected to your life.
Something!
Well, Donna was a bit strange.
She had a funny, little moment
this morning all because of that book.
What book?
Here you are,
his name's Joshua Naismith.
That's the man.
I was shown him by the Ood.
-The what?
-By the Ood.
-What's the Ood?
-They're just the Ood.
But it's all part of the convergence
maybe...
Maybe touching Donna's subconscious.
Oh, she's still fighting for it,
even now. The Doctor Donna.
Dad, what are you up to?
You! But... Get out of here!
-Merry Christmas.
But she can't see you!
What if she remembers?
DONNA: Mum, where are those tweezers?
-Go!
-I'm going.
Yeah, me, too.
Oh, no, you don't.
Mum? Gramps?
-Dad, I'm warning you!
-Bye, see you later.
I'm a bit old for hide-and-seek.
Stay right where you are!
-You can't come with me.
-You're not leaving me with her.
-Dad!
-Fair enough.
-DONNA: Mum?
-Just you listen to me.
I forbid it! Get out of there!
Doctor, bring my father back right now!
Come back here!
Come back here, I said. Come back!
Are you shouting at thin air?
Yes.
Possibly. Yes.
Naismith!
If I can track him down...
Ah! Right. Yes.
Bigger on the inside. Do you like it?
I thought it'd be cleaner.
Cleaner?
I can take you back home right now.
Listen, Doctor. If this is
a time machine, that man you're chasing,
why can't you just pop back
to yesterday and catch him?
I can't go back inside my own timeline.
I have to stay relative to the Master
within the causal matrix.
-Understand?
-Not a word.
-Welcome aboard.
-Thank you.
You can demonstrate.
Oh, that's not from Earth.
And neither are you.
A perfect combination, don't you think?
(CLEARING THROAT) Uh, excuse me, sir.
If I could check the basement?
We're getting fluctuation
on the power cord.
-Of course.
-Miss Addams.
If you could bring
the calibration statistics?
Who the hell is he?
What if he finds out?
An expert, they said.
Well, what sort of expert?
-Who is he?
-I don't know!
According to the records,
Harold Saxon was Prime Minister
of this stupid country.
I am choking in this thing!
I'm sorry.
(SIGHING)
Oh, by the saints, that's better.
Oh, these people are so flat.
(GROANING)
Well, what do we do?
We were so close.
We almost had it working!
What if this visitor
is some sort of genius?
Well, think about it.
We are hijacking this project.
Maybe we can use him, too.
Harold Saxon or whatever he is
might be exactly what we need.
The gate was found inside a spaceship
buried at the foot of Mount Snowdon.
It was moved to an institute
known as Torchwood.
But when Torchwood fell,
let's just say I acquired it.
I like you.
Thank you.
You'd taste great.
Mr Danes.
The visitor will be given food.
Ah.
Anyway, the device came equipped
with its own power supply.
A nuclear bolt.
One technician remains in charge
of the feedback 24 hours a day.
And the power feeds through to the gate.
It encourages some sort of
cellular regeneration.
Miss Hollands was our test subject.
She carried some burns as result of
an accident when she was a child,
down her left side. If you could...
The gate mended her.
Thank you.
But what do you want it for?
We calculate that, if this device can be
fully repaired by your good self,
it can restore the body forever.
Hence its given title,
The Immortality Gate.
Because that's what I want.
Not for me, but for my daughter.
I want her never to die. My gift to her.
She will be immortal.
Abigail. It means, "Bringer of joy".
(INHALING)
Better get to work.
We've moved! We really moved!
-You should stay here.
-Not bloody likely.
And don't swear. Hold on.
Just a second out of synch.
Don't want the Master
finding the TARDIS.
That's the last thing we need.
That book said he's a billionaire.
He's got his own private army.
Stay here.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Miss Addams, we're getting
some encouraging results
from the ratio foldback.
Can you confirm?
The man's a miracle. All the systems
are slotting back into place.
Shatter treads have harmonised,
the fibre links have densified.
Multiple overshots have triplicated...
-Nice gate!
-Hello!
Look, sorry, don't try calling security
or I'll tell them
you're wearing a shimmer.
'Cause I reckon anyone wearing a shimmer
doesn't want the shimmer to be noticed
or they wouldn't need a shimmer
in the first place.
I'm sorry, what's a shimmer?
Shimmer.
(SIGHING)
Oh, my Lord. She's a cactus.
Miss Addams? Miss Addams?
If you'll would just excuse me.
Now, please don't imagine
I'm a slave driver.
You can resume work
on Boxing Day, Mr Saxon.
My name
is the Master.
Oh, excellent! Excellent!
-Mr Danes.
-The visitor will be restrained.
What? But I repaired it.
I'm not an idiot!
Don't let him anywhere near that thing.
(LAUGHING)
He's got it working, but what is it?
What's working? What are you doing here?
Shimmer!
Now, tell me quickly, what's going on,
the Master, Harold Saxon?
Skeletor, whatever you're calling him,
what's he doing up there?
Your reputation precedes you, sir.
I have no doubt you've laid traps.
Perhaps explosives,
a means of escape and murder.
But everything you've done to the gate
will be checked and double-checked
before anyone stands inside.
But I checked the readings.
He's done good work. It's operational.
Who are you, though?
"Cause I met someone like you.
He was brilliant,
but he was little and red.
No, that's a Zocci.
We're not Zocci, we're Vinvocci.
-Completely different.
-ADDAMS: And the gate is Hipocci.
We're a salvage team.
We picked up a signal
when the humans re-activated it.
And as soon as it's working,
we can transport it to the ship.
But what does it do?
Well, it mends. It's as simple as that.
It's a medical device
to repair the body.
It makes people better.
No, there's got to be more.
Every single warning says the Master
is gonna do something colossal.
So that thing is like a sick-bed, yeah?
-More or less.
-WILFRED: Well, pardon me for asking,
but why is it so big?
Oh, good question. Why is it so big?
(SCOFFING) It doesn't just mend
one person at a time.
(CHUCKLING) That would be ridiculous.
It mends whole planets.
It does what?
It transmits the medical template
across the entire population.
Come on, it's time for the broadcast.
President's grand initiative.
You might want to see this, sir.
Proof that the human race
can mend its own problems.
And now, anticipation is rising
as we go live to Washington.
Here, on Christmas Day,
the President has promised
an instant and radical solution
to the worldwide depression.
Barack Obama will lead us all
into a new age of prosperity.
WOMAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States.
I'd like to speak briefly
about the state of our economy.
Turn the gate off right now!
Man arms!
No, no, no, no. Whatever you do,
just don't let him near that device!
Oh, like that was ever gonna happen.
(SCREAMING)
Homeless, was I? Destitute and dying?
Well, look at me now!
Deactivate it!
All of you, turn the whole thing off!
(MASTER LAUGHING)
He's inside my head.
Get out of there!
Doctor! Doctor, there's this face...
-What is it? What can you see?
-Well, it's him. I can see him.
I can see his face.
Something's wrong.
It seems to be affecting the President.
(MASTER LAUGHING)
-I can't turn it off!
-That's because I locked it, idiot.
Wilfred!
Get inside, get him out!
Get out!
Just need to filter the levels.
Oh! I can see again! He's gone!
Radiation shielding.
Now press the button, let me out!
You what?
I can't get out until you
press the button. That button there!
Fifty seconds and counting.
To what?
Oh, you're gonna love this.
He was hiding the codes.
He's extrapolated the gate pattern
a million times over!
It's not affecting us.
He set the template to human!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Hello... Oh.
-Donna'!
-Where are you?
It's Mum and Shawn.
Something's wrong with them.
There's his face.
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Wait a minute. I mean, what about you?
Can't you see anything?
I can see them. That's bad enough.
Not now, Winston!
Wilfred! Those dreams...
I can remember that face!
There's a face in my head!
Wilfred?
It's everyone!
What is it, hypnotism? Mind control!
You're grafting your thoughts
inside them, is that it?
Oh, that's way too easy.
No, no, no.
They're not gonna think like me.
They're gonna become me.
And...begin!
(MASTER LAUGHING)
-He can't have!
-What is it?
(GASPING)
They've changed. Granddad.
It's like...like the sort of thing
that happened before!
My head! Oh, my head! My head!
Doctor! She's starting to remember.
What is it? What have you done,
you monster?
Oh, I'm sorry. Are you talking to me?
Or to me?
ALL: Or to us?
Breaking news. I'm everyone.
And everyone in the world is me!
I'm President.
President of the United States!
Look at me!
-Whoo!
-Come on!
Ooh. Financial solution...deleted.
(LAUGHING)
The human race was
always your favourite, Doctor.
But now, there is no human race.
There is only the Master race!
(LAUGHING)
NARRATOR: And so it came to pass
on Christmas Day
that the human race did cease to exist.
But even then,
the Master had no concept
of his greater role in events,
for this was far more
than humanity's end.
This day was the day
upon which the whole of creation
would change forever.
This was the day
the Time Lords returned.
For Gallifrey.
ALL: For Gallifrey.
For victory!
ALL: For victory!
For the end of time itself!
ALL: For the end of time itself!
WOMAN: This is
the Doctor's final battle.
He must stand at arms
or lose himself and all this world.
(LAUGHING)
NARRATOR: A rhythm of four.
The heartbeat of a Time Lord.
WILFRED: The Master is gonna kill you.
Kill him first.
(GUNSHOT)
At last.
Sometimes, I think
a Time Lord lives too long.