(SONAR PINGING)
(ALL TALKING, INDISTINCT)
MAN: (ON PA) Signal is genuine.
Signal is genuine.
-Prepare to launch nuclear weapons.
-Aye, sir.
MAN: (ON PA)
Moscow confirming launch sequence.
The Firebird stands ready to serve.
-For the motherland.
(CLANGING)
MAN: # This means nothing to me
# This means nothing to me
# Oh, Vienna #
Have I interrupted something?
We were about to
blow up the world, Professor.
Again?
Ultravox, I bloody love 'em.
Got a friend who sends me the tapes.
This is the captain. Drill abandoned.
All hands stand down.
Repeat, drill abandoned.
With respect, sir, we must run it again.
Tomorrow.
Comrade Captain, the NATO exercises...
Sabre rattling.
-I don't think so.
-Oh, you don't think so?
Sir, American aggression
gets more intolerable by the day.
We must run the drill again.
Tomorrow.
-Did you have your specimen stored okay?
-Yeah, Piotr's looking after him.
Well, at least we have something to show
for our little hunting expedition.
What is it? A mammoth?
Probably.
What are you, milaya moya?
Professor wants you thawed out
back in Moscow
but, well, life's too short to wait.
(THUMPING)
(CREAKING)
(GROWLING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(SCREAMING)
Gangway! Alarm! Alarm!
(GROANING)
-Hull breached, port side!
-Evasive manoeuvres!
-Descending 200 metres. Descend!
-We're under attack!
-Bring her up! Bring her up!
-It's no good, sir!
(WHOOSHING)
Viva Las Vegas!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAN: Stranger on the bridge!
-Who the hell are you?
-Not Vegas, then?
No. But this is much better.
-A sinking submarine?
-A sinking Soviet submarine!
Bring out sidearms, restrain them.
410! 420! Turbine still not responding!
They've got to!
Ah! Sideways momentum!
You've still got sideways momentum!
What?
Your propellers work independently
of the main turbines.
You can't stop her going down
but you can manoeuvre the sub laterally.
-Do it!
-Get these people off the bridge now!
Just listen to him, for God's sake!
Geographical anomaly to starboard.
Probably an underwater ridge.
-How do you know this?
-Look, we have just a shot
to stop the descent
if we settle on it. Dive!
Six hundred metres! Sir! 610!
Or this thing is going to implode!
Lateral thrust to starboard,
all propellers!
-Sir?
-Now!
You're going to let this madman
give the orders?
-Lateral thrust!
-Going, sir!
660, 680!
(ALARM BLARING)
Descent arrested at 700 metres.
It seems we owe you our lives,
whoever you are.
I'll hold you to that.
It might come in handy.
Search them.
Yes, I know. It's a woman.
Now, search them.
Hey? Ooh!
-Are we going to be okay?
-Oh, yes.
-Is that a lie?
-Possibly.
Very dangerous time, Clara.
East and West standing on the brink
of nuclear oblivion.
Lots of itchy fingers on the button.
-Isn't it always like that?
-Sort of.
But there are flash points
and this is one of them.
Hair, shoulder pads, nukes.
It's the '80s. Everything's bigger.
I would like a receipt, please.
What is this?
(CRASHING)
-(CLARA SCREAMS)
-No! Clara!
-No! No, no, no, no, no!
-(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
No, no, no!
DOCTOR: Captain, we did not
attack your ship.
Now, if we can get the pump working,
we can get her afloat.
ZHUKOV: Yeah,
we'll last till the rescue ship comes.
DOCTOR: If it comes.
ZHUKOV: Oh, this sinking
is just a coincidence, is it?
Who are you?
(GRUNTING)
(BANGING)
All right, captain, all right!
You know what, just this once,
no dissembling, no psychic paper,
no pretending to be an Earth Ambassador.
Doctor. Me and Clara are
time travellers. Clara, you okay?
-Think so.
-Time travellers?
We arrived out of thin air.
You just saw it happen.
-I didn't.
-Your problem, mate. Not mine.
-We were sinking.
-DOCTOR: Yes.
-What happened?
-DOCTOR: We sank.
-What happened to the Tardis, I mean?
-Never mind that. Listen.
Captain, breath's precious down here.
-Let's not waste it, eh?
-You're right.
Maybe I could save a little oxygen
by having you both shot!
-Uh...
-What does it matter how we arrived?
-The important thing is to get...
-(HISSING)
-...out.
-DOCTOR: Exactly.
Number one priority, not suffocating.
Huh? Oh! Oh.
Thank you. Finally seeing sense.
Now, what sort of state is the sub in?
-Doctor.
-What about the radio? Can we send...
-Doctor!
-What?
(HISSING)
What is that, gas? Could be gas.
(SNARLING SOFTLY)
Ah!
-It never rains but it pours.
-(CREATURE HISSING)
We were drilling for oil in the ice.
I thought I found a mammoth.
It's not a mammoth.
No.
-What is it, then?
-It's an ice warrior.
A native of the planet Mars.
And we go way back.
-Way back.
-Martian? You can't be serious!
-I'm always serious, with days off.
-Doctor.
Just keeping it light, Clara.
They're scared.
-They're scared? I'm scared!
-(GUN COCKING)
-No, no! No, no, no, no, no.
-(WEAPON POWERING UP)
Please! Please! Wait, just...
There is no need for this.
Just hear me out. You're...
You're confused, disorientated.
And of course you are, you've been lying
dormant in the ice for... For how long?
-How long, Professor?
-By my reckoning, 5,000 years.
5,000 years. That's a hell of a nap.
Can't blame you if you got out
on the wrong side of bed.
Look, nobody here wants to hurt you.
Please, just...
Why don't you tell us your name?
What are you talking about, name?
It has a name?
Of course it has a name. And a rank.
This is a soldier
and it deserves our respect.
This is madness. That is a monster!
Skaldak.
-What did you say?
-I am Grand Marshal Skaldak.
Oh, no.
You idiot!
-(SKALDAK HISSING)
-You idiot.
Grand Marshal Skaldak.
You...know him.
Sovereign of the Tharsyssian caste.
Vanquisher of the Phobos heresy.
The greatest hero the proud Martian race
has ever produced.
So what do we do now?
Lock him up.
(GROWLING)
Is it true?
Uh, true?
I slept for 5,000 years?
Uh...
Uh, that's what the professor says.
Five thousand years.
DOCTOR: 7The ice warriors
have a different creed, Clara,
a different code.
By his own standards, Skaldak is a hero.
And it was said
his enemies honoured him so much
they'd carve his name
into their own flesh before they died.
Oh, yeah. Very nice. He sounds lovely.
An ice warrior? Explain.
-DOCTOR: There isn't time.
-Try me.
Martian reptile
known as the ice warrior.
When Mars turned cold,
they had to adapt. Their biomechanoids,
cyborgs,
built themselves survival arm our
so they could exist in the freezing cold
of their home world.
But a sudden increase in temperature
and the arm our goes haywire.
-Like with the cattle prod thing?
-Like that cattle prod thing.
Bit of a design flaw, to be honest.
I've always wondered
why they never sorted it.
Oh, look, you've got me telling you
about them and I said there wasn't time!
Is he that dangerous?
This one is.
Find me, my brothers,
if you are still out there.
Find me.
(SONIC BUZZING)
(HUNGRY LIKE THE WOLF
PLAYING IN HEADPHONES)
STEPASHIN: Why are we listening
to this nonsense, Captain?
These people are clearly enemy agents.
-Huh?
-Spies, Captain.
Pretty bad spies, mate.
Don't even speak Russian.
-What?
-I don't...
Am I speaking Russian?
How come I'm speaking Russian?
Now? We have to do this now?
-Are they speaking Russian?
-Seriously, now?
It's the Tardis Translation Matrix.
In my opinion, comrade Captain,
this creature is a Western weapon.
-Are they?
-Yes. They're Russians.
-A weapon?
-Survival suit.
What is the alternative?
The little green man from Mars?
Correction.
It's a big green man from Mars.
I don't appreciate your levity,
Professor.
Why does that not surprise me?
-Maybe they're telling the truth.
-The truth?
Yes. A revolutionary concept, I know.
STEPASHIN: It's essential that we inform
Moscow of what we have found.
Oh, the radio is out of action,
in case you hadn't noticed, Stepashin.
They have our last position.
They will find us.
-When they do...
-Yes?
Well, Cold War won't stay
cold forever, Captain.
For God's sake, Stepashin,
you're like a stuck record.
We have other priorities right now.
I want you back on repairs immediately.
We need to keep this ship alive.
Dismissed.
Sir?
Dismissed, Stepashin.
All we needed to do
was let Skaldak go
and he'd have forgotten us.
But you attacked him, you declared war.
"Harm one of us and you harm us all.”
It's the ancient Martian code.
You hear that?
(BUZZING)
Skaldak has sent out a distress call.
He will bring down the fires of hell
just for laying a glove on him.
Unless you talk to it?
-I'm the only one who can.
-No. Out of the question.
We're not losing you. I'll do it.
-What?
-You can talk to it through me.
But Skaldak won't talk to you.
You're an enemy soldier.
-And how would he know that?
-A soldier knows another soldier.
He'll smell it on you,
smell it on you a mile off.
And he wouldn't smell it on you, Doctor?
Just let me in there
before it's too late.
It can't be you or any of your men.
Well, it can't be you.
(CLARA CLEARING THROAT)
Well, there really is only one choice,
isn't there?
I don't smell of anything.
To my knowledge.
You? No! No! No way!
You're not going in there alone, Clara.
Absolutely not!
No, no. Never!
(DOOR CLOSES)
With your permission.
Be my guest.
-(FEEDBACK HUMS)
-Ready, Clara?
-Yeah.
-DOCTOR: Okay.
CLARA: Grand Marshal Skaldak.
The salute.
Do the salute like I showed you.
(SKALDAK HISSING)
-Okay?
-Good.
Good. Now, like we rehearsed.
"Sovereign of the Tharsyssian caste..."
Sovereign of the Tharsyssian caste,
by the moons I honour thee.
DOCTOR: Good.
It's okay, Clara. Go closer.
Grand Marshal, I'm...
We're sorry about this.
It's not what you deserve.
-It isn't what you deserve.
-(THUD)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Oh. Oh, great.
Hey, it's okay, Clara. Keep going.
You're a long way from home.
Five thousand years.
And 5,000 years adrift in time.
Please let us help you.
You are not our enemy.
And yet I am in chains.
Doctor, what do I say?
SKALDAK: Yes, Doctor,
what should she say?
I think he wants to speak
to the organ-grinder, not to the monkey.
I heard that.
You are restrained
until we can trust each other, Skaldak.
You would do
exactly the same in my position.
And don't even think
about using that sonic weapon.
Not in the torpedo room.
SKALDAK: I was fleet commander
of the Nix Tharsyss.
My daughter stood by me.
It was her first taste of action.
We sang the songs of the old times.
The songs of the red snow.
Five thousand years.
Now my daughter will be dust.
Only dust.
No, no, no, listen.
Your people live on, Skaldak,
scattered all across the universe
and Mars will rise again, I promise you.
Just let me help you.
SKALDAK: I require no help.
There will be no help.
-DOCTOR: Careful, Clara.
-I'm okay.
No, listen, Clara, don't get too close.
I'm okay.
Doctor, something's wrong.
What?
Something's...
(GASPING)
It's not there, it's gone!
(BEEPING)
Gone? Gone? Gone?
What do you mean, gone?
It's got out!
SKALDAK: It is time I learnt
the measure of my enemies
and what this vessel is capable of.
No, no, no, Skaldak!
SKALDAK: Harm one of us
and you harm us all.
By the moons, this I swear. (SNARLS)
Clara, get out of there. Get out!
(GUN COCKS)
I have never seen one do this before.
Actually, I've never seen one
out of its arm our before.
Won't it be more vulnerable
out of its shell?
No. It will be more dangerous.
(SKALDAK HISSING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Clara! Clara!
(HISSING CONTINUES)
Oh! (WHIMPERS)
(WHOOSHING SHARPLY)
Clara!
Clara! Clara! Clara!
-(PANTING)
-I'm okay.
(LAUGHS) I'm okay. I'm okay.
Where did he go?
(SIGNAL BEEPING)
How did I do? Was I okay?
This wasn't a test, Clara.
-I know but...
-You were great, yeah.
Really?
Really.
Doctor. The signal, it stopped.
Skaldak got no answer
from his Martian brothers.
Now he's given up hope.
-ZHUKOV: Hope of what?
-Being rescued.
He thinks he's been abandoned.
He's got nothing left to lose.
(RUMBLING)
ZHUKOV: Well, what can he do?
Stuck down here like the rest of us.
How bad can it be?
This sub's stuffed
with nuclear missiles, Zhukov.
It's fat with them.
What do you think Skaldak's going to do
when he finds that out?
How bad can it be? How bad can it be?
It couldn't be any worse.
(CRASHING)
(CLARA SCREAMS)
Okay. Spoke too soon.
(BEEPING)
(METALLIC CLANGING)
Hello. Who's there?
Who's there?
(METALLIC RATTLING)
(RATTLING)
(SKALDAK GROWLING SOFTLY)
What do you want with me?
SKALDAK: Much.
(SNARLING)
Comrades, you know our situation.
The reactor is drowned.
We are totally reliant on battery power
and our air is running out.
Rescue is unlikely.
But we still have a mission to fulfil.
If the Doctor is right,
then we are all that stands
between this creature
and the destruction of the world.
Control of one missile is all he needs.
We are expendable, comrades.
Our world is not.
I know I can rely on every one of you
to do his duty without fail.
That is all.
Listen to me. (PANTING)
We both understand each other.
This... This mewling time of peace,
it doesn't suit us.
We're both warriors.
And together, we can form an alliance.
SKALDAK: An alliance?
Yes.
To win the Cold War.
SKALDAK: Cold War?
(STEPASHIN GRUNTS)
Both sides are capable
of completely obliterating the other.
It's a state we call
mutually assured destruction.
SKALDAK: Mutually assured destruction.
But this has not occurred.
No.
SKALDAK: Not yet.
(SKALDAK HISSING)
Even if a missile did get launched,
that wouldn't be it, would it?
[1] It'll?
End of the world, game over.
I mean, what if they fired one
by accident? What would happen then?
Well, I told you, Clara, Earth is like
a storm waiting to break right now.
Both sides baring their teeth,
talking up war.
It would only take one tiny spark.
Yeah, but the world didn't end in 1983,
did it? Or I wouldn't be here.
You. History is in flux.
It can be changed.
Rewritten.
How many of us are left?
Twelve. And we can't find Stepashin.
We split up and comb the sub.
One team stays here to guard the bridge.
That's it? That's the plan?
Well, it's either that or we stay here
and wait for him to kill us.
Okay.
Is it true you've never seen one
outside of its shell suit?
-"Shell suit"? Clara.
-Hmm.
For an ice warrior to leave its arm our
is the gravest dish on our.
Skaldak is desperate. He's deadly.
And we have got to find him.
Will this help?
Ah! You saved it!
No, no. It was on the floor with this.
Oh! Oh! Professor, I could kiss you!
If you insist.
Later.
Ah!
Do you think it's true, sir?
A Martian?
I don't know what to think.
So why have you got a cattle prod
on a submarine?
-Polar bears.
-Ah, right.
We run across them when we're drilling.
Can be quite nasty, you know.
I'd swap one for an ice warrior
any day. Cuddlier.
Courage, my dear.
-(BUZZING)
-PROFESSOR: I always sing a song.
-What?
-To keep my spirits up.
Yeah, that would work,
if this was Pinocchio.
(ALARM BLARING)
Do you know Hungry Like the Wolf?
What?
Duran Duran, it's one of my favourites.
Come on!
I'm not singing a song.
(GROWLING ECHOES)
-What was that?
-Pressure. Just pressure.
We're 700 metres down, remember?
Don't worry about it.
Think of something else.
(SCATTING)
# I'm hungry like the wolf #
I'm not singing.
-Don't you know it?
-Of course I know it.
We do it at karaoke, the odd hen night.
"Karaoke"? "Hen night"?
You speak excellent Russian, my dear,
but sometimes I don't understand
a word you're talking about.
If we get out of here,
we'll be bloody heroes.
If we get out of here.
The first people in the world
to discover a genuine living...
Alien? I don't know.
You hear stories, don't you?
Stories about the things
the Kremlin doesn't want us to...
Onegin?
Onegin!
(SKALDAK SNARLING, MEN SCREAMING)
Good God!
Torn apart.
He's a monster, a savage.
No, Professor, not savage. Forensic.
Well, he's dismantled them.
Skaldak's learning.
Learning all about you.
Your strengths.
Your weaknesses.
Come on.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-Stay here.
-Okay.
-Stay here, don't argue.
-I'm not.
Right! Good.
(PROFESSOR PANTING)
It's a young man's game,
all this dashing about.
Clara? What is it?
I was doing okay.
I mean, I went in there
and I did the scary stuff, didn't I?
I went in there with the ice warrior
and it went okay.
Actually, it went just about as badly
as it could've done
but that wasn't my fault.
Not at all.
-So I'm happy about that.
-Yes.
Sure.
And so you should be.
So what's the matter?
Seeing those bodies back there,
it's all got very real.
-Are we going to make it?
-Yes, of course.
(METAL CLANKING)
(HISSING)
It's in the walls.
DOCTOR: Oh, Stepashin.
(RATTLING)
(HISSING)
Oh, oh! Oh! Fast.
He's fast.
(HISSING)
(GROANING ECHOES)
What was that?
The Doctor told you,
it's just the boat settling.
Tell me about yourself.
What do you like doing?
-Clara?
-(RATTLING)
-Stuff, you know, stuff.
Stuff. Very enlightening.
And The Doctor...
What he said, is it true?
You're... You're from another time?
From our future? Clara?
-Yes.
-Tell me what happens.
-I can't.
-Well, I need to know.
-I'm not allowed. I can't!
-No, please!
Ultravox, do they split up?
(LAUGHS)
Funny. You're funny.
(HISSING)
Let her go!
See? I don't just like Western music.
(HISSING)
No, please don't hurt him.
Please! Please!
SKALDAK: You attacked me.
Martian law decrees that the people
of this planet are forfeit.
I now have all the information
I require.
It will take only one missile
to begin the process
to end this Cold War.
Grand Marshal,
there is no need for this. Listen to me.
My distress call has not been answered.
It will never be answered.
My people are dead. They are dust.
There is nothing left for me
except my revenge.
(SNARLING)
There is something left for you,
Skaldak. Mercy.
Mercy?
You must wear that arm our for a reason,
my friend. Let's see, shall we?
No, Captain, wait!
I will do whatever it takes
to defend my world, Doctor.
Yes, great. Fine, good.
But we are getting somewhere here.
We are... We are negotiating.
-Jaw-jaw, not war-war.
-Churchill?
-Churchill.
-Very well.
Wwe'll negotiate,
but from a position of strength.
SKALDAK: Excellent tactical thinking.
-My congratulations, Captain.
-Thank you.
Unfortunately, your position
is not, perhaps,
as strong as you might hope.
(HISSING)
What do you mean?
(HEAVY CLANKING)
(GROWLS)
-DOCTOR: He summoned the arm our.
-How did it do that?
Sonic tech, Clara.
The song of the ice warrior.
DOCTOR: No!
SKALDAK: My world is dead!
But now there will be
a second red planet.
Red with the blood of humanity.
Skaldak! Skaldak, wait!
(ALARM BLARING)
No! Skaldak, wait! Wait! Wait!
He's arming the warheads!
Where is the honour in condemning
billions of innocents to death?
Five thousand years ago,
Mars was the centre of a vast empire,
the jewel of this solar system.
The people of Earth had only just begun
to leave their caves.
Five thousand years
isn't such a long time.
They're still just frightened children.
Still primitive.
Who are you to judge them?
I am Skaldak.
This planet is forfeit
under Martian law.
Then teach them. Teach them.
Grand Marshal, show them another way.
Show them there is honour in mercy.
Is this how you want
history to remember you?
Grand Marshal Skaldak,
destroyer of Earth?
Because that's what you'll be
if you send those missiles.
-Not a soldier. A murderer.
-(GRUNTS)
Five billion lives extinguished.
No chance for goodbyes.
A world!
A world snuffed out like a candle flame!
All right. All right, Skaldak.
You leave me no choice.
I'm a Time Lord, Skaldak.
I know a thing or two
about sonic technology myself.
A threat? You threaten me, Doctor?
No. No, not you.
All of us.
I will blow this sub up
before you can even reach that button,
Grand Marshal,
blow us all to oblivion.
You would sacrifice yourself?
In a heartbeat.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
Mutually assured destruction.
DOCTOR: Look into my eyes, Skaldak.
Look into my eyes.
Tell me you're capable of doing this.
Huh?
Can you do that?
Dare you do that?
Look into my eyes, Skaldak, come on!
Face to face.
Well, Doctor.
Which of us shall blink first?
Why did you hesitate?
Back there, in the dark?
You were going to kill
this man, remember?
I begged you not to and you listened.
Why show compassion, then,
Skaldak, and not now?
(HISSING)
The Doctor's right.
Billions will die.
Mothers, sons, fathers, daughters.
Remember that last battle, Skaldak?
Your daughter.
-You sang the songs...
-Of the red snows.
(CRASHING)
What's happening?
My people live. They have come for me.
ZHUKOV: We're rising.
We're rising!
PROFESSOR: 600 metres.
550.
(PINGING)
DOCTOR: We've surfaced.
Your people have saved us.
Saved me, not you.
Just go, Skaldak, please.
Please, go in peace.
-We did it.
-(ALARM BEEPING)
-We did it!
-No. No, no, no, no, no.
It's still armed.
A single pulse from that ship...
I'll destroy us if I have to.
I will destroy us if I have to.
Show mercy, Skaldak.
Come on. Show mercy.
# Da da da
# I'm lost and I'm found
# And I'm hungry like the wolf #
(ALARM STOPS)
-DOCTOR: Now we're safe.
-(SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Saved the world, then.
Yeah.
That's what we do.
(DOCTOR WHISTLES)
The Tardis! Where's the Tardis?
You never explained.
-Oh, well, don't worry about that.
-Stop saying that. Where is it?
-Yeah. Well, I wasn't to know, was I?
-Know what?
I've been tinkering, breaking her in.
I'm allowed.
What did you do?
(MUMBLING) I reset the HADS.
-Huh?
-I reset the HADS.
-The what?
-The HADS.
The Hostile Action Displacement System.
If the Tardis comes under attack,
gunfire, time winds, the sea,
it...relocates.
Oh, Doctor.
I haven't used it in donkey's years.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
Well, never mind.
It's bound to turn up somewhere.
-(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
-Ooh! Ha!
See? Right on cue. Brilliant.
Brilliant.
The Tardis is at the Pole.
Not far, then.
The South Pole.
Ah.
Can we have a lift?
(LAUGHING)
(MIMICKING ZHUKOV)
I'm talking to the spirit
that inhabits this house.
Spooky.
You didn't come here for the ghost,
did you?
Clara. Where is she?
CLARA: Do you feel like
you're being watched?
-You coming?
-Where?
DOCTOR: 70 find the ghost.
Doctor!
-The Caliburn Gast.
-(GASPS)
The Maiden in the Dark,
the Witch of the Well
She's coming.
I think she's here.