River? Are you okay? Talk to me.
Okay. Um, uh...
Breathe, breathe, come on.
Got to keep breathing. Uh...
(PANTING)
River, you are holding your breath.
(GROANS)
You're a fine one to talk about holding.
How many hands do you have?
Get up! What are you doing?
-Who's shooting at you?
-Oh, just a few Sontarans.
Chased me halfway across the galaxy.
I probably shouldn't have asked
them if they were on a hen night.
-River, you can't do things like that.
-Or what?
You've already had me banged up in jail
for five years.
What else are you going to do? Spank me?
-Now, that...
-Doctor,
have you brought someone else here?
Does anyone agree to wear that dress?
Where is she?
River, think it through.
This happened the
last time we were here.
-You brought someone else.
-No, I didn't.
Yes, you did.
I heard you talking to her.
It's the same night!
Doctor, were you talking to someone?
No, no, just me.
-Were you talking to someone?
-No, no, dear. Just me.
You nostalgic idiot.
You just can't keep away, can you?
Doctor, why have you brought
another one of these?
Who else is here?
River, could you just check
the light on top?
I think the bulb needs changing.
-The bulb?
-Mmm-hmm.
-Who were you talking to?
-You.
I'm talking to you.
Back to Storm Cage, Dr Song.
Oh, at least give me a lift. You know
what this thing does to my hair.
-It's always like that.
-(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(CHUCKLES)
The light's fine. I don't know
what you're talking about.
No, River, wrong Tardis.
I'm parked round the back.
-(GASPS)
-Younger version.
Two of you!
-The mind races, does it not?
-Come on, we'll be late.
He's taking me to the
Singing Towers of Darillium.
He's been promising for ages.
The first time we met her at the library
when she...
Died, yes.
She said the last time she saw us
was at Darillium.
Is that now?
Spoilers! Good luck tonight.
You, too.
Yeah.
There's two of you! The mind races.
Right, come on, you.
Let's go and see the stars.
-But I haven't changed.
-And you never will, River.
Never ever.
What was the other you doing here?
-Sorry, can't say.
-What's that word you use?
(LAUGHS) Spoilers.
-I like that word.
-I thought you might.
(SIGHS) Doctor, you and your secrets.
-You'll be the death of me.
-Mmm.