(THUNDER CRASHING, WIND HOWLING)
-How are we looking?
-Oh!
-About ready, I think.
-Hmm.
Any thoughts on the, uh, interference?
Um, a stray FM broadcast, possibly,
but I've fitted some ferrite suppressors
and some RF chokes.
Just in case.
Are you sure you want to
go through with this?
-I mean, the last time it was very...
-But she's so lonely.
Excellent, then.
Excellent.
(FEEDBACK)
Caliburn House, night four,
November 25th, 1974,
11:04 p.m.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
I'm talking to the spirit
that inhabits this house.
-Are you there?
-(STATIC)
Can you hear me?
I'm speaking to the lost soul
that abides in this place.
(CLANKING)
(FEEDBACK)
Come to me. Speak to me.
Let me show you the way home.
(GROANING, FEEDBACK INTENSIFYING)
(DISTANT MOANING)
Let me show you the way home!
(GASPING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
-Emma?
-(WHEEZING)
-She's so...
-So0...so what?
Dead.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Boo! (LAUGHS)
Hello. I'm looking for a ghost.
And you are?
Ghostbusters.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
-I'm The Doctor.
-Doctor what?
If you like, and this is Clara.
Ah, but you are very different.
Ha! You are Major Alec Palmer,
member of the Baker Street Irregulars,
the Ministry of Ungentlemanly Warfare,
specialise in espionage, sabotage
and reconnaissance behind enemy lines.
You're a talented watercolourist,
professor of psychology and...
ghost hunter.
Total pleasure.
-Massive.
-Actually, you're wrong.
Professor Palmer spent
most of the war as a POW.
Actually, that's a lie
told by a very brave man
involved in very secret operations.
The type of man
who keeps a Victoria Cross
in a box in the attic, eh?
But you know that
because you're Emma Grayling.
-The professor's companion.
-Assistant.
It's 1974.
You're the assistant and
"non-objective equipment"”.
-Meaning psychic.
-Getting that. Bless you, though.
Relax, Emma. He's military intelligence.
-So, what is all this in aid of?
-Health & Safety.
Yeah. The Ministry got wind
of what's going on down here,
sent me to check that
everything's in order.
They don't have the right.
Don't worry, governor,
I'll be out of here in five minutes.
Oh! Oh, look!
Oh, lovely, the ACR99821.
Oh, bliss. Nice action
on the toggle switches.
You know, I do love a toggle switch.
Actually, I like the word "toggle".
(CHUCKLES)
Nice noun. Excellent verb.
Oi, don't mess with the settings.
-(BUZZING)
-What's that?
Gadget. Health & Safety.
Classified, I'm afraid.
You know, while the backroom boffins
work out a few kinks.
EMMA: What's it telling you?
It's telling me that
you haven't been exposed to
any life-threatening
transmundane emanations.
So...
-where's the ghost? Huh?
-(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Show me the ghost.
(THUDDING)
It's ghost time.
ALEC: I will not have this stolen out
from under me, do you understand?
Um... No, not really. Sorry.
I will not have my work stolen
and be fobbed off with a pat on the back
and a letter from the Queen.
Never again.
This is my house, Doctor,
and it belongs to me.
-Is this actually your house?
-It is.
(CHUCKLES) Sorry.
You went to the bank and said,
"You know that gigantic,
old haunted house on the moors?
"The one that dossers are
too scared to doss in,
"the one that birds are
too scared to fly over?”
And then you said, "I'd like to
buy it, please, with my money"?
Yes, I did, actually.
-That's incredibly brave.
-(DOOR CREAKS)
(GASPS)
Listen, Major.
We just need to know
what's going on here.
-For the Ministry?
-You know I can't answer that.
(SIGHS)
Very well.
Follow me.
So what's an empathic psychic?
Sometimes I sense feelings,
the way a telepath can sense thoughts.
Sometimes, though, not always.
The most compassionate people
you will ever meet, empathics.
And the loneliest.
I mean, exposing themselves
to all those hidden feelings,
all that guilt,
pain and sorrow and...
-Doctor.
-Yes.
Shh!
Do you, uh, care to have a look?
Caliburn House is over 400 years old,
but she has been around much longer.
The Caliburn Gast.
She's mentioned in local Saxon poetry
and parish folk tales.
The Wraith of the Lady.
The Maiden in the Dark.
The Witch of the Well.
Is she real?
As in actually real?
ALEC: Oh, she's real.
In the 17th century,
a local clergyman saw her.
He wrote that,
"Her presence was accompanied by
"a dreadful knocking,
"as if the Devil himself
demanded entry".
During the war,
American airmen stationed here
left offerings of tinned Spam.
The tins were found in 1965
bricked up in the servants' pantry,
along with a number
of handwritten notes,
appeals to the Gast.
"For the love of God,
"stop screaming.”
She never changes.
The angle's different,
the framing, but she's
always in exactly the same position.
Why is that?
We don't know.
She's an objective phenomenon.
But objective recording equipment
can't detect her.
Without the presence of
a powerful psychic.
Absolutely.
Very well done.
(GASPING) She knows I'm here.
I can feel her
calling out to me.
What is she saying?
"Help me."
DOCTOR: The Witch of the Well.
So, where is the well?
A copy of the oldest plan
that we could find.
There is no well on the property.
None that we could find, anyway.
(GASPING)
-(WHISPERS) You coming?
-Where?
-To find the ghost.
-Why would I want to do that?
Because you want to. Come on.
-Well, I dispute that assertion.
-Eh?
I'm giving you a face.
Here. Can you see me?
Look at my face.
(GRUMBLING) Fine.
Dare me.
I dare you. No takesie-backsies?
The music room is
the heart of the house.
Say we actually find her.
What do we say?
We ask her how she came to be
or if she is.
-Why?
-Because I don't know.
And ignorance is, um,
what's the opposite of bliss?
-Carlisle?
-Yes.
Yes, Carlisle. Ignorance is Carlisle.
Is he really from the Ministry?
Uh, I don't know.
He's certainly got the right demeanour.
Capricious, brilliant.
-Deceitful.
-Yes. (CHUCKLES)
He's a liar.
But you know,
that's often the way that it is
when someone's seen a thing or two.
Experience makes liars of us all.
We lie about who we are,
about what we've done...
And how we feel?
Yes.
Always.
Always that.
You know, I have to, um...
I have to be getting on with things.
The, um...
-The equipment and so forth.
-Of course.
DOCTOR: Ah, the music room.
The heart of the house.
Do you feel anything?
-No.
-Your pants are so on fire.
(CLARA LAUGHING)
(BLOWING)
(BUZZING)
(WHISPERING) Do you feel like
you're being watched?
What does being watched feel like?
Is it that funny tickly feeling
on the back of your neck?
-That's the chap.
-Then, yes, a bit.
Well, quite a big bit.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(FLOOR CREAKING)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
(CREAKING)
I think she's here.
(EXHALES)
Cold spot.
Spooky.
Cold.
Warm.
Cold. Warm.
Cold. Warm. Cold.
-Warm. Cold.
-(METALLIC CLICKING)
Doctor?
-Doctor!
-What?
I'm not happy.
No.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Hey!
-(THUDDING)
-Oh...
What was that?
(THUDDING)
(BOTH GASPING)
Does it seem colder?
(COUGHS)
(THUDDING)
She's coming.
Okay. What is that?
It's, uh, it's a very loud noise.
It's a very loud, very angry noise.
-What's making it?
-I don't know. Are you making it?
-(THUDDING CONTINUES)
-(YELPS)
-Doctor?
-Yes.
-I may be a teeny, tiny bit terrified.
-Yes?
-But I'm still a grown-up.
-Mainly. Yes, and...
There's no need to
actually hold my hand.
-Clara?
-Yeah.
I'm not holding your hand.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Oh!
-Has this happened before?
-Never.
Ah! Camera. Camera!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WAILING)
(GASPING) Doctor!
(SCREAMING)
-GHOST: Help me!
-Oh!
(CRASHING)
CLARA: Doctor.
Oh!
I'd rather have a nice cup of tea.
Me, too.
Whisky is the eleventh
most disgusting thing ever invented.
(SIGHS)
I had a little peek at your records
back at the Ministry.
Well, you've certainly seen
a thing or two in your time.
Disrupting U-boat operations
across the North Sea.
Sabotaging railway lines across Europe.
Operation Gibbon.
The one with
the carrier pigeon"s brilliant.
I do love a carrier pigeon.
I did my duty
but then so did thousands of others.
Millions of others.
I was just lucky enough to come back.
Yes, but how does that man,
that war hero, end up here,
in a lonely old house
looking for ghosts?
Because I killed.
And I caused to have killed.
I sent young men and women
to their deaths.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
But here I am, still alive and...
But it does tend to haunt you,
living, after so much of...
the other thing.
So, you and Professor Palmer,
have you ever...
-You know.
-(SIGHS) No.
Why not?
You do know how he feels
about you, don't you?
You of all people.
(SIGHS) I don't know.
People like me,
sometimes we get our signals mixed up.
We think people are feeling
the way we want them to feel.
You know, when they're special to us.
When really, there's nothing there.
Oh, this is there.
-How do you know?
-Because it's obvious.
It sticks out, like a big chin.
You see, I was alone and unmarried and
you know, I didn't mind dying.
I mean, not for that cause.
It was a very, very fine cause.
Defeating the enemy.
And if you could contact them,
what would you say?
Well, I'd very much like to thank them.
Ah.
Ping.
What do you think she is?
Not what I thought she'd be.
-What did you think she'd be?
-Fun.
Can I borrow your camera?
Ta.
What about you and The Doctor?
Oh. Don't think so.
-Good.
-Sorry?
Don't trust him.
There's a sliver of ice in his heart.
DOCTOR: Clara!
I've got this weird feeling
it's looking at me.
It doesn't like me.
The Tardis is like a cat.
A bit slow to trust
but you'll get there in the end.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hey!
You need a place to keep this.
I've got one.
Or I had one. I think I had one.
Look around. See if you can find it.
Did I have one? Am I going mad?
No, not in here!
How do you expect her to like you
if she's soaking wet?
It's a Health & Safety nightmare.
Sorry.
(ELECTRONIC RUMBLING)
So, where are we going?
Nowhere. We're staying right here.
Right here, on this exact spot,
if I can work out how to do it.
So, when are we going?
(LAUGHING) Oh, that is good.
That is top-notch.
-And the answer is?
-We're going always.
-Totally.
That's not actually a sentence.
Well, it's got a verb in it.
What do you think?
Uh, colour's a bit boisterous.
I think it brings out my eyes.
Makes my eyes hurt.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Did you... Did you see where he went?
I could hear an engine
but I can't see any lights.
(GASPING)
Back off! Hot suit! Hot, hot, hot!
When are we?
About six billion years ago.
It's a Tuesday, I think.
Hmm?
(WHOOSHING)
Back in a mo.
Are you all right?
Totally. Peachy keen.
Okay, then. Well, don't press
any buttons or pull any levers
or make any funny faces.
Actually, don't move.
Stand completely still. Don't breathe.
Well, you can breathe.
But shallow breaths.
(SIGHING IN RELIEF)
What's wrong?
Did the Tardis say something to you?
Are you being mean?
No, it's not that.
Have we just watched the entire
life cycle of Earth, birth to death?
-Yes.
-And you're okay with that?
Yes.
How can you be?
The Tardis, she's time.
We... We're the vortex.
And so on.
-It's not what I mean.
-Okay.
Some help. Context.
Cheat sheet. Something?
I mean, one minute you're in 1974,
looking for ghosts,
but all you have to do is open your eyes
and talk to whoever is standing there.
To you, I haven't been born yet.
And to you, I've been dead
a hundred billion years.
Is my body out there somewhere,
in the ground?
Yes, I suppose it is.
But here we are, talking,
so I am a ghost.
To you, I'm a ghost.
We're all ghosts to you.
We must be nothing.
No. No.
You're not that.
Then what are we?
What can we possibly be?
You are the only mystery worth solving.
(WHOOSHING)
(WIND HOWLING)
What's wrong?
I just saw something I wish I hadn't.
What did you see?
That everything ends.
No, not everything.
Not love. Not always.
Right! Done! That's it, gather round,
gather around. Roll up! Roll up!
The Gast of Caliburn House.
Never changing,
trapped in a moment of fear and torment.
But what if she's not?
What if she's just trapped somewhere
time runs more slowly than it does here?
What if a second to her
was 100,000 years to us?
And what if somebody has a magic box,
a blue box probably,
what if said somebody could
take a snapshot of her, say,
every few million years?
She's not a ghost.
But she's definitely a lost soul.
Her name is Hila Tacorian.
She's a pioneer.
A time traveller, or at least
she will be in a few hundred years.
Time travel is not possible.
The paradoxes...
Resolve themselves, by and large.
How long has she been alone?
Well, time travel is a funny old thing.
I mean, from her perspective,
she crash-landed three minutes ago.
Crash-landed? Where?
She's in a pocket universe,
a distorted echo of our own.
They happen sometimes
but never last for long.
Our universe. Hila Tacorian's here,
in a pocket universe.
You're a lantern,
shining across the dimensions,
guiding her home,
back to the land of the living.
-But what's she running from?
-(SNAPS) Well, that's the best bit.
We don't know yet. Shall we see?
Oh.
What is that?
I don't know.
Still, not to worry.
So what do we do?
Not we, you.
You save Hila Tacorian
because you are Emma Grayling.
You are the lantern. The rest of us
are just along for the ride, I'm afraid.
We need some sturdy rope
and a blue crystal from Metebelis III,
plus some Kendal Mint Cake.
-Don't do it.
-I'm sorry?
Nobody asked her to risk her life.
This woman, she doesn't deserve...
Whoever she is, however brilliant,
however brave, she's not you.
She is not worth risking a single hair
on your head, not to me!
Tell me what I'm thinking.
I can't. I don't have your gift.
You don't need it.
Just look at me and tell me.
There you are. You read my mind.
-Can't you just... You know.
-What?
Fly the Tardis into a parallel universe.
Ah, it's not a parallel universe,
it's a pocket universe.
Plus, it is collapsing.
I mean, the Tardis could
get in there, all right,
but entropy would
bleed her power sources, you see,
trap her there until the entire universe
decayed back into the quantum foam,
which would take about three minutes,
give or take, you know.
(ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
What is that?
Subset of the Eye of Harmony.
-I don't...
-Of course you don't.
Bit weird if you did.
I barely do myself.
Right, you, sit down.
All the way from Metebelis III.
-What does it do?
-It amplifies your natural abilities,
like a microphone or a pooper-scooper.
(CLOCKS TICKING)
What exactly is this arrangement?
A psycho-chronograph.
Forgive me, but isn't it all
a little bit, well, make do and mend?
Non-psychic technology won't work
where I'm going.
Listen, all I need to do
is dive into another dimension,
find the time traveller,
help her escape the monster,
get home before the entire dimension
collapses and Bob's your uncle.
Doctor,
will it hurt?
No.
Well, yes, probably. A bit.
Well, quite a lot, I don't know.
It might be agony.
To be perfectly honest,
I'd be interested to find out.
(GULPS)
(BOTH EXHALING)
I'm talking to the lost soul
that abides in this place.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I'm speaking to Hila Tacorian.
(GROANS)
(ELECTRONIC PINGING)
See? The Witch of the Well.
It's a wormhole.
A reality well.
A door to the echo universe.
Ready?
Ready!
(NECK CRACKING)
Geronimo.
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
Doctor!
Whoa!
Hila! Hila!
Hila Tacorian!
(RUSTLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(RUSTLING CONTINUES)
One,
two,
three!
HILA: Help me!
Help!
-(EXCLAIMS) Hila Tacorian, I presume?
-Who are you?
Collapsing universe, you and me dead.
Two minutes, no time
complete sentences. Abandon planet!
Wait!
There's something in the mist.
Then, run. Run!
(PANTING)
EMMA: Doctor?
Doctor!
Come home!
Doctor, come home!
(GROWLING)
Okay, not that way, which means...
Uh, probably...
-What's wrong?
-You know that exit I mentioned?
-Yeah.
-I seem to have misplaced it.
(RUSTLING)
(LOW GROWLING)
-EMMA: Doctor!
-This way.
Doctor!
Come home!
Doctor, we're here.
-Whoa.
-What's that?
DOCTOR: An echo house
in an echo universe.
Clever psychic. That is just top-notch.
Doctor!
(RUSTLING)
-(GROWLING)
-Shh!
(RUSTLING)
It's looking for the way in.
(BANGING)
(CRASHING)
I'm not strong enough!
Just a few more seconds!
(SCREAMING)
Grab the rope.
Give it three tugs, quick as you like.
-What about you?
-I'll be next.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(BANGING)
Oh, that's what that noise was. Lovely.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
-Huh.
-(SNARLING)
Oh, dear.
Where are you?
(WHISPERS) Wake up!
Wake up! Open the thing!
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry, don't be.
What you did...
Wasn't enough. She needs to do it again.
-She can't. Look at her!
-She has to!
We can't leave him.
I know that you feel
that you can't do this, Emma,
but look at that woman over there.
You saved her. She's only here
because of your strength.
And so am I.
(PANTING)
(RATTLING)
Oh, come on!
Oh, let me in, you grumpy old cow!
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Whoa.
Emma, I was as lost as her
but being with you,
you gave me a reason to be, Emma.
You brought me back from the dead.
-What's this now?
-The Tardis voice visual interface.
I'm programmed to select the image
of a person you have seen.
Of several billion such images
in my data banks,
this one best meets the criterion.
Oh! Oh, you are a cow. I knew it!
Whatever. You have to help The Doctor.
-The Doctor is in the pocket universe.
-You can enter the pocket universe.
The entropy would drain the energy
from my heart.
In four seconds, I'll be stranded.
In 10, I'll be dead.
You're talking but all I can hear is,
"Meh-meh-meh-meh-meh.”
Come on, let's go!
Hey, hey, hey!
Doctor.
Can you hear me?
Doctor!
Oh, come on!
Doctor, can you hear me?
(SCREAMING)
Doctor!
Doctor, we're here.
Come home!
Emma?
(CREATURE SNARLS)
(GROWLING)
What do you want?
To frighten me I suppose, hey?
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
'Cause that's what you do, you hide.
You're the bogeyman under the bed,
seeking whom you may devour.
(GASPING)
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
You want me to be afraid.
And well done.
I am The Doctor
and I am afraid.
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
(CLARA SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
EMMA: Doctor!
Hurry!
(CREATURE SNARLS, DOCTOR GASPS)
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
So why am I still here, huh?
Why not just eat me?
Huh?
Come on.
-Because you still need me.
-(GROWLING)
Yeah, you need me
to piggyback you across. (LAUGHS)
Ah. To which I say...
Come on, then, big boy.
Chase me.
(GROWLING)
(GROANING)
(CLARA SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(EMMA SOBBING)
(WHISTLES IN RELIEF)
(GROANING)
It's over. (LAUGHING)
You wanted a word?
-Well, if that's...
-That's fine.
You didn't come here
for the ghost, did you?
No.
-You came here for me.
-Yes.
-Why?
-I needed to ask you something.
-Then ask.
-Clara.
Yes?
-What is she?
-She's a girl.
Yes, but what kind of girl,
specifically?
She's a perfectly ordinary girl.
-Very pretty.
-Mmm.
-Very clever.
More scared than she lets on.
-And that's it, is it?
-Why? Is that not enough?
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
Where will you go?
He can't take me home.
History says I went missing.
But he can change history.
No. No, no. I can't, actually.
There are fixed points in time, you see.
-(CLEARS THROAT) Hi.
-What?
I knew you were there.
-I could feel you.
-I know.
-Have we...
-We can't have.
-You haven't even been born yet.
-No, you can't have met but she can be
your great-great-great-great-great-
granddaughter.
Eh? Yours, too, of course. But you
guessed that already, didn't you?
Oh. Apparently not.
-The paradoxes...
-Resolve themselves, by and large.
That's why the psychic link
was so powerful,
blood calling to blood, out of time.
Not everything ends, eh?
Not love. Not always.
Doctor, what about, um...
(CLEARS THROAT) What about us?
Emma and me?
-What about you?
-Well,
what's supposed to happen?
I mean, what do we do now?
Hold hands.
That's what you're meant to do.
Keep doing that and don't let go.
That's the secret.
CLARA: Doctor! I'm not happy.
Yeah, you need me
to piggyback you across.
I'm not holding your hand.
(SNARLING)
Oh, I'm so slow!
I am slow. I'm notorious for it.
That's always been my problem, but...
but I get there in the end. Oh, yes.
-Doctor?
-How do sharks make babies?
-Carefully.
-No. No, no, no. Happily.
Sharks don't actually smile.
They just, well... They've got lots
and lots of teeth. They're quite eaty.
Exactly. But birds do it, bees do it,
even educated fleas do it.
Every lonely monster needs a companion.
-There's two of them!
-(DOCTOR LAUGHING)
You know, it's the oldest story
in the universe, this one or any other.
Boy and girl fall in love, get separated
by events, war, politics,
accidents in time.
She's thrown out of the hex,
or he's thrown into it.
Since then they've been yearning
for each other
across time and space,
across dimensions.
This isn't a ghost story,
it's a love story.
Sorry.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Sorry to interrupt
the rest of your life.
So, tiny favour to ask.
I'm sorry! I understand now!
-(GROWLING)
-I can take you to her.
I can take you to a safe place,
far away from here.
You can be together!
(EXCLAIMS)
Well, come on, then. She's waiting.
(GROWLING)
Well, hello again, you old Romeo, you.
-(WHOOSHING)
-Now, here she comes.
CLARA: Ha-ha! (WHOOPS)
(YELLING)
(CLARA WHOOPING)
Get ready to jump.
Running away with a spaceman in a box,
anything could happen to you.
Whoa!
It's good salvage. I can smell it.
Clara. Where is she?
She's still onboard.
If you help me get her out,
you get the machine.
The salvage of a lifetime.
MAN: Multiple life forms
onboard the Tardis.
What do you keep in here?
What are you, eh? A trick? A trap?
We do what we came for,
tear this ship apart.
If we're going to die here,
you're going to tell me what they are.
-(GROWL)
-I can't.
-Where are we going?
-The centre of the Tardis.