I'm going to die.
But I was told.
He will knock four times.
What is it? What's inside your head?
It's real!
The darkness heralds only one thing,
the end of time itself.
My head! Oh, my head!
If she ever remembers me,
her mind will burn and she will die.
What have you done, you monster?
LORD PRESIDENT: And so it came to pass
on Christmas Day
that the human race did cease to exist.
This day was the day
upon which the whole of creation
would change forever.
This was the day
the Time Lords returned.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
LORD PRESIDENT: What news of the Doctor?
Disappeared, My Lord President.
But we know his intention.
He still possesses the moment.
And he'll use it to destroy Daleks
and Time Lords alike.
The Visionary confirms it.
Ending, burning, falling,
all of it falling!
Black and pitch and screaming fire,
so burning!
All of her prophecies say the same,
that this is the last day
of the Time War,
that Gallifrey falls, that we die today.
Ending! Ending! Ending! Ending!
Perhaps it's time.
This is only the furthest edge
of the Time War.
But at its heart,
millions die every second,
lost in bloodlust and insanity,
with time itself resurrecting them
to find new ways of dying,
over and over again,
a travesty of life.
Isn't it better to end it, at last?
Thank you for your opinion.
(SCREAMING)
I will not die!
Do you hear me?
A billion years of Time Lord history
riding on our backs.
I will not let this perish.
I will not!
There is, um...
There is one part
of the prophecy, My Lord.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
It's rather difficult to decipher.
But it talks of two survivors
beyond the final day,
two children of Gallifrey.
Does it name them?
It foresees them locked
in their final confrontation,
the enmity of ages,
which would suggest...
The Doctor!
And the Master.
One word keeps being repeated, My Lord,
one constant word.
-Earth.
-VISIONARY: Earth.
Earth! Earth! Earth! Earth! Earth!
The planet Earth, indigenous species,
the human race.
Maybe that's where the answer lies.
Our salvation, on Earth.
(LORD PRESIDENT LAUGHING)
Now then, I've got a planet to run.
Is everybody ready?
6,727,949,338 versions of us,
awaiting orders.
This is Washington.
As President of the United States,
I can transfer all of the United Nations
protocols to you immediately,
putting you in charge
of all the Earth's defences.
UNIT HQ, Geneva reporting,
all under your command, sir.
And this is the Central Military
Commission, here in Beijing, sir,
with over 2.5 million soldiers, sir.
Present arms!
Enough soldiers and weapons
to turn this planet into a warship.
Nothing to say, Doctor?
What's that? Pardon? Sorry?
You let him go, you swine.
Your dad's still kicking up a fuss.
Yeah, well, I'd be proud if I was.
Hush now.
Listen to your Master.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
MASTER: But that.. that's a mobile.
Yeah, it's mine. Let me turn it off.
No, no, no, no, no.
I don't think you understand.
Everybody on this planet is me.
And I'm not phoning you,
so who the hell is that?
It's nobody, I tell you. It's nothing.
It's probably one of
them ring-back calls.
Ooh, look at this. Good man!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Donna? Who's Donna?
She's no one. Just leave it.
DONNA: Gramps, don't hang up.
You've got to help me.
I ran out. Everyone was changing.
Who is she? Why didn't she change?
DONNA: Gramps, I can't hear you.
Well, it was this thing the Doctor did.
He did it to her. The Meta-Crisis.
Oh, he loves playing with Earth girls!
-DONNA: Are you there?
-Find her! Trace the call
Trace the call.
DONNA: Are you still there?
Can you hear me?
Say goodbye to the freak, Granddad.
Donna, get out of there!
WILFRED: Look, just get out of there!
I'm telling you, run!
She's on Wessex Lane, Chiswick.
Open the phone lines.
-Everyone on Wessex Lane, red alert.
-DONNA: What do I do?
Run, sweetheart, that's all!
Run for your life!
-There's more of them.
-WILFRED: Donna? What's happening?
-Are you still there?
-They're everywhere.
-WILFRED: Donna!
-Oh, I'm starving.
WILFRED: Look, I'm telling you
to run, Donna!
I'm still hungry!
Just run, sweetheart! Just run!
It's not just them.
I can see those things again.
Those creatures.
Why can I see a giant wasp?
Donna, don't think about that,
Donna, my love, don't!
It hurts!
My head, it keeps getting hotter
and hotter and hotter and hotter!
(SCREAMING)
I don't want to die.
Donna, what was that?
Donna?
Donna, are you there?
Donna! Donna!
Donna!
That's better. Hello.
But, really, do you think I'd leave my
best friend without a defence mechanism?
WILFRED: Doctor, what happened?
She's all right, she's fine, promise.
She'll just sleep.
Tell me,
where's your TARDIS?
You could be so wonderful.
Where is it?
You're a genius.
You're stone-cold brilliant, you are,
I swear, you really are.
But you could be so much more.
You could be beautiful.
With a mind like that,
we could travel the stars.
It would be my honour,
'cause you don't need
to own the universe,
just see it.
To have the privilege of seeing
the whole of time and space.
That's ownership enough.
Would it stop, then?
The noise in my head?
DOCTOR: I can help.
I don't know what I'd be
without that noise.
Wonder what I'd be without you.
(SNIFFLING)
Yeah.
What does he mean? What noise?
It began on Gallifrey,
as children.
Not that you'd call it childhood.
More a life of duty.
Eight years old.
I was taken for initiation,
to stare into the Untempered Schism.
What does that mean?
DOCTOR: It's a gap
in the fabric of reality.
You can see into the Time Vortex itself.
And it hurts.
They took me there, in the dark.
I looked into time, old man,
and I heard it
calling to me.
Drums, the never-ending drums.
The Untempered Schism,
that's when it began.
History says,
"The Master heard a rhythm,
"a torment that stayed with him
for the rest of his life."
A drumbeat, a warrior's march.
A symptom of insanity, My Lord.
(TAPPING)
LORD PRESIDENT: A rhythm of four.
The heartbeat of a Time Lord.
(TAPPING CONTINUES)
Listen to it.
Listen.
Let's find it, you and me.
Except...
Oh! Oh, wait a minute!
-Oh, yes! Oh, that's good!
-What? What is?
The noise exists within my head
and now within six billion heads!
Everyone on Earth can hear it.
Imagine. Oh!
Oh, yes!
(LAUGHING)
The gate wasn't enough.
You're still dying.
This body was born out of death.
All it can do is die.
What did you say to me,
back in the wasteland?
You said, "The end of time".
I said something is returning.
I was shown a prophecy.
That's why I need your help.
What if I'm part of it?
Don't you see?
The drumbeat is calling
from so far away,
from the end of time itself!
And now it's been amplified
six billion times!
Triangulate all those signals!
I could find its source!
Look, Doctor,
that's what your prophecy was.
Me!
(EXCLAIMING)
Where's the TARDIS?
Just stop. Just think.
Kill him.
I need that technology, Doctor.
Tell me where it is
or the old man is dead.
-WILFRED: Don't tell him!
-I'll kill him right now!
Actually, the most impressive thing
about you is that, after all this time,
you're still bone-dead stupid.
Take aim.
You've got six billion pairs of eyes,
but you still can't see the obvious,
can you?
Like what?
That guard is one inch too tall.
Oh, my God, I hit him!
I've never hit anyone in my life!
Well, come on!
We need to get out of here, fast.
God bless the cactuses!
That's cacti.
That's racist!
This prophecy of yours, Doctor,
where did it come from?
Doctor?
Come on! We've got to get out!
There's too many buckles and straps!
Just wheel him!
No, no, no! Get me out!
No, no, don't! No!
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
What's going on?
Doctor!
-Which way?
-This way.
No, no, no, no, no, the other way!
I've got my TARDIS!
-I know what I'm doing.
-No, no, no, just...
Just listen to me!
Find him! Find him!
Not the stairs! Not the stairs!
Whoa!
(EXCLAIMING IN PAIN)
Worst rescue ever!
Underneath the gate room, sir.
-Basement! Get him!
-ALL: Yes, sir!
Just.. just stop and listen to me!
Gotcha.
You think so?
No, no, no, don't!
Now get me out of this thing!
Don't say thanks, will you?
He's not going to let us go.
Just hurry up and get me out!
Oh, my goodness me.
We're in space!
DOCTOR: Come on!
ADDAMS: All right!
WILFRED: Oh!
DOCTOR: Get a move on!
Open the teleport and follow him!
(EXCLAIMING IN FRUSTRATION)
-Come on!
-ADDAMS: All right!
Are they still up there?
Target practice!
-Where's your flight deck?
-But we're safe.
We're 100,000 miles above the Earth.
And he's got every single missile
on the planet ready to fire!
(MOUTHING)
Good point.
-But we're in space.
-Yep.
Doctor!
(PANTING)
Turn everything you've got to the skies!
Find me that ship!
And prime the missiles!
Open up the radar, maximum scan.
ALL: Yes, sir.
We've got to close it down!
ROSSITER: No chance, mate.
We're going home.
We're just a salvage team.
Local politics has
got nothing to do with us,
not unless it's a carnival.
The sooner we get back
to the Vinvocci space, the better.
We're not leaving.
Anything?
(SHUSHING)
(SPACESHIP CREAKING)
Sorry, sir, nothing.
Lost him.
What about teleport coordinates?
I need that information.
He's cut the link, sir.
No trace. All dead.
Still...
Open fire!
No way back now.
He's stranded.
No sign of any missiles.
No sign of anything.
You've wrecked the place!
The engines are burnt out.
All we've got is auxiliary light.
Everything else is kaput.
We can't move. We're stuck in orbit.
Thanks to you, you idiot!
Yeah, I know you, though. I'll bet
you've got a plan, haven't you, eh?
Come on. You've always got
a trick up your sleeve.
A nice, little bit
of the old Doctor flimflam,
(IMITATING TOMMY COOPER)
ha-ha-ha, sort of thing, eh?
Oh, blimey.
Night has fallen. Are we ready?
Every single one of us is prepared.
Then we listen, all of us,
across the world.
Just listen.
Concentrate. Find the signal.
(RHYTHMIC TAPPING)
There!
The sound is tangible.
Someone could only have designed this.
But who?
The signal has been sent.
The simple task of four beats
transmitted back through time
and implanted in the Master's mind
as a child.
Then we have a link
to where the Master is right now.
But we're still trapped
inside the time-lock, sir.
The link is nothing more
than a thought, an idea.
Then we need something
to make the contact physical.
Something so simple...
So small and shining,
shining bright and cold,
a tiny, tiny star, falling, falling,
burning, burning, burning.
Small enough to follow the link.
And if this were on Earth...
The sound, it's coming from above.
It's coming from the sky!
There!
Find it. Get out there and find it!
ALL: Yes, sir.
It's a diamond, sir.
Oh...
The most impossible diamond.
You won't believe this.
It's a white-point star.
(LAUGHING)
WILFRED: Doctor? Hello?
Hello?
(CLANGING)
Is that you?
Doctor?
Anyone?
Oh, I think I'm lost.
And, yet, you are found.
Events are closing.
The day is almost upon us.
But tell me, old soldier,
did you take arms?
I brought this.
But what am I supposed to do?
This is the Doctor's final battle.
At the end of his life,
he must stand at arms
or lose himself and all this world
to the end of time.
But he...he never carries guns.
He doesn't...
Who are you?
I was lost,
so very long ago.
Aye, aye. Got this old tub mended?
I'm just trying to fix the heating.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHING)
You know, I've always dreamt
of a view like that.
(CHUCKLING)
I'm an astronaut.
There's dawn over England. Look.
Brand-new day.
My wife's buried down there.
I might never visit her again now.
Do you think he changed them,
in their graves?
I'm sorry.
Not your fault.
Isn't it?
Oh, 1948, I was over there.
End of the mandate in Palestine.
Private Mott.
A skinny, little idiot, I was,
stood on this rooftop
in the middle of a skirmish.
Like a blizzard,
all them bullets in the air.
The world gone mad.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah, you don't want to listen
to an old man's tales, do you?
I'm older than you.
Get away.
I'm 906.
-What, really, though?
-Yeah.
Nine hundred years?
We must look like insects to you.
I think you look like giants.
Listen, I...I want you to have this.
I've kept it all this time,
and I thought...
No.
No, but if you take it, you could...
You had that gun in the mansion.
You could have shot the Master,
there and then.
Too scared, I suppose.
I'd be proud.
Of what?
If you were my dad.
Oh, come on, don't start.
Well, you said you were told
he will knock four times
and then you die.
Well, that's him, isn't it, the Master?
That noise in his head.
The Master is gonna kill you.
Yeah.
Then kill him first.
And that's how the Master started.
It's not like I'm an innocent.
I've taken lives.
And I got worse, I got clever.
Manipulated people
into taking their own.
Sometimes, I think
a Time Lord lives too long.
I can't.
I just can't.
If the Master dies,
what happens to all the people?
-I don't know.
-Doctor, what happens?
The template snaps.
What, they go back to being human?
They're alive and human.
Then don't you dare, sir.
Don't you dare put him before them.
Now, you take this.
That's an order, Doctor. Take the gun.
You take the gun and save your life!
And please don't die.
You're the most wonderful man
and I don't want you to die.
Never.
MASTER: (ON PA)
A star fell from the sky.
Don't you want to know where from?
MASTER: Because now
it makes sense, Doctor.
It's an open broadcast.
Don't reply or he'll know where we are.
MASTER: The whole of my life,
my destiny.
The star was a diamond.
And the diamond is a white-point star.
And I have worked all night
to sanctify that gift.
Now the star is mine.
I can increase the signal
and use it as a lifeline.
Do you get it now? Do you see?
Keep watching, Doctor.
This should be spectacular.
Over and out.
What's he on about? What's he doing?
Doctor, what does that mean?
The white-point star is only found
on one planet, Gallifrey,
which means it's the Time Lords.
The Time Lords are returning.
Well, I mean, that's good, isn't it?
I mean, that's your people.
Open up the nuclear bolt
and fuse the power lines to maximum.
Nuclear bolt accelerating, sir.
Send the signal back
and the link becomes a pathway.
(RHYTHMIC PULSING)
Come home.
(RHYTHMIC PULSING ON PA)
What's that?
Coming from Earth.
It's on every single wavelength.
Contact. At last.
We have contact.
Now the High Council of Time Lords
must vote.
Whether we die here today
or return to the waking world
and complete the ultimate sanction,
for this is the hour
when either Gallifrey falls
or Gallifrey rises!
ALL: Gallifrey rises!
Gallifrey rises!
But you said your people were dead,
past tense.
Inside the Time War,
when the whole war was time-locked.
Like sealed inside a bubble.
It's not a bubble,
but just think of a bubble.
Nothing can get in or get out
of the time-lock.
Don't you see?
Nothing can get in our get out,
except something that was already there.
The signal! Since he was a kid!
If they can follow the signal,
they can escape before they die.
Well, then, big reunion.
We'll have a party.
There will be no party.
But I've heard you talk about
your people like they're wonderful.
That's how I choose to remember them,
the Time Lords of old.
But then they went to war,
an endless war,
and it changed them, right to the core.
You've seen my enemies, Wilf.
The Time Lords are more dangerous
than any of them.
Time Lords? What lords?
Anyone want to explain?
Right, yes, you,
this is a salvage ship, yes?
You were trawling the asteroid fields
for junk.
Yeah, what about it?
So you've got asteroid lasers!
Yeah, but they're all frazzled.
Consider them unfrazzled.
You there, what's your name,
I'm gonna need you on navigation.
And you, get in the laser pod.
-Wilfred!
-Yeah?
Laser number two.
The old soldier's got one more battle.
This ship can't move. It's dead!
Fix the heating.
But now they can see us.
Oh, yes!
Sir, we've got a fix,
105,000 miles in orbit.
This is my ship
and you're not moving it.
Step away from the wheel.
There's an old Earth saying, Captain,
a phrase of great power and wisdom
and consolation to the soul
in times of need...
What's that, then?
Allons-y!
He's moving, sir.
Get a fix on him.
He's moving very fast.
Come on!
Come on, now!
You are freaking, flipping mad!
You two, do what I say! Lasers!
What for?
Because of the missiles!
DOCTOR: We've gotta
fight off the entire planet!
All NATO defences coordinated, sir,
awaiting your command.
I don't need him!
Any second now,
I'll have Time Lords to spare!
Take him out! Launch missiles!
Launch missiles.
ALL: Missiles launching
in three, two, one, zero...
Hey!
(WHISTLING)
How does this thing work?
The tracking's automatic!
Just deploy the trigger on the joystick!
Oh! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
ADDAMS: We've got incoming!
Look at this one! Oh, my God!
You two, open fire!
ROSSITER: Oh, my word!
Whoa! Whoa!
(ULULATING)
Open fire! Come on, Wilf!
(EXCLAIMING)
Whoo!
WILFRED: Oh, I wish Donna
could see me now!
Second wave, launch missiles.
Yes, sir.
And there's more! Sixteen of them!
Oh, and another sixteen.
Then go to the rearguard lasers!
You two, open fire! Now!
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, no, you don't!
(ADDAMS SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Come on!
Fire!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoa, wow!
Yes!
-Lock on navigation!
-Onto what?
England! The Naismith mansion!
He's heading straight for you.
But too late!
They are coming!
The vote is taken.
Only two stand against
and will stand as monument
to their shame.
Like the weeping angels of old.
Now the vanguard stands prepared,
as the children of Gallifrey
return to the universe,
to Earth!
(LAUGHING)
Destination?
Fifty klicks and closing!
We've locked on to the house.
We are going to stop, though?
Doctor?
We are going to stop?
(LAUGHING)
Closer!
And closer! And closer!
Doctor! Doctor!
You said you were going to die!
He said what?
WILFRED: But is that all of us?
I won't stop you, sir, but is this it?
-I think I should warn you...
-Not now!
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(PANTING)
My Lord Doctor...
Lord Master...
We are gathered for the end.
Left! Left! Turn it round! Land it!
We are not going in there!
I am not leaving that man on his own,
not today!
Land it!
(GRUNTING)
Listen to me.
You can't...
It's a fitting paradox
that our salvation
comes at the hands of
our most infamous child.
DOCTOR: Oh, he's not saving you.
Don't you realise what he's doing?
Hey, no, hey! That's mine. Hush.
Look around you.
I've transplanted myself
into every single human being.
But who wants a mongrel, little species
like them?
Because now I can transplant myself
into every single Time Lord.
Oh, yes, Mr President, sir,
standing there,
all noble and resplendent and decrepit.
Think how much better
you're gonna look as me!
No, no! No, no! No, stop it! No, no!
No, no, don't!
(ALL GASPING)
On your knees, mankind.
That's...that's fine. That's good.
Because you said "salvation”.
I still saved you. Don't forget that.
The approach begins.
Approach of what?
Something is returning.
Don't you ever listen?
That was the prophecy.
Not some-one, some-thing.
What is it?
They're not just
bringing back the species.
It's Gallifrey!
Right here, right now!
Donna! Where's Donna?
(GIRL SCREAMING)
Donna? Donna!
Donna!
Oh, Doctor, please!
We're getting out of here.
This whole planet's going to be
knocked out of orbit.
What about the Doctor?
Well, he said he was dying!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
But I did this! I get the credit!
I'm on your side!
Come on, get out of the way!
Get out of the way!
Doctor?
Please! Somebody, please!
All right, I've got you, mate!
I've got you!
Wilf, don't! Don't!
I've got you! Grab on! Open that! Go on!
But this is fantastic, isn't it?
The Time Lords restored!
You weren't there
in the final days of the war.
You never saw what was born.
But if the time-lock's broken,
then everything's coming through,
not just the Daleks,
but the Skaro Degradations,
the Horde of Travesties,
the Nightmare Child,
the Could-Have-Been King with
his army of meanwhiles and never-weres,
the war turning to hell.
And that's what you've opened,
right above the Earth.
Hell is descending!
My kind of world.
Just listen! 'Cause even the Time Lords
can't survive that!
We will initiate the Final Sanction.
The end of time will come
at my hand.
The rupture will continue
until it rips the Time Vortex apart.
That's suicide.
We will ascend
to become creatures
of consciousness alone,
free of these bodies, free of time
and cause and effect,
while creation itself ceases to be.
DOCTOR: You see now?
That's what they were planning
in the final days of the war.
I had to stop them.
Then take me with you, Lord President.
Let me ascend into glory!
You are diseased,
albeit a disease of our own making.
No more.
Choose your enemy well. We are many.
The Master is but one.
But he's the President!
Kill him and Gallifrey could be yours!
He's to blame, not me!
Oh, the link is inside my head.
Kill me, the link gets broken,
they go back.
You never would, you coward.
Go on, then.
Do it!
Exactly!
It's not just me! It's him!
He's the link! Kill him!
The final act of your life is murder.
But which one of us?
(CHOIR SINGING)
Get out of the way.
The link is broken!
Back into the Time War, Rassilon!
Back into hell!
VISIONARY: Gallifrey falling!
Gallifrey falls!
You'll die with me, Doctor!
I know.
Get out of the way.
You did this to me!
All of my life!
You made me!
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
(GROANING)
I'm alive.
I've...
(GASPING)
What...
I'm still alive.
(LAUGHING SHAKILY)
(FOUR-BEAT KNOCKING ON GLASS)
(ENERGY CRACKLING)
They gone, then?
Yeah, good-o.
If you could, uh, let me out...
Yeah.
Only this thing seems to be making
a bit of a noise.
The Master left
the nuclear bolt running.
It's gone into overload.
And that's bad, is it?
No.
'Cause all the excess radiation
gets vented inside there.
Vinvocci glass contains it.
All 500,000 rads
about to flood that thing.
Oh.
(CHUCKLING)
Well, you better let me out, then.
Except it's gone critical.
Touch one control and it floods.
Even this would set it off.
I'm sorry.
Look, just leave me.
Okay, right, then, I will.
'Cause you had to go in there,
didn't you?
You had to go and get stuck, oh, yes!
'Cause that's who you are, Wilfred.
You were always this...
Waiting for me, all this time.
No, really, just leave me.
I'm an old man, Doctor.
I've had my time.
Well, exactly! Look at you.
Not remotely important.
But me?
I could do so much more!
So much more!
But this is what I get.
My reward. Well, it's not fair!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHING)
Lived too long.
WILFRED: No.
No, no, please. Please, don't.
No, don't! Don't!
Please, don't! Please!
Wilfred,
it's my honour.
Better be quick.
Three, two, one...
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMING SOFTLY)
WILFRED: What?
Hello.
I._..
Still with us?
(GASPING)
The system's dead.
I absorbed it all.
Whole thing's kaput.
Oh, now it opens, yeah.
Well, here we are, then, safe and sound.
Mind you, you're in a hell of a state.
You've got some battle scars there.
(GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLING)
(SIZZLING)
But then... Your face...
How did you do that?
It's started.
(SOBBING)
It's no good.
She's freezing!
How long was she lying out there?
It's like hypothermia. Try them again.
I did. It's engaged.
Everyone's dialling 999.
I can't get through.
We gotta do something.
We gotta wake her up.
Donna, can you hear me?
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Donna?
Donna? It's me. I'm here.
You're safe. You're home.
But... I was...
What happened?
Did I miss something? Again?
Oh, she's smiling.
As if today wasn't bad enough.
Anyway...
I don't think that
this is goodbye, Wilf.
I'll see you again, one more time.
What do you mean? When's that?
Just keep looking. I'll be there.
Where you going?
To get my reward.
I told you to stay behind.
Well, you looked like you needed help.
(SCOFFING)
Besides, you're the one
who persuaded me to go freelance.
Yeah, but we're being fired at
by a Sontaran.
A dumpty with a gun.
And this is no place
for a married woman.
Well, then, you shouldn't
have married me.
If we go in here
and down to the factory floor
and down past that corridor,
then he won't know that we're here.
Mickey.
(GASPING)
Hey!
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
That was the maddest Christmas
ever, Clyde.
Mum still doesn't know what happened.
She got Mr Smith to put out this story
saying that Wi-Fi went mad
all across the world,
giving everyone hallucinations.
I mean, how else are you
going to explain it?
Everyone with a different face?
(HORN HONKING)
It's you!
You're...
Mum!
What? What is it?
-It's him!
-What?
It's the Doctor.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
(GLASS SMASHING)
From the man over there.
So, Alonso,
going my way?
How do you know my name?
I'm kind of psychic.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Do you know what I'm thinking right now?
Oh, yeah.
(LAUGHING)
No, it's not just a story, no.
Every word of it's true.
I found my great-grandmother's diary
in the loft
and, she was a nurse in 1913,
and she fell in love with this man
called John Smith,
except he was a visitor
from another world.
She fell in love with a man
from the stars.
And she wrote it all down.
MAN: Thank you.
-And who's it for?
-The Doctor.
"To the Doctor."
Funny, that's the name he used.
Was she happy, in the end?
Yes. Yes, she was.
Were you?
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
Everyone, three cheers! Hip, hip...
ALL: Hooray!
-Hip, hip!
-ALL: Hooray!
Right, then, come on, you lot. Get in!
This photo is just with friends.
Come on, and I want all of you in it.
Come on, that's it.
Well, friends, and Nerys.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, I'm only joking. Oh, look at her.
You made me wear peach.
That's 'cause you are a peach.
Fair of skin, stone inside, going off.
Okay, smile!
ALL: Cheese!
(CHEERING)
-How about it, Wilfred?
-Eh?
-Well, it's never too late.
-Yeah...
Will you behave, Minnie? Honestly.
I'm going to catch that bouquet.
Oh, dear.
(WILFRED CHUCKLING)
Dad!
And here you are, eh? Same old face.
Didn't I tell you you'd be all right?
Oh, they've arrested Mr Naismith.
It was on the news.
"Crimes undisclosed.” And his daughter.
Both of them, locked up.
Yeah, but I keep thinking, Doctor,
there's one thing you never told me.
That woman, who was she?
I just wanted to give you this.
Wedding present.
Thing is, I never carry money,
so I just popped back in time,
borrowed a quid off a really lovely man.
Geoffrey Noble, his name was.
"Have it," he said.
"Have that, on me."
WOMAN: Smile!
Oh, don't tell me, it's a bill.
Just what I need right now.
A lottery ticket?
What a cheap present! Who was that?
Still, you never know.
It's triple rollover this week.
I might get lucky.
Oi! Shawn!
Come on, we're on a tight schedule.
I was told soup at 2:30.
(WHOOSHING)
We're late now. I've missed it.
Midnight. Mickey's going to be
calling me everything.
This is your fault.
No, it's not. It's Jimbo.
He said he was gonna give us a lift
and then he said his axle broke.
I can't help it.
Get rid of him, Mum. He's useless.
Listen to you. With a mechanic!
Be fair, though.
My time of life,
I'm not gonna do much better.
Don't be like that.
Never know.
There could be someone out there.
Maybe, one day.
-Happy New Year!
Don't stay out all night.
Try and stop me.
(GRUNTING)
You all right, mate?
Yeah.
Too much to drink?
Something like that.
Maybe it's time you went home.
Yeah.
Anyway, happy New Year.
And you.
What year is this?
Blimey, how much have you had?
2005, January the 1st.
Tell you what.
I bet you're gonna have
a really great year.
Yeah?
See you.
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMING IN PAIN)
We will sing to you, Doctor.
The universe will sing you
to your sleep.
(CHOIR SINGING)
This song is ending,
but the story never ends.
I don't want to go.
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Legs! I've still got legs!
Good.
Arms, hands! Ooh, fingers!
Lots of fingers!
Ears, yes. Eyes, too. Nose.
I've had worse. Chin.
Blimey! Hair.
I'm a girl!
No! No!
I'm not a girl. No.
And still not ginger.
There's something else.
There's something important. I'm...
I'm..I'm...
(CRASHING)
Ha! Crashing!
Ha-ha!
(WHOOPING)
Ah!
Geronimo!