DOCTOR: Appalapachia.
-AMY: Say it again?
-Appalapachia!
Appalapachia!
-Appalapachia.
Appalapachia! What a beautiful word!
-Beautiful word, beautiful world.
-(AMY EXCLAIMS)
Appalapachia!
Voted number two planet
in the Top Ten Greatest Destinations for
the Discerning Intergalactic Traveller.
-Why couldn't we go to number one?
-It's hideous!
Everyone goes to number one,
planet of the coffee shops.
Appalapachia. I give you sunsets,
spires, soaring silver colonnades.
I give you...
Doors.
Doors, yes. I give you doors.
But on the other side of those doors,
I give you sunsets, spires,
soaring silver colonnades.
Have you seen my phone?
-Your phone?
-Yeah.
Your mobile telephone.
I bring you to a paradise planet
two billion light years from Earth
and you want to update Twitter?
Sunsets, spires,
soaring silver colonnades.
It's a camera phone.
On the counter, by the DVDs.
Thank you.
-How do we get in?
-I don't know. Push a button.
Okay, so, rain check
on the soaring silver colonnades.
Yeah.
It's a magnifying glass.
-Hey, hey, it's locked.
-Yeah, push the button.
Rory?
Come on, Amy.
Great.
Where is she?
Where on wherever we are is my wife?
Rory, I think I've found her.
What do you mean you've found her?
Whoa! But...
No, but she's not here!
DOCTOR:
I can see her, but she's not here.
Where am I? In fact, where are you?
-(ELECTRIC BUZZING)
-Whoa!
Hands, hello, Hands.
Robot with hands, Rory.
HANDBOT: Welcome to
the Two-Streams Facility.
Will you be visiting long?
Uh, Doctor, something's happening.
Amy? Stay calm, stay still.
Time's gone wobbly.
I hate it when it does that.
Will you be visiting long?
Good question. A bit sinister.
What's the answer to not get us killed?
It's okay. I've got you. You're fine.
Will you be visiting long?
Doctor, a little help, Doctor.
And where have you been?
-Will you be visiting long?
-What do I tell it?
I've been here a week.
-A week?
-RORY: A week!
I'm so sorry.
Aha! Same room, different times.
Two different time streams running
parallel, but at different speeds.
Amy, you're in a faster time stream.
Doctor, it's going again!
-Doctor!
-Amy!
Doctor!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Ah, come on. Gotcha! There!
Stabilised. Settled. Shh.
Why has this got hands?
Organic skin.
Ultimate universal interface.
Grown and grafted, not born.
I mean, it's actually seeing
with its fingers, scanning the room.
-But why not just give it eyes?
-Will you be visiting long?
DOCTOR: As long as it takes.
Amy, what exactly did you do?
I just came in
and pressed a door button.
Oh! Amy, there are two buttons.
The green anchor and the red waterfall.
Which one did you push?
I pushed the red waterfall.
Great.
(DOCTOR TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(EXHALES)
Amy?
Argh!
I pressed red waterfall
and she wasn't there!
DOCTOR: Okay, so,
you can't follow her directly...
No, it's never simple.
Did you hear that, Handbot?
She pressed the wrong button,
that's all.
We're aliens, we didn't know!
Statement rejected.
Appalapachia is under
planet-wide quarantine.
This is a Kindness Facility,
for those infected with Gen-7.
What?
DOCTOR: Gen-7.
RORY: Hmm?
The one-day plague.
-What, you get it for a day?
-No, you get it and you die in a day.
There are 40,000 residents
in the Two-Streams Facility.
Please remain in the sterile areas.
Visiting hours are now.
Sterile area, I'm safe.
What about me?
Gen-7 only affects two-hearted races,
like Appalapachians.
-And Time Lords.
-Yeah, like me.
Walk into that facility,
I'm dead in a day.
Time is faster on
Amy's side of the glass.
Uh, Amy, you said you'd been here
a week. What did you eat?
-Nothing. I wasn't hungry.
-No.
Because with that big waterfall,
time is compressed.
That's the point of the time glass.
It syncs up the two time streams
for visits.
You could be in here for a day.
And watch them
live out their entire lives.
And watch them grow old
in front of your eyes.
That's horrible!
No, Rory, it's kind.
You've got a choice.
Sit by their bedside for 24 hours
and watch them die
or sit in here for 24 hours
and watch them live.
Which would you choose?
Doctor?
Doctor, no, don't leave me.
I'm here, Amy. I'm right here.
Where are you? Am I looking at you?
Turn left, just a fraction.
Bit more. Stop.
That's it.
Eye to eye?
Eye to eye, do I.
Hello.
Amy, I'm taking the time glass
back to the Tardis.
Like SatNav, I can use it
to get a lock on you,
then smash through
using the Tardis to get you out.
Until then, you're on your own.
-Uh, what are you doing?
-Locking it onto Amy.
Small act of vandalism,
no one will mind.
-(ALARM BLARING)
-Ah!
That'll be the
small act of vandalism alarm.
Amy, I need you to go into the facility,
just for a bit.
Find somewhere safe to leave me a sign.
Remember, you are immune to Gen-7
but don't let them give you anything.
They don't know you're alien.
Their kindness will kill you. Now, go.
Rory, I love you.
Now, save me. Go on.
Ugh!
This is locked onto Amy permanently.
Play the signal into the console,
the Tardis will follow it.
Now, then, I know you're in here...
-(ALARM CLOCK RINGING)
-Um... Um...
Ha-ha!
-How do I look?
-Ridiculous.
Glasses are cool, see?
Oh, yes. Hello, handsome man.
Oh, hello.
Hello, Rorycam, huh?
-Oh, you can see what I see, right.
-You're breaking into Two-Streams.
Now, I can't go in there,
the Gen-7 will kill me. No regeneration.
You will be my eyes and ears.
-Rorycam. Rescue Amy. Got it.
-Mmm-hmm.
That's the spirit. Now, smashing through
a time wall could get a bit hairy.
-Is it safe?
-Don't know. Never tried. Best hold on.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome to the Two-Streams Facility.
Um, who are you and why can't I see you?
I am the interface between yourself and
the systems of the Two-Streams Facility.
I will be your guide, your teacher,
your friend.
Welcome to Two-Streams.
What is your name, please?
Amy, Amy Pond.
Welcome, Amy Pond.
I see you're travelling alone.
As a resident,
you will now have access to
all of the entertainment zones inside.
For a taste of adventure,
why not try the mountain zone,
and explore Appalapachia's famous
glass mirror mountains?
Or try our roller coaster zone.
Authentically model led on the famous
Warp-speed Death Ride
at Disneyland Cloumne.
All that you could wish for and more
is through the departure gate,
provided for you with kindness.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Unexpected visitor.
Welcome. Please seek assistance.
Hello? Hey! Oi, wait.
HANDBOT: You are carrying
unregistered bacteria.
Please let me help you.
No, I'm not from this world.
Your medicine will kill me.
Statement rejected.
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
No, no, please, I hate you.
Secondary delivery system engaged.
Unauthorised infection on check in.
Version 223.
(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Unauthorised resident detected.
HANDBOT: This is a kindness.
Do not be alarmed.
This is a kindness.
(SCREAMING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Unauthorised resident detected.
No!
HANDBOT: This is a kindness.
Do not be alarmed.
This is a kindness.
This is a kindness. Do not be alarmed.
No residents detected.
They didn't see me. They didn't see me.
(DOCTOR LAUGHING)
-Red Waterfall. We made it!
-Good on us.
How do we know that
we're in the same Red Waterfall as Amy?
Focus on the positive.
We locked onto Amy's time stream.
Eyes front, soldier.
Right, yes, sorry.
Appalapachians are the great
cultural scavengers, Rory.
This gallery's a scrapbook
of all their favourite places.
Bit of Earth, bit of alien, bit of...
whatever the hell that is.
Interface?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
I am here, Amy Pond.
Shh! Turn that light off!
So, um, what is this? How does it work?
This is the gate.
From here, you may depart to any of
Two-Streams' entertainment zones.
Cinema.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Aquarium.
(WATER GURGLING)
-Garden.
-Garden?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Why not?
Garden.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
It's beautiful.
I mean, freaky hedges.
The perfect replica of a Shiel
Governor's mansion on Sheilama.
You really could spend a lifetime here.
Not that I'm going to.
-Interface?
-Amy Pond?
Listen, I need somewhere safe
to hide and wait for my friends.
Where in Two-Streams is safe?
Two-Streams is a safe,
nurturing environment.
You know what I mean. Where can I go
so the Handbots can't find me?
Okay. Um, before, I was saved
by a sort of vent,
and there was light and smoke,
and the Handbots couldn't see me.
Why not?
Okay, I will put it another way.
What were those vent thingies?
The vents channel the exhaust fumes
from the temporal engines
that hold the multiple time streams
in place.
And these temporal engines
mess up the Handbots' sensors.
So, where's the temporal engines?
Temporal engines held within.
Okay.
HANDBOT:
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
Ha! Don't like that, do you?
Temporal engines. Somewhere to hide.
Where is everyone?
All right, Rory,
switch the time glass on the sonic key.
I'm sending a command signal
to the screwdriver.
Amy's here somewhere.
If I can just get a lock on her.
I wonder what happens
if we mix the filters?
And there they are.
40,000 time streams overlapping.
Red Waterfall isn't one time stream.
It's thousands.
Are they happy?
Oh, Rory, trust you to think of that.
I think they're happy to be alive.
Better than the alternative.
I come in peace.
Peace, peace, peace, peace.
(ELECTRONIC VOICE) I waited.
Sorry, what?
I waited for you.
Amy.
Doctor, what's going on?
Uh...
Amy.
DOCTOR: I think the time stream lock
might be a bit wobbly.
RORY: No, please, please.
Duck.
-Oh!
-Argh!
Handbots carry a black box
in case they go offline.
I've changed the cause of termination
from 'hostile' to 'accidental'.
Easy to reprogram, use my sonic probe.
-Amy.
-Rory.
Why?
Because the only way
I've survived this long
is by making the Handbots think
I don't exist.
Don't touch the hands.
There's an aesthetic transfer
in the skin.
If they touch you, you go to sleep.
But you're still here.
You didn't save me.
But... This is the saving.
This is the us saving you.
The Doctor just got
the timing a bit out!
(MOUTHING)
I've been on my own here
a long, long time.
I've had decades
to think nice thoughts about him.
Got a bit harder to stay charitable
once I entered decade four.
40 years? Alone?
36 years. Thanks.
No, right, I mean...
You look great. Really. Really.
Eyes front, soldier.
Still can't win, then?
In fact, I think I can now
definitely say I hate him.
I hate the Doctor.
I hate him more than
I've ever hated anyone in my life.
And you can hear it every word of this
through those ridiculous glasses,
can't you, raggedy man?
Uh, yes.
Putting the speakerphone on.
You told me to wait and I did.
A lifetime.
-Amy!
-You've got nothing to say to me.
Amy, behind you!
Feedback knocks them out.
Learned that trick on my first day.
Okay, so we just take the Tardis back
to the right time stream, eh?
We can stop any of this happening.
DOCTOR:
We locked onto a time stream, Rory.
This is it
This is so wrong.
I got old, Rory.
What did you think was going to happen?
Hey, I don't care that you got old.
I care that we didn't grow old together.
Amy, come on, please.
Don't touch me. Don't do that.
It's like you're not even her.
Thirty-six years, three months,
four days of solitary confinement.
This facility was built
to give people a chance to live.
I walked in here and I died.
Did you have anything to say?
Anything, Doctor?
Where did you get a sonic screwdriver?
I made it. And it's a sonic probe.
You made a sonic screwdriver?
Probe.
Oh!
Don't worry about him. Sit down, Rory.
-You named him after me?
-Needed a bit of company.
-Oh, so, he's like your...
-Pet.
-Is it safe?
-Yeah. I disarmed it.
How?
Oh. You disarmed it.
Oh, don't get sentimental.
It's just a robot.
You'd have done the same.
I don't that I would've.
And there he is. The voice of God.
"Survive, because
no one's going to come for you.”
Number one lesson. You taught me that.
DOCTOR: Is that really all I taught you?
Don't you lecture me.
Blue box man flying through
time and space on whimsy.
All I've got, all I've had for 36 years
is cold, hard reality.
So, no, I don't have a sonic screwdriver
because I'm not off on a romp.
I call it what it is. A probe.
And I call my life what it is.
Hell.
Amy Pond, I'm going to put this right.
You said you learned from an interface.
Can I speak with it?
It doesn't work in here.
2:23, the garden will be clear now.
Stay or go?
Sorry, me? No, I'm coming with you.
Then try not to get killed,
or do, whatever.
When I first came here,
I had to trick the interface
into giving me information.
I've reprogrammed it now.
It will tell me anything
except how to escape.
You hacked it? That's genius.
DOCTOR: Sorry to interrupt
that beautiful moment,
but temporal engines like that
have a regulator valve,
has to be kept at a distance
from the main reactor
or there'd be feedback.
Interface, where's the regulator?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
The regulator valve is held within.
Oh, very, very, ah...
Interface, I need to run through
some technical specifications.
Rory, give me to Amy a minute.
Here you go.
They look ridiculous.
That's what I told him.
Still, anything beats a fez, eh?
(LAUGHING)
What is it?
I think that's the first time
I've laughed in 36 years.
I'll just, um,
leave you two geniuses alone.
I'll be back in a minute.
DOCTOR: There's still time, Amy.
There's still time to fix everything.
How can you have a door without a wall?
-(THUMPS)
-Oh!
Holographic wallpaper?
Oh!
HANDBOT:
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
Rory? Rory.
(GROANING)
Glasses.
Stupid!
Oh!
-You saved me.
-Don't get used to it.
You've been crying.
-A little bit.
-Shut up, Rory.
You have, haven't you?
Woman with a sword. Don't push it.
Ha!
Okay. So, here's the plan.
Time is always a bit wibbly-wobbly
but in two streams, it's extra wobbly.
I've worked out a way to hijack
the temporal engines
and use them to fold two points
of Amy's timeline together.
We're bringing her out of the "then”
and into the "now"!
Amy, I just need to
borrow your brain a minute.
It won't hurt, probably.
Almost probably and then,
Amy Pond, I'm going to save you.
No!
Time's up. Handbots coming.
DOCTOR:
Amy, you've got to help us help you.
I need you to think back 36 years ago.
Amy?
Amy!
You told her to leave us a sign.
She did and she waited.
Oh, Amy.
Why won't you help yourself?
He wants to rescue past me
from 36 years back,
which means I'll cease to exist.
Everything I've seen and done dissolves.
Time is rewritten.
That's...
That's good, isn't it?
I will die.
Another Amy will take my place.
An Amy who never got trapped
at Two-Streams,
an Amy who grew old with you.
And she, in 36 years, won't be me.
But you'll die in here!
Not if you take me with you.
You came to rescue me, so rescue me.
Leave her and take you?
We could take this Amy with us easy.
But if we do, our Amy has to wait
36 years to be rescued.
So I have to choose
which wife do I want?
She is me. We're both me.
You being here is wrong.
For a single day, an hour,
let alone a lifetime.
I swore to protect you.
I promised.
-Rory.
-This is your fault.
-I am so sorry, but Rory...
-No, this is your fault!
You should look at a history book
once in a while,
see if there's
an outbreak of plague or not.
That is not how I travel.
Then I do not want to travel with you.
(FEEDBACK WHINING)
(AMY CRYING)
DOCTOR: Rory, if the time glass is
still on, if the link's still active,
I think I can hear Amy. Our Amy.
(AMY CRYING)
Oh, Amy.
Look me in the face
and say you won't help her.
I will not help her.
Okay.
Look me in the face and say it now.
(AMY SOBBING)
AMY: Rory? Rory, is that you?
Rory, where are you?
RORY: Same place as you.
Only I'm a bit ahead.
I remember this.
Who's she?
There's no one else here, but...
Me?
Why are we still here?
Because they leave you here.
Because they get in their Tardis
and they fly away.
No.
Rory wouldn't. Not ever.
Something must have stopped him.
You did.
Or rather, the old version of you.
The me version of you.
I refused to help them.
I won't let them save myself.
Why?
If you escape,
then I was never trapped here.
The last 36 years of my life rewrites
and I cease to exist.
That's why the old me
refused to help then,
that's why I am refusing to help now.
And that's why you'll refuse to help
when it's your turn.
And nothing you can say
will change that.
Three words.
What about Rory?
Rory.
I called my robot Rory.
You called your robot Rory?
Oh, so, you didn't call it The Doctor?
Or Biggles, our favourite cat?
Do you, um...
Do you remember that summer
when he came back to school
with that ridiculous haircut?
He said he'd been in a rock band.
Liar.
And then he had to learn
to play the guitar.
So we would know he couldn't play it.
Mmm-hmm.
All those boys chasing me.
But it was only ever Rory.
Why was that?
You know when sometimes
you meet someone
so beautiful,
and then you actually talk to them
and five minutes later
they're as dull as a brick?
Then there's other people,
and you meet them and you think,
"Not bad. They're okay."
And then, you get to know them
and their face just sort of
becomes them.
Like their personality is
written all over it.
And they just, they turn into something
so beautiful.
BOTH: Rory is the most beautiful man
I have ever met.
Please,
do it for him.
Oh, you...
You're asking me to defy destiny,
causality, the nexus of time itself,
for a boy.
You're Amy.
He's Rory.
Oh, yes I am.
I am going to pull time apart for you.
Okay, Doctor,
Two-Streams is back on air.
Right, okay, so this is big news.
This is temporal earthquake time.
I'm officially changing my own future.
Hold onto your spectacles.
In my past, I saw my future self
refuse to help you.
I am now changing that future
and agreeing.
Every law of time says
that shouldn't be possible.
Yes, except sometimes knowing
your own future
is what enables you to change it.
Especially if you're bloody-minded,
contradictory
and completely unpredictable.
So, basically, if you're Amy, then.
Yes, if anyone could defeat pre-destiny,
it's your wife.
It's not about what I'm doing,
it's about who I'm doing it for.
I am trusting you
to watch my back, Rory.
Always.
-You and me, always.
-Because here is the deal.
You take me, too, in the Tardis.
Me, too.
But that means there'll be
two of you, permanently.
RORY: Forever.
FUTURE AMY:
And that way we both get to live.
Two Amys together. Can that work?
I don't know. It's your marriage.
Doctor!
Perhaps, maybe if I shunted
the reality compensators on the Tardis,
we calibrated the doomsday pumpers
and jettison the karaoke bar, yes,
maybe, yes.
It could do it.
The Tardis could sustain the paradox.
RORY: Right.
Army.
And Amy.
The wife and the wife. Right.
Okay, Amy, Past Amy, stand by the door.
Future Amy, you, too.
Future Amy, can I borrow
your sonic screw...
It's a probe.
It's a screwdriver.
DOCTOR: Rory, sonic at double-out power.
Amy now, you're our link to Amy then.
We need to get a signal through
and that signal will be a thought.
Amy now and Amy then, share a thought.
Something so powerful
that it can rip through time.
Rory, sonic the pin front.
Inside you will find three levers
and a jumble of wire.
That's the regulator valve.
After we reroute it, you'll have
10 minutes to get back to the Tardis.
-Okay.
-Pull out the red and green receptors.
Reroute blue into the red
and the green into the blue.
Leave the red loose,
and on no account touch anything yellow.
Come on, Rory,
it's hardly rocket science.
It's just quantum physics.
Yes, right. Okay, blue into red.
Red into...
Now the levers, throw them in order.
And Amy, start thinking the most
important thought you have ever had.
Hold it in your head
and do not let it go.
Lever one.
-Macarena.
She's doing the Macarena.
Macarena!
-Our first kiss.
-Lever two, Rory.
Lever three!
Oh, Amy!
-Oh, my God!
(LAUGHING)
Yeah. Sorry.
-Hello.
-I don't know what...
Weird.
-Okay, this is weird.
-Right, just stop doing that.
How about, Amy 1 speaks first?
-Which one's Amy 1?
Well, you...
-I am
-I am.
-No, I am.
-Rory!
-Rory, just stop doing that.
Ah!
Rory, Rory, take the glasses off.
You'll get temporal feedback.
Whoa! Calm down there, Rory.
Amy, we've created a massive paradox
and the Tardis hates it.
Trying to get out of here.
What's the nasty Amy done to you?
Just calm down there.
Hang on in there, eh?
Rory, you've got eight minutes left.
I'm sorry, you're on your own now.
I'm not on my own.
I've got my wives.
HANDBOT: Do not be alarmed.
RORY: They're coming!
This is a kindness.
-With me.
-Do not be alarmed.
This is a kindness.
-This is a kindness.
-Amy.
-Deactivate.
-Kate Hatter. Year 10 hockey.
Go for the shins.
This is a kindness.
RORY: They're cutting off
the departure gate.
We can't get back to the Tardis.
Side door. We'll go behind them.
(ALARM BLARING)
AMY: So you think you're going to
come with us, just like that?
FUTURE AMY: Yeah, just like that.
-Rory, talk to her.
Now, ladies.
AMY: Where are you going to live?
FUTURE AMY:
Not with you, don't worry.
I'll go travelling.
Pop back for Christmas, maybe Easter.
Amy, you always said
cooking Christmas dinner,
you wished there were two of you.
Can't we just teleport in?
It's not a teleport, it's a time-jump.
We can't jump
within the same time-stream.
Yes.
The Tardis is in the gallery.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Gallery closed.
The controls are stuck.
They've locked them from the outside.
Can you unlock them?
Yeah, give me a minute
and your cutest smile.
That's the one.
Can you stop flirting with me?
-You're old enough to be my...
-I've known you my whole life.
How many games of doctors and nurses?
-Shh.
-Don't get coy now.
-Um...
-(BANGING)
HANDBOT: Do not be alarmed.
This is a kindness.
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
(GRUNTING)
-Come on!
-Go!
I've got your back.
(SCREAMS)
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
No.
(SHOUTING)
DOCTOR: It's okay, Rory. Here.
Ah, it's just an an aesthetic.
She'll be fine.
I'm sorry.
-What are you doing?
-I lied to her, Rory.
-FUTURE AMY: Doctor!
-There can never be
two Amys in the Tardis.
The paradox would be too massive.
You can't leave her, she'll die!
-Doctor, let me in.
-No. She'll never have existed.
When we save our Amy,
this future won't have happened.
-She happened. She's there!
-FUTURE AMY: Doctor, please!
I trusted you!
-No, she's not real.
-She is real. Let her in.
Look, if we take this Amy,
we leave ours.
There can only be one Amy in the Tardis.
Which one do you want?
It's your choice.
This isn't fair.
You're turning me into you.
-Your choice, Rory.
-(STUTTERS) I...
(FUTURE AMY BANGS ON DOOR)
FUTURE AMY: Doctor! Doctor!
Doctor! Doctor!
Rory, please.
The look on your face
when you carried her...
me,
her,
when you carried her away,
you used to look at me like that.
I'd forgotten how much you loved me.
I'd forgotten
how much I love being her,
the Amy Pond in the Tardis
with Rory Williams.
(SOBBING)
I'm sorry. I can't deal with this.
If you love me, don't let me in.
Open that door, I will.
I will come in. I don't want to die.
I won't bow out bravely.
I'll be kicking, screaming, fighting
to the end.
Amy.
-Amy, I love you.
-I love you, too.
(SNIFFLES)
Don't let me in.
Tell Amy,
your Amy, I'm giving her the days.
The days with you.
Days to come.
I'm so, so sorry.
The days I can't have.
Take them, please.
-I'm giving you my days.
-I'm so, so sorry.
(HANDBOTS APPROACHING)
HANDBOT: Do not be alarmed.
This is a kindness.
Do not be alarmed. This is a kindness.
Interface?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
I am here, Amy Pond.
Show me Earth.
Show me home.
Did I ever tell you about this boy
I met there
who pretended to be in a band?
(HANDBOTS APPROACHING)
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Did you always know it would never work,
saving both Amys?
I promised you I'd save her,
and there she is.
Safe.
Yeah,
there she is.
I'll leave you two alone.
-You all right?
-Mmm-hmm.
-How are you feeling?
-Where is she?
The rooms have things in them.
(SCREAMS)
There's a room here
for everyone, Doctor,
even you.
We're going to catch ourselves
a monster.
Here comes the candle
to light you to bed.
Here comes the chopper
to chop off your head.
Chop!