(SNORING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Incoming salvage.
Please validate.
Incoming salvage. Please validate.
-Incoming salvage. Please validate.
-(SIGHS)
Rusty garbage.
It's not worth lacing up my boots.
Wasting our time.
There's no salvage this far out.
You're a lucky boy, Tricky.
You're an android.
You don't get bored.
He won't turn back.
Not with half a cargo.
He's not captain. We're equal partners.
Yeah. Right.
-You said...
-I know what I said.
I was the one who said it.
You said it was looking at you funny.
I was tired. Overwrought.
I didn't mean it.
It's an appliance, it does a job.
Yes, pretty cool appliance.
We're not talking cheese grater here.
You're not getting me to talk
to your ship, that's properly bonkers.
(WHISPERS) It's okay, it's okay.
Oh, you're like one of those guys
who can't go out with a girl
unless his mother approves.
It's important to me you get along.
I can leave you two alone together.
Now you're creeping me out.
Take the wheel. Not the wheel.
I'll make it easy.
Shut it down to basic mode for you.
Basic?
-'Cause I'm a girl?
-No.
Everyone suit up. It's good salvage.
-I can smell it.
-It's just trash.
No, look. There's something tasty
in the Magoo field.
(BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Magoo-Grab ready.
Engaging.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Move yourself!
(TARDIS POWERING DOWN)
What have I done?
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Uh... Okay.
(BEEPING)
Doctor?
The electrical impulses are jammed.
I can't get the shields back up.
(GRUNTS) She's completely vulnerable.
I swear, I just touched it.
Magnetic Hubble field!
We're flying right into it.
Clara! Stay by me!
Please tell me there's a button
you can press to fix this.
Oh, yes. Big friendly button.
-You're lying.
-Yeah.
To stop me freaking out?
-Is it working?
-Not so much!
Ow!
(SCREAMS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
What is it?
-Some kind of escape pod?
-Come on.
Crack it open.
(GRUNTING)
It's doing nothing.
Use a thermo charge and blast it.
No, no, no! Wait!
It's like, it's alive. She's...
(WARBLING)
She's... She's suffering.
-I can feel it, I can feel it!
-It's just a robot, Bram.
No, Gregor, he's right.
Looks like there's a broken fuel line.
All right. All right, throw it back.
No salvage today, boys.
Open the bay doors.
Wait.
TRICKY: Somebody's under that thing.
The crew was still aboard
when we dragged her in.
We did nothing. If anyone asks, right,
the ship was already busted.
You got that?
And you, make sure you keep
your oily mouth shut. All right?
It's rude to whisper.
Hi. I'm The Doctor. And you are...
Van Baalen and...
Van Baalen.
Van Baalen and Van Baalen.
That's going to get confusing later.
We found you drifting.
Yeah, your ship was
junked up pretty bad.
What broke my ship was a Magoo-Grab.
I found this remote in your pocket. Eh?
What are the chances?
Outlawed in most galaxies,
this little beasty
can disable whole vessels.
Unless you have shield oscillators,
which I turned off so Clara could fly.
Dammit!
Clara! Where is she?
A girl about so high, feisty.
She's still on board.
No, wait! Your pod is leaking fuel.
If she's still in there, she's dead.
Oh.
Ah. Respirators.
We can open the doors for a split
second, reach in and grab her.
Trust me, we can't.
Now, please. Help me get her out.
-I'm telling you, she...
-Shut it, tin mouth!
What sort of fee are we talking?
If you help me get her out,
you get the machine, all the scrap.
-Eh?
-It's not worth the risk.
Four feet of metal? No.
What if I can guarantee you
the best haul you've ever had?
Bram, open the bay doors.
No, no, please, stop. Listen, listen.
Right behind those doors
is the salvage of a lifetime.
Doctor?
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BLOWING)
(ALARM BEEPING)
Red flashing light.
Means something bad.
"Get out of here fast"?
Or possibly "whatever you do,
don't open this door".
Bad decision.
(SNARLING)
Hey, are we really going to risk it?
That thing is spewing poison.
Should blow it back into space.
-Get your gear.
-Hey.
I don't take orders from my kid brother.
Don't try and form sentences, all right?
Stick to what you do best.
Tell me, since when does an android
need a blast suit and a respirator?
Flesh coating.
Same as us, he'd burn up.
No fear, no heat, no pain.
Salvage of a lifetime?
I feel pretty confident
I can deliver on that.
Here we go!
I don't get it.
Thought she was lying on her side.
The Tardis is special.
She has her own gravity.
I'd explain if I had some charts
and a board pen.
It's, it's...
-It's bigger.
-On the inside.
You know, I get that a lot.
Whoa! Awesome.
Well put. "Whoa" and "awesome".
Safe to breathe.
Okay, now,
the last thing I remember,
you were right here.
Come on, Clara. Talk to me.
How big is this baby?
Picture the biggest ship
you've ever seen.
-Are you picturing it?
-Yeah.
Good. Now forget it,
because this ship is infinite.
Take you hours to find the girl.
Days. Plus this whole place is toxic.
She'd be dead by the time I reach her.
So, here's the mission.
We're going to find her in one hour.
-We?
-You're my guys for this.
-That wasn't the deal.
-It is now.
What makes you think we'll help?
I just activated
the Tardis self-destruct system.
One hour until this ship blows.
Don't try to leave.
The Tardis is in lockdown.
I'll open those doors
when Clara's by my side.
You crazy lunatic!
My ship! My rules!
You'll kill us all. And the girl.
She's going to die
if you don't help me.
Don't get into a spaceship
with a madman.
Didn't anyone ever teach you that?
Okay. A little gentle persuasion.
Say 30 minutes.
We'll die even quicker now!
We all perform better under pressure.
-Anybody want to go for 15 minutes?
-ALL: Whoa!
It's your own time you're wasting.
Salvage of a lifetime.
You meant the ship,
I meant Clara.
(CREATURE GROWLING, CLARA GASPS)
Report.
What's on board this thing?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Dynamorphic generators.
Conceptual geometer.
Beam synthesiser.
Orthogonal engine filters.
Guys, guys, look.
I think we should split up.
It's our best chance
of finding the girl.
You know it is.
Don't touch a thing.
The Tardis will get huffy if you mess.
Keep in radio contact, all right?
Get back to the console. Strip it apart.
-Okay.
-All right?
(GROWLING)
(CREATURE SNARLING)
Now, that's just showing off.
(GRUNTING)
(PREVIOUS DOCTOR AND COMPANION
VOICES OVERLAPPING)
WOMAN: ...Time And Relative Dimension
In Space.
THIRD DOCTOR:
Dimensionally transcendental.
(OVERLAPPING VOICES CONTINUE)
NINTH DOCTOR:
The assembled hordes of Genghis Khan
couldn't get through that door.
Believe me, they've tried.
AMY: We are in space!
(OVERLAPPING VOICES CONTINUE,
INDISTINCT)
(SENSOR BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Everything.
What? Report.
Everything behind that door.
-Everything?
-Sensor detects
everything you could possibly want.
Everything.
I don't understand. Give me a price tag.
Incalculable.
What?
More valuable than
the total sum of any currency.
Living metal. Bespoke engineering.
Whatever machine you require,
this system will build it.
(GASPS)
No! No, no, stop. Please.
Don't... Don't touch it.
Please. She won't let you touch it.
I can feel a Tardis tantrum coming on.
What the hell is this place?
Architectural reconfiguration system.
It reconstructs particles
according to your needs.
A machine that makes machines?
Yes. Basically.
What are you doing?
No, no. Don't, don't!
If you walk out of here
with that circuit,
the Tardis will try to stop you.
Now, listen to me.
Look, the clock is ticking.
We must find Clara.
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE BLARING)
What the...
Where's the door gone?
Ever seen a spaceship get ugly?
This isn't happening.
DOCTOR: She won't relinquish it.
Her basic genetic material.
Torch it.
I said torch it.
Can't you feel it, Gregor? The ship...
The ship's in torment.
Like it's a living thing.
You can't hurt it.
What's the matter, Tardis?
Scared to fight me?
So that's who...
(DOOR CLANGS, CREATURE GROWLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(VOICES ECHOING, MUFFLED AND INDISTINCT)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(OVERLAPPING VOICES, INDISTINCT)
(LOW GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
It's the same. It's just the same.
It's diverting us.
Spinning a maze around us.
We will never reach Clara in time.
Hey! Hey!
It's just the same, again.
No point in building walls,
you'll just know how to smash them down.
It's found other ways
of controlling you.
Smart bunch, Time Lords.
No dress sense,
dreadful hats, but smart.
If you want to get out of here,
let that circuit go.
It is creating a labyrinth.
Bram. Bram, can you hear me?
TRICKY: Bram, the ship is alive.
Get out of there.
Bram, don't touch anything.
You're just the sweetest thing ever.
Oh, thank you. (LAUGHS)
Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you!
(LAUGHING)
Oh!
No.
The door.
Where has the door gone now?
You can't do this!
Bram, you've got to get out of there.
Come on.
(SPARKING)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
(GROWLING)
(COUGHING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING)
(BRAM SCREAMING)
-Channel's dead.
-You've got to help him.
Gregor, do something. Do something!
It's too late. He's gone.
Just worry about the salvage.
You care more about a circuit
than you do about him.
Your concern for your brother
is really touching.
The android is more cut up
about it than you are.
Now, will you two
stop bickering and listen!
There is something else down there.
(CREATURE HISSING)
We've got to get out of here.
Gregor, give it back.
-Give it back to her.
-What are you doing?
You're always on the side
of the machines.
Fellas!
Multiple life forms on board the Tardis
with us, I am getting a massive signal.
-Where are they?
-You're not going to like the answer.
-(WHISPERS) About two steps away.
-(GROWLING)
One step.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Tricky! Look out! Careful!
Gregor! No!
We have to stay together! Come on, go!
Tricky! Come on!
I'm sorry.
Oh, why are you doing this?
Back where we started?
No.
It's an echo.
The console room.
It's the safest place on the ship.
It could replicate itself
any number of times.
It's trying to protect us.
Because I tried to give back
the circuit?
Team Tardis.
Where did... Where did that go?
There's more than one echo room.
Hey, look. Look!
The Tardis has got Clara safe.
That was her. That was her there.
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
But why... Why can't we see her?
Well, it's like a light switch.
Two positions.
(MIMICKING SWITCHES CLICKING)
Flickering at super infinite speeds.
We're only together for a brief second.
(SWITCH FLICKS, CLARA GASPS)
Shh.
(CLARA PANTING)
I can hear her.
(CREATURE SNARLING, CLARA GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
She's let it in. She's let it in!
(CREATURE GROWLING)
Ah. If I can just isolate her position,
I could match your connection,
reach in and grab her.
What are you?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Console room.
Echo imprint of the original.
You're coming with me.
I need you to get me out of here.
-(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
-Scanning for female human.
Scanning for female human.
Unidentified human.
-It doesn't know Lancashire.
-What?
It doesn't know sass.
Yes! It's found Clara!
-It's found her. She is right there.
- (CLARA SCREAMING)
(CREATURE SNARLING)
It's okay. Clara, I'm so, so sorry.
Sorry. Please, please forgive me, Clara.
Ow! Okay. So we're not doing hugging.
I get that now.
What do you keep in here?
Why have you got zombie creatures?
Good guys do not have zombie creatures.
-Rule one, basic storytelling!
-Not in front of the guests.
-Who are they?
-Friends.
Well, people who aren't
trying to kill us.
I don't need punching again.
All right, all right. Look,
a deal's a deal. You got the girl back.
-Now, cancel the self-destruct.
-Ah! Ah.
Ha! You know, I've got to tell you,
-I won't be needing you in my quiz team.
-What?
There is no self-destruct.
Hey? Hey? Hey?
Had you going, though, boys, didn't I?
I just wiggled a few buttons.
Yeah, the old wiggly button trick.
And the face. You've got to do the face.
"Save her or we all die."
-I thought I rushed it a bit but...
-So, you're telling us we're safe?
Ish, apart from the monsters
and the Tardis reinventing
the architecture every five minutes.
Guys, don't worry.
The countdown's a fake.
Look, just give me a second,
I'll turn it off.
I only made it look as though the engine
was actually exploding.
(ALARM BLARING)
Ah. Okay, that's not good.
Okay, don't panic. Well, maybe panic.
Something you want to share
with the rest of us?
It appears the engine is damaged.
We're in trouble, Clara. Proper trouble.
It needs fixing or we're toast.
So, now would be a good time
to use that big friendly button, right?
Yes. Sorry, I should have
had one built in.
-TRICKY: Where are we going?
-Detour.
The centre of the Tardis.
-(CREATURE SNARLING)
-Shh.
Something's in here.
Those things, they followed us.
Doctor, what are they?
What aren't you telling me?
Trust me,
some things you don't want to know.
(SNARLING)
They're on the move again.
Run! Move! Move!
(SNARLING)
Doctor?
Doctor!
Again!
(SIZZLING)
CLARA: I know what I said.
I was the one who said it.
DOCTOR: You said it was
looking at you funny.
Now you're creeping me out.
Please tell me there is a button
you can press to fix this?
(GASPS) Oh, thank God.
Doctor?
What's going on?
Say something.
Clara, stop.
Don't touch it.
There's a rupture in time
somewhere on board this ship,
a small tear
in the fabric of the continuum.
It must have happened when the Tardis
was pulled in by the salvage vessel.
-The Tardis is leaking.
-Leaking what?
The past. You and me.
Everything we've done,
everything we've said.
Recent history.
It's not real. It's a memory.
What about this?
If you're giving me the option,
I'd say this one's real.
(GROWLING)
-She's right onto us.
-She?
Clara, don't ask me any more.
CLARA: You're like one of those guys
who can't go out with a girl
unless his mother approves.
DOCTOR: It's important to me
you get along.
I can leave you two alone together.
(CLANGING)
-What's that noise?
-(CREAKING)
We're right under the primary fuel cell.
So... So what?
So... So...
Well, the fuel's spilled out.
So the rods will be exposed.
-Means they'll cool and...
-And start to warp.
-And start to warp, maybe even...
-No, you don't say it.
-Mmm.
-Don't you dare say it.
Maybe even...break apart.
-Run?
-I'm liking how you're thinking.
(MAN SCREAMING)
No, cut it off. Just cut my arm off.
-No!
-It's the quickest way to release me.
No fear. No, hate, no...no pain.
I can get a new one. Disposable part.
Just do it.
It won't hurt me.
-Tricky, you don't understand.
-I'm an android, cut me!
You made it through.
What's the matter with you?
Why won't you cut me?
(GROANING)
Tell him.
Tell me what?
You can't, can you?
You're a coward.
You won't save him
but you're scared to tell him why.
What's he going on about?
Robots don't need blast suits,
they don't need respirators.
They don't get frightened
of monsters in the dark.
What's he talking about?
Two bionic eyes
and a synthetic voice box.
But you, my friend, are human.
Flesh and blood.
-It was a joke.
-What?
It was just a stupid joke.
-We did it to relieve the boredom.
-Well, it was very funny.
They lied to you.
Changed your identity, just to provide
some in-flight entertainment.
I'm sorry.
-(GROANS)
-You're human, Tricky.
Cut the metal.
-Cut the metal! Go!
-(TRICKY GROANING)
GREGOR: Where are we?
Power source.
Right. You lot wait here,
I'll check it's safe. We can only
survive for a minute or two in there.
Um, what happens if we stay longer?
Our cells will liquefy
and our skin will start to burn.
I always feel so good
after we've spoken.
-Marvellous. Keep this door shut.
-That will not be a problem.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Lancashire. Sass.
Intelligent sensor.
Ever pointed that thing at
yourself, Gregor? What would it see?
What sort of person
does this to another human?
Made them believe
they're made of metal.
Who am I?
(GROANING)
My mouthy little kid brother.
Why... Why don't I remember?
It was a salvage accident.
Big explosion.
You lost your sight, voice
and your memory.
And you... You thought of a way
you could have some fun with me.
I just wanted a brother beside me.
You were always the smart one, Tricky.
He wanted you to take over.
He made you Captain.
He?
Dad.
I don't... I don't remember him.
You did this to me
just to be captain of a...
of a heap of junk?
-CLARA: Stop!
-Tricky? Listen to me.
Ask yourself why he couldn't cut you up.
He has just one tiny scrap
of decency left in him
and you helped him find that. Okay?
Now, you... Don't ever forget this.
Okay! Move, move, move!
The Eye of Harmony.
Exploding star, in the act
of becoming a black hole.
Time Lord engineering.
You rip the star from its orbit,
suspend it
in a permanent state of decay.
This way, quickly!
(GROWLING)
There's no way out, we're trapped.
You're going to tell me right now!
If we're going to die here
you're going to tell me what they are.
-I can't.
-Tell me.
What's the use of secrets now?
Secrets protect us.
Secrets make us safe.
We're not safe!
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Sensor detects animal DNA.
Human core element.
Calculating data. Calculating data.
No, no, turn it off!
Lancashire. Sass.
Identifiable substance.
Clara.
-That's me.
-I'm so sorry.
That's me. I burn in here.
It isn't just the past leaking out
through the time rift.
It's the future.
Listen. I brought you here
to keep you safe but it happened again.
You died again.
What do you mean, again?
(SIGHS)
(SNARLING)
Hang on.
As long as we interrupt the time line,
this can't happen.
Don't touch each other. Otherwise,
the future will reassert itself.
Gregor!
Gregor, let go of the circuit.
-Just let it go!
-Gregor!
Gregor!
DOCTOR: Come on.
Okay.
Uh... Okay.
(GROANING)
Tricky!
No! Don't touch him
or time will reassert itself!
(BOTH GROANING)
The engine room.
The heart of the Tardis.
(SCREAMS) We're outside.
No. We're still in the Tardis.
-There's no way across.
-No, okay. You're right.
So, what do we do? Time for a plan.
Do you have a plan?
Well...no. No plan, sorry.
-If you don't have a plan, we're dead.
-Yes, we are.
-So, just tell me.
-Tell you what?
Well, there's no point now.
We're about to die.
Just tell me who you are.
-You know who I am.
-No, I don't.
I look at you every single day and I
don't understand a thing about you.
Why do I keep running into you?
-Doctor, you invited me. You said...
-Before that.
I met you at the Dalek asylum.
There was a girl in a shipwreck
and she died saving my life
and she was you.
She really wasn't.
Victorian London. There was a governess
who was really a barmaid
and we fought
the Great Intelligence together.
She died and it was my fault.
And she was you!
-You're scaring me.
-What are you, eh?
-A trick? A trap?
-I don't know what you're talking about!
You really don't, do you?
I think I'm more scared
of you right now
than anything else on that Tardis.
You're just Clara, aren't you?
Eh? Huh? (CHUCKLING)
Oh!
Okay. I don't know what the hell this
is about but the hug is really nice.
We're not going to die here.
This isn't real.
-It's a snarl.
-What?
What does a wounded animal do?
It tries to scare everyone away.
We're close to the engine.
The Tardis is snarling at us,
trying to frighten us off.
We need to jump.
-You're insane.
-We'll cross the portal to the engine.
-How can you be so sure?
-Well, I can't.
Okay, then, well, that's watertight.
Hey, now, Clara.
I have piloted this ship
for over 900 years.
Trust me this one time, please.
Okay. Okay.
As well as all the other times.
Ready?
Geronimo.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
The heart of the Tardis.
The engine.
It's already exploded. It must have been
the collision with the salvage ship.
CLARA: We're not dead.
She wrapped her hands around the force.
-Froze it.
-So...
So it's safe.
Temporary fix.
Eventually, this whole place will erupt.
There's no way I can save her now.
She's just always been there for me
and taken care of me
and now it's my turn
and I don't know what to do.
(STUTTERING) It just...
Oh, Clara.
Oh.
-You are beautiful.
-(CLARA CHUCKLES)
Beautiful, fragile, human skin.
Like parchment, thank you.
The rift in time,
all the memory's leaking out.
I need to find the moment we crashed.
I need to find...
the music.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
The time rift!
Recent past, possible future.
-What are you going to do?
-Rewrite today, I hope.
I've thrown this through
the rift before.
I need to make sure this time,
going to take it in there myself.
There might be
a certain amount of yelling.
It's going to hurt?
Things that end your life often do that.
Wait!
All those things you said.
How we've met before, how I died...
Clara, don't worry.
You'll forget. Time mends us.
It can mend anything.
I don't want to forget. Not all of it.
The library. I saw it.
You were mentioned in a book.
I'm mentioned in a lot of books.
You call yourself Doctor.
Why do you do that?
You have a name. I've seen it
in one corner of that tiny...
If I rewrite today, you won't remember.
You won't go looking
for my name.
-We'll still have secrets?
-Uh-huh. It's better that way.
Whoo!
(SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Magnetic Hubble field!
We're flying right into it.
Clara! Stay by me!
Please tell me there's a button
you can press to fix this.
Oh, yes. Big friendly button.
-You're lying.
-Yeah.
-To stop me freaking out?
-Oh, is it working?
-Not so much!
-(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
Doctor. Doctor.
I'm from your future.
We haven't got long. This'll reset time.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
Clara! No! No!
(CHUCKLING) Big friendly button.
I don't get it.
It was on-screen, then it was gone.
BRAM: Hey, robot!
Go get me some food.
I'm starving.
Oi. Leave him alone.
What's the matter with you?
Maybe I've just got
a little tiny scrap of decency.
(SCOFFS)
I feel exhausted. I feel...
We've had two days
crammed into the space of one.
-Why would you say that?
-I don't know. I say stuff.
Ignore me.
Do you feel safe?
Of course.
Give me a number out of 10,
10 being "whoo-hoo!”, one being...
-"ahhh!"
-You're being weird.
I need to know if you feel safe.
I need to know...
-you're not afraid.
-Of?
The future.
Running away with a spaceman in a box.
Anything could happen to you.
That's what I'm counting on.
Push the button.
We are going to the North.
Sweetville. An ideal community
for happy, prosperous workers.
No one who ever goes to live there
ever seems to come out.
I suspect all is not quite as it seems.
Time for a plan.
You do seem to keep turning up
like a bad penny, young man.
The Crimson Horror.
That's what they're calling it.
My plans must be accelerated.
Mrs Gillyflower, we've got to stop her.
In the wrong hands, that venom
could wipe out all life on this planet.