(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING ON PA)
(WOMEN SPEAKING OVER RADIO, INDISTINCT)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
(HYSTERICAL LAUGHTER ECHOES)
My name is Lucy Hayward
and I'm the last one left.
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
It's funny. You don't know what's going
to be in your room until you see |It.
Then you realise it could never
have been anything else.
(WATER RUNNING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
The gaps between my worship
are getting shorter.
This is what happened to the others.
(MONSTER GROWLING)
-Praise him.
-MALE VOICE: (WHISPERING) Praise him.
LUCY: It's all so clear now.
I'm so happy. Praise him.
Praise him.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MONSTER GROWLING)
Praise him.
MALE VOICE: Praise him.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
"Let's go to Ravenscala,” he says.
"The people are 600 feet tall,
"you have to talk to them
in hot-air balloons,
"and the tourist information centre is
made of one of their hats," he says.
I'm sorry, but I don't
see any huge hats.
Amy, Beaky, this could be the most
exciting thing I have ever seen.
You're kidding.
How could he be excited about a
rubbish hotel on a rubbish bit of Earth?
Because, oh simple Pond,
this is not Earth.
This has just been made to
look like Earth.
The craftsmanship involved.
Can you imagine?
AMY: What? Then where are we?
I don't know. Something must have
yanked us off course.
Look at that detail on that
cheese plant.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
RORY: Right, but who would
mock up an Earth hotel?
Colonists, maybe.
Recreating a bit of home.
Like when ex-pats open
English pubs in Mallorca.
No,
whoever did this,
I'm shaking his/her hand/tentacle.
Have you seen these?
Look at the labels underneath.
"Commander Halke. Defeat."
"Tim Heath. Having his photo taken."”
"Lady Silvertier. Daleks."
"Bruce Barnes. Other people's socks."
"Tim Nelson. Balloons."
"Nevis Prion. Sabre wolves."
"Royston Le Gould. Plymouth."
"Lucy Hayward.
"That brutal gorilla.”
Doctor, what does it mean?
I don't know, let's find out.
(SCREAMING)
-Whoa!
-Well, that was quick.
-We surrender!
-No, it's okay, we're not...
-We surrender.
-We're nice!
She's threatening me with a chair leg.
-Who are you?
-Oh God, we're back in reception.
-We surrender!
-I've never been threatened
with a chair leg before.
No, hang on, I tell a lie.
Did you just say,
"It's okay, we're nice"?
Okay, I need everyone to shut up now!
Uh, Rita, be careful, yeah?
Their pupils are dilated.
They are as surprised as we are.
Besides which, if it's a trick,
it'll tell us something.
Oh, you're good.
Oh, she's good.
Amy, with regret, you're fired.
-What?
-I'm kidding.
(MOUTHING) We'll talk.
I take it from the pathological
compulsion to surrender
you're from Tivoli?
Yes, the most invaded
planet in the galaxy.
Our anthem is called
Glory To "Insert Name Here".
You with the face,
Howie, you said you were surprised
to be back in reception.
The walls move, everything changes.
You, clever one,
what's he talking about?
The corridors twist and stretch.
Rooms vanish and pop up somewhere else.
-(CHEERFUL INSTRUMENTAL PLAYING)
-It's like the hotel's alive.
-(MUSIC CLICKS OFF)
-That's quite enough of that.
Yeah, and it's huge.
-With, like, no way out.
-Have you tried the front door?
No, in two days it never occurred
to us to try the front door.
Thank God you're here.
(LAUGHING)
They're not doors, they're walls.
Walls that look like doors.
Doorwalls, if you like, or dwalls.
Wdoors, even.
Though you probably got it
when you said they're not doors.
I mean, the windows are...
Right, big day for a fan of walls.
It's not just that. The rooms have...
things in them.
Things? Hello! What kind of things?
Interesting things?
I love things. Ask anyone.
Bad dreams.
Well, that killed the mood.
How did you get here?
I don't know. I just started my shift.
I must have passed out,
because suddenly I was here.
Look, I was, er, blogging,
next thing this.
Oh, well, I was at work,
I'm in town planning.
We're lining all the highways with trees
so invading forces
can march in the shade.
-DOCTOR: Oh.
-Which is nice for them.
DOCTOR: Yeah.
So what have we got?
People being snatched from their lives
and dropped into an endless shifting
maze that looks like a 1980s hotel
with bad dreams in the bedrooms.
Apart from anything else,
that's just rude.
We'll pop back to the Tardis,
I'll do a planet-wide diagnostic sweep,
then we'll have a sing-song.
Where's the Tardis?
You parked it there, didn't you?
What's a Tardis?
Our way out. And it's gone.
(TAPE BEGINS PLAYING)
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING ON PA)
Okay.
This is bad. At the moment,
I don't know how bad
but certainly we're three buses, a long
walk and eight quid in a taxi from good.
Are there any more of you?
Joe, but he's, uh, tied up right now.
Doing what?
No, I mean, he's tied up right now.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(WOOD CREAKS, LAUGHTER STOPS)
Hello.
I'm the Doctor.
We're going to die here.
Well, they certainly didn't
mention that in the brochure.
Is Joe there? Can I have a quick word?
Oh, it's still me, Doctor.
But I've seen the light.
I lived a blasphemous life
but he has forgiven my inconstancy
and soon, he shall feast.
Well, you've been here for two days,
what's he waiting for?
We weren't ready.
We were still raw.
But now you're what?
-Cooked?
-If you like.
Soon you will be, too.
Be patient. First, find your room.
My room?
There's a room here
for everyone, Doctor.
Even you.
-You said you'd seen the light now.
-Nothing else matters any more.
Only him.
It's like these things. I used to hate
them. They make me laugh now.
(LAUGHS HYSTERICALLY)
Gottle o' geer, gottle o' geer!
(ALL LAUGHING)
You should go.
He'll be here soon.
I think you should come with me.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON PA)
Why you four?
That's what I don't understand.
Aside from all the other things
I don't understand.
What does it matter?
Sooner or later, someone will come along
and rescue us.
Or enslave us.
First, we find the Tardis.
Quick thing before we go, if you feel
drawn to a particular room,
do not go in and make sure someone else
can see you at all times.
Joe said, "He will feast."
Is there something here with us?
(JOE LAUGHING)
Something to add, Joe?
"Here comes a candle
to light you to bed
"Here comes a chopper
to chop off your head
"Chop chop chop chop.”
Can we do something about him?
Personally, I think
you've got the right idea.
At times like this
I think of my old school motto,
"Resistance is exhausting”.
I've worked out where we are.
-Hmm?
-Norway!
-Norway?
-See, the US government
has entire cities hidden
in the Norwegian mountains.
See, Earth is on a collision course
with this other planet.
And this is where they're going to send
all the rich people when it kicks off.
-Amazing.
-It's all there on the internet.
No, it's amazing you've come up
with a theory even more insane
than what's actually happening.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Hello.
You've forgotten your PE kit again?
Right, that's it.
You're doing it in your pants.
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
Hey, don't...
(ALL CHATTING AND GIGGLING)
Oh look, girls. It's H-H-Howie!
(ALL GIGGLING)
(SCREAMING AND LAUGHING)
What's loser in K-K-K-Klingon?
-(STUTTERING)
-MALE VOICE: Praise him.
Shut the-the-the door!
This is just some messed-up CIA stuff.
I'm telling you...
You're right. Keep telling yourself
that. It's a CIA thing. Nothing more.
(GROWLING)
Uh, guys...
Look.
(MONSTER GROWLING FIERCELY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Well, whatever that is,
it's not real, yeah?
No, no. I'm sure it isn't. But just in
case, let's run away and hide anyway.
In there!
No, this way!
I found a...
A B in Mathematics?
You are lazy.
Do you understand me, girl? Lazy.
I'm sorry. Daddy, I'm so sorry.
-(SCREAMING AND LAUGHING)
-(FEMALE VOICE) Praise him.
-Rory, come on! Come on!
-It was a...
(EXCLAIMS)
Don't blink.
What?
DOCTOR: Amy, get back!
Why haven't they got us yet?
-Amy, they're not real.
-What?
They should have got us by now.
Amy, look at me. Focus on me.
It's your bad dream, that's all.
-I don't even think they're for us.
-(THUDDING FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MONSTER ROARING)
Hide!
(MONSTER GROWLING)
Doctor, what are you doing?
It's all right, I just have to see what
it is. I've just, I have to see.
(GROWLING, FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Oh, look at you!
You are beautiful.
(MONSTER GROWLING)
Oh, dear.
I think it's going after joe.
Come on, come to me. Come to me.
(SCREAMING AND LAUGHING)
Praise him.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(GROWLING)
Leave him alone!
Joe!
Joe?
Joe, what happened?
(MONSTER GROWLING)
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
HOWIE: If we can wedge a chair
under the doorknob,
that should stop anything
from getting in.
RITA: Help yourself to tea.
Guys, tea over here.
If it's any consolation,
I've met the Weeping Angels.
So I know how...
In fact, I thought that room was for me.
Joe was right.
Whatever it is in here,
it actually wants to kill us.
Not oppress us or enslave us, kill us!
Listen,
the Doctor's been part of
my life for so long now
and he's never let me down.
Even when I thought he had when
I was a...a kid and he left me,
he came back.
He saved me. (LAUGHS)
And now he's going to save you.
But don't tell him I said that because
the smugness would be terrifying.
Of course, if the Weeping Angels
were meant for me,
then your room is still out there,
somewhere.
Every time the Doctor gets pally with
someone, I have this overwhelming urge
to notify their next of kin.
(STARTLED REACTION)
Sorry, last time I said something
like that, you hit me with your shoe.
I think you literally had to sit down
and unlace it first.
(LAUGHING)
What exactly happened to him?
He died.
You are a medical doctor, aren't you?
You haven't just got a degree in
cheese-making or something...
No. Well, yes. Both, actually.
I mean, there is no cause.
All his vital organs simply stopped
as if the simple spark of life,
his loves and hates,
his faiths and fears were just...
(SNIFFING) ...taken.
And this is a cup of tea.
Of course, I'm British.
It's how we cope with trauma.
-Oh.
-That and tutting.
But how did you make it?
All hotels should have a well-stocked
kitchen. Even alien fake ones.
I heard you talking when you arrived.
Look, it's no more ridiculous
than Howie's CIA theory or mine.
Which is?
This is Jahannam.
You're a Muslim!
Don't be frightened.
You think this is Hell?
The whole '80s hotel thing
took me by surprise, though.
Ah. And all these fears and phobias
wandering about, most are
completely unconnected to us.
So why are they still here?
(SIGHS) Maybe the cleaners have
gone on strike?
(CHUCKLES)
I like you, you're a right clever clogs.
But this isn't Hell, Rita.
You don't understand.
I say that without fear.
Jahannam will play its tricks and there
will be times I want to run and scream,
but I've tried to live a good life
and that knowledge keeps me sane,
despite the monsters
and the bonkers rooms.
- (GARGLES)
-Gibbis...
-is an alien, isn't he?
-Yeah.
-Sorry.
-Okay. I'm going to file that under
-"freak out about later".
-AMY: Doctor, look at this.
I found it in a corridor.
I completely forgot I had it.
"My name is Lucy Hayward
and I'm the last one left.
"It took Luke first.
"It got him on his first day,
almost as soon as we arrived."
"You don't know what's going
to be in your room until you see it.
"Then you realise it could never
have been anything else.
"I just saw mine, it was a gorilla
from a book I'd read as a kid.
"My God, that thing used to terrify me.
"The gaps between my worships
are getting shorter, like contractions.
"This is what happened to the others.
"And how lucky they were.
"It's all so clear now.
"I'm so happy.”
-LUCY: Praise him.
-"Praise him."
Praise him.
What did you just say?
Nothing.
-Praise him!
-This is what happened to Joe.
Oh, God. It's going to come for me now.
-No, it won't.
-(ALL SPEAKING AT ONCE)
I won't leave you. I promise.
You have my word on it.
-I don't want to get eaten.
-AMY: Howie, calm down.
He's gonna lead the monster right here!
-Howie!
-(LOUD WHIRRING)
Don't you see?
You'll lead him right here.
What do you suggest?
Look, whatever it is out there,
it's obviously chosen Howard
as its next course.
Now, tragic though that is,
this is no time for sentiment.
I'm saying if it were to find him,
it may be satisfied
and let the rest of us go.
(SIGHS) AILI want to do is go home
and be conquered and oppressed.
Is that too much to ask?
It's okay. I'll stay with Howie.
You take the others and go.
No. We stay together.
Your civilisation is
one of the oldest in the galaxy.
Now I see why.
Your cowardice isn't quaint,
it's sly, aggressive.
It's how that dune of gutlessness
has survived
while so many others have perished.
Well, not today.
No one else dies today.
Right?
(MUTTERING)
Brilliant.
Howie, any second now,
it's going to possess you again.
When it does, I'm going to ask you some
questions. Please try to answer them.
I hope my mum's all right.
She's going to be worried.
DOCTOR: Howie?
Howie.
Howie, you're next.
We're all dead jealous.
So, tell us,
how do we get a piece of the action?
-(CHUCKLES)
-Why isn't he possessing all of us?
You guys have got
all these distractions.
All these obstacles.
It'll be so much easier if you just
let it go, you know? Clear the path.
You want it to find you, even though
you know what it's going to do?
Are you kidding?
He's going to kill us all.
How cool is that?
It's as I thought. It feeds on fear.
Everything. The rooms, Lucy's note.
I mean, even the pictures in reception
have been put here to frighten us.
So we have to resist it.
Do whatever you have to.
Cross your fingers. Say a prayer.
Think of a basket of kittens.
But do not give in to the fear.
Okay, but what are we
actually going to do?
We're going to catch ourselves
a monster.
HOWIE: Bring me death.
Bring me glory!
My master, my lord, I'm here.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Come to me.
I'm waiting, here, for you.
He has promised me a glorious death.
Give it to me now.
I want him to know my devotion.
Is he to do with you?
-AMY: How's it going?
-Don't talk to the clown.
HOWIE: Praise him.
Praise him.
Rory, he's in!
HOWIE: Let his name
be the last thing I hear.
Let his breath on my skin
be the last thing I feel.
I was lost in the shadows
but he found me.
His love was a beacon
that led me from darkness to light
and now I am blinded by his majesty.
Humbled by his glory!
-Praise him.
-That's quite enough of that.
(FEEDBACK SCREECHING)
What's going on?
You lied to me.
Calm down, Howie.
This is for your own good.
At least stand where I can see you.
I've been told not to speak to you.
It don't mean you can't listen.
Nothing personal.
(GROWLING)
I just think
we should take things slow.
Get to know each other.
(ROARING)
You take people's most primal fears
and pop it in a room.
Tailor-made hell just for them. Why?
(GROWLING)
Did you say "they take"?
(GROANS)
Ah, what is that word? The...guard?
No, the...the warden.
This is a prison.
You were right, you know.
Chances are, if you hand me over,
he'll leave you alone.
Yeah, but we saw how that idea
got shot down in flames.
It's not like kicking me out of a plane
to lighten the load.
I'm asking you for this.
I'm begging you.
You're possessed. You'd say anything.
Possessed guys can be quite strong.
Who's to say I didn't overpower you?
DOCTOR: So what are we? Cellmates?
Lunch?
(GROWLING)
We are not ripe.
This is what Joe said,
that we weren't ready.
So, what? What? You make us ready?
You, what? Replace?
Replace what? Fear?
You have lived so long,
even your name is lost.
You want this to stop.
Because you are just instinct.
(GROWLING)
Then tell me. Tell me how to fight you.
HOWIE: My master, my lord. I'm here!
-That's Howie.
-He's got out.
Oh! Bring me death.
No, no, no, no!
Rory, watch out!
(EXCLAIMS)
Stay back!
Pond, bring the fish.
The fish? Oh, the fish.
-Where'd he go?
-Somebody hit me.
Was it Amy? (LAUGHS)
Rory, you all right?
We should find the Doctor.
VOICES: (WHISPERING) Praise him.
Praise him. Praise him.
You shouldn't have done that.
-What did you see?
-Nothing.
-Nothing. I don't know. It was weird.
-Come on.
He got free. He overpowered me.
It might leave us alone now.
Maybe now we'll be safe.
Wait!
Have you found your room yet?
No.
Is that good or bad?
Maybe you're not scared of anything.
Well, after all the time I spent
with you in the Tardis,
what was left to be scared of?
You said that in the past tense.
No, I didn't.
You know,
Howie had been in speech therapy.
He'd just got over this massive stammer.
What an achievement.
I mean, can you imagine?
I'd forgotten not all victories
are about saving the universe.
Rita! Brilliant!
How are you? Not panicking, are you?
Good, good.
Because I'm literally an otter's toenail
away from getting us out of here.
-Why?
-Excellent question.
Excellent question.
Why what?
Why is up to you to save us?
That's quite a God complex
you have there.
DOCTOR: I brought them here.
They'd say it was their choice,
but offer a child a suitcase
full of sweets and they'll take it.
Offer someone all of time and space
and they'll take that, too.
Which is why you shouldn't.
Which is why grown-ups were invented.
-All of time and space, eh?
-Oh, yeah.
And when we get out of this,
I'll show you, too.
I don't know what you're talking about,
but whatever it was,
-I have a feeling you just did it again.
-(CHUCKLES)
Right down to the smallest detail.
Got you, Mr Minotaur.
Praise him.
VOICES: (ECHOING) Praise him.
Praise him. Praise him.
(ECHOING CONTINUES)
Of course.
Who else?
Oh, you beauty! Come on, big fella.
Where are you?
Ah. Ahh...
Rita, where are you going?
(PHONE RINGING)
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
(PHONE PICKS UP)
Rita, where are you going?
Can you take the phone
into the corridor? Will it reach?
You started to praise it, didn't you?
Rita, come back, please.
We'll find a way to stop it,
I swear to you.
No, I need to get as far away
from you all as possible.
No, no, no, you don't. The creature
only wants whoever's praising it.
And then you'll put yourself in its way.
I'm coming to get you. Block out the
fear and stay focused on your belief.
The hotel will keep us apart.
I could be 50 miles away by now.
(FAINT GROWLING)
I want you to do me
one last favour, Doctor.
I can feel the rapture approaching
like a wave.
I don't want you to witness this.
I want you to remember me the way I was.
(ROARING)
What's going on? Rita's disappeared.
What is she doing there?
Rita.
Rita, please.
Let me find you.
You stay where you are.
Please, let me be robbed of my faith
in private.
Look, Rita, Rita, go into the room.
Lock the door.
I'm not frightened. I'm blessed, Doctor.
(GROWLING)
I'm at peace.
-I'm going to hang up.
-No, no, no, Rita.
-Goodbye, Doctor.
-Rita!
-Thank you for trying.
-Rita, please! Please!
Please!
(ROARING)
(WHIRRING)
(CRASHING)
(YELLING)
Okay.
He preys on people's fear
and possesses them.
But Rita wasn't afraid.
She was brave and calm.
Maybe it's something to do
with the people,
some connection between the four of you
that will tell me how to fight it.
Yes, you keep saying that,
but you never do.
And while we wait, people keep dying,
and we'll be next!
Look, he'll work it out, he always does.
Just let him riff and move
anything expensive out of his way.
Oh, no.
-Oh, no, no...
-Doctor, what is wrong?
It's not fear.
It's faith.
Not just religious faith.
Faith in something.
Howard believed in conspiracies, that
external forces controlled the world.
Joe had dice cuff links and a chain
with a horseshoe. He was a gambler.
Gamblers believe in luck, an intangible
force that helps them win or lose.
Gibbis has rejected
any personal autonomy, and he's waiting
for the next batch of invaders
to oppress him and tell him what to do.
They all believe there's something
guiding them, about to save them.
That's what it replaces.
Every time someone was confronted
with their most primal fear,
they fell back on
their most fundamental faith.
And all this time,
I have been telling you to dig deep,
find the thing that keeps you brave.
I made you expose your faith.
Showed them what they needed.
But why us? Why are we here?
It doesn't want you. That's why
it kept showing you a way out.
You're not religious or superstitious,
so there's no faith
for you to fall back on.
It wants her.
Me?
-Why?
-Your faith in me.
That's what brought us here.
But why do they lose their faith
before they die?
And start worshipping...it?
It needs to convert the faith
into a form it can consume.
Faith is an energy,
the specific emotional energy
the creature needs to live.
Which is why, at the end of her note,
Lucy said...
-AMY: "Praise him."
-Exactly.
No.
Oh, please, no.
(FOOTSTEPS POUNDING)
(GROWLING)
Amy!
-What are you doing?
-Oh, he's beautiful.
GIBBIS: Leave her. Just leave her!
(GROWLING)
Doctor, it's happening. It's changing
me. It's changing my thoughts.
I can't save you from this.
There's nothing I can do to stop this.
-What?
-I stole your childhood
and now I've led you by the hand
to your death.
But the worst thing is, I knew.
I knew this would happen.
This is what always happens.
Forget your faith in me.
(BELLOWS)
I took you with me because I was vain.
Because I wanted to be adored.
Look at you.
The glorious Pond,
the girl who waited for me.
I'm not a hero.
I really am just a madman in a box.
And it's time we saw each other
as we really are.
Amy Williams...
it's time to stop waiting.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(MONSTER BREATHING HEAVILY)
I severed the food supply,
sacrificing their faith in me.
Gave you the space to die.
(SHUSHING)
What is it? A minotaur or an alien?
Or an alien minotaur?
That's not a question
I thought I'd be asking this morning.
I mean, it's both, actually.
Yeah. Here we go.
A distant cousin of the Nimon.
They descend on planets and set
themselves up as gods to be worshipped,
which is fine until the inhabitants
get all secular
and advanced enough
to build bunkers, prisons.
RORY: Correction.
-Prisons in space.
-AMY: Where are the guards?
No need for any. It's all automated.
It drifts through space,
snatching people with belief systems,
and converts their faith into food
for the creature.
See that planet there?
-Which one?
-The grey one, there.
-Mmm-hmm.
-That's where I'm from.
It didn't want just me.
So, you must believe in some god
or someone
or they'd have shown you the door, too.
So what do Time Lords pray to?
According to the in-flight recorder,
the programme developed glitches.
Got stuck on the same setting.
The fears from the people before us
weren't tidied away.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
AMY: What's it saying?
"An ancient creature,
drenched in the blood
"of the innocent.
"Drifting in space
through an endless shifting maze.
"For such a creature,
"death would be a gift."
Then, accept it.
And sleep well.
(GROWLING)
"I wasn't talking about myself."
GIBBIS: Could I have a lift?
Just to the nearest galaxy will do.
(WHOOSHING)
Don't tell me. This isn't Earth.
That isn't a real house.
Inside lives a goblin
who feeds on indecision.
Nope. Real Earth. Real house.
Real door keys.
-You're not serious.
-The car, too?
That...that's my favourite car.
How did you know
that was my favourite car?
You showed me a picture of it once
and said, "That's my favourite car."
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Rory, can you give us two minutes?
Two minutes.
She'll say that we can't accept it
because it's too extravagant
and we'll always feel
a crippling sense of obligation.
It's a risk I'm willing to take.
Hey.
So...
You're leaving, aren't you?
You haven't seen the last of me.
Bad Penny is my middle name.
Seriously, the looks I get
when I fill in a form, it's...
Why now?
Because you're still breathing.
Well, I think
this is about the washing up.
Oh, you're right. There's still
heaps of stuff out there to look at.
Do you know, there's a planet
whose name literally translates
as "Volatile Sadness"?
Or maybe there's a bigger, scarier
adventure waiting for you in there.
Even so, it can't happen like this.
After everything we've been through,
Doctor,
everything,
you can't just drop me off at my house
and say goodbye like we've shared a cab.
And what's the alternative?
Me standing over your grave?
Over your broken body? Over Rory's body?
If you bump into my daughter,
tell her to visit her old mum sometime.
Look after him.
Look after you.
Bye.
(WHOOSHING)
What happened?
What's he doing?
He's saving us.
Hello, Craig. I'm back.
-What are you here for?
-I'm the Doctor. I work in a shop now.
OWENS: You noticed something
and you're investigating it,
and because it's you,
it's going to be dangerous and alien.
What is that?
Help me!
No!
-Doctor!
-Craig!
(SCREAMING)