-Where is it?
-(BEEPING)
Oh, it just happened.
I went to the bathroom.
Thank you for the hologram leopard,
by the way.
An unexpected pleasure.
And my bedroom was completely missing.
(SIGHS) Just tell me where you put it.
Hang on, I know what the problem is.
Is this the first time
he's brought a girl home?
(BEEPING)
Are you laughing? You are, aren't you?
What's so funny?
(BEEPING)
Blimey.
That's, um... That's quite a selection.
Dear God, that woman is made of legs.
That's the most legs
on any living human.
Okay.
-Not the first, then.
-(BEEPING)
This is the Doctor we're talking about.
He's in a co-dependent relationship
with a screwdriver.
I mean, if he had to choose between
an enormous complicated machine
he could fix with a tool kit
and a girl, who would he go with?
Yeah, you're right. Both of them.
Using the same tool kit.
So what do we do?
(SIGHS)
I give in.
I'm going to go find my dumb bedroom.
Do your worst.
Can't wait to see your next trick.
Whoa!
Who the hell are you?
You, from tomorrow night.
Okay. Where have you put it?
Where is my bedroom?
This isn't funny! I'm exhausted.
Where is it?
You think you've got problems?
We've got to share a bed.
Oh, dear God.
(MULTIPLE CLARAS TALKING AT ONCE)
(ALL SHOUTING ANGRILY)