(DOG BARKING)
I still can't believe I'm allowed him.
-He's your son.
-That's what I'm talking about.
I mean, who authorised this?
It's the single most terrifying thing
that's ever happened to me.
-I mean, what if I break him?
-Yeah, you best try not to do that.
(BABY GURGLING)
You all right, mate?
See? Nothing!
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
He's fine. He loves you.
See?
-(BABY GURGLING)
-Hey!
It's just when I look into his eyes,
I see everything I'm going to do wrong
for the next 60 years
reflected back at me.
You're going to be an amazing dad,
"cause you're an amazing man.
Okay.
(BABY GURGLING)
Huh? That's good.
Still not broken.
Another one. Have you seen
all these people disappearing?
And you're absolutely sure about this?
Me and him on our own
for a whole weekend?
Of course,
what is the worst that could happen?
Don't ever say that! If you say that,
terrible things will happen.
Have you never seen a film?
Come on, it's his bath time.
What? We literally
just did that yesterday.
Oh, for God's sake, stop your fussing.
Everything is going to be fine.
It's wet elbows,
not the end of the world. Come on.
Fine. Let's get you in the bath.
Do I have to bath him while you're gone?
(GLASS SHATTERING)