EDMUND: If I have not returned
in an hour, you must fetch the police.
Edmund!
Don't fret, Effie, my dear,
all will be well.
But we must get to the bottom of
this dark and queer business,
no matter what the cost.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Mrs Gillyflower.
We have come about
your husband, my dear.
A tragedy.
My husband?
Your late husband.
There must be some mistake,
my husband is quite well.
(EDMUND SCREAMING)
We're so very sorry for your loss.
(EFFIE SCREAMS)
Oh, hellfire, that's put me
right off me mash. (LAUGHS)
-Another one.
-Another?
He's not the first one
I've had in here looking like that.
The Crimson Horror,
that's what they're calling it.
I have no interest in the deplorable
excesses of the penny dreadfuls.
Hey, hey. Payment in advance, flower.
Taking a big risk, you see, I am.
They'll have me vitals
for fiddle strings
if they knew I'd let you come to
look at one of their precious stiffs.
This stiff is my brother.
I've come up from London
to bring him home.
Oh, aye?
MR THURSDAY: Thank you
for agreeing to this meeting.
I'm told you're the investigator to see
if there are strange goings-on.
I read of your brother's death.
Another victim of the Crimson Horror,
I believe?
So it is claimed.
He was a newspaper man.
He and a young woman
were working undercover.
Tell me, Madame,
-do you know what an Octagram is?
-(VASTRA CHUCKLES)
VASTRA: It's a silly superstition, sir.
The belief that the eye can retain
an image of the last thing it sees.
-Good grief!
-MR THURSDAY: Oh, gosh!
(THUDDING)
Well, I'll be blowed.
I think, Madame, that we'd better
make plans to head north.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
According to my research,
Sweetville's proprietor
holds recruitment try-outs
for her little community.
She is only interested in the fittest
and the most beautiful.
You may rely on me, ma'am.
I was, in fact, speaking to Jenny.
Jenny.
If this weak and fleshy boy
is to represent us...
-Ah.
-...I strongly advise
the issuing of scissor grenades,
limbo vapour
and triple blast brain-spitters.
What for?
Just generally.
Remember, we are going to the North.
MRS GILLYFLOWER: Bradford,
that Babylon of the moderns,
with its crystal light and its glitter.
All a-swarm with
the wretched ruins of humanity.
-(CONGREGATION MURMURING)
-Men and women
crushed by the Devil's juggernaut.
Moral turpitude
can destroy the most delicate of lives.
Believe me, I know.
I know.
(CONGREGATION GASPING)
My own daughter,
blinded in a drunken rage
by my late husband.
-MAN: Disgraceful!
-(ALL GASPING)
Her once-beautiful eyes
pale and white as mistletoe berries.
And what, my friends, is your story?
Will you be found wanting
when the End of Days is come?
When judgement rains down upon us all?
Or will you be preserved
-against the coming apocalypse?
-(CONGREGATION MURMURS)
Do not despair.
I offer a way out.
There is a different path.
Sweetville.
(CONGREGATION GASPING)
-Wow.
-(CONGREGATION CHATTERING)
Join us! Join us
in this shining city on the hill.
ALL: # Bring me my bow
# Of burning gold
# Bring me my arrows of desire #
You wish to join us, my dear?
If it's all the same with you, ma'am.
Oh, yes, dear, you'll do very nicely.
If our stratagem succeeds,
Jenny will infiltrate deep into
the black heart of this curious place.
And how will she locate the Doctor?
To find him, she needs only
ignore all "keep out"” signs,
go through every locked door
and run towards any form of danger
that presents itself.
-Business as usual, then?
-Business as usual.
(CHAINS CLINKING)
Did you think I'd forgotten you,
dear monster?
-Hmm?
-(BANGS)
(GASPS)
I have travelled from London
expressly to see Madame Vastra.
Will you be so kind as to
announce me, my good man?
STRAX: Who shall I say is calling?
(THUDDING)
It asked permission to enter,
and then it fell over.
What are we to make of it?
I imagine Mr Thursday wants to know
what progress we are making.
The question is
how did the Doctor's image come to
be preserved in a dead man's eye?
It's a scientific impossibility.
I wonder how Jenny is getting on?
If she hasn't made contact by nightfall,
I suggest
a massive frontal assault
on the factory, Madame.
Casualties could be kept to
perhaps as little as 80%.
I think there may be subtler ways
of proceeding, Strax.
Suit yourself.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I'm dead nervous, aren't you?
They have to be sure, you see.
Only the best for Sweetville.
I hope me teeth don't let me down.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
I'm Abigail.
-Pleased to meet you.
-You're not local, are you?
No. Up from London.
-Different here, I bet.
-Oh, yeah.
-A bleeding horse market.
-(CHUCKLES)
Do you know anyone
who's come to live here?
-In Sweetville, I mean?
-(STAMMERS)
I had a pal who come here
three month back.
She wrote to tell me
how perfect it all were.
Funny, though. I've not heard a peep
from her since.
MAN: Next, please.
ABIGAIL: Hang on, we're moving.
What are you doing?
Do me a favour, cause a distraction.
-What?
-Swoon.
Have a funny turn.
-Fit of the vapours.
-Are you crackers?
Go on.
There's a guinea in it for you.
Done.
(GASPING DRAMATICALLY)
(CROWD MURMURING)
(LOUD RHYTHMIC CLANGING)
(CLANGING CONTINUES)
Them new manufacturers can
do horrible things to a person.
Horrible!
I've pickled things in here
that'll fair turn your hair snowy
as top of Buckden Pike.
-You know what I'm looking for?
-Oh, aye.
All them bits found in t'canal.
The Crimson Horror.
(EXHALES)
It hardly seems possible.
-Eh?
-I think...
I think I have seen
these symptoms before.
Oh, aye?
-A long time ago.
-Oh, aye, how long?
About 65 million years.
(SLURPING)
I trust you had a pleasant day, Mama?
Tolerable.
Will Mr Sweet ever join us
for dinner, Mama?
Mr Sweet is rather tired tonight,
I fear.
Oh, dear me. (CHUCKLING)
How clumsy I'm getting.
To keep the devil at bay.
(LIQUIDS BUBBLING INSIDE)
(METALLIC CLANG)
(CLANGING CONTINUES)
(DOORKNOB RATTLES)
(SHRIEKS)
All right, mate.
You just stay calm, now.
(BANGS)
I could open this door.
Would you like that?
(BANGS)
I thought you might.
But you and me has got
to come to an arrangement,
-savvy?
-(BANGS)
Now, you stand well back,
do you hear me?
I don't mean no harm to you,
but you try anything funny
and I'll leave you here to rot.
-Is that understood?
-(BANGS TWICE)
Right.
(GASPS) Doctor!
(GROANING)
What happened to you?
Ah, ah, ah... (GROANS)
-Can't you speak?
-(GROANING)
-(MAKES A HOLLOW SOUND)
-(GASPS)
Right. Well, we're getting out of here.
(DOCTOR GROANING)
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
-Come on.
-(GROANS)
Come on.
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
(BUBBLING)
Oh, my God!
(GRUNTING)
You are all I have, monster.
But all will be well.
Imperfect as we are,
there will be room for us
in the new Jerusalem.
(DOOR CREAKS)
No. No!
Where are you, monster? Where are you?
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
-You want to go in there?
-(GRUNTS LOUDLY)
(GRUNTING)
-Ha! Miss me?
-Doctor!
Jenny! Jenny, Jenny, Jenny, Jenny.
Just when you think your favourite
lock-picking Victorian chambermaid
will never turn up,
-Jenny!
-(GASPS)
(GROANS)
You have no idea
how good that feels. Ooh!
Right! Mrs Gillyflower,
we've got to stop her.
And then there's Clara. Poor Clara.
Where's Clara?
Clara?
-Doctor, wait!
-Can't, Clara, got to find.
What happened to you?
How long have you been like that?
Days, weeks? Don't know. Long story.
I'll keep it short.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
Okay, so...
Not London, 1893.
Yorkshire, 1893. Near enough.
You're making a habit of this,
getting us lost.
Sorry. It's much better
than it used to be.
Ooh, I once spent a hell of a long time
trying to get a gobby Australian
to Heathrow Airport.
-What for?
-Search me. Anyway...
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Brave heart, Clara.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
EDMUND: It's another one. Don't you see?
Another victim!
Why won't any one of you listen?
We'll listen.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
EDMUND: Mrs Winifred Gillyflower,
an astonishing woman.
Prize-winning chemist
and mechanical engineer, so why?
Why has she decided to open up
a match factory in her old hometown?
And no one who ever goes to live there
ever seems to come out.
Same as the rest.
All dead from causes unknown
and their flesh...
Glowing. Like something manky
in a coal cellar.
They keep turning up in t'canal.
The Crimson Horror.
Ooh, good name!
Hey, that's good, isn't it?
The Crimson Horror.
(CHUCKLES) I wonder what it is?
Do you know
the old Romany superstition, Clara,
that the eye of a dead person retains
an image of the last thing it sees?
Nonsense, of course.
Unless the chemical composition
of the body
has been massively corrupted.
Wow, this is nasty. An organic poison,
a sort of venom. And you think
it's connected to Sweetville?
-I do.
-Well, then,
we need a plan.
Doctor and Mrs Smith.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, yes!
You'll do very nicely.
Oh, grand! Smashing!
Hey, the missus and I couldn't be
more chuffed. Could we, love?
-Huh?
-(GIGGLES)
Sweetville will provide you
with everything you need.
You won't have to worry about a thing
ever again.
-The name, Sweetville...
-Yes.
Why not name it after yourself?
After all, it's your creation.
Gillyflower Town, eh?
Gillyflower Land,
you could have rollercoasters.
It is named in tribute to my partner.
-Your late partner?
-No. My...
silent partner.
Mr Sweet likes to
keep himself to himself.
Shall we move on?
-Who lives here?
-(CHUCKLES) Oh, names don't matter here.
All you need to know is we only
recruit the brightest and the best.
(GASPING)
Like pretty maids all in a row.
The process improves with every attempt.
Mr Sweet is such a clever old thing.
Oh!
Into the canal with the rejects, Ada.
Yes.
(MAN GROANING)
(ADA GASPS)
Sometimes the preservation process
goes wrong.
Only Mr Sweet knows why.
And only Mama is allowed
to talk to Mr Sweet.
But if you're very good,
you can stay here.
(WHISPERS) You'll be my secret.
My special monster.
Shh. (GIGGLES)
(DOCTOR GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(SCREAMING)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
Poor Edmund
must have come looking for us
and then fallen into a vat
of the pure venom.
Or was pushed.
He didn't stand a chance.
What is that stuff, though?
Deadly poison.
And Mrs Gillyflower has been dipping
her pilgrims in a dilute form
to protect and preserve them.
Process didn't work on me,
maybe because I am not human.
I ended up on the reject pile.
Preserve them against what?
Well, according to her,
the coming apocalypse.
(WHISTLING)
"When the End of Days has come
and judgement rains down upon us all..."
What?
-Nothing.
-No, no, no. What?
Something Mrs Gillyflower said
in one of her sermons.
Madame will come looking for me.
We best get on.
Yes, Clara, got to find Clara.
But Doctor...
Clara's dead.
Isn't she?
It's complicated.
Horse, you have failed in your mission.
We're lost, with no sign of Sweetville.
Do you have any final words
before your summary execution?
(SNUFFLES)
The usual story.
Fourth one this week,
and I'm not even hungry.
BOY: Sweetville, sir?
-Do you know it?
-Turn around when possible,
then, at the end of the road,
turn right.
-What?
-Bear left for a quarter of a mile,
you will have reached your destination.
Thank you. What is your name?
Thomas, sir. Thomas Thomas.
I think you will do well, Thomas Thomas.
Are we talking about the same person,
about that Clara?
Doctor!
-What...
-(DOOR CLOSES)
I couldn't see much from where I was
but I think
she survived the process.
She must be here somewhere.
But Clara died!
-The ice lady...
-(DOOR CLOSES)
Doctor!
(STAMMERING) Uh...
(WHISPERS) It's complicated.
(YELLS)
(SOBBING)
What is the meaning of this?
(SOBBING) Oh, Mama!
I have been foolish.
(SNIFFLES) I have formed a...
sentimental attachment.
An attachment? To whom?
A young man.
Unlike the others,
he survived rejection.
He must be strong, worthy of salvation.
Wrecker. Berserker!
You have loosed a reject
onto the outside world.
-I have disappointed you.
-My plans must be accelerated.
Nothing must interfere
with the great work.
But please say there is still room
for me in your new Eden, Mama,
-promise me that.
-I'll set my pilgrims onto him.
No!
Kindly do not claw and slobber
at my crinoline.
You know I cannot bear
to look at sick people.
Promise me you will not
abandon me, Mama.
-Promise me that.
-Do you not yet understand?
There can be no place
for people such as you.
And only perfection is good enough
for myself and Mr Sweet.
(SOBBING)
The bright day is done, child,
and you are for the dark.
(SOBBING)
JENNY: Can she be revived like you were?
I hope so.
JENNY: Doctor!
Oh, great, great!
Attack of the supermodels.
Time for a plan.
No, Doctor, this one's on me.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
That is a plan.
Okay, time for a new plan.
-Run!
-(GASPS)
STRAX: Sontar ha! (CACKLING)
(LAUGHING)
-Let's go!
-No, ma'am, we're not escaping.
We've got to help the Doctor with Clara.
Long story.
What now, Madame? We could
lay my magnetic cluster bands!
-Strax...
-Or dig trenches
-and fill them with acid.
-Strax! You're overexcited.
Have you been eating
those jelly sherbet fancies again?
No.
Go outside and wait for me
until I call for you.
-But Madame...
-Go!
(GRUNTS)
(MUMBLING) I'm going
to go play with my grenades.
Okay. I think she's about done.
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
I know who you think she is,
but she isn't.
(WHISPERS) She can't be.
I was right, then, you and Clara
have unfinished business.
Hey, hey!
-Hello, stranger.
-(CHUCKLES)
-Doctor.
-Yeah.
-Uh-huh.
-(CHUCKLES)
Hi.
What's going on?
Oh. Haven't you heard, love?
There's trouble at mill.
She's a lizard.
My people once ruled this world,
as well you know,
but we did not rule it alone.
Just as humanity fights a daily battle
against nature, so did we.
And our greatest plague,
the most virulent enemy,
was a repulsive red leech.
Ooh, the repulsive red leech.
Now, on balance,
I think I prefer the Crimson Horror.
What was it, exactly?
A tiny parasite.
It infected our drinking water.
Once in our systems,
it secreted a fatal poison.
It's been hanging around,
lurking in the shadows.
Maybe it's evolved.
Maybe it's had help.
Doctor, I've been thinking.
-The chimney...
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
way past that now.
Yucky red parasite
from the time of the dinosaurs
pitches up in Victorian Yorkshire.
-Didn't see that one coming.
-Yeah, but the chimney...
Yeah, but what's the connection
to Mrs Gillyflower?
"Judgement will rain down on us all.”
An empty mill...
A chimney that doesn't blow smoke.
Clever-clogs.
-Miss me?
-Yeah, lots.
-She's going to poison the air.
-How?
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
With that, I should think.
DOCTOR: And there's the poison.
All right, gang, I've got a plan.
(METAL CLANGS ON FLOOR)
Okay.
(ADA SOBBING)
Who is it?
Who is there?
Okay.
You...
It's you, my monster.
You've come back.
-But you're...
-Warm and alive.
Thanks to you, Ada.
You saved me from
your mother's human rubbish tip.
Now, hey. What's wrong?
She does not want me, monster.
I am not to be chosen.
Perhaps it was my own sin.
The blackness in my heart
that my father saw in me.
Ada, no!
That's nonsense,
stupid, backwards nonsense,
and you know it.
(SOFTLY) You know it.
-CLARA: What is it?
-Who is that?
I'm...
I'm a friend.
A friend of his.
ADA: Then you are fortunate indeed.
It isn't good to be alone. (SIGHS)
DOCTOR: Now, Ada,
I need you to tell me something.
Who is Mr Sweet?
Ada...
Oh, dear monster.
-Please.
-I cannot.
Even now, I cannot.
I cannot betray Mama.
(SOBBING)
Well, come with us, then.
There is something you need to know.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, you do seem
to keep turning up
-like a bad penny, young man.
-Force of habit.
Can I offer you something?
Tea? Seed cake? (GASPS)
A glass of amontillado?
No, thanks, we've had a skinful already,
as you might say.
(CHUCKLES) Very funny.
Hmm, yes. I'm the Doctor,
you're nuts and I'm going to stop you.
I am afraid Mr Sweet and I
cannot allow that.
Ah, yes. Would it be impolite to ask
why you and Mr Sweet are petrifying
your workforce
with diluted prehistoric leech venom?
So, when do we get to meet him,
this silent partner of yours?
Why is he so shy?
Mr Sweet is always with us.
You do seem to have a very
close relationship, you and your pal.
Oh, yes, Doctor. Exceedingly close.
Symbiotic, you might say.
Doctor, what is it?
A survivor.
He has grown fat on the filth
humanity has pumped into the rivers.
That's where I found him.
-Very enterprising.
-His needs are simple.
And in return he gives me his nectar.
Mrs Gillyflower,
you have no idea
what you are dealing with.
In the wrong hands, that venom
could wipe out all life on this planet.
Do you know what these are?
(LAUGHING) The wrong hands.
Planning a little fireworks party,
are we?
You have forced me to advance
the great work somewhat, Doctor.
But my colossal scheme
remains as it was.
My rocket will explode
high in the atmosphere,
raining down Mr Sweet's beneficence
onto all humanity.
And wiping us all out. You can't!
My new Adam and Eves will sleep
but for a few months
before stepping out into a golden dawn.
Is it not beautiful, Doctor?
Now, tell us about Ada, Mrs Gillyflower.
-What?
-Your daughter.
You do remember your daughter?
Tell us about your daughter.
How can you speak of such trivia
when my hour is at hand?
The child is of no consequence.
Is that why you experimented on her?
CLARA: Experimented?
DOCTOR: The signs are all there.
The pattern of scarring.
You used her as a guinea pig,
didn't you?
-God!
-Sometimes sacrifices must be made.
-Sacrifices?
-It was necessary.
I had to find out how much of the venom
would produce an antitoxin
to immunise myself, don't you see?
It was necessary!
Mama? Is it...
Is it true?
-Ada...
-It is!
-It's true. True!
-Ada, listen to me.
You hag!
You perfidious hag!
You virago! You harpy!
All these years I have helped you,
served you, looked after you,
does it count for nothing?
Nothing at all!
MRS GILLYFLOWER: Oh, stop!
Stop! Oh!
Hang on, hang on,
I've got a sonic screwdriver.
Yeah? I've got a chair. (GRUNTS)
No!
DOCTOR: Yeah.
That worked.
I'm afraid your rocket
isn't going anywhere, Mrs G.
(MRS GILLYFLOWER SOBBING)
Please, come to me, Ada.
(ADA SOBBING)
Oh, my child.
You have always been so very
useful.
No, Mrs Gillyflower.
Please, Mama, no more, no more.
And now, if you will forgive us,
we must be going.
It is long past Ada's bedtime.
No, no, Clara.
If we follow straight after her,
she'll shoot Ada on the spot.
-She wouldn't!
-She would.
Chairs are useful.
(GRUNTING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Come along, Ada, don't dawdle.
Please, Mama, stop!
Has the venom been loaded?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Then heaven awaits you.
ADA: Stop!
Just let her go.
Mrs Gillyflower, let Ada go.
Secondary firing mechanism, Doctor.
Mr Sweet and I were too smart
for you after all.
Just let your daughter go,
Mrs Gillyflower.
-(SOBBING) Monster!
-Ada!
(ADA GROANS)
Shoot if you wish, Mama.
It is of no matter,
for you killed me a long time ago.
# I'll lab our night and day
# To be a pilgrim #
(CACKLING)
Now, Mr Sweet.
Now the whole world will taste
your lethal kiss.
I don't think so, Mrs Gillyflower.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
MRS GILLYFLOWER: Oh!
Very well, then.
If I can't take the world with me,
you will have to do.
Die, you freaks!
Die!
-Die!
-STRAX: Put down your weapon,
human female.
(GASPS)
-Oh.
-(YELLS)
(MRS GILLYFLOWER THUDDING)
Ouch!
No!
Mr Sweet. Where are you going?
You can't leave me now.
-Mr Sweet.
-CLARA: Ugh!
-What's it doing?
-It knows she's dying.
She's no longer of any use to it.
MRS GILLYFLOWER: Mr Sweet!
(MRS GILLYFLOWER GROANING)
Ada...
Ada.
(MRS GILLYFLOWER GROANING)
Are you there?
I'm here, Mama.
MRS GILLYFLOWER: Forgive me, my child.
Forgive me.
Never!
That's my girl.
(ALL GASP)
(WHISTLES)
JENNY: What will you do with that thing?
DOCTOR: Take it back
to the Jurassic era, maybe.
Out of harm's way.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
On the other hand... Ooh.
Right, right, London.
We were heading for London, weren't we?
Was there any particular reason?
No, no, just thought you might
like it.
Yeah.
Maybe had enough
of Victorian values for a bit.
-You're the boss.
-Am I?
No. No! Get in.
(STRAX CHATTING, INDISTINCT)
Now, Ada, I'd love to stay
and help clear up the mess but...
I know, dear monster,
you have things to do.
And what about you?
Oh, there are many things a bright
young lady can do to occupy her time.
It's time I stepped out of
the darkness and into the light.
Good luck, Ada.
You know, I think you will be just...
splendid!
Well! Thanks a million,
you three, as ever.
Have some Pontefract cakes on me.
I love Pontefract cakes.
(IMITATES SWORD) Ha!
See you around, eh?
I shouldn't wonder.
But Doctor, that girl, Clara...
You haven't explained.
(STAMMERS) No, I haven't.
Ah, look at the muck in here.
Right.
Another one for the vault?
Ah, there you are.
I called to see
if there had been any progress.
(TARDIS WHOOSHING)
The boss.
Yep, that's me.
"I am the boss."
It's you, isn't it?
It's from the '70s,
but it's definitely you.
Of course it's not.
And that's you, too.
From 1983, I found it at school.
No, that's just someone
who looks like me.
And that's someone
who looks like your boyfriend.
Is he an alien?
-ANGIE: Why would he be an alien?
-Uh, the chin.
And the time travel?
-That's not right.
-You were in Victorian London?
No, I was in Victorian Yorkshire.
-How come you didn't tell us?
-Time travel, that's so cool!
-Can we have a go?
-Can you have a what?
-We want a shot at the time machine.
-No, no, no, no, no. Listen!
Okay. Or...
Wwe'll have to tell Dad
that our nanny's a time traveller.
DOCTOR: Hedgewick's World,
the biggest and best
amusement park there will ever be.
It closed down.
Reports of people just vanishing.
No need to panic my young friends.
We all know there are
no more living Cybermen.
Attack formation! Quickly!
Don't wander off.
(SCREAMING)
Take defensive positions.
They're here!
Hail to you, the Doctor,
saviour of the Cybermen!