(STREET LIGHT BUZZING)
-Thank you.
(SIGHS)
(CASH REGISTER BEEPING)
Better cash up, then.
I suppose John Joe can just wait for me.
No, I'll do it. You head off.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
When's the council going to fix this?
Last night, my telly went off
in the middle of 7op Model.
John Joe's waiting.
I'll do the changing rooms, too.
Oh, thanks, Shona.
There's a list on the fridge.
I saw it.
And I've labelled the food
and sort of numbered it.
Sophie, you don't need to number food.
It's just a suggestion.
Also, my mum might phone.
-Might?
-And your mum and my dad.
And, you know, just innocent people.
I can cope on my own.
Now, please go and have a rest.
You need it.
-I love you.
-I love you, too.
And thank you for this.
And I do know you can cope on your own.
And I may have drawn some arrows
in the fridge.
Okay, you really have to go now.
(SIGHS) Oh, Kelly!
(CLATTERING)
Hello? Sorry, we need to close up.
Two minutes, okay?
Mum, it's not just you.
I'm phoning everybody.
I'm texting the world,
"Craig Owens can do it on his own."
No one is coming to help me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Mum, I'm going to have to call you back.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
I'm coping. I'm coping on my own.
I'm coping on my own!
Hello, Craig. I'm back!
She didn't...
How could she phone you?
How could who phone me?
Nobody phoned me. I'm just here.
Oh, you've redecorated!
I don't like it.
It's a different house. We moved.
Yes, that's it.
Doctor, what are you doing here?
Social call. Thought it was about time
I tried one out.
How are you?
I'm fine.
This is the bit where I say
I'm fine, too, isn't it?
I'm fine, too.
-Good.
-Love to Sophie. Bye.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
Something's wrong.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER HUMMING)
On your own, you said.
But you're not.
You're not on your own.
Just... Shh.
Increased sulphur emissions.
And look at the state of this place.
-What are you not telling me?
-Doctor, please.
-Shh.
-No, you shush.
-Shh!
-No, you shush!
Doctor...
Hello?
Who's in there?
Whoever you are, get off this planet.
(BABY CRYING)
You've woken him!
(CRAIG SIGHING)
Hello?
Are you all right?
(SCREAMING)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
So, when you say on your own...
Yes, I meant on my own
with the baby, yes.
Because no one thinks I can cope
on my own, which is so unfair.
Because I can't cope on my own with him.
I can't. He just cries all the time.
I mean, do they have off switches?
Human beings? No.
Believe me, I've checked.
No, babies!
Same difference.
Sometimes this works, though.
Shh.
-Can you teach me to do that?
-Probably not.
Oh, please. Come on. I need something.
I am rubbish at this.
-At what?
-Being a dad.
You read all the books and they tell you
you'll know what to do
if you follow your instincts.
I have no instincts.
That's what this weekend's about,
trying to prove to people
I can do this one thing well.
(LAUGHING)
So what did you call him? Will I blush?
No, we didn't call him The Doctor.
No, I didn't think you would.
He's called Alfie.
What are you doing here, anyway?
Yes, he likes that, Alfie,
though personally he prefers to be
called Stormageddon, Dark Lord of AIL
-I'm sorry, what?
-That's what he calls himself.
And how do you know that?
I speak baby.
Of course you do.
I don't even know
when his nappy needs changing,
I'm the one
who's supposed to be his dad.
Oh, God.
Yeah, I'm wondering where his mum is.
Where is Sophie?
She's gone away with Melina
for the weekend. She needs a rest.
(COOING)
No, he's your dad.
You can't just call him Not Mum.
-"Not Mum"?
-That's you.
Also Not Mum, that's me.
And everybody else is...
-(BURBLING)
-Peasants.
That's a bit unfortunate.
What are you here for? What's happening?
-Just popped in to say hello.
-You don't do that.
I checked upstairs when we moved in.
It's real.
And next door, both sides,
they're humans.
Is it the fridge?
Are there aliens in my fridge?
I just want to see you, Craig.
Cross my hearts.
Been knocking around on my own
for a bit,
bit of a farewell tour.
One last thing, popping in to see you,
then I'm off to see
the Alignment of Exodor.
The Alignment of Exodor?
Seventeen galaxies in perfect unison.
Meant to be spectacular.
I can't miss it.
Literally can't.
It's locked in a time stasis field.
I get one crack at flying my Tardis
straight into it,
if I get my dates right,
-which I have.
-Sounds nice.
So this is me, popping in and
popping out again, just being social,
just having a laugh.
Never mind that.
-Never mind what?
-Mmm, nothing.
No, you've noticed something. You've...
You've got your noticing face on.
I have nightmares about that face.
Nope. Given all that up.
Done noticing things.
Didn't even notice that, for example.
Well, got to go. Good seeing you, Craig.
Goodbye, Stormageddon.
(BABBLING)
No, wait, wait.
Can you do the shushy thing?
No, it only works once, and only on
life forms with underdeveloped brains.
Hang on! You said "farewell tour”.
-What do you mean, farewell...?
-Shh.
Just go. Stop noticing. Just go.
Stop noticing. Just go. Stop noticing.
Just go. Stop it.
Am I noticing? No.
No, I am not.
And what I'm not doing is scanning
around for electrical fluctuations.
Oh, shut up, you.
I'm just dropping in on a friend.
The last thing I need right now is
a patina of teleport energy.
I'm going. Do you hear me? Going.
Not staying, going.
I am through saving them.
I'm going away now.
(TOYS SQUEAKING AND WHIRRING)
(IMITATING AEROPLANE SOUND)
It goes up, tiddly-up, it goes down,
diddly-down, for only 49.99,
which I personally think is a bit steep.
But then again, it's your parents' cash
and they'll only waste it
on boring stuff
like lamps and vegetables.
Yawn.
Yeah, Soph. Just enjoy your holiday.
Yeah, coping.
Nobody panic,
but I appear to be losing control.
-Yeah, love you...
-Oopsy-daisy.
Guys, guys. Ladies and gentlemen,
while I deal with this awkward moment,
you go and find your
parents-slash-guardians.
Try in lamps.
Craig!
What the hell are you doing here?
Oh, I'm the Doctor.
I work in a shop now. Here to help.
Look, they gave me a badge with my
name on in case I forget who I am.
Very thoughtful, as that does happen.
You were leaving.
The Alignment of...Exeter.
What about that?
One chance to see it, you said.
Well, I was on my way...
Saw a shop, got a job.
You've got to live in the moment!
-Craig, mind Yappy!
-What?
Yappy.
The robot dog.
Not as much fun as I remember. (LAUGHS)
You look awful.
(SIGHS) Well, I haven't slept, have I?
I still can't stop him crying.
I even tried singing to him last night.
Yeah, he did mention that.
He thought you were crying, too.
He didn't get a wink.
Yappy, say goodbye to Craig
and Stormageddon.
"Goodbye, Craig!
Goodbye, Stormageddon!”
What was that?
You're here for a reason, aren't you?
You've noticed something
and you're investigating it.
And because it's you,
it's going to be dangerous and alien.
It might not be.
-Doctor, I live here. I need to know.
-No, you don't.
My baby lives here. My son.
Sheila Clark went missing Tuesday.
Hadif Gosh, last seen Friday.
Tom Luka, last seen Sunday.
Why is none of this on the front page?
Oh, page one has an exclusive on Nina,
a local girl who got kicked off
Britain's Got Talent.
These people are on pages seven, 19, 22.
Because no one's noticed yet.
They're far too excited
about Nina's emotional journey,
which, in fairness, is quite inspiring.
And what else?
These funny old power fluctuations,
which just happen to coincide
with the disappearances.
No, but that's just the council
putting in new cables, isn't it?
Oh, yes. That's it.
Mystery solved. Wasting my time.
Now, you can go home
and I can go to Exodor.
Goodbye. And here's the lift!
-It says it's out of order.
-Not any more.
See? Here to help.
It says, "Danger!"
Oh, rubbish. Lifts aren't dangerous.
Do I look like I'm stupid?
(COOING)
(CHUCKLES) Quiet, Stormy.
Oh, all right.
There's more.
Just between you, me and Stormy,
don't want to frighten the punters,
someone's been using a teleport relay
right here in this shop.
Missing people last seen in this area.
Before you ask, CCTV's been wiped.
A teleport?
A tele... A big...
A teleport? Like a beam-me-up
-teleport, like you see in Star Trek?
-Exactly.
Someone's been using
a beam-me-up Star Trek teleport.
Could be disguised as anything.
But a teleport in a shop?
That's ridiculous.
What was that?
Was that the lights, again?
(HIGH-PITCHED) Yes, that's it.
That's all. It's the lights.
Why'd you say that like that?
Like what? (LOWERS PITCH) Like what?
Like that, in that high-pitched voice.
Just keep looking at me, Craig.
Right at me. Just keep looking.
-Why?
-Well, because, because...
Because I love you.
You love me?
Yes, Craig, it's you.
It's always been you.
Me?
Is that so surprising?
Doctor, are you going to kiss me?
Yes, Craig. Yes, I am.
Would you like that?
Bit out of practice,
but I've had some wonderful feedback.
Doctor, no. I can't. I'm taken!
(SCREAMING) Oh, my God!
Or we could just hold hands if
it'd make you feel more comfortable.
What is happening?
Well, first of all, I don't really
love you, except as a friend.
What is that?
(YELLING)
-Quick reverse.
-Okay, what the hell just happened?
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
They must have linked the teleport
relay to the lift, but I've fused it.
They can't use that again.
-Stuck up there on their spaceship.
-What were those things?
Cybermen.
A ship?
A spaceship?
We were in space!
It's got to be up there somewhere.
Can't get a fix. It must be shielded.
But you fused the teleport.
You sorted it.
They can't come back.
No, no, no.
I just bought myself a little time.
I've still got to work out what
they're doing before I can stop it.
But if they've got the teleport,
and they're that evil,
why haven't they invaded already?
Craig, take Alfie and go.
No.
-No?
-No.
I remember from last time.
People got killed.
People that didn't know you.
I know where's safest for me and Alfie,
-and that's right next to you.
-Is that so?
Yeah, you always win.
You always survive.
Those were the days.
I can help you.
I'm staying.
Craig...
All right!
All right, maybe those days
aren't quite over yet.
Let's go investigate.
I mean, there's no immediate danger now.
-Good afternoon, Val.
-Hello.
(CRAIG STUTTERING)
Where am I investigating?
Well, look around.
Ask questions.
People like it when you're with a baby.
Babies are sweet. People talk to you.
That's why I usually take
a human with me.
-So I'm your baby?
-You're my baby.
Mmm.
Okay.
I hope you don't mind my saying, Doctor,
but I think you look ever so sweet.
You and your partner and the baby.
Partner? Yes, I like it.
Is it better than companion?
"Companion.” Sounds old-fashioned.
There's no need to be coy these days.
Not noticed anything unusual
around here lately, Val?
-Well...
-Yes, yes?
Mary Wornock saw...
Don Petheridge snogging Andrea Groom
outside the Conservative Club
on his so-called day off golfing.
Yeah?
Maybe this wasn't such a good idea
after all.
And then there's that silver rat thing.
What?
(ALFIE COOING)
All right, Alfie,
you watch Daddy investigate.
You look cute, I'll do the talking.
(BEEPING)
Good afternoon, sir. Can I help you?
Hiya.
-I'm Craig.
-Yeah?
Do you mind if I ask you some questions?
You what?
Just between me and you, in confidence.
Have you noticed anything
unusual?
-Interesting?
-You what?
Talk to me about ladies wear.
George!
Hi, George.
Nice uniform.
Silver rat...
Glowing red eyes.
Yes.
Then it zizzed off.
I wanted to get one for my nephew,
but stockroom say there's no such item.
Oh, I bet they do.
Well, what was it, then? Answer me that.
Can I help you, sir?
Have you seen how cute my baby is?
(LAUGHING) We're going to
head off, actually.
All right. Whoa!
What's all that hullabaloo?
Um... That'll be my partner.
Ah...
Make a habit of hanging around
in women swear, sir?
-(ALFIE CRYING)
-I'm sorry. Oh, shh, Alfie, come on.
He's a pervert. Look at him.
Hello, everyone. Here to help!
-Hello, Doctor.
Hello. Has anyone seen a silver rat?
No. Okay, long shot.
I see you've met my friend Craig.
-Nice uniform, George.
-Hmm.
-(WHISTLES)
-Thank you, Doctor.
If he's with you,
that's all right, then.
Sorry.
I thought he was hassling me
'cause that's the last thing
I need today.
'Cause Shona's not turned up, right?
So I'm doing twice the work
for the same money, if you don't mind...
Shh.
-Please teach me how to do that.
-No. Hold on, un-shh.
-Shona?
-My supervisor.
She's meant to be in today
but never showed up.
Where did you last see her?
How'd you do that?
It's a power, isn't it?
Some sort of weird alien hypnotic power.
I bet you excrete some sort of gas
that makes people love you.
Would that I could, Craig.
-(WOMAN SCREAMS)
-Ah! Sorry, madam.
I'd try that in red if I were you.
-I'm right, though, aren't I?
-Well, you love me.
I've never excreted any weird
alien gases at you.
I don't love you.
Don't start that again.
(COOING)
Yes, I know. Of course he does.
Of course you do. We're partners.
Yeah, but I did exactly
what you would've done
and I nearly got arrested.
(COOING)
Stormy thinks you should
believe in yourself more.
Great. So now my baby's reviewing me.
Here. Right here. Last night.
A Cyberman took Shona.
A Cyberman?
I thought it was a little silver rat.
It's not a rat.
It's a Cybermat.
All right. Don't have a go at me
just because I don't know the names.
Cybermats are infiltrators.
Very small, very deadly.
They collect power
like bees collect pollen.
One of them has been sucking
the electrical energy from this area.
But why a shop?
You know, why not
a nuclear power station?
-Okay, why?
-Let's ask it.
We wait for the shop to shut,
we stake the place out,
we grab ourselves a Cybermat.
And this is just a coincidence, is it?
-What is?
-Aliens in Colchester.
Aliens twice in my life,
happening to me just when you turn up.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
this is not my fault, Craig.
Oh, shh, look what you've done now.
It's his nappy. He's mentioned it twice.
Yeah, well, sorry,
I don't speak baby, do I?
There's a changing station
over by Electrical Goods.
Of course you'd know that.
Come on, Alfie.
Craig! It's a coincidence!
It happens,
it's what the universe does for...
Can I have your autograph, please?
Uh, yeah, sure.
...fun.
AMY: Uh, what's your name?
GIRL: Ellie.
"To Ellie."
-I like your hairband.
-Thank you.
-Here you go.
Amelia Pond.
Okay, shh.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER HUMMING)
Right.
Let's be having you then, Cybermat.
(ALFIE CRYING)
Shh!
Can't you put that on quiet?
No. It's a sonic screwdriver.
Sonic equals sound.
Take this.
I got it on my discount, 10% off.
It's a papoose.
-Why do I need a papoose?
-Alfie wants you attached to him.
You are far too slow
when he summons you.
When's he going to stop giving me marks?
Never. It's parenthood.
Couldn't you have just got a babysitter?
-(ALFIE COOING)
-No, any babysitter.
Doesn't have to be a hot one.
I told everyone I know
-I didn't need their help this weekend.
-Well.
They won't even answer my calls.
I didn't know there was going to be
an invasion of Cybermen.
(SHUSHING)
(BUZZING)
(ALFIE FUSSING, BOTH SHUSHING)
-It's okay.
-(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
(GASPS)
A-ha!
It's very hot.
Must be on low power.
I'm better at that than I remember.
(CRAIG PANTING)
-Oh, is that it?
-Yeah.
Oh, that's quite cute. Look at that.
-Look, Alfie, look...
-(BOTH YELL)
(CRAIG GASPING)
(CLATTERING)
Metal rat, real mouth!
-Yes, I know it is.
-Metal rat...
Stop, stop screaming! Shh!
(GEORGE SCREAMING)
Come on!
George!
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
George.
(GRUNTS)
CRAIG: Doctor!
Doctor!
What happened?
Oh, I've been chipped...
Chapped...
Chopped!
(GRUNTS) The Cyberman.
It killed George.
Took him back to the ship.
The Cybermen are here?
-But you said...
-Yeah, I know what I said, okay?
A lot of things.
But I fused the teleport.
It should've taken them days to repair.
Are you okay?
Oh, I should be dead, but the arm
it chopped me with, it was damaged.
Old spare parts. Must have changed
those missing people. (MUMBLES)
Changed the missing into Cybermen?
Why didn't they change you?
Long story. I'm not exactly compatible,
but why are they using spare parts?
Why? Everything I find out
makes less sense.
Doctor, listen to me. If the Cybermen
are here, then we're not safe.
We've got to go.
We've got to go back to base.
We've got a base?
When did we get a base?
I'm going down the shop.
We've run out of milk.
You know what to do if he cries.
No.
-Me, neither!
-(DOOR CLOSES)
(ALFIE CRYING)
Oh.
Hello, Stormageddon.
(WHINING)
It's the Doctor,
here to help.
Um, shh, shh-shh.
-Hey! There, there.
-(COOING)
Be quiet.
Go to sleep.
(ALFIE FUSSING)
Oh. Really?
Stop crying. You've got a lot
to look forward to, you know.
A normal human life on earth.
Mortgage repayments,
the nine-to-five, a persistent,
nagging sense of spiritual emptiness.
(COOING)
Save the tears for later, boy-o.
(GRUMBLING) No, that was...
crabby.
No, that was old.
But I am old, Stormy.
I am so old.
So near the end.
(BEEPING)
You, Alfie Owens,
you
are so young.
Aren't you?
And you know, right now,
everything's ahead of you.
You could be anything.
-(WHINING)
-Yes.
I know.
You could walk among the stars.
They don't actually look like that,
you know.
They are rather more impressive.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Yeah.
You know, when I was little like you,
I dreamt of the stars.
I think it's fair to say,
in the language of your age,
that I lived my dream.
I owned the stage.
Gave it 110%.
I hope you have as much fun
as I did, Alfie.
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Your dad's trying his best, you know.
(ALFIE COOING)
Yes, I know. It's not his fault,
he doesn't have mammary glands.
(ALFIE CRIES)
No, neither do I.
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Alfie,
why is there a sinister beeping
coming from behind me?
Oh, no, you don't!
Come on, Alfie, run! It's only stunned.
(CRYING)
Yes, we're okay. Good, Alfie.
We'll go outside.
Don't worry about it, we'll go outside.
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Yeah, look...
Oops.
I'm back!
(VIBRATING)
Come on, Craig, pick up,
pick up, pick up!
Doctor?
(SOFTLY) Doctor?
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
Craig, don't worry.
Alfie is fine,
but on no account enter the house.
Doctor!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Alfie!
Where's Alfie? Where's Alfie?
-He's safe! He's safe!
-Get it off me!
I just have to find the right frequency
to shut it down.
-Kill it!
-Whoa!
All right, all right, all right, move!
(YELLING)
(YELLING) Baking tray, Craig,
baking tray!
(BOTH YELLING)
-Hold it down.
-Get on with it.
Oh, it must be shielded from
metastatic energy, of course!
-Yeah, of course!
-Don't worry, I have an app for that.
Stand back. Stand back!
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Success.
That was amazing.
You must be really, really strong!
That thing should've had you easily.
It's definitely dead?
Inactive, yes.
Technically, never been alive.
It was "playing possum” before
to take us by surprise.
Bravo.
-(CHUCKLES)
-Hey?
(BOTH SIGHING)
(WHOOPING)
Alfie!
(YAWNING) I'm knackered.
That thing was eating up
the electricity?
And transmitting it up to the Cybership.
But why?
And why do they need power?
Why are those conversions
not complete yet?
And what are they doing up there?
You said you were going to
look at its brain.
Well, I had to wipe its brain.
Now, I can reprogram it,
use it as a weapon against them.
The Cybermat came after us.
No, after me.
-They sent it after us.
-After me.
Because of me,
you and Alfie nearly died.
(ALFIE COOING)
Do you still feel safe with me, Craig?
(CHUCKLES)
Can't help who your mates are.
No.
I am a stupid, selfish man.
Always have been.
I should've made you go.
I should never have come here.
What would've happened
if you hadn't come?
Who else knows about
the Cybermen and teleports?
I put people in danger.
Stop beating yourself up.
If it weren't for you,
this whole planet
would be an absolute ruin.
Uh, Craig, very soon I won't be here.
My time is running out.
I don't mean Exodor.
"Silence will fall
when the question is asked."
I don't even know what the question is.
I always knew I'd die still asking.
The thing is, Craig,
it's tomorrow.
Can't put it off any more.
Tomorrow is the day I...
(EXHALES)
(ALFIE COOING)
(CYBERMAT BEEPING)
Safe mode.
Clever me.
Come along, bitey.
SOPHIE: So, I'll be back about 10:00,
because Melina's
totally gone off on one.
She's going to kill David Jenkins.
I know I'm stupid to worry.
-I can't wait to get home...
-No, no, no. Doctor?
Love you, Alfie. Love you, Craig.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
You idiot!
-Morning.
Teleport's still fused.
They didn't repair it.
So, the Cyberman last night,
how did it get down here?
How did it get out? And why?
Why am I asking you?
You found the silver rat?
But where are the silver men?
I'm sorry, Alfie, I can't
leave you here on your own.
There's something up with the Doctor
and we owe him.
I wouldn't have you or Mummy
if it wasn't for him.
(ALFIE GURGLING)
He needs someone.
He always needs someone.
He just can't admit it.
I promise nothing's
going to happen to you.
All right, come on. Here we go.
Secondary teleport?
No, there is no other teleport.
They must have had a backup system.
Something complicated.
Something powerful. Something shielded.
Something like...
a door? A door.
A dyscillium-bonded steel door,
disguised as a wall.
That is cheating!
So...
they didn't teleport down,
they climbed up.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER HUMMING)
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(WHISTLES)
Well, well, well. You have been busy.
Doctor? Doctor?
Another row?
He went in the changing room.
Something about silver men.
Oh, God, no. Val,
I need you to look after Alfie
for me, okay?
Please look after him.
-The Doctor needs me.
-I understand.
You two need time alone.
Don't follow me!
I wasn't intending to.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
You have come to us.
Took me a while.
A lot on my mind.
Let's see. This ship crashed here
centuries ago.
No survivors, but the systems
are dormant, waiting for power,
and then the council
stick a load of new cables
right on top of you.
Bitey wakes up and channels the power.
You start crewing up from the shop
as best you can.
Not enough power. Not enough parts.
When we are ready, we will emerge.
We will convert this planet
to Cyber-form.
What, six of you?
You know that is enough.
You know us. You are the Doctor.
Correct. And the Doctor always
gives you a choice.
Deactivate yourself or I deactivate you.
Doctor! Doctor!
Oh!
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
(YELLING)
He must be the new leader.
No. He is not like us.
Brain and binary muscular system
incompatible.
They will be discarded,
other body parts may be of use.
Oi!
Cybermen, you get off my planet
or I activate this.
Craig, stop this. Get out!
It's like you said, Doctor,
you got to believe you can do it.
You located us?
Yeah, the teleport in the lift.
A bit rubbish.
And that little Cybermat
never stood a chance.
You see what you're dealing with?
You are compatible. You are intelligent.
(SCREAMING)
No! I'm not intelligent.
You don't want me.
Do not fear.
We will take your fear from you.
You will be like us.
You will be more than us.
No, no, no!
Your designation is Cyber Controller.
-You will lead us.
-No!
We will conquer this world.
-Doctor!
-Craig!
-Do something, please!
-(GRUNTS)
Doctor!
Craig, don't worry. I've reprogrammed
their Cybermat. It'll drain their power.
(BEEPS)
You have failed, Doctor.
Begin conversion, phase one.
Cleanse the brain of emotions.
No.
Craig, fight it. They can't convert you
if you fight back.
-You're strong. Don't give into it.
-Help me!
Think of Sophie. Think of Alfie.
Craig, don't let them take it all away.
Make it stop! Please, make it stop!
Please, listen to me. I believe in you.
I believe you can do this.
I've always believed.
In all of you, all my life!
(GROANING)
I'm going to die, Craig.
Tomorrow I'm going to die, but I don't
mind if you just prove me right.
Craig!
Begin full conversion.
(ALFIE CRYING)
Don't worry.
It's just a little light going out.
(ALFIE CRYING)
CYBERMAN: Unknown sound wave detected.
It is the sound of fear.
It is irrelevant.
We will remove all fear.
Alfie, I'm so sorry!
Alfie, please, stop. I can't help him.
Emotions eradicated.
Conversion complete.
(ALFIE CONTINUES CRYING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Alert. Emotional subsystems rebooting.
This is impossible.
He can hear him. He can hear Alfie.
Oh, please, just give me this.
Craig, you wanted a chance
to prove you're a dad,
you are never going to get
a better one than this.
What is happening?
What's happening, you metal moron,
a baby is crying
and you'd better watch out
because guess what?
(LAUGHS) Daddy's coming home!
Alfie!
(LAUGHING)
Alfie, I'm here! I'm coming for you!
Guess what? It stopped.
Alfie!
(CRYING)
Alfie needs you!
Emergency! Emotional influx.
You've triggered a feedback loop
into their emotional inhibitors.
(CYBERMEN GRUNTING)
All that stuff they cut out of
themselves, now they're feeling it.
Which means a very big explosion.
Overload! Overload! Overload!
-Get out! We need to get out!
-Ah! They've sealed the ship.
-We've got to get out of here!
-I know!
The teleport!
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
-How did you get in there?
-Alfie!
Here's your daddy.
(ALFIE GIGGLING)
That was another review, 10 out of 10.
The Cybermen, they blew up.
I blew 'em up with love.
No, that's impossible.
And also, grossly sentimental
and oversimplistic.
You destroyed them
because of the deeply ingrained
hereditary human trait
to protect one's own genes.
Which, in turn, triggered a...a...a...
Yeah. Love.
You blew them up with love.
The building should be totally safe,
structurally, and of course,
the bonded dyscillium
contained the explosion.
Right. Why are you telling me all this?
I don't know. Shh.
-It suits you.
-Thanks.
-Discount applies to partners.
-Great!
Are you two married, then?
No. No, we talked about it, but
it's just a piece of paper, isn't it?
Thank you for your help, Val.
Good noticing, keep 'em peeled.
I will. I'm glad you two made up,
for baby's sake.
Aw.
How do you mean?
It's nice for baby to have two daddies
who love each other.
Wait. (LAUGHING) Hang on a sec.
Two daddies? You think that I'm...
-His companion.
-(LAUGHS)
Doctor...
VAL: Gone. Now where's he rushed off to?
He's gone.
Who's tidied all this up?
(CHUCKLES)
See? I do come back.
-How did you...
-Time machine.
But even with time travel,
getting glaziers on a Sunday,
tricky.
You went back in time,
that means you used up your hours.
What about Exodor?
What about you being in trouble
with Sophie when she comes back?
I couldn't let that happen.
You used up your time for me?
Course I did, you're me mate.
I notice Stormageddon"s
very quiet and happy.
(GIGGLES)
Oh, he prefers the name Alfie now.
(COOING)
And he's very proud of his dad.
-He calls me Dad?
-Yes, of course he does now.
(GURGLING)
Yeah, I know, he's a bit thick,
isn't he?
(LAUGHING) Oi, shut up, you two.
Well...
Now it's time. I have to go.
Doctor, I know that something's wrong.
I can help you.
Nobody can help me.
Um, I hope Sophie won't mind,
I need these.
-Where are you going to go?
-America.
Sophie will be home any second,
are you sure...
I can't miss this appointment, Craig.
Goodbye, mate.
Wait there. One second.
From Sean's dad.
-Wow.
-You ride 'em, partner.
Oh, thanks!
Bye.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Doctor, that'll be Sophie...
(KNOCKING)
Hello, hello. I forgot my key.
Oh, I missed you so much.
I missed you, too. Both of you.
Are you wearing a papoose?
Yeah, it's...
Oh, my God. The place is spotless.
Has something happened?
You look different.
Nothing happened. Nothing weird.
Look at you two, thick as thieves.
Who's Daddy's little boy, then?
ALFIE: Doctor Who.
What?
Craig?
Well, then, old girl.
One last trip, eh?
Hey.
I'm the Doctor.
I was here to help.
And you are very, very welcome.
It was funny, he seemed so happy
but so sad at the same time.
I was just a kid, I thought maybe he
was a cowboy on his way to a gunfight.
I really liked his hat.
MADAME KOVARIAN:
Tick-tock goes the clock,
and what now shall we play?
now summer's gone away.
Hello?
Such a lovely old song.
But is it about him?
-You know about the Doctor?
-So very well.
Oh, don't try and remember me.
We've been far too thorough
with your dear little head.
(GASPS)
What are they? What are those things?
-Your owners.
-My what?
So they made you a Doctor today,
did they?
Dr River Song.
How clever you are.
You understand what this is, don't you?
According to some accounts,
it's the day the Doctor dies.
"By Silencio Lake,
on the Plain of Sighs
"an Impossible Astronaut will rise
from the deep
"and strike the Time Lord dead.”
It's a story.
And this is where it begins.
(DOOR BUZZES OPEN)
You never really escaped us,
Melody Pond.
We were always coming for you.
-How do you know who I am?
-I made you what you are.
The woman who kills the Doctor.
(YELLING) No! No! No! Oh!
(GASPING)
Tick-tock goes the clock,
and all the years they fly.
Tick-tock, and all too soon,
your love will surely die.
CHILDREN: # Tick-tock goes the clock
# The cradle man, he rocked her
# Tick-tock goes the clock
# Till River kills the Doctor #
Before I go, I'd like to know
why I have to die.
Silence will fall
when the question is asked.
All the times I've heard those words,
I never realised it was my silence,
my death.
(SCREECHING)
It's time.