(WHOOSHING)
Well, here we are! Hedgewick's World!
The biggest and best
amusement park there will ever be
and we've got a golden ticket!
Eh? Eh? Fun!
Fun?
Your stupid box can't even
get us to the right place.
This is like a moon base or something.
Well, it's not the moon.
Actually, I think it does look
like the moon, only dirtier.
Hey, guys. It's not the moon, okay?
It's the Spacey Zoomer ride, or it was.
Psst! Excuse I. I don't suppose
you happen to be my lift off planet?
Dave's Discount Interstellar Removals?
'Fraid not.
You know, they were meant to be here
six months ago.
Well, that's Dave for you, you see,
unreliable.
-CAPTAIN: Stay where you are!
-Whoops!
Throw down your weapons
and identify yourselves!
No! No weapons!
Golden ticket! Spacey Zoomer!
Free ice cream!
Who are you?
This planet is closed by Imperial order.
How's this?
Oh. Welcome, Proconsul.
Wish they'd told us you were coming.
-Any news of the Emperor?
-Oh, the Emperor.
No, no. None that you'd...
We pray for his return.
If there is anything you need,
my platoon is at your service.
Right, righty-o!
Well, carry on, Captain.
CAPTAIN: Platoon! Let's move out!
On the double! Two, three, four.
Two, three, four. Two, three, four.
-Have they gone?
-Yes.
Uniforms. Give me the heebie-jeebies.
Come on.
They can't stop me being here
but they don't like it.
Ha ha!
You see?
I told you it was amazing.
Well, it used to be.
It closed down. Wish I'd known that
before I landed here.
But let me show you my collection.
Come along. Follow me. This way.
This way in. Come on! (CHUCKLES)
Welcome to my ship,
Webley's World of Wonders.
Miracles, marvels and more await you.
I am Impresario Webley.
(COUGHS)
You see before you
waxwork representations.
Of the famous... (CHUCKLES)
...and the infamous.
Anybody here play chess?
Perhaps you, young man.
Actually, I'm in my school chess club.
Ah, follow me.
Now, let me demonstrate to you all
the wonder of the age,
the miracle of modernity.
We defeated them all
a thousand years ago
but now he's back to destroy you.
Behold, the enemy!
Cyberman! Get down!
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
No need to panic, my young friends.
We all know there are
no more living Cybermen.
What you are seeing is a miracle.
The 699th wonder of the universe.
Um, as displayed before
the Imperial Court
and only here to destroy you at chess!
Careful, now. An empty shell.
And yet it moves.
How?
-Magic.
-That might well be, young lady.
But a single penny wins you
five Imperial shillings
if you can beat this empty shell
at chess.
I haven't got a penny
but I've got a sandwich!
All right. Take a seat.
It is free of all devices
and yet it has never been beaten.
Would you like to make the first move,
young man?
Oh, no, Artie. No, don't do that.
That's a fool's mate.
If you can tell me how it works,
I'll give you a silver penny.
I think you do it with mirrors?
Hmm, mirrors. Clever girl.
Well, let's see, hey? Low-tech.
It's a puppet. Mono-filament strings,
which means brains.
-Hello.
-I'm the brains.
-Hello. Give us a hand.
(GRUNTS)
They call me Porridge.
(NECK CRACKING)
Oh, it's good to be out of that box.
For you, miss,
an Imperial penny.
I have not one
but three Cybermen in my collection.
Is that the king?
Emperor Ludens Nimrod Kendrick,
et cetera, et cetera, the 41st.
Defender of humanity,
Imperator of known space.
He looks a bit full of himself.
Don't say things like that
about the Imperial family.
You can end up on the run
for the rest of your life.
They don't sound very nice.
Go on.
If the kids want to ride
the Spacey Zoomer,
then I can operate the gravity console.
Angie!
(KIDS LAUGHING AND EXCLAIMING)
Smile! Say "Spacey Zoomer".
(LAUGHING) Whoa!
-We're flying!
-Having a good time?
I think that was the most fun I've had
in my whole life.
It was...okay.
Clara, I think outer space
is actually very interesting.
Right. Wonderful day out, Doctor,
but time to get the kids home.
Yeah, um, no.
Not actually ready to leave.
-CLARA: Why not?
-Oh, you know.
-Reasons.
-What reasons?
Insects, funny insects.
I should add them
to my funny insect collection.
-You collect funny insects?
-Yeah, I'm starting to.
Right now.
How long do we have to stay here?
Not long. Have a nap.
I'll wake you when
we're ready to leave.
Comfy?
-Sleep well.
-Goodnight.
Don't wander off!
Now, I'm not just saying,
"Don't wander off.”" I mean it.
Otherwise, you'll wander off.
And the next thing you know,
somebody's going to have
to start rescuing somebody.
-From what?
-Nothing!
Nobody needs rescuing from anything.
Don't wander off.
Sweet dreams.
Mmm. Mmm.
Total takings for the day,
one sandwich.
Better than no sandwich, of course.
Not as good as two sandwiches.
Or even a chicken.
That's a bit odd. That's not funny.
Give me my hands back!
CYBERMAN: Upgrade in progress.
(SCREAMS)
ANGIE: I hate the future. It's stupid.
There's not even phone service.
I'm out of here.
The Doctor said not to wander off.
He said that and then he wandered off.
I don't think Clara would like that.
She's not our mum.
Don't leave me here.
Was this really the biggest
amusement park in the universe?
Yeah. Hedgewick bought the planet cheap.
It had been trashed in the Cyberwars.
-Who were we fighting?
-Cybermen.
Technologically upgraded warriors.
We couldn't win.
Sometimes we fought to a draw
but then they'd upgrade themselves,
fix the weaknesses and destroy us.
It's hard to fight an enemy that uses
your army as its spare parts.
You beat them, though. You beat them
or you wouldn't be here. How?
Look up there.
That corner of sky, what do you see?
Nothing. It's just black.
No stars, no nothing.
Well, it used to be
the Tiberian Spiral Galaxy.
A million star systems,
a hundred million worlds,
a billion trillion people.
It's not there any more.
No more Tiberian Galaxy.
No more Cybermen.
It was effective.
-It's horrible.
-Yeah.
-I feel like a monster sometimes.
-Why?
Because instead of mourning
a billion trillion dead people,
I just feel sorry for the poor blighter
who had to press the button
and blow it all up.
Clara, did you tell Angie she could
go to the barracks?
You know I didn't.
-She hasn't.
-She's just gone in there.
Come on.
I can't fix this.
It can't be broken. It's a solid state
sub-ether ansible-class communicator.
Just run the diagnostics.
There's nothing left to diagnose.
It's not broken, it's empty.
All the components have gone.
Well, you must have replacement parts.
Not enough to build a new one!
Captain, the weather controller
is malfunctioning again.
There's storms, heatwaves, snow.
(BELL RINGING)
Hello? I'm bored.
Where's your big sister?
Clara? She's not my sister.
She's stupid.
She's talking to Porridge.
She talks to her porridge?
Porridge, that little bloke.
We need to have a chat.
I'm not scared, if you're wondering.
I just think I ought
to turn the lights back on.
(GASPS)
(POWER BUZZING)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
So, tell me about the little bloke.
Well, you must have seen him.
Angie!
She always has to turn up
and spoil everything.
I wasn't doing anything!
Why can't you just leave me alone?
-Cyberman!
-Angie!
Attack formation!
(SHOUTING)
No!
Attack formation, quickly!
CYBERMAN: Upgrade in progress.
Angie!
(SCREAMS)
CLARA: Angie!
DOCTOR: Clara, Clara!
That was a Cyberman.
But they're extinct!
Listen to me, I will get her back.
Captain, a word, please.
Now, correct me if I'm wrong,
but I take it your platoon
doesn't do much fighting.
-What do you expect?
-What?
We're a punishment platoon.
That's why they sent us out here,
so we can't get into trouble.
Right, right, well, okay.
As Imperial consul,
I'm putting Clara in charge.
Clara, stay alive until I get back.
And don't let anyone
blow up this planet.
Is that something they're likely to do?
Get to somewhere defensible.
-Where are you going?
-I'm getting Angie,
finding Artie
and looking for funny insects.
Stay alive.
And you lot, no blowing up this planet!
Put me down! I hate you!
Artie? Artie, what's happening?
(ROBOTIC VOICE) Please stand by.
You will be upgraded.
(SCREAMING)
Cyberiad-class weaponry.
I've taken it out of storage.
Good. We need to find somewhere
defensible, where?
The Beach.
Giant's Cauldron.
Natty Longshoe's Comical Castle.
-Real castle? Drawbridge? Moat?
-Yes, but comical.
We'll go there.
Ma'am, my platoon can deal with
one Cyberman
and there are protocols if we cannot
immediately find and destroy it.
-Blowing up the planet protocols?
-Respectfully, ma'am...
Somewhere defensible.
No blowing up the planet.
She's your commanding officer now,
isn't she, Captain?
Yes.
Sir.
-You really saw a Cyberman?
-We really did.
Have you reported it to the Imperium?
-No communicators.
-So you're going to do what she says?
Right, let's all spend the night at
Natty Longshoe's Comical Castle.
Artie!
Firstly,
if anybody's watching this,
those children are under my protection,
I'm coming to get them.
And secondly, little metal machine,
you are beautiful.
(STATIC NOISE)
Not even a Cybermat any more, eh?
Cybermites.
Now, there's a local transmat link
open to your home,
if I can just find the frequency.
Hey, that really shouldn't have worked.
ARTIE: Doctor, help her.
Angie! Artie!
Webley?
We needed children
but the children had stopped coming.
You brought us children.
Hail to you, the Doctor.
Saviour of the Cybermen!
CLARA: What would the Empire do
if they were alerted?
I told you, they'd tell me
to blow up the planet.
After they got us off.
-Captain, you want to take that one?
-No, ma'am, just blow the sucker up.
Drawbridge, moat, brilliant.
With respect, ma'am,
we ought to be hunting the creature.
The only reason I'm still alive
is because I do what the Doctor says.
Can you guarantee me you'd bring me back
my children alive and unharmed?
-I trust the Doctor.
-You think he knows what he's doing?
I'm not sure I'd go that far.
As the battle raged between
humanity and the Cyberiad,
the Cyberplanners built a Valkyrie
to save critically damaged units
and bring them here
and, one by one, repair them.
The people who vanished from
the amusement park,
they were spare parts for repairs?
We've upgraded ourselves.
The next model will be undefeatable.
Nothing's undefeatable.
We needed children
to build a new Cyberplanet.
A child's brain, with its infinite
potential, is perfect for our needs.
But we no longer need the children.
The Cybermites have been scanning
your brain, Doctor.
-It's quite remarkable.
-Also completely useless to you.
Cybermen use human parts.
I'm not human.
You can't convert non-humans.
Well, that was true a long time ago
but we've upgraded ourselves.
Current Cyberunits use almost
any living components.
(GASPING)
(BEEPING)
(MOANING)
Ahh!
Incorporated, yes.
Ahh, unfamiliar pulmonary setup.
Nervous system hyperconductive.
Remarkable brain processing speed.
(LAUGHING)
Amazing.
Get out of my head!
Stop rummaging in my mind!
Just you try and stop me.
Ooh...
Who's Clara? Why are you thinking
about her so much?
Enough.
Fascinating, a complete mental block.
Highly effective.
Ugh! Relax, relax.
If you just relax, you will find this
a perfectly pleasant experience.
You are being upgraded and incorporated
into the Cyberiad as a Cyberplanner.
Get out of my head!
What is this place? A network?
A hive? You're getting signals
from every Cyberman everywhere.
And there you are, there.
Oh...
This is brilliant!
I'm so clever already
and now I'm a million times more clever
and what a brain!
Not a human brain,
not even slightly human.
I mean, I'm going to have to completely
rework the neural interface
but this is going to be
the most efficient
Cyberplanner!
Not a great name, that, is it?
I could call myself...
Mr Clever.
So much raw data. Time Lords.
There's information
on the Time Lords in here.
Oh, this is just dreamy.
Right.
I'm allowing you access to memories
on Time Lord regeneration.
(LAUGHING)
Fantastic!
I could regenerate now.
Big blast of regeneration energy,
burn out any little
Cyber-widgets in my brain.
Along with everything you're
connected to. Don't want to.
Use this me up, eh,
who knows what we'll get next?
But I can.
Stalemate, then.
One of us needs to control this head.
We're too well-balanced.
What did you say? No, no, no, no.
I heard you.
Rhetorical device to keep me
thinking about it a bit more.
Stalemate.
We each control 49.881% of this brain.
0.238 of the brain
is still in the balance.
Whoever gets this gets the whole thing.
Do you play chess?
The rules of chess
are in my memory banks.
You're proposing we play chess
to end the stalemate?
Winner takes all.
Nobody can access that portion
of the brain without winning the game.
(ELECTRIC ECHO)
You can't win!
Try me.
You understand, when I do win
the Cyberiad gets
your brains and memories?
All of it.
Yeah, when I win,
you get out of my head,
you let the children go
and nobody dies.
You got that?
Nobody dies!
MAN ON RADIO:
Castle clear. Missy, confirm status.
All clear in the power station.
(THUD)
It's Missy.
Something's out there.
What do you mean?
Did you see the Cyberman?
I don't know, I couldn't see it.
It was only for a moment.
Can I hide? Is it okay if I hide?
Don't move! I'm in the army!
Oh, God.
(EXHALING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMS)
Uh, ma'am, Missy said she saw something
and then she went quiet.
It's on its way, then. Weapons. Show me.
Only one gun?
Cybermen have been extinct
for a thousand years.
Even one anti-Cyber gun is a miracle.
These things are hand pulsers.
Touch the back of a Cyberman's head,
the electromagnetic pulse
deactivates it.
And what's this for? Just a mad
guess here. It blows up the planet?
Implodes it.
There's also a trigger unit.
I'll have that, then.
Is there any other way to activate
the bomb?
It's set to respond to my voice.
I have the verbal code.
You will not activate it without
a direct order from me.
I will follow my orders.
Your orders come from me, don't they?
You'll need to sign for that
trigger unit, ma'am.
Thanks.
Mind if I take one of these?
Might be handy.
Help yourself. I'll teach you
how to use it, upstairs.
Now.
There, that was easy.
The game has just started.
Doctor, why is there no record of
you anywhere in the data banks
of the Cyberiad?
Oh. You're good.
Oh, you've been eliminating yourself
from history.
You know, you could be reconstructed
by the hole you've left.
Good point.
I'll do something about that.
The rules of chess allow only
a finite number of moves.
And I can use other Cyberunits
as remote processors.
You cannot possibly win!
I can. I know things you don't.
For example, did you know
very early versions of
the Cyber operating system
could be seriously scrambled by exposure
to things like gold or cleaning fluid?
And what's interesting is
you're still running some of that code.
Really?
That's your secret weapon?
Cleaning fluid?
Nope, gold!
Oh! Like a charm.
Right, you, Cyber-Webley, and you,
kid things, I'll bring the chess board,
let's get out of here.
(BEEPING)
You knew it was me.
I was in the Imperial Guard
on Caspartine.
Mostly just parades but I had the
honour to guard the old Emperor.
During the ice picnic.
When the snow bears came
and danced for us. That was a day.
We're a punishment platoon.
We can't beat a Cyberman.
The Imperium has to know
what's happening.
Like you said,
the communicators are out.
The only way you can report this now
is to activate the bomb.
-Yes!
-And I forbid you to do that.
I don't get it.
Why would you blow up
a whole planet and everybody on it
just to get rid of one Cyberman?
We tried other ways but they only
worked sometimes.
So now we take drastic action.
And it works.
If you find a Cyberman
and you can't destroy it immediately,
you implode the planet.
I was sent here
because I didn't follow orders.
I can make up for that.
Put it down, I forbid you!
Yeah! What she said.
You ran away.
I will do what I was brought up to do.
Live for the Empire, fight
for the Empire, die for the Empire!
This is Captain Alice Ferry,
Imperial ID 1-9-Delta-1-3-B. Activate...
Cyberman, get down!
The Doctor said to get somewhere
easily defensible.
But if we just stay in the castle,
he'll pick us off one by one.
We have to take it out!
Is that an order, ma'am?
-Yes.
-Good.
You know what to do.
Pulse to the back of the head,
fry the brain circuit interface.
It's going to be hard to get in
close enough.
(GRUNTING)
I've heard about the Cybermen
since I was in my cradle.
I'm not afraid of you!
Now!
(LAUGHS)
Hold it right there!
What's happening to them?
One more step and I fire!
Don't fire that.
A pulse will deactivate them.
And anyway, it's a waste of charge.
We may need it again.
You don't think that
was the only one, then?
Ah! Don't shoot, don't shoot!
I'm nice. Please, don't shoot.
Hey, Clara, you haven't let them
blow up the planet. Good job.
Did you get the kids? Are they
all right? What's going on?
Um, bit of a good news, bad news,
good news again thing going on.
So, good news,
I kidnapped the Cyberplanner
and right now I'm sort of
in control of this Cyberman.
Bad news?
Bad news,
the Cyberplanner is in my head
and different bad news, the kids are...
Well, it's complicated.
Complicated how?
Complicated as in walking coma.
Oh!
-Please tell me you can wake them up.
-Hope so!
-Other good news?
-Well, in other good news,
there are a few more repaired
and reactivated Cybermen on the way
and the Cyberplanner's
installing a patch for the gold thing.
No, wait, that isn't
good news, is it? Um...
So, good news, I have a very good chance
of winning my chess match!
-What?
-I'll explain later.
In a bit of a hurry. Get me to a table!
And somebody tie me up!
Need hands free for chess.
But immobilise me. Quickly.
Right, that's good. I won't be able
to move but hands free, good.
-You're playing chess with yourself?
-And winning.
Actually, he has no better
than a 25% chance of winning
at this stage in the game.
Some very dodgy moves at the beginning.
Hello, flesh girl. Fantastic!
I'm the Cyberplanner.
-Doctor?
-Afraid not. I'm working the mouth now.
Allons-y! Oh, you should see the state
of these neurons.
He's had some cowboys in here.
Ten complete rejigs.
You aren't the Doctor.
No, but I know who you are.
You're the impossible girl.
Oh, he's very interested in you.
-Why am I impossible?
-Hasn't he told you, the sly devil?
Dear me. Listen. Soon we wake.
We'll strip you down for spare parts,
then build a spaceship and move on.
More Cybermen?
They're waking from their tomb
right now.
You can either die
or live on as one of us.
The Doctor will stop you.
He can't even access the lips.
Ow!
Ow! Oh, that hurt.
No, stop, enough, bit of pain, neural
surge, just what I needed. Thank you.
-Why am I the impossible girl?
-It's just a thing in my head,
-I'll explain later.
-Chess game. Stakes?
If he wins, I give up my mind
and he gets access to all my memories
along with knowledge of time travel,
but if I win, he'll break his promises
to get out of my head
and then kill us all anyway.
-That's not reassuring!
-No.
Please tell me you can fix
whatever happened to the children.
Children. Yeah, they're fine.
I mean, right now their brains
are just in standby mode.
-That is not fine!
-Listen.
Right now, they have
a much better chance
of getting out of this situation alive
than you do.
Which one of you said that?
Me, Cyberplanner. Mr Clever.
Now, if you don't mind,
I have a chess game to finish.
And you have to die, pointlessly
and very far from home.
Toodle-o00.
CLARA: Apparently, there are more
Cybermen on the way.
There's at least a dozen more shots left
in the gun before it needs to recharge.
We might have more than a dozen
Cybermen to worry about.
-What's that cable?
-Power line for the park.
What would happen
if we unhooked the end,
dropped it into the moat
and turned it on?
Fry anything alive
that entered the water.
-Can Cybermen fly?
-No, ma'am.
First good news of the day. Do it!
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
Stop that. I felt that.
Of course you did. It's time to get up.
Wakey-wakey, boys and girls.
Wakey-wakey.
-There. Get that in you. Warm you up.
-Oh, thank you, Porridge.
DOCTOR: Hey, Clara!
I'll see what he wants.
-Call me if there's any change.
-Right.
Hey! Clara, there you are.
Now, quick rundown.
What's our weapon strength?
One big gun,
five of those hand pulser units
and a shiny black bomb
that implodes the planet.
Yeah, yeah. That one. Now, tell me.
Does it happen possibly to have
a sort of remote triggery thing?
-Brilliant. Pass it here.
-No.
-Why not?
-In case you're not you right now.
-Or even if you are, just in case.
-Oh, don't worry.
The Cyberplanner's hibernating
between moves right now.
Shh.
Prove you're you.
Tell me something only the Doctor knows.
Clara...
I suppose
I'm the only one who knows
how I feel about you right now.
How funny you are. So funny.
And pretty.
And the truth is I'm starting to like
you in a way that is more than just...
- (ELECTRIC SURGE)
-Ow! Ow! Ow!
Yes. Ah, it's me. That really hurt.
How did you know that was him?
Because even if that was true,
which it is obviously not,
I know you well enough to know that
you would rather die than say it.
Finish your stupid game!
-Doctor, let go.
-I can't.
He's got control of the left arm.
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
-Doctor?
-He got what he wanted.
He destroyed the trigger. My move.
What do you mean,
he got what he wanted?
He means good news, boys and girls.
They're here!
One gun, five hand pulsers
and a planet-squashing bomb
that doesn't work any more.
-Why not?
-Broken trigger unit.
But you signed for that.
I have learnt so much from you, Doctor.
It's been an education. But now,
it's time for the endgame.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Brilliant.
Upgrade in progress.
Ah.
-Who's our best shot?
-Probably it's me.
Shoot any of them who make it across.
The rest of you,
take defensive positions.
-Porridge?
-Yes?
Keep yourself safe.
(METALLIC MARCHING)
Alice Ferry, you should have destroyed
this planet when you had the chance.
They're nearly here. Now, you can
take my bishop and keep limping on
for a little longer, or you can
sacrifice your queen
and get the children back.
But it's mate in five moves.
And I get your mind.
Go!
Take my queen
and give me back the children.
Emotions! Can't you see
what a foolish move that was?
You've lost the game!
Kids! Back! Now!
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMING)
Emotions, Doctor.
All for two human children
you barely know.
And it was a pointless sacrifice,
anyway.
So, Doctor,
do you think the children's death
will affect your relationship
with Miss Clara?
(EXCLAIMING)
Welcome to Webley's World of Wonders,
children.
Now presenting Delights,
Delicacies and Death.
Doctor!
(ELECTRICAL SURGES)
Angie, are you okay?
Just look after Artie, okay?
Upgrade in progress.
Your move. But before you take it,
just so you know, sacrificing my queen
was the best possible move
I could have made.
The Time Lords invented chess. It's our
game and if you don't avoid my trap,
it gives me mate in three moves.
How?
I've got no charge left!
Come on. Call yourself
a chess-playing robot?
How?
(LAUGHING) Hey, you figure it out.
Or don't you have the processing power?
Hmm?
Please stand by. You will be upgraded.
-Welcome to the Cyberiad.
-Upgraded.
-You will be upgraded.
-Welcome to the Cyberiad.
(SLOWING, GARBLED)
You will be upgraded.
What are you doing?
Doctor. Doctor.
Doctor, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor.
I'm pulling in extra processing power.
Three million Cyberbrains
working on one tiny chess problem.
How long do you think it's going to
take us to solve it?
That's cheating.
No, no, no, no. Just pulling in
the local resources.
(ALL LAUGHING)
There's no way you can get to
mate in three moves.
Three moves!
You want to know what they are?
You're lying!
No!
Move one, turn on sonic screwdriver.
Move two, activate pulser.
Move three, amplify pulser.
(PULSER BEEPING)
See ya.
That's cheating!
Just taking advantage of the local
resources.
Ah, hello.
Could somebody untie me, please?
Do you think I'm pretty?
No. You're too short and bossy
and your nose is all funny.
Good enough.
What happened to the Cyberplanner?
Out of my head and redistributed
across three million Cybermen right now
and about to wake them all up, kill us
and start constructing a spaceship.
We need to destroy this planet before
they can get off it!
Okay. It has a fallback
voice activation.
The Captain, but she's dead.
-I think you should ask Porridge.
-Why?
Well, he is the Emperor.
I bet he knows the activation codes.
Oh, come on, it's obvious.
He looks exactly like he does on
the coin. And on the waxwork.
Except they made him a bit taller.
But look, am I the only one paying
attention to anything around here?
-You are full of surprises. Porridge?
-She's right.
So you can save us?
We all die in the end.
Does it matter how?
What do we do?
I don't want to be emperor.
If I activate that bomb, it's all over.
And if you don't, three million Cybermen
will spread across the galaxy.
Isn't that worth dying for?
-Doctor...
-Three million Cybermen.
The bomb, the throne,
it's all connected.
I just have to say,
"This is Emperor Ludens Nimrod
Kendrick Cordlongstaff the 41st,
"defender of humanity,
Imperator of known space.
"Activate the desolator."”
And it's done.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
It'll blow in about 80 seconds, easily
long enough for the Imperial flagship
to locate me from my identification,
warp jump into orbit and transmat us
to the state room.
Nice ship. A bit big.
Not blue enough. Listen,
there is a large blue box
at coordinates 6-Ultra-19-P.
I need it transmatted
up here right away.
Right. Did you get that?
And that's that. 76, 77, 78, 79...
Farewell, Cyberiad.
You know, it was good to get away.
Good to be a person.
Good not to be lonely or emperor of
a thousand galaxies
with everyone waiting for me
to tell them what to do.
Can't you run away again?
They'll be keeping
a close eye on me this time.
That's what happens when you're emperor.
-Loneliest job in the universe.
-You don't have to be lonely.
I don't.
Clara, will you marry me?
What?
-He said...
-She heard what he said.
You're smart and you're beautiful
and I've never met
anyone like you before.
And being Emperor won't be as hard
if you're by my side.
And you'd rule a thousand galaxies.
This sounds like
an actual marriage proposal. Tricky.
Now, if you want my advice...
You, not one word.
This is between me and the Emperor.
Porridge, I don't want
to rule a thousand galaxies.
Yeah, silly of me.
-I'm really sorry.
-But that's stupid.
You could be queen of the universe.
How can you say no to that?
When someone asks you if you want
to be queen of the universe,
you say yes. You watch.
One day, I'll be queen of the universe.
Of course, I could
have you all executed,
which is what a proper emperor would do.
You're not actually going
to do that, though, are you? It's...
-(LAUGHING)
-Oh, you're... Hey?
Go on, get out of here. All of you.
Before I change my mind.
Thank you for having me.
It was very interesting.
My pleasure. Thank you for coming.
Now, I've got something for you.
It's not from me, it's from the Tardis.
-Ah! New phone.
-Thanks!
-You're welcome.
-Sorry I said this box was stupid.
Bye!
-Bye!
-ARTIE: Thanks, Clara.
Thanks, Clara's boyfriend.
(DOOR CLOSES)
-Thank you, Doctor.
-For what?
Kids day out,
getting us off the planet alive,
whatever you were doing
with the Cybermen.
Goodnight.
-See you next Wednesday!
-Well, a Wednesday, definitely.
Next Wednesday, last Wednesday.
One of the Wednesdays.
Impossible girl.
A mystery wrapped in an enigma,
squeezed into a skirt that's
just a little bit too tight.
What are you?
Signs of any Cybertech remaining?
No, Majesty.
Have you ever wanted
to be Emperor, Gloria?
No, Majesty.
That's the right answer.
Come on, let's go home.
DOCTOR: There is one place
you must never go.
CLARA: Where?
VASTRA:
This is the Doctor's greatest secret.
And it is discovered.
RIVER SONG: He can't go there,
you know he can't.
I have a duty.
CLARA: You just said it's one place
you must never go.
DOCTOR: I'm about to cross my
own timeline in the biggest way possible
but the Tardis doesn't like it...
Die, reptile!
Doctor! Doctor!
What is your name?
-It's... Doctor.
-Doctor Who?!