-(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
-Stop it!
Stop it! Stop whispering!
Stop!
(WHISPERING STOPS)
(SIGHS)
(SHOUTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Leave me alone!
You're not real!
I know you're not real.
You're just voices inside my head.
Leave me alone!
(SNARLING)
What do you want from me, hmm?
The Doctor.
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
Do you want to live?
You can save me?
We can give you information.
These symbols. You will memorise them.
I don't...
(GROANING)
Their meaning and purpose
ls now within your mind.
You will give this information
to the reptile detective.
What kind of men are you?
We are not men. We are the Intelligence.
All of time and space is known to us.
Will this save me? Huh?
WillL I still hang tomorrow?
A pardon will be yours.
The rope will not.
Will you finally leave me alone?
You will live a good, long life.
Except you will always have
such trouble sleeping.
No. No!
(SNARLING)
You leave me alone.
Leave me alone! You are not real!