My time is running out.
You understand what this is, don't you?
Melody Pond.
The woman who kills the Doctor.
-How do you know who I am?
-I made you what you are.
One last trip, eh?
Whatever happens now,
you do not interfere.
A robot worked by tiny people.
Access personal records, the Doctor.
Records available.
-Who wants me dead?
-The Silence.
The Silence is not a species.
It is a religious order or movement.
Their core belief is that silence
will fall when the question is asked.
What question?
The first question.
The oldest question in the universe.
Hidden in plain sight.
Yes, but what is the question?
Unknown.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
RADIO ANNOUNCER: And it's another
beautiful day in London.
There are reports of sunspot activity
and solar flares
causing interference across all radio
signals, so apologies for that.
Guys, look!
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
MAN ON TV: So, do you think you can
top last year's Christmas special?
And can you tell us anything about it?
Well all I can say now
is that it involves ghosts in the past
and the present and the future,
all at the same time.
Oh, we love a ghost story.
(LAUGHING)
Crowds lined the Mall today as the
Holy Roman Emperor, Winston Churchill,
returned to the Buckingham Senate
on his personal mammoth.
Not too many late nights in Gaul,
I hope?
Just the one.
I had an argument with Cleopatra,
dreadful woman.
Oh, excellent dancer.
I can tell from your blood pressure.
What time do you have, Doctor?
Two minutes past five, Caesar.
It's always two minutes past five.
Day or night,
it's always two minutes past five
in the afternoon.
Why is that?
-Because that is the time, Caesar.
-And the date.
It's always the 22nd of April.
Does it not bother you?
The date and the time
have always been the same, Caesar.
Why should it start bothering me now?
I want to see the soothsayer,
where is he?
In the Tower.
-Where you threw him the last time.
-Get him!
Leave us.
Tick-tock goes the clock.
As the old song says.
But they don't, do they?
The clocks never tick.
Something has happened to time.
That's what you say,
what you never stop saying.
All of history is happening at once.
But what does that mean?
What happened?
Explain to me
in terms that I can understand.
What happened to time?
A woman.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
DOCTOR: Imagine you were dying.
Imagine you were afraid and a long way
from home, and in terrible pain.
Just when you thought
it couldn't get worse,
you looked up
and saw the face of the Devil himself.
Hello, Dalek.
DALEK: Emergency! Emergency!
Weapons system disabled!
(PITCH CHANGING)
Emergency protocol put in place...
Hush now, I need some information
from your data core.
Everything the Daleks know
about the Silence.
Gideon Vandaleur. Get him. Now.
Who says he's here?
Father Gideon Vandaleur.
Former envoy of the Silence.
-(WHISPERING) My condolences.
-Your what?
Gideon Vandaleur has been dead
for six months.
(SONIC SCREWDRIVER BUZZING)
Can I speak to the Captain, please?
DOCTOR: Hello again.
The Tesselecta time-travelling,
shape-changing robot,
powered by miniaturised people.
Never get bored of that.
Long time since Berlin.
Doctor, what have you done
to our systems?
DOCTOR: 04, it'll be fine if you behave.
Now, this unit can disguise itself
as anyone in the universe.
So, if you're posing as Vandaleur,
you're investigating the Silence.
Tell me about them.
-Tell you what?
-One thing. Just one.
Their weakest link.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
The crowd are getting restless.
They know the queen
is your only legal move.
Except you've already moved it 12 times,
which means there are now over
four million volts running through it.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
That's why they call it live chess.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
Even with the gauntlet, you'll never
make it to bishop 4 alive.
I am a dead man
unless you concede the game.
But I'm winning.
-Name your price.
-Information.
I work for the Silence.
They would kill me.
They're going to kill me, too,
very soon.
I was just going to lie down
and take it. But you know what?
Before I go, I'd like to know
why I have to die.
Dorium Maldovar.
-He's the only one who can help you.
-Dorium's dead.
-The Monks beheaded him at Demon's Run.
-I know.
Concede the game, Doctor,
and I'll take you to him.
The Seventh Transept.
Where the Headless Monks
keep the leftovers.
Watch your step,
there are traps everywhere.
I hate rats.
-There are no rats in the Transept.
-Oh, good.
The skulls eat them.
The Headless Monks behead you alive,
remember?
DOCTOR: Why are some of them in boxes?
Because some people are rich
and some people are left to rot.
And Dorium Maldovar was always
very rich.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(SNEEZING)
-Thank you for bringing me, Gantok.
-My pleasure.
It saves me the trouble of burying you.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
Nobody beats me at chess.
(SCREAMING)
Gantok!
(HISSING)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
Hello? Is someone there?
Ah, Doctor. Thank God it's you.
The Monks, they turned on me.
Well, I'm afraid they rather did a bit.
Give it to me straight, Doctor.
How bad are my injuries?
Well...
(LAUGHING)
-Oh, your face.
-Yes...
This is absurd. Other worlds?
Carnivorous skulls? Talking heads?
I don't know why I'm listening to you.
Because in another reality,
you and I are friends.
And you sense that.
Just as you sense
there is something wrong with time.
-You mentioned a woman.
-Yes.
-I'm getting to her.
-What's she like?
-Attractive, I assume?
-Hell...
in high heels.
Tell me more.
Oh, it's not so bad, really.
As long as they get your box
the right way up.
I got a media chip fitted in my head
years ago
and the Wi-Fi down here is excellent.
So I keep myself entertained.
-I need to know about the Silence.
-Oh.
A religious order of great power
and discretion.
The sentinels of history,
as they like to call themselves.
And they want me dead?
No, not really. They just don't want
you to remain alive.
That's okay, then.
I was a bit worried for a minute there.
You're a man with a long
and dangerous past.
But your future is infinitely
more terrifying.
The Silence believe it must be averted.
You know, you could have told me
all this the last time we met.
(SIGHS) It was a busy day
and I got beheaded.
What's so dangerous about my future?
On the Fields of Trenzalor
at the fall of the Eleventh,
when no living creature could speak
falsely or fail to answer,
a question will be asked.
A question that must never,
ever be answered.
"Silence will fall
when the question is asked."
"Silence must fall"
would be a better translation.
The Silence are determined that
the question will never be answered,
that the Doctor
will never reach Trenzalor.
I don't understand.
What's it got to do with me?
The first question.
The oldest question in the universe,
hidden in plain sight.
-Would you like to know what it is?
-Yes.
Are you sure?
Very, very sure?
Of course.
Then I shall tell you.
But on your own head be it.
(CHUCKLING)
It's not my fault. Put me back!
Ow!
I've fallen on my nose!
Have you got Wi-Fi here? I'm bored
already. And my nose is hurting.
We all have to die, Doctor.
But you more than most.
You do see that, don't you?
You know what the question is now.
You do see that you have to die.
But what was the question?
Why did it mean your death?
Suppose there was a man
who knew a secret,
a terrible, dangerous secret
that must never be told?
How would you erase that secret
from the world,
destroy it forever,
before it can be spoken?
If I had to,
I'd destroy the man.
And Silence would fall.
All the times I've heard those words,
I never realised it was my silence.
My death.
The Doctor will fall.
-Why are we here?
-This?
-This is the senate room.
-Why did we leave your office?
Well, we wanted to stroll, didn't we?
I think I've been running.
Why do you have your revolver?
Well...
you're dangerous company, soothsayer.
Yes.
I think I am.
Resume your story?
Doctor.
Please. Open my hatch.
I've got an awful headache.
Which, to be honest,
means more than it used to.
It's like some terrible weight
pressing down on my...
Oh. I see.
Why Lake Silencio? Why Utah?
It's a still point in time.
Makes it easier to create a fixed point.
And your death is a fixed point, Doctor.
You can't run away from this.
Been running all my life,
why should I stop?
Because now you know what's at stake,
why your life must end.
Not today.
What's the point in delaying?
How long have you delayed already?
Been knocking about,
bit of a farewell tour.
Things to do. People to see.
There's always more.
I can invent a new colour.
Save the dodo. Join the Beatles.
Hello! It's me. Get him. Tell him
we're going out and it's all on me
except for the money and the driving.
I have got a time machine,
Dorium, it's all still going on.
For me, it never stops.
Liz I is still waiting in a glade
to elope with me.
I could help Rose Tyler
with her homework.
I could go on all Jack's stag parties
in one night...
Time catches up with us all, Doctor.
Well, it has never laid a glove on me!
-Hello?
-Doctor, I'm so sorry.
We didn't know how to contact you.
I'm afraid Brigadier Lethbridge-Stewart
passed away.
A few months ago.
-Doctor?
-(STUTTERS) Yeah...
-Yes, yes, er...
-It was very peaceful.
He talked a lot about you,
if that's any comfort.
Always made us pour an extra brandy
in case you came round
one of these days.
Doctor, what's wrong?
Nothing, I...
just...
It's time.
Surely you could deliver the messages
yourself?
It would involve crossing
my own time stream.
Best not.
According to our files,
this is the end for you.
Your final journey.
We'll deliver your messages.
You can depend on us.
Thank you.
Doctor?
Whatever you think of the Tesselecta,
we are champions of law and order,
just as you've always been.
Is there nothing else we can do?
CHURCHILL: Why would you do this?
Of all the things you've told me,
this I find hardest to believe.
Why would you invite your friends
to see your death?
If I had to die,
I didn't have to die alone.
-Doctor!
-(LAUGHING) It's the Pond!
DOCTOR: Amy and Rory. The Last Centurion
and the girl who waited.
However dark it got,
I'd turn around and there they'd be.
If it's time to go,
remember what you're leaving.
Remember the best.
My friends have always been
the best of me.
And did you tell them
this was going to happen?
It would help if you didn't keep
asking questions.
(WHISPERING) We don't have much time.
(GUNSHOT FIRING)
CHURCHILL: And this woman you spoke of,
did you invite her?
Hello, sweetie.
DOCTOR: Yes, she was there.
River Song came twice.
Napoleon gave me this bottle.
Well, I mean, I said "gave". Threw.
Salut!
ALL: Salut!
So, when are we going to 19697
DOCTOR: Everything was in place.
I only had to do one more thing.
I only had to die.
Oh, my God!
You all need to stay back.
Whatever happens now,
you do not interfere.
RORY: That's an astronaut.
-That's an Apollo astronaut in the lake.
-Look...
Well, then.
Here we are at last.
I can't stop it. The suit's in control.
You're not supposed to.
This has to happen.
-Run!
-I did run.
-Running brought me here
-I tried to fight it, but I can't.
-It's too strong.
-I know.
It's okay.
This is where I die.
This is a fixed point. This must happen.
This always happens.
Don't worry.
You won't even remember this.
Look over there.
It's me.
How can I be there?
That's you from the future,
serving time for a murder
you probably can't remember.
-My murder.
-Why would you do that?
-Make me watch?
-So that you know this is inevitable.
And you are forgiven.
Always and completely forgiven.
Please, my love.
Please, please, just run.
-Can't.
-Time can be rewritten.
Don't you dare.
Goodbye, River.
(RIVER GRUNTING)
Hello, sweetie.
What have you done?
Well, I think I just drained
my weapon systems.
But it's fixed.
-This is a fixed point in time.
-Fixed points can be rewritten.
No, they can't. Of course they can't.
Who told you?
Well, what happened?
-Nothing.
-Nothing?
Nothing happened.
And then it kept happening.
Or, if you'd prefer, everything happened
at once and it won't ever stop.
Time is dying. It's going to be 5:02
in the afternoon for all eternity.
-The needle's stuck on a record.
-A record?
Good Lord, man,
have you never heard of downloads?
Said Winston Churchill.
(SNIFFING) Gun smoke. That's gun smoke.
Oh, I appeared to have fired this.
-We seem to be defending ourselves.
-I don't understand.
The creatures that lead the Silence,
remarkable beings, they're memory-proof.
-But what does that mean?
-Well, you can't remember them.
The moment you look away,
you forget they were ever there.
Don't panic.
In small numbers,
they're not too difficult.
(CHITTERING)
(BEEPING)
Go!
-(SCREAMING)
-Go! Go! Go!
Keep the Silence in sight at all times.
And keep your eye drives active.
Who the devil are you?
Identify yourselves.
Pond.
Amelia Pond.
(LAUGHING)
No! She's on our side.
It's okay, Winston.
DOCTOR: (WHISPERING) No.
No, Amy.
Amy.
Why are you wearing the...
MAN: The government is again apologising
for extensive radio interference
caused by solar flare
and sunspot activity.
Amy.
Those stun guns aren't fun, I'm sorry.
I wanted to avoid a long conversation.
You need to get up, though,
we'll be in Cairo shortly.
Amy Pond.
Amelia Pond from Leadworth,
please, listen to me.
I know it seems impossible,
but you know me.
In another version of reality,
you and I were best friends.
We... We travelled together.
We had adventures.
(GRUNTING)
Amelia Pond.
You grew up with a time rift
in the wall of your bedroom.
You can see what others can't. You can
remember things that never happened.
And if you try, if you really,
really try, you'll be able to...
Oh.
Oh!
You look rubbish.
You look wonderful.
So do you. But don't worry.
-We'll soon fix that.
-Oh.
(LAUGHING)
Geronimo!
Okay, you can turn around now.
How do I look?
-Cool.
-Really?
-No.
-Cool office, though.
Why do you have an office? Are you like
a special agent boss lady or something?
-Not sure about the eye patch, though.
-It's not an eye patch.
Time's gone wrong. Some of us noticed.
There's a whole team of us
working on it. You'll see.
And you've got an office on a train!
That is so cool!
Can I have an office?
Never had an office before. Or a train.
Or a train/office.
God, I've missed you!
Okay, hugging and missing now.
-Where's the Roman?
-You mean Rory?
-DOCTOR: Mmm.
-My husband, Rory, yeah? Um...
That's him, isn't it? I have no idea.
I can't find him.
I love him very much, don't I?
Apparently.
I have to keep doing this.
Writing and drawing things.
It's just so hard to keep remembering.
But it's not your fault.
Time's gone wrong.
Do you remember why?
-Lakeside.
-Lake Silencio, Utah. I died.
But then you didn't die. See,
I remember it twice, different ways.
Two different versions
of the same event,
both happening in the same moment.
Time split wide open. Now look at it.
All of history happening at once.
But does it matter?
I mean, can't we just stay like this?
Time isn't just frozen.
It's disintegrating.
It will spread and spread and
all of reality will simply fall apart.
(DOOR OPENING)
Ma'am, we're about to arrive.
Eye drives need to be activated
as soon as we disembark.
Good point.
Thank you, Captain Williams.
Hello.
Hello, sir. Pleased to meet you.
Captain Williams, best of the best.
Couldn't live without him.
(LAUGHING) No!
What is wrong?
Amy, you'll find your Rory,
you always do.
-But you really have to look.
-I am looking!
Oh, my Amelia Pond,
you don't always look hard enough.
Why are you older?
If time isn't really passing,
then how can you be ageing?
Time is still passing for me.
Every explosion has an epicentre.
I'm it.
I'm what's wrong.
What's wrong with you?
I'm still alive.
You have to put it on, sir.
An eye patch? What for?
-It's not an eye patch.
-It's an eye drive, sir.
It communicates directly with the
memory centres of the brain.
Acts as external storage.
Only thing that works on them.
Because no living mind
can remember these things.
The Silence,
we've captured over a hundred
of them now.
All held in this pyramid.
Yeah, I've encountered them before.
Always wondered what they looked like?
AMY: Well, put your eye drive on
and you'll retain the information,
but only for as long
as you're wearing it.
The Silence have human servants,
they all wear these?
-They'd have to.
-This way.
(CLICKING)
They seem to be noticing you.
Yeah, they would.
So why aren't the human race
killing the Silence on sight any more?
That was a whole other reality.
What are the tanks for?
They can draw electricity from anything,
it's how they attack.
The fluid insulates them
and I really don't like the way
they're looking at you.
-Me, neither.
-Ma'am.
I'm sure it's nothing,
but I should really check this out.
They haven't been this active
in a while.
You two, upstairs.
Check all the tank seals.
Then the floors above.
Get everyone checking.
Sir.
-You go ahead, ma'am.
-Thank you, Captain Williams.
Doctor, this way.
DOCTOR: Captain Williams, nice fella.
-What's his first name?
-Captain. Just through here.
Just, uh, give us a moment.
Just need to check something, ma'am.
We're in. He's on his way.
Loyal soldier, waiting to be noticed.
Always the pattern. Why is that?
Sorry, sir?
Your boss, you should just ask her out.
She likes you. She said so.
Really, sir?
CAPTAIN: What did she say?
Oh, she just sort of
generally indicated.
-What exactly did she say?
-She said that
you were a Mr Hottie...ness.
And that she would like to
go out with you for
texting and scones.
You really haven't done this
before, have you?
No, I haven't.
See you in a moment, sir.
Yes.
Come on, Doctor. Time for you
to meet some old friends.
Attention, all personnel.
Please check all the site
containment units.
You were right.
Just his presence in the building
caused the loop to extend
by nearly four cronons.
(BEEPING)
Hi, honey, I'm home.
And what sort of time do you call this?
The death of time.
The end of time.
The end of us all.
Oh, why couldn't you just die?
Did my best, dear, I showed up. You just
can't get the psychopaths these days.
Love what you've done with the pyramids!
How did you swing all this?
Hallucinogenic lipstick.
Works wonders on President Kennedy.
And Cleopatra was a real pushover.
-I always thought so.
-She mentioned you.
-What did she say?
-"Put down that gun.”
-Did you?
-Eventually.
Oh, they're flirting.
Do I have to watch this?
It was such a basic mistake,
wasn't it, Madame Kovarian?
Take a child, raise her into
a perfect psychopath,
introduce her to the Doctor.
Who else was I
going to fall in love with?
That's not funny, River.
Reality is fatally compromised.
Tell me you understand that.
-Dinner?
-I don't have the time.
Nobody has the time.
Because as long as I'm alive,
time is dying, because of you, River.
Because I refuse to kill the man I love.
Oh, you love me, do you?
Aw, that's sweet of you...
-Get him!
-Come here, you.
I'm not a fool, sweetie.
I know what happens if we touch.
Get off me!
Get him off me! Doctor, no, let go!
Please. Let go!
Moving...
-Time's moving!
-Get him off me!
-Doctor!
-I'm sorry, River, it's the only way.
Ah!
Cuff him!
Oh, why do you always have handcuffs?
It's the only way, River. We're the
opposite poles of the disruption.
If we touch, we short out the
differential. Time can begin again.
And I'll be by a lakeside, killing you.
And time won't fall apart.
The clocks will tick.
Reality will continue.
There isn't another way.
I didn't say there was, sweetie.
(CRACKING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
RIVER: There are so many theories
about you and I, you know?
-Idle gossip.
-Archaeology.
-Same thing!
-Am I the woman who marries you
-or the woman who murders you?
-Oh.
-I don't want to marry you.
-I don't want to murder you.
-(WATER DRIPPING)
-DOCTOR: Well, this is no fun at all.
It isn't, is it?
Doctor, what's that?
DOCTOR: The pyramid above us.
How many Silence have you got
trapped inside it?
None. They're not trapped.
They never have been.
They've been waiting.
For this, Doctor.
For you.
They're out! All of them!
(CHITTERING)
MAN: Fall back!
(SCREAMING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
CAPTAIN: No one gets in here.
Ma'am, my men out there
should be able to lock this down.
We have them outnumbered.
And you're wearing eye drives
based on mine, I think. Whoops.
What do you mean?
(SCREAMING)
Help her! Help her!
She's dead.
MAN: Fall back now!
(SCREAMING)
Eye drives off now! Remove them!
Ahh!
The Silence would
never allow an advantage
without taking one themselves.
The effects will vary
from person to person,
either death or debilitating agony.
But they will take you all, one by one.
What are you doing? No, it's me.
Don't be stupid!
You need me.
Stop it!
Stop that!
We can stop this right now, you and I.
Get it off me!
-Amy, tell her!
-We've been working on something.
-Just let us show you.
-No point. There's nothing you can do.
-My time is up.
-We're doing this for you!
And people are dying for me.
I won't thank you for that, Amelia Pond.
-Just let us show you.
-Please!
Captain Williams, how long do we have?
Ah, a couple of minutes?
That's enough.
We're going to the receptor room,
right at the top of the pyramid.
I hope you're ready for a climb.
I'll wait down here, ma"am,
buy you as much time as I can.
-You'll have to take your eye drive off.
-Can't do that, ma'am.
-Can't forget what's coming.
-But it could activate any second.
It has activated, ma'am.
But I'm of no use to you
if I can't remember.
You have to go now, ma'am!
-Yes.
-Now.
Yes. Thank you, Captain Williams.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(SCREAMING)
SILENT: Rory Williams,
the man who dies
and dies again.
Die one last time.
And know she will
never come back for you.
(RORY SCREAMING)
Come on, you, up you get. You all right?
(SHOUTING)
Amy, help me.
You took my baby from me.
And hurt her.
And now she's all grown up
and she's fine,
but I'll never see my baby again.
But you'll still save me, though.
Because he would.
And you'd never do anything to
disappoint your precious Doctor.
Ma'am, we have to go, now!
The Doctor is very precious to me,
you're right.
But do you know what else he is,
Madame Kovarian?
Not here.
(GASPING) Ah!
River Song didn't get it all from you,
sweetie.
(SCREAMING)
So, you and me, we should
get a drink sometime.
-Okay.
-I'm married.
Fine.
(MEN SCREAMING)
What's this? Oh, it's a tiny-winy
distress beacon. Who built this?
I'm in charge of the Tardis.
I understand the physics.
Yes, but that's all you've got,
is a distress beacon?
I've been sending out a message.
A distress call.
Outside the bubble of our time,
the universe is still turning
and I've sent a message everywhere.
To the future and the past,
the beginning and the end of everything.
"The Doctor is dying,
"please, please help."
River! River, this is ridiculous!
That would mean nothing to anyone.
It's insane!
Worse, it's stupid!
You embarrass me!
We barricaded the door,
we've got a few minutes. Just tell him.
Just tell him, River!
Those reports of the sunspots
and the solar flares,
they're wrong. There aren't any.
It's not the sun. It's you.
The sky is full
of a million, million voices
saying, "Yes, of course. We'll help."
You've touched so many lives,
saved so many people.
Did you think when your time came
you'd really have to do
more than just ask?
You've decided that the universe
is better off without you.
But the universe doesn't agree.
River, no one can help me.
A fixed point has been altered.
Time is disintegrating.
I can't let you die!
-But I have to die!
-Shut up!
I can't let you die
without knowing you are loved.
By so many, and so much!
And by no one more than me.
River, you and I,
we know what this means.
You know, we are ground zero of an
explosion that will engulf all reality.
Billions on billions
will suffer and die.
I'll suffer if I have to kill you.
More than every living
thing in the universe?
Yes.
River, River. Why do you
have to be this?
Melody Pond! Your daughter!
I hope you're both proud!
I'm not sure I completely understand.
Um, we got married
and had a kid and that's her.
Okay.
Amy, uncuff me now.
Okay, I need a strip of cloth
about a foot long. Anything will do.
Never mind. River, take one end of this.
Wrap it around your hand
and hold it out to me.
-What am I doing?
-As you're told.
Now, we're in the middle
of a combat zone,
so we'll have to do the quick version.
Captain Williams, say,
"I consent and gladly give.”
-To what?
-Just say it! Please.
I consent and gladly give.
Need you to say it, too.
Mother of the bride.
I consent and gladly give.
Now, River, I am about to whisper
something in your ear
and you have to remember it
very, very carefully
and tell no one what I said.
I just told you my name.
Now, there you go, River Song,
Melody Pond.
You're the woman who married me.
And, wife, I have a request.
This world is dying and it's my fault.
And I can't bear it another day.
Please, help me.
There isn't another way.
Then you may kiss the bride.
I'll make it a good one.
You'd better.
DOCTOR: And you are forgiven.
Always and completely forgiven.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(CLOCKS CHIMING)
CHILDREN: # Tick-tock goes the clock
# He gave all he could give her
# Tick-tock goes the clock
# Now prison waits for River #
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
Heard there was a freak
meteor shower two miles away.
So I got us a bottle.
Thank you, dear.
So, where are we?
I just climbed out of the Byzantium.
You were there. So young.
Didn't have a clue who I was.
-Hmm?
-You're funny like that.
Where are you?
The Doctor is dead.
How are you doing?
How do you think?
Well, I don't know, unless you tell me.
I killed someone.
Madame Kovarian.
In cold blood.
In an aborted timeline,
in a world that never was.
Yeah, but I can remember it,
so it happened, so I did it.
What does that make me now?
I need to talk to the Doctor,
but I can't now, can I?
If you could talk to him,
would it make a difference?
He's dead so... So I can't.
Oh, Mother! Of course he isn't!
Not for you, I suppose.
You're seeing the younger versions of
them, running around, having adventures.
Yeah, I am.
But that's not what I mean.
Then what do you mean?
Okay,
I'm going to tell you
what I probably shouldn't.
The Doctor's last secret.
Don't you want to know
what he whispered in my ear?
-He whispered his name.
-Not his name, no.
Yeah, it was. He said it was.
-Rule one?
-The Doctor lies.
So do I. All the time. Have to.
Spoilers.
Pretending I don't know
you're my mother,
pretending I didn't recognise
a space suit in Florida.
-What did he whisper in your ear?
-Oh...
that man!
He was always one step
ahead of everyone. Always a plan.
River, what did he tell you?
River?
(LAUGHING)
(AMY YELPING)
Hey!
(INDISTINCT)
-(RIVER LAUGHING)
-Are you sure, River?
-Are you really, properly sure?
-Of course I'm sure! I'm his wife!
Yes! And I'm his...
mother-in-law.
Father, dear, I think Mummy
might need another drink.
Yes, yes.
DORIUM: Who's carrying me?
I demand to know!
I'm a head. I have rights!
I want my doors open this time.
I demand that my doors are open!
Is it you? It is, isn't it?
It is you. I can sense it!
But how did you do it?
How could you have possibly escaped?
Is there nothing else we can do?
Actually, thinking about it...
Look into my eye.
Shh!
The Tesselecta.
A Doctor in a Doctor's suit.
Time said I had to be on that beach,
so I dressed for the occasion.
Barely got singed in that boat.
So you're going to do this,
let them all think you're dead?
It's the only way.
Then they can all forget me.
I got too big, Dorium, too noisy.
Time to step back into the shadows.
And Dr Song? In prison all her days?
Her days, yes. Her nights...
Well, that's between her and me, eh?
So many secrets, Doctor.
I'll help you keep them, of course.
Well, you're not exactly going anywhere,
are you?
But you're a fool, nonetheless.
It's all still waiting for you.
The Fields of Trenzalor,
the fall of the Eleventh
and the question.
Goodbye, Dorium.
The first question.
The question that must
never be answered!
Hidden in plain sight!
The question you've been
running from all your life!
Doctor who?