DOCTOR: Amy? Amy? Whew..
Amy, it's me, the Doctor.
-Hello. Bit of a situation here.
-(ALARM BLARING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Intruder alert.
I've got my finger on a button,
which is fine,
but as soon as I
take my finger off the button,
the spaceship is going to explode.
(YELLING)
Which is good in one way,
because the spaceship in question
is about to attack the Earth,
but bad in another way
because I'm on the spaceship
and I'm going to get all smithereened.
Now, plan.
I'm going to send you the coordinates
so you can fly the Tardis here
and rescue me.
Only three flaws in this plan,
far as I can see.
One, I don't have the coordinates.
Two, you can't fly the Tardis.
Three... Oh, dear!
You're not even there.
You left ages ago. Oh, well.
I think I just wanted a chat
before all the...
smithereening.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(WHISPERING) Merry Christmas, Amelia.
(HIGH-PITCHED TONE RINGING)