CLARA: One day, you meet the Doctor.
And of course, it's the best day ever.
It's just the best day of your life.
Because... Because he's brilliant
and he's funny and mad.
And best of all, he really needs you.
The trick is
don't fall in love.
I do that trick quite a lot,
sometimes twice a day.
And once you start running,
you start to forget,
slowly.
After a while,
you just stop asking.
Who are you?
Where are you from?
What set you on your way
and where are you going?
Oh.
And what is your name?
You get used to not knowing.
I thought I never would.
I was wrong.
I know who he is.
I know how he began
and I know where he's going.
I learnt the truth about the Doctor
and his greatest secret.
The day we went to Trenzalore.
DOCTOR: From the beginning,
she was impossible.
The impossible girl.
I met her in the Dalek Asylum.
Never saw her face and she died.
I met her again in Victorian London
and she died.
Saved my life both times
by giving her own.
But now she's back.
And we're running together
and she's perfect.
Perfect in every way for me,
except she can't remember
that we ever met.
Clara.
My Clara.
Always brave,
always funny,
always exactly what I need.
Perfect.
Too perfect.
You get used to not knowing.
I thought I never would.
I was wrong.
I know who Clara Oswald is.
I know how she came to be in my life
and I know what she will always mean.
I found out
the day we went to Trenzalore.