(MONITOR BEEPING)
Something wrong?
It's the repair shop.
What kind of idiot would try and steal
a faulty Tardis?
CLARA: Doctor?
-Doctor?
-Yes? What is it? What do you want?
Sorry. But you're about to make
a very big mistake.
CLARA: I don't know where I am.
It's like I'm breaking
into a million pieces
and there's only one thing I remember.
(GASPING)
I have to save the Doctor.
He always looks different.
Doctor!
I always know it's him.
Sometimes I think
I'm everywhere at once,
running every second just to find him.
Doctor!
Just to save him.
(HORN HONKING)
Doctor!
(GASPING)
Doctor?
But he never hears me.
Oi!
Almost never.
I blew into this world on a leaf.
-(HORN BLARING)
-I'm still blowing.
I don't think I'll ever learn.
I'm Clara Oswald.
I'm the impossible girl.
I was born to save the Doctor.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
MAN: Do you hear the Whispermen?
The Whispermen are near.
If you hear the Whispermen,
then turn away your ear.
Do not hear the Whispermen,
whatever else you do.
For once you've heard the Whispermen,
they'll stop
and look at you.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
One word from you
could save me from the rope.
Then you may rely on my silence.
I have information.
Valuable information.
Are you bargaining for your life?
You have the blood of 14 women
on your hands.
There are no words
that can save your neck.
The Doctor.
Ah, yes.
I know all about him,
your dangerous friend.
-How?
-In the babble of the world,
there are whispers,
if you know how to listen.
-The Doctor has a secret, you know.
-He has many.
He has one he will take to the grave.
And it is discovered.
Well?
We can't let that terrible man live.
He lives till I understand
what he told me.
We're going to need a conference call.
I'll send out the invitations,
you fetch the candles.
Yes, ma'am.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
-Where's Strax got to?
-The usual.
-It's his weekend off.
-(SIGHING)
I wish he'd never discovered that place.
(MEN CHANTING) Sontar ha!
Sontar ha!
Yeah!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Out of the way or I'll kill you,
you filthy wee maggot.
Prepare to die in agony
for the glory of the Sontaran Empire!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Excuse me, Master Strax?
What is it, girl?
Can't you see I'm trying to crush
the brains of this stinking primitive?
-Sorry about this.
-Oh, no problem.
It's a telegram, sir. Very urgent.
(SIGHING) Conference call.
Sorry, Archie, I'm going to have
to ask you to render me unconscious.
Fine.
Better use this.
It might take a while.
(SHOUTING)
(VIVALDI'S FOUR SEASONS PLAYING)
-Sleep well, my love.
-You, too.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(BOTH MOANING)
Oh, I like the new desktop.
Mmm. I was getting a little bored
of the Taj Mahal.
Mmm. The tea should be superb.
It's drawn from
one of my favourite memories.
(THUD)
-Strax, good of you to join us.
-It better be important.
I was in the middle of destroying
some very pleasant primitives.
(SIGHING) I apologise
for the interruption
but there is urgent news
concerning the Doctor.
Who else is coming?
The women.
(HUMMING)
Oh, no. You're going to try and make
a souffle again, aren't you?
My mum's souffle, yeah.
Although this time I will get it right.
This time I will be Souffle Girl.
How can it be your mum's souffle
If you're making it?
Because, Artie,
it's like my mum always said,
"The souffle isn't the souffle,
the souffle is the recipe.”
-Was your mum deep on puddings?
-She was a great woman.
-What's this?
-Oh, it arrived today. It's for you.
VASTRA: "My dearest Clara,
"the Doctor entrusted me
with your contact details
"in the event of an emergency.
"And I fear one has now arisen.
"Assuming this letter
will have reached you
"as planned on April 10th, 2013,
"please find and light
the enclosed candle.
"It will release a soporific
which will induce a trance state,
"enabling direct communication
across the years.”
Ew!
"However, as I realise
you have no reason to trust this letter,
"I have taken the liberty
of embedding the same soporific
"into the fabric of the paper
you are now holding.
"Speak soon.”
(GASPING)
So glad you could make it.
-Where am I?
-Exactly where you were, but sleeping.
VASTRA: Time travel
has always been possible in dreams.
We are awaiting
only one more participant.
Oh, no. Not the one
with the gigantic head.
It's hair, Strax.
Ugh! Hair.
-Madame Vastra.
-Professor.
-Help yourself to some tea.
-Why, thank you.
-How did you do that?
-Disgracefully.
Ah, perhaps you two haven't met.
This is the Doctor's companion. Er...
That is, his current
travelling assistant.
-Assistant?
-Have you gone a darker green?
Clara Oswald.
Professor River Song.
The Doctor might have mentioned me?
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah,
of course he has. Professor Song.
Sorry, it's just that
I never realised you were a woman.
Well, neither did I.
Perhaps we should get down
to the business at hand.
That might be good, dear, yes.
VASTRA: Clarence DeMarco, murderer.
Under sentence of death,
he offered us this
in exchange for his life.
Space-time coordinates.
This, Mr DeMarco claims,
is the location of the Doctor's
greatest secret.
-Which is?
-We don't know. It's a secret.
The Doctor does not discuss his secrets
with anyone, my dear.
If you're still entertaining the idea
that you're an exception to this rule,
ask yourself one question.
What is his name?
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
-RIVER SONG: Well, I know it.
-What?
You know his name? He told you?
-I made him.
-CLARA: How?
It took a while.
So... So you were a friend of his, then?
A little more than a friend,
a long time ago.
-He's still never contacted you?
-He doesn't like endings.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(GASPS)
RIVER SONG: So what else
did this DeMarco tell you?
He didn't just buy his life
with some coordinates.
How did he prove their value?
-One word only.
-What word?
A word I've heard in connection
with the Doctor before.
Trenzalore.
How exactly did he describe
what he was giving you?
The Doctor has a secret, you know.
He has one he will take to the grave.
And it is discovered.
You misunderstood.
Ma'am, sorry, I... I just realised
I forgot to lock the door.
It doesn't matter, Jenny.
-What misunderstanding? Tell me.
-No, ma'am, please.
I should have locked up
before we went into the trance.
Jenny, it doesn't matter!
Someone's broken in.
-Someone's with us. I can hear them.
-(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
-(SNARLING)
-Jenny, are you all right?
Sorry, ma'am, so sorry.
So sorry, so sorry.
I think I've been murdered.
Jenny?
-What's happened to her?
-Jenny, can you hear me?
-Speak to us, boy.
-Jenny!
You're under attack.
You must wake up now.
Just wake up! Do it!
(GASPS)
Who are you? What have you done to her?
(SNARLING)
You too, Strax. Wake up now.
(GASPS)
(SNARLING)
WHISPER MEN: Tell the Doctor.
Tell the Doctor.
Tell him what?
His friends are lost for evermore
unless he goes to Trenzalore.
No, you can't say that.
He can't go there. You know he can't.
(DOCTOR CALLING OUT, INDISTINCT)
The Doctor can never go to Trenzalore!
DOCTOR: Am I getting warm? Angie?
Artie? Am I getting warm?
Am I getting warm?
Am I getting warm? Look, I'm pretty sure
you have to tell me if I'm getting warm.
(STAMMERING) I'm pretty sure
that's in the rules.
-Doctor?
-Ha, Clara!
How are you? Don't worry.
Everything is under control.
-What are you doing?
-Oh, um...
Mr Maitland went next door,
so I said I'd look after the kids.
Uh, they wanted to go to the cinema
but I said, "No."
I said, "No, not until you wake up.”
I was very firm.
At which point
they suggested Blind Man's Bluff.
Yes. Where are they?
At the cinema.
The little Daleks!
What's wrong?
So who was she?
The lady with the funny name
and the space hair?
An old friend of mine.
-What, like an ex?
-Yes, an ex.
River asked Vastra for the exact words,
what were they?
"The Doctor has a secret
he will take to the grave.
"It is discovered."
Doctor?
(SOFTLY) Sorry.
And it was Trenzalore?
It was definitely Trenzalore?
Yeah.
Oh, dear.
Sorry. (SNIFFLES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Well?
Trenzalore. I've heard
the name, of course.
Dorian mentioned it, a few others...
We all suspected what it was,
never wanted to find out myself.
River would know, though.
River always knew.
Right. Come here, give me your hand.
Now, the coordinates
you saw will still be in your memory.
I'm linking you
into the Tardis telepathic circuit.
-Won't hurt a bit.
-Ow!
- I lied.
-(TONE WHINING)
Okay, what is Trenzalore?
-Is that your big secret?
-No.
Okay. What, then?
When you are a time traveller,
there is one place you must never go.
One place in all of space and time
you must never,
ever find yourself.
Where?
You didn't listen, did you?
You lot never do, that's the problem.
"The Doctor has a secret he will
take to the grave. It is discovered.”
He wasn't talking about my secret.
No, no, no.
That's not what's been found.
He was talking about my...grave.
Trenzalore is where I'm buried.
-How can you have a grave?
-Because we all do
somewhere out there in the future,
waiting for us.
The trouble with time travel,
you can actually end up visiting.
But you're not going to. You just said
it's one place you must never go.
I have to save Vastra and Strax.
Jenny, too, if it's still possible.
They cared for me during the dark times.
Never questioned me, never judged me,
they were just...
kind.
I owe them, I have a duty.
No point in telling you
this is too dangerous?
None at all.
How can we save them?
Apparently
by breaking into my own tomb.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
-What's that?
-Right.
She's just figured out
where we're going. She's against it.
I'm about to cross my own timeline
in the biggest way possible.
The Tardis doesn't like it.
Because she's fighting it.
Hang on. Hang on!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
-Ah!
-(SCREAMING)
(DOCTOR COUGHING)
-Now what?
-She doesn't want to land.
She's shut down.
So we're not there?
(PANTING)
We must be close.
Okay, so that's where I end up.
I always thought maybe I'd retire,
take up watercolours
or beekeeping or something.
Apparently not.
So, how do we get down there? Jump?
Don't be silly! We fall.
She's turned off practically
everything except the anti-grave.
Guess what I'm turning off?
(CLARA SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(CRASHING)
Oh.
Oops.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You okay?
Visiting your own grave,
anyone would be scared.
It's more than that.
I'm a time traveller.
I've probably time-travelled
more than anyone else.
-Meaning?
-Meaning...
my grave is potentially
the most dangerous place
in the universe.
Well, shall we?
-The gravestones are a bit basic.
-It's a battlefield graveyard.
My final battle.
-Why are some of them bigger?
-They're soldiers.
Bigger the gravestone, higher the rank.
CLARA: It's a hell of a monument.
DOCTOR: It's the Tardis.
-I can see that.
-No.
When a Tardis is dying,
sometimes the dimension dams
start breaking down.
They used to call it a size leak.
All the bigger on the inside
starts leaking to the outside
and it grows.
When I say that's the Tardis,
I don't mean it looks like the Tardis,
I mean it's actually is the Tardis.
My Tardis from the future.
What else would they bury me in?
RIVER SONG: Clara!
Don't speak, don't say my name.
He can't see or hear me, only you can.
-Well, come on, then!
-We're mentally linked.
It's the conference call.
I kept the line open.
Who are you talking to?
We need to get...
River?
-That can't be right.
-No, it can't.
-She's not dead.
-Oh, she's dead, I'm afraid.
She's been dead for a very long time.
Yeah, I probably should have
mentioned that. Never the right time.
But I met her.
Long story.
But her grave can't be here.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(GASPS) Doctor!
(WHISPERING) 7his man must fall,
as all men must.
The fate of all is always dust.
If it isn't my gravestone,
then what is it?
What do you think
that gravestone really is?
-The gravestone?
-RIVER SONG: Maybe it's a false grave.
CLARA: Maybe it's a false grave.
DOCTOR: Yep, maybe.
Maybe it's a secret entrance
to the tomb.
to the tomb!
Yes, of course. Makes sense.
-They'd never bury my wife out here.
-Your what?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(WHISPERING) The man who lies
will lie no more.
Where this man lies it's Trenzalore.
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
This place is surrounded.
Lay down your weapons
and your deaths will be merciful.
Jenny. Jenny!
This planet is now
property of the Sontaran Empire.
Surrender your women and intellectuals.
Strax, please!
She's dead.
(BEEPING)
No heartbeat.
Complete cardio collapse, shock-induced.
Get her back for me!
Get her back for me now
or I will cut you to pieces.
-Unhand me, ridiculous reptile.
-(GROANS)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINE)
(JENNY COUGHING)
STRAX: There we go.
Just a standard electrocardio restart.
She'll be fine.
Are you all right, my love?
Can you hear me?
Ah, it is a relatively simple thing.
But I've not found it to be so.
(JENNY GASPING)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
I see you have repaired your pet.
No matter.
I was only attracting your attention.
-I presume I have it?
-Dr Simeon.
This is not possible.
And yet here we are, meeting again.
So very far from home.
He died. You told me.
Simeon died.
But the creature
that possessed him lived on.
I take it I am now talking
to the Great Intelligence?
Welcome to the final resting place
of the cruel tyrant,
of the slaughterer of the 10 billion,
and the vessel of the final darkness.
Welcome to the tomb of the Doctor.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Where are we?
-Catacombs.
-I hate catacombs.
-So how come I met your dead wife?
-Oh, well.
You know how it is when you lose
someone close to you.
I sort of made a backup.
RIVER SONG: I died saving him.
In return, he saved me to a database
in the biggest library in the universe,
left me like a book on a shelf.
Didn't even say goodbye.
He doesn't like endings.
Clara! Come on, run, run!
DR SIMEON: It was a minor skirmish
by the Doctor's blood-soaked standards.
Not exactly the Time War
but enough to finish him.
In the end, it was too much
for the old man.
Blood-soaked?
The Doctor has been many things,
but never blood-soaked.
Tell that to the leader of the Sycorax,
or Solomon the trader.
Or the Cybermen or the Daleks.
The Doctor lives his life
in darker hues day upon day.
And he will have other names
before the end.
Storm, the Beast, the Vale yard.
Even if any of this were true,
which I take the liberty of doubting,
how did you come by this information?
I am information.
You were a mind without a body
last time we met.
-And you were supposed to stay that way.
-Alas, I did.
As you can see.
-Okay, come on, quickly.
-Ah!
-(SNARLING)
-Doctor!
Clara!
Clara! (GRUNTS)
Ah!
(PANTING)
Yowza.
There's still a bit of a climb.
I think I remember the way.
Clara?
Clara, hey, it's okay. You're fine.
The dimensioning forces
this deep in the Tardis,
-they can make you a bit giddy.
-I know, I know.
How do I know?
-How do I know that?
-Clara, it's okay.
-You're fine.
-Have we... Have we done this before?
We have.
We have done this before,
climbing through a wrecked Tardis.
You said things.
Things I'm not supposed to remember.
We can't do this now.
The Tardis is a ruin.
The telepathic circuits are awakening
memories you shouldn't even have.
Why do I keep meeting you?
Clara?
The Dalek asylum,
there was a girl in a shipwreck
and she died saving my life.
And she was you.
Clara?
Victorian London. There was a governess
who was really a barmaid
and she died. She was you.
Clara! Clara, what's wrong?
(GASPING)
What do you mean you keep meeting me?
You said I died. How could I die?
That is not a conversation
you should even remember...
What do you mean I died?
WHISPER MEN: The girl who died
he tries to save.
She'll die again beside his grave.
Run. Run!
The doors require a key.
The key is a word.
The word is the Doctor's.
DOCTOR: Here I am.
Late to my own funeral.
Glad you could make it.
-Jenny.
-DR SIMEON: Open the door, Doctor.
Speak and open your tomb.
-No.
-Because you know what's in there?
I will not open those doors.
The key is a word lost to time,
a secret hidden in the deepest shadow
and known to you alone.
-The answer to a question.
-I will not open my tomb.
Doctor,
what is your name?
The Doctor's friends.
Stop their hearts.
(SNARLING)
Madame, boys, combat formation.
They are unarmed.
-So are we.
-Do not divulge our military secrets.
Stop this, leave them alone.
Your name, Doctor. Answer me.
CLARA: Doctor?
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMS)
Do you want me to do that again?
DR SIMEON: Doctor Who?
(SCREAMING)
-Please, stop it.
-Doctor Who?
Unhand me, sir!
(SCREAMING)
Leave him alone, let him be.
Don't worry, sir.
I think I've got him rattled.
JENNY: Don't! (GRUNTING)
Doctor!
-Doctor Who?
-Please!
Ah!
RIVER SONG: The Tardis
can still hear me.
Lucky thing.
Since him indoors is being so useless.
Why did you open the door, sir?
I had them on the run.
I didn't do it.
I didn't say my name.
No. But I did.
Is everyone all right?
Is everyone okay?
-Clara? Clara?
-(COUGHING)
Clara, are you okay?
-That was not nice.
-I know, I know. I'm sorry.
Now, then.
Dr Simeon
or Mr G Intelligence,
whatever I call you,
do you know what's in there?
DR SIMEON: For me, peace at last.
For you, pain everlasting.
Won't you invite us in?
(GRUNTING)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
What's that?
What were you expecting, a body?
Bodies are boring.
I've had loads of them.
That's not what my tomb is for.
But what is the light?
It's beautiful.
-Shall I destroy it?
-Shut up, Strax.
Doctor, explain, what is that?
The tracks of my tears.
Less poetry, Doctor. Just tell them.
Time travel is damage.
It's like a tear
in the fabric of reality.
That is the scar tissue of my journey
though the universe,
my path through time and space,
from Gallifrey to Trenzalore.
FIRST DOCTOR:
Have you ever thought what it's like
to be wanderers in the Fourth Dimension?
SECOND DOCTOR:
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred
the most terrible things.
NINTH DOCTOR: Absolutely fantastic!
(DOCTORS' SPEECH OVERLAPPING)
My own personal time tunnel.
All the days,
even the ones that I, uh...
Even the ones that I haven't lived yet.
(GRUNTS)
-Doctor! Doctor. Doctor!
-(GASPING)
Which is why I shouldn't be here.
The paradoxes, it's very bad.
(GROANING) No.
No, what are you doing?
Somebody stop him!
The Doctor's life is an open wound.
And an open wound can be entered.
No, it will destroy you.
Not at all. It will kill me.
It will destroy you.
I can rewrite your every living moment.
I can turn every one of your victories
into defeats.
Poison every friendship.
Deliver pain to your every breath.
It will burn you up. Once you
go through, you can't come back.
You will be scattered along my timeline
like confetti.
It matters not, Doctor.
You thwarted me at every turn.
Now you will give me peace
as I take my revenge,
every second of your life. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Doctor.
(SIMEON SCREAMING)
(WHISPER MEN SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
-(SCREAMING)
-What's wrong with him?
What's happening?
He's being rewritten.
VASTRA: Simeon is attacking
his entire timeline.
-He's dying all at once.
-(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
-The Dalek asylum, Androzani.
-(SCREAMING)
What did you say?
Did you say the Dalek asylum?
Now he's dying in London, with us.
(ROARING)
SIMEON: (ECHOING) It is done.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
Oh, dear goddess.
-What's wrong?
-The universe without the Doctor.
There will be consequences.
Jenny, with me.
The Dalek asylum.
You said it was me that saved you, how?
Victorian London, how? How could
I have been in Victorian London?
(GROANING)
DOCTOR: Now, please, stop my life.
My whole life is burning.
What are you scanning for?
-Local star systems.
-STRAX: Why?
-Because they're disappearing.
-Disappearing how?
The Doctor's timeline
has been corrupted,
his every victory reversed.
Think how many lives that man saved,
how many worlds!
He saved your life when we met.
Jenny?
Please, Jenny. No!
Oh, God! Oh, please, no.
(BEEPING)
STRAX: Reptile scum.
(GASPING)
You are an affront to Sontaran purity.
-Prepare to perish.
-We're friends.
Strax, your past is changing.
But I swear, we are comrades.
Die, reptile!
(SIGHING)
Strax?
Strax!
I have to go in there.
Please... Please, no.
But this is what I've already done.
You've already seen me do it.
I'm the impossible girl.
And this is why.
Whatever you're thinking
of doing, don't.
If I step in there, what happens?
RIVER SONG: The time winds will tear you
into a million pieces.
A million versions of you,
living and dying
all over time and space,
like echoes.
But the echoes
could save the Doctor, right?
But they won't be you.
The real you will die.
They'll just be copies.
But they'll be real enough to save him.
It's like my mum said,
"The souffle isn't the souffle,
the souffle is the recipe.”
It's the only way to save him, isn't it?
VASTRA: The stars are going out.
And Jenny and Strax are dead.
There must be something we can do.
Well, how about that?
I'm Souffle Girl after all.
No. Breathe.
If this works,
get out of here as fast as you can.
And spare me a thought now and then.
No, Clara...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
In fact, you know what?
Run. Run, you clever boy.
And remember me.
No! Clara!
CLARA: I don't know where I am.
Clara!
I just know I'm running.
Sometimes it's like I've lived
a thousand lives in a thousand places.
I'm born, I live, I die.
(GASPING)
And always there's the Doctor.
Always I'm running to save the Doctor,
again and again and again.
Oi!
And he hardly ever hears me.
But I've always been there.
-Doctor?
-Yes? What is it? What do you want?
Right from the very beginning.
Sorry. But you're about to make
a very big mistake.
Don't steal that one, steal this one.
The navigation system's knackered
but you'll have much more fun.
Right from the day he started running.
Run, you clever boy.
And remember me.
It was an unprovoked and violent attack
but that's no excuse.
We are all restored,
that's all that matters now.
We are not all restored.
RIVER SONG: You can't go in there.
It's your own time stream,
for God's sake.
-I have to get her back.
-Of course, but not like this.
But how?
Is she still alive?
It killed Dr Simeon.
Clara's got one advantage
over the Great Intelligence.
-Which is?
-Me.
Doctor, please listen to me,
at least hear me.
Now, if I don't come back,
and I might not...
-Doctor.
-...go to the Tardis,
the fast return protocol should be on.
She'll take you home,
then shut herself down.
There has to be another way.
Use the Tardis, use something!
Save her, yes,
but for God's sake, be sensible...
How are you even doing that?
I'm not really here.
You're always here to me.
And I always listen.
And I can always see you.
Then why didn't you speak to me?
Because I thought
it would hurt too much.
I believe I could have coped.
No, I thought it would hurt me.
And I was right.
Since nobody else in this room
can see you, God knows how that looked.
There is a time to live
and a time to sleep.
You are an echo, River.
Like Clara, like all of this.
In the end, my fault, I know.
But you should have faded by now.
It's hard to leave
when you haven't said goodbye.
Then tell me, because I don't know.
How do I say it?
There's only one way I'd accept.
If you've ever loved me,
say it like you're going to come back.
Well, then.
See you around, Professor River Song.
Till the next time, Doctor.
-Don't wait up.
-Oh, there's one more thing.
-Isn't there always?
-I was mentally linked with Clara.
If she's really dead,
then how can I still be here?
Okay. How?
Spoilers.
Goodbye...
Sweetie.
CLARA: I don't know where I am.
I don't know where I'm going
or where I've been.
I was born to save the Doctor.
But the Doctor is safe now.
I'm the impossible girl
and my story is done.
(GRUNTS)
(LOUD THUD)
(WIND SWIRLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
Doctor?
Doctor!
(LOUD THUD)
Please, please. I don't know where I am!
(SOBBING)
-DOCTOR: Clara.
-(GASPS)
You can hear me. I know you can.
-I don't see you.
-I'm everywhere.
You're inside my time screen.
Everything around you is me.
I can see you.
All your different faces are here.
DOCTOR: Those are my ghosts, my past.
Every good day, every bad day.
(DOCTOR SCREAMING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(GRUNTS)
I'm not sure what's happening.
DOCTOR: I'm inside my own time stream.
It's collapsing in on itself.
Well, get out, then!
DOCTOR: Not until I've got you.
CLARA: (SOBBING)
I don't even know who I am.
DOCTOR: You're my impossible girl.
I'm sending you something.
Not from my past, from yours.
Look up. Look.
This is you, Clara.
Everything you were or will be.
Take it
You blew into the world on this leaf.
Hold tight, it will take you home.
(LOUD THUD)
DOCTOR: Clara.
Clara. Clara, come on!
Come on. To me, now.
You can do it. I know you can.
How?
Because it's impossible
and you're my impossible girl.
How many times have you saved me, Clara?
Just this once, just for the hell of it,
let me save you.
You have to trust me, Clara. I am real.
Just one more step.
(CLARA SOBBING)
Clara! My Clara!
Who's that?
-Never mind. Let's get back.
-But who is he?
He's me.
There's only me here, that's the point.
Now, let's get back.
But I never saw that one.
I saw all of you.
Eleven faces, all of them you.
You're the 11th Doctor.
I said he was me,
I never said he was the Doctor.
I don't understand.
Look, my name, my real name...
That is not the point.
The name I chose is the Doctor.
The name you choose,
it's like a promise you make.
He's the one who broke the promise.
-(GASPING)
-Clara? Clara! Clara!
(GRUNTING)
He is my secret.
-MAN: What I did, I did without choice.
-I know.
In the name of peace and sanity.
But not in the name of the Doctor.