TASHA LEM: Once there was a planet,
much like any other
and unimportant.
This planet sent the universe
a message,
a bell tolling among the stars,
ringing out to all
the dark corners of creation.
And everybody came to see.
Although no one understood the message,
everyone who heard it
found themselves afraid,
except one man,
the man who stayed for Christmas.
I bring proof of courage
and comradeship.
What is this ship and why are you here?
Identify yourselves by species
and planet of origin.
(SONIC BEEPING)
Exterminate!
-Exterminate!
-Handles?
-Handles, wrong ship.
-Exterminate!
-Ah! Handles, it's wrong. Handles!
Exterminate!
Every ship I go on,
they just shoot at me.
Handles, I said put me on a ship.
I didn't say put me on a Dalek ship.
Don't put me on a Dalek ship
when I'm holding a broken bit of Dalek!
Ow!
-You did not indicate a preference.
-Use your head!
It's not like you've got a lot
of alternatives. They're all here.
Daleks, Sontarans,
Terileptils, Slitheen,
and they're not even fighting,
they're just parked. Why?
The message was received
throughout the universe.
Yes, yes, the message, the message.
Even I can't translate it.
Why is everyone here
if they don't understand it?
You're here.
Well, you know.
I'm OCD, what's their excuse?
What does this message mean?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Oh, no! And remind me,
I've got to patch the telephone
back through the console unit,
this is getting ridiculous.
-Attention! Information available.
-Okay.
You must patch the telephone device
back through the console unit.
No, no, no, no, no, not now!
Remind me later.
-When?
-I don't know, just later,
-just pick a time.
-When?
I don't know, just any old time,
just when you think I've forgotten.
-When?
-Just pick a random number,
express that number
as a quantity of minutes
and when that time has elapsed,
remind me to patch the telephone
back through the console unit.
Affirmative.
-(TELEPHONE RINGING)
-How those Cyber-evenings must fly.
-Hello, the Tardis.
-Emergency. You're my boyfriend.
Ding-dong! Okay, brilliant.
I may be a bit rusty in some areas
but I will glance at a manual.
No, no, you're not actually
my boyfriend.
Well, that was quick.
It's a roller coaster, this phone call.
But I need a boyfriend really quickly.
Well, I hope you're nicer
to the next one.
No, shut up! Christmas dinner,
-me cooking.
-So?
So I may have accidentally
invented a boyfriend.
Yeah, I did that once. And there's
no easy way to get rid of an android.
No, not an android, a pretend one,
an imaginary one,
and I said he'd be coming
to Christmas dinner.
Yeah.
Handles, that's a new ship.
Okay, we'll take the Tardis this time.
I just need you to come for
Christmas dinner, just do that for me.
Just come to Christmas dinner
and be my Christmas date.
Sorry, missed that last bit.
Got to dash!
Okay, don't be alarmed, I come in...
Alert alert!
Peace. No!
Intruder detected.
The intruder will be upgraded.
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Sorry!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
I need you.
I'm cooking Christmas dinner!
-I'm being shot at by Cybermen!
-Well, can't we do both?
Ohh... Yeah, why not?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
PRESENTERS: Happy Christmas!
-How's the turkey doing?
-Great, yeah, yeah, it's doing great.
Well, dead and decapitated, but that's
Christmas when you're a turkey.
Actually, maybe I will have
a little more.
-There you go, Gran.
-Did you put it in early enough?
Dad, I put it in when you phoned me.
-I emailed you some instructions.
-Oh, you certainly did.
(WHOOSHING)
Doctor, I so need you...
Clara!
No, stop. Stop, don't move.
Don't do anything.
-Why, what is it? What's wrong?
-You're naked.
Yes, I am naked.
I wondered if you'd notice.
-Doctor, why are you naked?
-Because I'm going to church.
-Better?
-Oh, that was quick.
Hologram clothes, projected directly
onto your visual cortex.
-So you're still naked underneath?
-Everybody's naked underneath.
Ugh! Don't say things like that,
it's Christmas.
Come meet my family.
Hello! So, er, here he is!
Hello, the Oswalds! Hello!
Merry Christmas. Hello, hello!
Hello, handsome.
Anyone for Twister?
So, this is the Doctor, my boyfriend.
(GRAN GIGGLES)
CLARA: Isn't anybody going to say hello?
Hello. (GIGGLES)
Excuse me a moment.
Listen, I've got an idea
to break the ice.
Why don't I project my clothes hologram
onto their visual cortexes, too?
So, to be clear, no one except me
can see your clothes?
Yes, and I'm starting to think
it may be causing tension.
Are we playing Twister now?
-Get in the kitchen!
-Hey? Sorry!
Sorry, he's Swedish.
Doctor, please!
Oh, that's never going to work, is it?
What's wrong?
Do you not think it's done yet?
I think a decent vet would
give it an even chance.
-Okay, well, use an app.
-An app?
On your screwdriver, app it.
Most certainly not,
it doesn't do turkey.
Nothing does turkey,
you'd need a time machine.
What?
You can't keep using
the Tardis like this.
Like what?
Missed birthdays, restaurant bookings.
And please, just learn
how to use iPlayer.
Ooh, vortex cooking?
Yep, exposure to the time winds.
It'll either come up a treat
or just possibly lay some eggs.
-CYBERHEAD: Information available.
-What's that?
Just a bit of a Cyberman.
He'll get us to the church on time.
I have developed a fault.
The organics are all gone but there's
still a full set of data banks.
Found it at the Maldovar market.
Planet identified
from analysis of message.
Right, cool. Go on, then, okay, tell us.
What is the planet? Go on.
Processing official designation.
Processing.
Okay, in your own time, dear,
don't rush.
So why haven't you just gone down there,
had a look?
It's shielded.
Even the Tardis can't break through it.
Gallifrey.
What did you say?
What are you talking about, Gallifrey?
What do you mean?
Confirmed.
Planet designation, Gallifrey.
You see that? Gallifrey is my home,
I know it when I see it.
That is not Gallifrey!
-Doctor, are you okay?
-It's not Gallifrey. Gallifrey's gone.
Unless... Unless you saved it.
You thought you might have.
Even if it survived,
it's gone from this universe.
That is not my home.
It can't be.
(SHIP'S HORN BLARING)
What's that?
The Papal Mainframe.
It's like a great big flying church.
The first ship to arrive,
they're the ones
who shielded the planet,
they can get us down there.
CLARA: Friend of yours?
Tasha Lem, the Mother Superious.
-Oh, she's inviting us aboard.
-Why?
Because I asked her. Swallow this.
-What is it?
-Your hologram projector.
You can't go to church
with your clothes on!
I don't feel like I'm wearing anything.
-I know, relaxing, isn't it?
-What is this place?
The Church of the Papal Mainframe,
security hub of the known universe.
A security church?
Yep, keeping you safe in this world
and the next.
I venerate the exaltation
of the Mother Superious.
Welcome to the Church
of the Papal Mainframe.
Your nudity is appreciated.
Hey, babes.
-Loving the frock.
-Is that a new body? Give us a twirl!
Tash, this old thing? Please!
I've been rocking it for centuries.
Nice, though. Tight.
So, uh, hello! Also here.
Clara, this is Tasha Lem, the head
of the Church of the Papal Mainframe.
(LAUGHING) Tash, this is my...
My associate, Clara Oswald.
Miss Clara Oswald.
We'll go to my chapel.
All honors in place,
no sacrifices required.
It was Tasha who shielded the planet.
But you could sneak me
down there, couldn't you, Tash?
I would have conditions.
I have confidential matters
to discuss with the Doctor.
Would you excuse us?
Anything you have to say to me
you can say in front of Clara.
Well, quite a lot of it.
Probably about half,
maybe a smidge under.
Actually, Clara, would you mind
waiting out here, please?
No worries.
You two get yourselves a room.
Yes, quite. No, stop it!
Boss of the psycho space nuns. So you!
DOCTOR: Well...
(GASPS)
(RASPING)
Doctor.
-That altar looks like a bed.
-That bed looks like an altar.
Yep.
Excuse me.
That message is transmitting
through all of space and time.
What did it make you feel?
Feel?
Every sentient being in the universe
who detected that signal felt something.
Something overpowering.
-What?
-Fear.
Pure, unadulterated dread.
I saw you and then I forgot you,
how does that work?
(RASPING)
Right, what's the signal,
where's it coming from?
It's a settlement.
Human colony, level two.
-A farm, basically.
-Right, anyone been for a look?
Any one ship lands, the rest
will follow, there will be bloodshed.
Fortunately, we got here first,
shielded the planet.
We maintain the truce
by blocking all of them.
Daleks, Cybermen. One of that lot
could break through your defenses.
Perhaps, but they're afraid, remember?
Nobody wants to go first.
-I do.
-I was counting on it.
(RASPING) Confess.
(GASPS)
Confess.
What are you?
Why do I keep forgetting you?
Confess.
To what?
You okay?
Fine. Yeah, fine, sorry.
Right, this is my personal teleport.
I can put you down
just outside the town.
Find the source of the message
and report back to me in one hour.
And on your life, Doctor,
you will cause no trouble down there.
When do I?
Don't answer that.
-What?
-I'm not an idiot.
Everyone in this church is trained
to see straight through holograms.
Ah, great!
Give now. You're taking no
technology of any kind down there.
What can I do with a key? You, in, now.
You could summon your Tardis.
The Tardis doesn't work by remote.
Fine, if it makes you feel any better,
there we are.
Remember, I want you back in one hour.
-(SHIVERING) Oh, cold, very cold.
-Okay, don't worry.
There's a heat loss filter
in your hologram shell,
it'll kick in, just give it a moment.
So, sweet little town covered in snow,
half the universe in terror. Why?
DOCTOR: Why?
-Oh, my God!
-What?
-Something under the snow, it's...
-What is it?
...cold.
Okay, just stand back, please, Clara.
It's stone.
It's just stone, it's only a statue.
-Clara, step away from it!
-(GASPS)
Clara, keep looking at it,
don't look away! Don't even blink!
-What is it?
-There is a Weeping Angel
under the snow.
It looks like a statue, isn't a statue.
Can you get your foot out?
Only if I can get it out of my shoe.
-You're not wearing a shoe.
-Good point.
Okay, just pull, hard!
-I'm trying!
-Go on! One, two, three!
(STRAINING)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
Oh, God!
They're climbing out of the snow.
-Oh! Oh, God.
-Keep looking at them, at all of them.
Why?
Quantum-locked life form,
it can only move if it's unobserved.
What are they doing here?
Same as everybody else,
they must have got past Tasha's shield.
Ah! Keep looking!
I can't, I can't see,
the snow is in my eyes.
Look, I just need to bring
the Tardis down.
-You can't fly it remotely.
-No, but it can hone in on the key.
-She took your key!
-She took one of them.
(GASPS)
Engines activating.
(WHOOSHING)
The old key-in-the-quiff routine,
classic!
Okay, homing in
on the mysterious message.
Ooh, yes, I like that,
the mysterious message.
You shaved your head?
Yep. Clever plan to get us
past the shield.
You got bored one night, didn't you?
Yeah, tiny bit bored.
Is that what happened to your eyebrows?
No, they're just delicate.
Right, setting us down
near the signal's source.
I'm going to turn the engines on silent,
don't want to make a fuss.
-Put it back on.
-Why?
-Your ears are like rocket fins.
-I know.
Oh, it's good to be wearing
clothes again.
That is so much better! Don't you think?
Now, what do we make of this place?
It's two o'clock in the afternoon,
must be very short days here.
The message is coming from that tower.
Hello! Hello there!
Right, we're a couple
from the next town,
my name's probably Hank
or Rock, something like that.
-Or Daisy?
-Shut up.
Hello, good to meet you, nice snow.
-Most pleasant to meet you, too.
-Most pleasant, most pleasant.
I'm the Doctor. I'm a Time Lord
from the planet Gallifrey.
I stole a time machine and ran away
and I've been flouting the principle law
of my own people ever since.
That wasn't quite
what I was meant to say!
I'm an English teacher
from the planet Earth
and I've run off with a man from space
because I really fancy him...
I think perhaps you should
stop talking till you get used to it.
Used to what?
What did you say your name was?
Bubbly personality masking
bossy control freak!
I'm wearing a wig!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
No, ah, I see. Yes, of course.
It's a truth field.
Oh, that is so quaint.
I haven't seen a truth field in years!
I'm wearing a wig!
No one can lie in this town.
Especially this close to the tower.
Doesn't that make life a bit difficult?
-Not at all.
-Yes.
-This town, what's it called?
-It's Christmas.
-It's July.
-No, the town.
The town is Christmas,
that's what it's called.
Be happy here. Be well!
How can a town be called Christmas?
I don't know,
how can an island be called Easter?
Maybe it's just nice here.
I almost hate to find out what's wrong.
There you are.
What took you so long?
What's wrong?
It's only a crack in the wall.
I knew. I always knew it wasn't over.
What is it?
A split in the skin of reality.
A tiny sliver of the 26th of June, 2010.
-The day the universe blew up.
-Missed that.
I rebooted it,
put it all back together again.
That's good.
Well, it was my Tardis that blew it up
in the first place,
I felt a degree of responsibility.
But the scar tissue remains.
A structural weakness
in the whole universe. Whoa!
And someone's trying to get through it
from outside our universe,
from somewhere else.
Of course, of course! Makes sense.
-It does?
-Yes.
If you were trying to break through
a wall, you'd choose the weakest spot.
If you were trying to break
into this universe,
you'd choose this crack because...
No. If you were trying to break back
into this universe.
You said Gallifrey.
Why did you say Gallifrey?
Analysis of message composition
indicates Gallifreyan origin,
according to Tardis data banks.
You said Gallifrey was gone.
No, I said it was in another universe.
The message is coming through here.
The truth field is, too, at a guess.
If it's the Time Lords,
if it's the Time Lords...
Seal of the High Council of Gallifrey,
nicked it off the Master
in the Death Zone.
There is an algorithm imprinted
in the atomic structure,
use it to decode the message.
Message decoding.
Message analysis proceeding.
Information available.
The message is a request
for information.
It's a question.
Why can't you just say it's a question?
It is being projected through
all of time and space
on a repeating cycle.
The oldest question in the universe,
hidden in plain sight...
Warning, translation will be available
to all life-forms in range.
Translation follows.
Doctor who?
THE GENERAL: Doctor who?
Patch me through to the Doctor. Now!
A question only I could answer,
a truth field to make sure
I'm not lying.
If I give my name, they'll know
they've found the right place
and that it's safe to come through.
The Time Lords?
Okay, so what then?
If you answer the question
and they come back, what happens?
Ah, you need to take this to the Tardis
and put it in the charger slot
for the sonic.
Why?
Hell. All hell, that's what happens
if the Time Lords come back.
There's half the universe up there
already, waiting to open fire.
Now, please, go to the Tardis
and just do as I say!
TASHA LEM: Doctor!
Speak with me.
Doctor! Face me now!
Doctor.
Mother Superious, there is only
one thing I need from you.
This planet, what's it called?
Trenzalore.
Okay, is that it?
Are you doing a clever thing?
If you speak your name,
the Time Lords will return.
If they return, they will come in peace.
It doesn't matter, they will be met
with a war that will never end.
The Time War will begin anew.
You know that Doctor.
(BEEP)
Done.
No... Don't you dare, no, no!
(WHOOSHING)
They're asking for my help!
And if you give it
war will be the consequence.
I will not let that happen at any cost.
Speak your name
and this world will burn!
No, this planet is protected.
(BELL TOLLS)
DOCTOR: So, you lot, quick word,
thank you.
Spot of news,
Christmas has a new sheriff.
Hello, everyone, I'm the Doctor.
Attention.
Attention all Chapels and Choirs
of the Papal Mainframe.
The siege of Trenzalore is now begun.
There will now be
an unscheduled faith change.
From this moment on,
I dedicate this church to one cause.
Silence.
The Doctor will not speak his name
and war will not begin.
Silence will fall!
ALL: Silence will fall.
TASHA LEM: In the time that followed,
the Papal Mainframe
strove to maintain the peace
between the Doctor and his enemies.
SONTARAN 1: We remain undetectable
to the Papal Mainframe.
Commander Skarr!
That's the detection warning.
(SONIC BEEPING)
Our invisibility cloak is compromised.
-What's wrong with it?
-I don't know, I can't see it.
Well, it looks invisible to me.
(THUD)
ETHEREAL VOICE:
The Church of the Papal Mainframe
apologizes for your death.
The relevant afterlives
have been notified.
TASHA LEM: As the days passed,
and the years,
the Doctor stayed true to his word.
On the fields of Trenzalore,
he stood as protector, both
of his own people and his new home.
Over time, the Doctor's enemies
would find new,
stranger ways to enter
the town called Christmas.
Are you there?
Hello?
Am I getting warm?
There's another one!
Doctor! Doctor! There's another one.
WOODEN CYBERMAN: Incinerate.
The Doctor is required.
-There you go, Barnable.
-Thanks.
Working fine, nice action.
Don't leave it out in the rain again.
Fixed the wheels and the anti-grave.
-The anti-what's?
-Yeah, might have gone a bit far.
Now, then, what do we have today?
Don't you move one step further.
Wooden Cyberman. Nice, like it.
Low-tech, doesn't set off
the alarms upstairs.
(CREAKING)
Only bit of tech allowed in,
got in before the truce.
Now, I just sent an instruction
to your firearm
to reverse the polarity
and fire out the back end.
Now, as we're standing in a truth field,
you'll understand I cannot be lying.
If you like,
you can scan my screwdriver,
verify that's the signal I sent.
Signal verified.
Yes, I probably should have mentioned,
this doesn't work on wood!
You send your friends up there
a message from the Doctor.
You tell them the Doctor stays.
Next.
(FIREWORKS BURSTING)
TASHA LEM: With every victory,
the town celebrated.
And there's me arm-wrestling
a Draconian...
In time, the Doctor seemed to forget
he'd lived any other life.
DOCTOR: Christmas is defended!
And the people of the town came to love
the man who stayed for Christmas.
If you want to be the drunk giraffe,
you've got to commit!
Don't be cool, guys. Cool is not cool.
ALL: Cool is not cool!
And what's the dance we're doing?
ALL: The drunk giraffe!
The drunk giraffe, yes! Merry Christmas!
Give me a hug, bring it in.
(ALL CHEERING)
How's your father's barn?
You've fixed the leak all right but
he say it's bigger on the inside now.
Shhh! They'll all want one!
(WHOOSHING)
BARNABLE: What is it? What's that noise?
Well, where have you been
for 300 years?
-BARNABLE: What's that?
-It's my ship.
-Your what?
-It's my Tardis.
That's how I got here
in the first place.
Does this mean you're leaving?
(ALL MURMURING)
(CLARA GASPS)
What are you doing here?
-I was in space.
-Well, you were in the time vortex.
She must have extended the force field.
No wonder! No wonder she's late,
dragging you around.
You tricked me.
I saved you!
You didn't even say goodbye!
I am furious with you!
Well, I am not even talking to you!
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
Ah, Doctor, fixing toys
and fighting monsters.
The turkey isn't done yet.
Is it still asking the question?
Oh, it never stops.
Come upstairs, it's almost time.
-What for?
-Dawn.
The light here lasts only a few minutes.
You don't want to miss it.
Well, it's a standoff.
They can't attack in case
I unleash the Time Lords
and I can't run away because they'll
burn this planet to stop the Time Lords.
Hey, after all these years,
I've finally found somewhere
that needs me to stick around.
A town called Christmas.
Could've been worse.
Right, there you go, buddy. Comfy?
(BEEPING)
Comfort is irrelevant.
How's that, is that better?
Affirmative.
You just take it easy, buddy.
He's getting old.
I do my best for him but
I just can't get the parts, you know.
Hey. Know the feeling.
Where'd you get these?
I have a supplier,
the pinks ones are best.
CYBERHEAD: I have developed a fault.
Hey, don't you worry, Handles.
You're just dreaming.
The sun's coming up very soon,
you just hang on in there.
I have developed a fault.
Hey, Handles. Come on. Come on.
One more dawn, you can do it.
You've got it in you, come on,
just hang on in there.
Attention! Emergency! Attention!
Handles? What is it, what's wrong?
Urgent action required!
You must patch the telephone device
back through the console unit.
Come back. Handles?
Handles?
(SIGHS)
Thank you, Handles.
And well done. Well done, mate.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
What do you think of my new place?
Come up here once a day
for a few minutes
to remind myself of what it is
I'm protecting.
It's beautiful.
Why did you send me away?
Because if I hadn't,
I'd have buried you a long time ago.
No, you wouldn't.
I would never have
let you get stuck here.
Ha! Everyone gets stuck somewhere
eventually, Clara.
-Everything ends.
-Except you.
Have you been paying attention?
I'm an old man now.
But you don't die. You change.
You pop right back up with a new face.
No, not forever.
I can change 12 times,
13 versions of me, 13 silly Doctors.
Okay, so you're number 11, so?
Ha! Are we forgetting
Captain Grumpy, huh?
I didn't call myself the Doctor
during the Time War
but it was still a regeneration.
Okay, so you're number 12.
Number 10 once regenerated
and kept the same face.
I had vanity issues at the time.
Twelve regenerations, Clara.
I can't ever do it again.
This is where I end up.
This face, this version of me.
We saw this planet in the future,
remember?
All those graves,
one of them mine.
-Change the future.
-I can't.
-You've got your Tardis back.
-Ha!
You think I'm just going to fly away,
abandon everyone?
Of course not.
But you've been protecting
this town for over 300 years,
do you not think
it's anybody else's go yet?
There is no one else to protect it.
(SIGHS) There's not going
to be you forever.
It's going to end the same way
whatever you do.
Every life I save is a victory.
Every single one.
What about your life?
Just for once, after all of this time,
have you not earned
the right to think about that?
(SIGHS) Sorry.
Wrong thing to say.
We shouldn't be having an argument.
Clara, I've been having that argument
for the last 300 years, all by myself.
But you didn't have your Tardis.
Ah, yes, well,
that made it easier to stay.
True.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
TASHA LEM: Doctor!
Ah, look who's woken up!
The Church of the Silence
requests parlay.
Your rights and safety are sanctified.
I'll be right up.
I'm sending a transporter.
Nah, don't bother.
I've got me motor back.
It's gone dark.
Yeah, well, the sun's gone down.
Already?
Everything ends, Clara.
And sooner than you think.
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
Hmm.
Are you guarding my Tardis, Barnable?
Are you coming back?
Ah, come on. You know me.
I'LL wait.
CLARA: She hasn't aged much.
DOCTOR: No, she's against aging.
Approach.
Confess!/
What are those things?
-Confess!
-DOCTOR: Confessional Priests.
Very popular, genetically engineered so
you forget everything you told them.
-Told who?
-There you go.
-(DOCTOR SNIFFS)
-TASHA LEM: Satisfactory?
Where are the pink ones?
E-numbers.
You're hyper enough as it is.
So this is sweet. Middle of a siege
and you two have little chats?
She's right.
This situation cannot continue.
It can't end, either.
DALEK: Report.
The Time Lord has entered the trap.
Why did you ever come to Trenzalore?
Well, I did come to Trenzalore
and nothing can change that now.
Didn't stop you trying, though, did it?
Not me. The Kovarian Chapter broke away.
They traveled back along your timeline
and tried to prevent
you ever reaching Trenzalore.
So that's who blew up my Tardis.
I thought I'd left the bath running.
They blew up your time capsule,
created the very cracks in the universe
through which the Time Lords
are now calling.
The destiny trap.
You can't change history
if you're part of it.
They engineered
a psychopath to kill you.
Totally married her.
I'd never have made it here
alive without River Song.
I'm not interested in
changing history, Doctor.
I want to change the future.
The Daleks send for
reinforcements daily,
they are massing for war.
Three days ago, they attacked
the Mainframe itself.
-They attacked here?
-How did you stop them?
Stop them?
It was slaughter.
Why didn't you call me?
I could have helped.
I tried.
I died in this room,
screaming your name.
(WHISPERING) No.
Oh, I died.
It's funny the things
that slip your mind.
(GRUNTS)
No! No, no, no, Tasha, no, please!
No, Tasha, no! Fight it.
Tash, fight it!
Step away from the Dalek unit, Doctor.
You shouldn't even know who I am.
Information concerning the Doctor was
harvested from the cadaver of Tasha Lem.
Bet she never told you how to break
the Trenzalore force-field, though.
She'd have died first.
Several times.
Well, you'd better kill me, then, go on.
But before you do...
THE GENERAL: Doctor who?
Doctor who? Doctor who?
I'm a tough old bird,
I'll be ages dying.
Way enough time to answer a question.
And oh dear, what happens then, boys?
-DALEK: You will die in silence, Doctor.
-(GASPS)
Or your associate will die.
Fine, go on. Kill her. Kill her!
See if I care. But tell me,
what are you going to do next?
See how the Time Lord betrays?
You'll kill me anyway,
what difference does it make?
I'm not afraid. I leave that to you.
You see, Tasha,
that's what I'm talking about!
That is a woman!
I always knew you were a bit spineless,
you and your pointless church.
Why did I ever rely on you?
Never trust a nun to do a Doctor's work.
(GRUNTS)
(EXPLOSIONS)
And she's back!
You never could resist a row.
-Kiss me when I ask!
-Well, you'd better ask nicely.
In your dreams!
Right, get us back to the Tardis,
can you do that?
Yep, but quickly,
the Dalek inside me is waking.
-Fight it.
-I can't.
Listen to me,
you have been fighting the psychopath
inside you all your life,
shut up and win!
That is an order, Tasha Lem.
The force-field will hold for a while
but it will decay
and there are breaches already.
Then this isn't a siege anymore,
it's a war.
It's all up to you now,
fight the Daleks, inside and out.
You can do it, I know you can.
Oh, I see.
You've got your Tardis back,
haven't you?
Time to fly away.
Tasha, please, please.
Thank you.
None of this was for you, you
fatuous egotist, it was for the peace.
Fly away, Doctor!
(WHOOSHING)
(TIMER DINGS)
-It's done.
-What is?
Your turkey.
Either that or it's woken up.
-(LAUGHS) You want some?
-Go on, then!
Got any plates?
Do you know,
I've even got Christmas crackers.
One thing.
Give me those big sad eyes,
look at me so I know you're not lying
and tell me you will never
send me away ever again.
Clara Oswald,
I will never send you away again.
CLARA: Turkey smells good!
DOCTOR: Yep, smells great.
CLARA: It's perfect.
Merry Christmas.
Doctor?
(TARDIS DOOR CLOSES)
(WHOOSHING)
If you're not leaving,
why did you bring it back?
It's a reminder.
Besides, I might leave tomorrow
or the next day.
Or the day after that.
TASHA LEM: And so,
to the fields of Trenzalore
came all the Time Lord's enemies.
For this was the winter of the Doctor.
In time, when all other races
had retreated or burned,
only the Church of the Mainframe
remained in the path of the Daleks.
(GROANS)
And so those ancient enemies,
the Doctor and the Silence,
stood back-to-back on
the fields of Trenzalore.
Merry Christmas, everyone!
LINDA: Other fish in the sea,
that's what I'm saying.
Linda, I don't think Clara
wants to talk about it.
I've got a suggestion, that's all.
I've got a list of suggestions.
Linda!
You could make
a boy band out of my list!
-I hate boy bands.
-Of course you don't, not at your age.
These crackers are rubbish.
-LINDA: I bought them.
-I know.
LINDA: They're classy.
They don't have jokes.
Exactly.
They've got poems.
They're more dramatic crackers.
I like the jokes.
Tell us a joke, Gran.
You know loads of jokes.
I think we're probably
talking about my list now.
Probably not.
Tell us how you met Dad.
The thing about the pigeon.
I saw him on a pier, on a rainy day.
No, no. Not that one,
the one about the pigeon.
I'd seen him before, lots of times.
But he just looked
so beautiful standing there.
The pigeon in the restaurant,
you remember?
I wanted everything to stop.
I wanted nothing to change ever again.
If he could just keep standing there,
so beautiful.
Long time ago.
Don't hug me so tight, dear,
you'll break something.
-(SOBBING)
-On that's nice, crying at Christmas.
Sorry.
I hope you made a wish.
(WHOOSHING)
Clara? What's wrong, Clara?
Everybody just stay put!
(PANTING)
You can fly the Tardis?
Flying the Tardis was always easy.
It was flying the Doctor
I never quite mastered.
What's happened to him?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
What am I supposed to do?
He shouldn't die alone.
Go to him.
(EXPLOSION)
DOCTOR: Barnable?
Clara.
Hello, Doctor.
Were you always so young?
Nah. That was you.
Huh.
Seek the Doctor.
-Merry Christmas.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, it's okay. It's fine. Don't worry.
Ah!
Is there a joke, huh?
Extract from Thoughts On A Clock
by Eric Ritchie junior.
Is it a knock-knock one?
Those are the best.
I don't think so.
Well, read it. Go on.
"And now it's time for one last bow
Like all your other selves
"Eleven's hour is over now
The clock is striking twelve's."
I don't get it.
DALEK: Doctor!
The Doctor will be brought!
The Daleks demand the Doctor.
They're here. The Daleks,
we can't stop them. They want you.
All right, Barnable. Are you Barnable?
No, Doctor.
It's okay, Barnable, don't worry.
I have got a plan.
Off you pop.
(EXPLOSION)
I haven't got a plan
but people love it when I say that.
Doctor, what are you going to do?
I don't know. (GROANING)
Talk very fast,
hope something good happens,
take the credit.
That's generally how it works.
-Doctor...
-Not this time, though. This is it.
-No!
-Yes.
We saw the future, Clara.
This is how it ends.
-Change it!
-Ha!
Like Tasha said, change the future!
I could have once,
when there were Time Lords.
Not anymore.
Locate the Doctor.
No, you're going to stay here.
Promise me you will.
-Why?
-I'll be keeping you safe.
One last victory. Allow me that.
Give me that,
my impossible girl.
Thank you
and goodbye.
Trouble with Daleks is
they take so long to say anything.
Probably die of boredom
before they shoot me.
The Doctor is required.
Listen to me, you lot. Listen! Help him.
Help him change the future.
Do it. Do something.
DALEK: Doctor!
You've been asking a question
and it's time someone told you,
you've been getting it wrong.
His name...
His name is the Doctor.
All the name he needs.
Everything you need to know about him.
And if you love him,
then you should...help him.
Help him.
(RUMBLING)
Sorry I'm a bit slow.
I may not be at my best right now.
You are dying, Doctor.
Yes, I'm dying.
You've been trying to kill me
for centuries and here I am,
dying of old age.
If you want something done,
do it yourself.
You will die and the Time Lords
will never return.
You still can't work up the courage
to shoot me, can you?
You're still worried I've got
something up my sleeve!
Well, you knock yourselves out, boys.
I've got nothing this time.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
DALEK: You will die now, Doctor.
This is the end of you.
The rules of regeneration are known.
You have expended all your lives.
Sorry, what did you say?
Did you mention the rules?
Now, listen! Bit of advice.
Tell me the truth
if you think you know it.
Lay down the law
if you're feeling brave.
But Daleks never, ever
tell me the rules!
-Emergency! Emergency!
-(CLOCK CHIMING)
The Doctor is regenerating!
Oh, look at this.
Regeneration number 13.
We're breaking some serious
science here, boys.
I tell you what,
it's gonna be a whopper! Ha-ha!
Exterminate! Exterminate the Doctor.
You think you can stop me now, Daleks?
If you want my life...
(LAUGHS)
...come and get it!
Get inside! Get off the street,
get inside, quick, quick!
(BELL TOLLING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Love from Gallifrey, boys!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Doctor?
(SIGHS)
Doctor!
Hello.
You're young again, you're okay.
You didn't even change your face.
Ha! It's started. I can't stop it now.
This is just the reset.
Whole new regeneration cycle, oh!
-Mmm!
-(LAUGHING)
Taking a bit longer.
Just breaking it in.
Oh!
(GRUNTS)
It all just disappears, doesn't it?
Everything you are, gone in a moment,
like breath on a mirror.
Any moment now
he's a-coming.
-Who's coming?
-The Doctor.
You, you are the Doctor.
Yep, and I always will be.
But times change and so must I.
(GIRL LAUGHS)
Amelia?
Who's Amelia?
The first face this face saw.
We all change. When you think about it,
we are all different people
all through our lives.
And that's okay, that's good,
you gotta keep moving,
so long as you remember
all the people that you used to be.
I will not forget one line of this.
Not one day.
I swear.
I will always remember
when the Doctor was me.
Raggedy man.
Good night.
No! No!
Please don't change.
(GROANS)
Kidneys! I've got new kidneys.
-I don't like the color.
-Of your kidneys?
-What's happening?
-We're probably crashing!
-Into what?
-Stay calm.
Just one question.
Do you happen to know
how to fly this thing?